<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 4:30<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I5089a870411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>4.</label.designator><headtext>Confidential Business Information and the Employment Relationship</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I52517020411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>V.</label.designator><headtext>Fiduciary Duty</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I5251be40411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>A.</label.designator><headtext>Analysis</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f65f316ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>4:30.</label.designator><headtext>Unfair Use of Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>It is clear that while fiduciaries usually cannot directly solicit former customers, they are normally entitled to generally solicit in the marketplace.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4c910f08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>] The Ontario High Court decision in <ital>Berkey Photo (Canada) Ltd. v. Ohlig</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id4c910f18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>] points to the fact that the real test for a fiduciary employee may be whether the employee acted fairly and cautiously in the solicitation of the plaintiff&apos;s clients and refrained from using written information acquired during the course of his or her employment.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The leading case of <ital>Edgar T. Alberts Ltd. v. Mountjoy</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id4c938008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">3</footnote.reference>] also held that a fiduciary will not be allowed to make unfair use of information gained during the course of the employment relationship:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>Thus we have a principle within a principle to the effect that the ex-employee is not entitled to make “an unfair use” of information acquired in the course of his employment, nor may he use confidential information so acquired to advance his own business at the expense of that of his former employer.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0002"/></paratext></para></display.quote><paratext>In the <cite.query w-src-number="0492175884" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1977148370" w-pub-number="0005150" ID="I3f2f44418e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Alberts</ital></cite.query> case, “unfair use” meant that the employee had taken a “substantial natural advantage” that opened up <begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>“the opportunity of taking over for his own profit a substantial trade asset”<end.quote refid="QT_0001"/> of the plaintiff, that being the plaintiff&apos;s relationship with its clients.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4c938018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">4</footnote.reference>] In <ital>Jones v. Klassen</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id4c938028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">5</footnote.reference>] the court relied on the decisions in <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175884" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2011192292" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I3f2f44448e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">RBC Dominion Securities Inc. v. Merrill Lynch Canada</cite.query> Inc.</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id4c938038e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">6</footnote.reference>] and <ital>CIBC World Markets Inc. v. MacDonald</ital>.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4c938048e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">7</footnote.reference>] In summary, where defendants have improperly removed client records that allow them to compete unfairly, the courts are very likely to restrain them. <eos/><bos/>In determining whether a particular piece of information should be considered confidential business information, it is appropriate to factor in the interests of third party clients to whom all those engaged in the litigation owe duties of competence and honesty are owed. <eos/><bos/>The specific clients&apos; interests may inform the decision as to whether an employee unfairly used confidential business information. <eos/><bos/>In <cite.query w-src-number="0492175884" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2011192292" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I3f2f44468e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>RBC Dominion Securities Inc. v. Merrill Lynch Canada Inc.</ital></cite.query>, the important interest of a client knowing that his financial investment advisor had changed firms led the British Columbia Court of Appeal to conclude that the advisors who left RBC were entitled to prepare and remove client lists but were not entitled to take copies of accounts or other documents regarding RBC clients. <eos/><bos/>In <ital>Unified Freight Services Ltd. v. Therriault</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id4c95f108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">8</footnote.reference>] the court found evidence that the defendant&apos;s motive was to remove confidential customer and service-provider information from Unified and stockpile it:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0003"/>Certainly, the more information he had, the more marketable he would become and the more able to get up and running quickly when and if he decided to open his own shop or join another company.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0003"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0004"/>Where Mr. Therriault crossed the line and breached his fiduciary obligations was through soliciting business in his letter to Unified customers dated January 15, 2001. <eos/><bos/>He compounded that breach of fiduciary duty when he followed up on that letter by telling the customers where he could be found --- at Titan.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0004"/></paratext></para></display.quote><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A number of subsequent cases have reinforced the concept of “general fairness”.<eos/><bos/> In <ital>57134 Manitoba Ltd. v. Palmer</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id4c95f118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">9</footnote.reference>] the court held that the defendant did have the right to solicit customers, but that <begin.quote ID="QT_0005"/>“he only had the right to do so fairly”<end.quote refid="QT_0005"/>. <eos/><bos/>In the circumstances of the case, the employee&apos;s activities were held to be “unfair” by any standard. <eos/><bos/>Many cases such as <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175884" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1993382959" w-pub-number="0005628" ID="I3f3119018e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Sure-Grip Fasteners Ltd v. Allgrade Bolt &amp; Chain</cite.query> Inc.</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id4c95f128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">10</footnote.reference>] frequently use terminology such as “fair competition”.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Embedia Technologies Corporation v. Blumell</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id4c95f138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">11</footnote.reference>] Embedia&apos;s application for an interim injunction enjoining the Blumell companies from using or disclosing to anyone what the parties agreed would be considered “Confidential Information”, continuing employment with, contracting with, or otherwise working with Draper with respect to <begin.quote ID="QT_0006"/>“Intelliflex/IO and any other Embedia products”<end.quote refid="QT_0006"/>, and being similarly engaged with any other Embedia customer, with respect to “Intelliflex/IO and any other Embedia products” was dismissed.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4ca97908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">12</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Blumell was a part owner in Embedia, was one of its directors, and was its most senior employee. <eos/><bos/>He was its most significant public face and client liaison. <eos/><bos/>He ran the company. <eos/><bos/>He oversaw sales, pricing, and marketing of Embedia products, as well as customer negotiations and relationships. <eos/><bos/>As an engineer and one of the founding partners, he was heavily involved in the development of the software and other knowledge-based assets of Embedia. <eos/><bos/>He signed a Non-Disclosure Agreement with Embedia, promising to not disclose any trade secrets, confidential information, or any other proprietary data. <eos/><bos/>Blumell resigned and since then, Embedia alleged that he had acted in breach of his contractual and fiduciary duties.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4cb0cc08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">13</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The first step of the well-known tripartite test for an injunction is modified in cases where, as here, the effect of the injunction may be to restrict the defendant&apos;s employment in a particular field. <eos/><bos/>Justice Jeffrey observed that Embedia was incorrect when it submitted that the first step threshold <begin.quote ID="QT_0008"/>“is a low one which only requires the applicant to demonstrate that the claim is not frivolous or vexatious, and that there is a serious issue to be tried”<end.quote refid="QT_0008"/>. <eos/><bos/>The first step threshold an applicant faces in a case such as this is much higher. <eos/><bos/>The applicant must demonstrate a “strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case” against the respondent. <eos/><bos/>A strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case means one that will “probably prevail at trial” or is “likely to succeed at trial”.<eos/><bos/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id4cb0cc18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">14</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Jeffrey was not persuaded that Embedia was likely to succeed in proving Blumell misappropriated to himself an opportunity to participate in the development of Draper&apos;s new smart motor product (Intelliflex/IO) that was available to Embedia. <eos/><bos/>Draper acknowledged receipt of the Embedia proposal but declined the offer, leaving only the impression that if in the future Draper became interested that it might then follow-up, nothing more. <eos/><bos/>It appeared that Draper did not see a role for Embedia while Blumell was with Embedia. <eos/><bos/>To the extent Blumell manipulated the circumstances in that direction he was in breach but Embedia did not have a strong prima facie case on that point.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4cb33d08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">15</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Jeffrey agreed that certain of the events pre- and post- resignation were consistent with Blumell having perhaps orchestrated or manipulated the chain of events to his own advantage, in conflict with his duty to Embedia. <eos/><bos/>Embedia pointed to evidence suggesting: Blumell first became interested in working with Draper personally, not as part of Embedia, since almost two years before his resignation; Blumell expressed his interest to the Embedia board, in March 2014, of working as an independent contractor but after the board said it would be a conflict of interest, he stated a week later he was no longer pursuing that; Blumell declined contributing more capital into Embedia in November 2015 when it was needed; and Blumell tried to sell his equity interest in Embedia around that time. <eos/><bos/>Justice Jeffery acknowledged that certain conduct of Blumell raised definite questions about whether he pursued his own interests to the detriment of Embedia&apos;s. <eos/><bos/>The most disconcerting events appeared to be (i) his involvement for Draper in the development of Intelliflex/IO, (ii) his signing a personal non-disclosure agreement with Draper committing to not disclosing to Embedia what he would then learn from Draper while running Embedia, and (iii) his resisting others at Embedia wanting to include a non-solicitation clause in an arrangement with Draper that would prohibit Draper from attracting Embedia employees. <eos/><bos/>However, Blumell explained each of the events by quite a different rationale than Embedia theorized. <eos/><bos/>Justice Jeffrey was not persuaded that Embedia&apos;s theory of the events of Blumell acting in breach of fiduciary duty was “likely to prevail” at trial. <eos/><bos/>The parties&apos; evidence would need to be heard on such matters for a court to assess where the truth might fall. <eos/><bos/>A likelihood of success by Embedia was not apparent at this stage. <eos/><bos/>Justice Jeffrey was unable to conclude that Embedia was likely to prevail at trial in part because of the conflicting evidence on material points. <eos/><bos/>While conflicting evidence on an interlocutory application is not necessarily cause for the court to shy away from a pre-trial disposition, it is when the evidence conflicts on material points in dispute.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4cb33d18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">16</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Draper witness said Blumell&apos;s role was <begin.quote ID="QT_0009"/>“to oversee the development of the”<end.quote refid="QT_0009"/> new product. <eos/><bos/>Justice Jeffrey observed that Embedia was not likely to succeed in showing Blumell&apos;s ‘overseeing’ was something that breached a fiduciary duty, such as being something he would have done under the banner of Embedia if still there. <eos/><bos/>Embedia was not likely to succeed in showing Blumell&apos;s interfacing was something that breached a fiduciary duty, without more. <eos/><bos/>That company that the Draper witness said was developing the product was more likely the entity doing, among other things more broadly on that project, the niche role Embedia sought. <eos/><bos/>In other words, it appeared the opportunity Embedia sought did not go to Blumell but to a company with which he interfaced on behalf of Draper.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4cb33d28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">17</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Blumell acknowledged that he played a role with respect to Intelliflex/IO coming to market. <eos/><bos/>However, it was not an Embedia product; not even a component aspect of it was a product opportunity still available to Embedia; and it did not appear certain that Blumell was involved in its readiness for market in any way that Embedia was proposing to be involved when Blumell was part of Embedia.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4cb33d38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">18</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Id4c910f08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175884" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1986268016" w-pub-number="0005653" ID="I3f4452e18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Coin-A-Matic (Pacific) Ltd. v. Saibil</ital></cite.query> (1986), 13 C.C.E.L. 59, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175884" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1986268016" w-pub-number="0005653" ID="I3f4452e28e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">12 C.P.R. (3d) 33 (B.C.S.C.)</cite.query>, which relied on <cite.query w-src-number="0492175884" w-seq-number="00007" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1985030763" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I3f4452e48e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Faccenda Chicken Ltd. v. Fowler</ital>, [1986] 1 All E.R. 617 (C.A.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175884" w-seq-number="00008" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1983171055" w-pub-number="0005150" ID="I3f4452e68e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>White Oaks Welding Supplies v. Tapp</ital> (1983), 149 D.L.R. (3d) 159, 42 O.R. (2d) 445 (H.C.J.)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>In one case, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175884" w-seq-number="00009" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1981177530" w-pub-number="0005150" ID="I3f4452e98e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>309925 Ontario Ltd. v. Tyrrell</ital> (1981), 127 D.L.R. (3d) 99 (Ont. H.C.J.)</cite.query>, it was held that there was a “right” and even a “moral obligation” to notify customers. <eos/><bos/>Other cases have concluded that fiduciary employees must be careful not to solicit employees of their former employer: see <ital>Corporate Classic Caterers v. Dynapro Systems Inc.</ital> (1997), 33 C.C.E.L. (2d) 58 (B.C.S.C.); <ital>Alnor Services Ltd. v. Sawyer</ital> (1990), 31 C.C.E.L. 34 (B.C.S.C.); <cite.query w-src-number="0492175884" w-seq-number="00010" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2009692908" w-pub-number="0006459" ID="I3f4452eb8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>C.B. Constantini Ltd. v. Slozka</ital>, 2006 BCSC 1210</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4c910f18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175884" w-seq-number="00011" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1983176309" w-pub-number="0005505" ID="I3f4516308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Berkey Photo (Canada) Ltd. v. Ohlig</ital> (1983), 43 O.R. (2d) 518, 2</cite.query> C.C.E.L. 113 (H.C.J.); <cite.query w-src-number="0492175884" w-seq-number="00012" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026833645" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I3f4516328e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Hub International (Richmond Auto Mall) Ltd. v. Mendham</ital>, 2011 CarswellBC 3672, 2011 BCSC 1780</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4c938008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175884" w-seq-number="00013" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1977148370" w-pub-number="0005150" ID="I3f453d408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgar T. Alberts Ltd. v. Mountjoy</ital> (1977), 79 D.L.R. (3d) 108 at p. 689, 16 O.R. (2d) 682 (H.C.J.)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>See also, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175884" w-seq-number="00014" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1994406465" w-pub-number="0005506" ID="I3f453d438e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Canadian Industrial Distributors Inc. v. Drague</ital> (1994), 20 O.R. (3d) 574, 7</cite.query> C.C.E.L. (2d) 60 (Gen. Div.).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4c938018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>4</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175884" w-seq-number="00015" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1977148370" w-pub-number="0005150" ID="I3f45d9808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgar T. Alberts Ltd. v. Mountjoy</ital> (1977), 79 D.L.R. (3d) 108 at p. 690, 16 O.R. (2d) 682 (H.C.J.)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>The courts have also used the concept of the employer&apos;s “vulnerability” to analyze the actions of an employee. <eos/><bos/>See, for example, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175884" w-seq-number="00016" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1985262283" w-pub-number="0005653" ID="I3f45d9838e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EJ Personnel Services Inc. v. Quality Personnel Inc.</ital> (1985), 6 C.P.R. (3d) 173 (Ont. H.C.J.)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>See also, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175884" w-seq-number="00017" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2002057671" w-pub-number="0006729" ID="I3f45d9868e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>KJA Consultants Inc. v. Soberman</ital></cite.query> (2002), 17 C.C.E.L. (3d) 261, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175884" w-seq-number="00018" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2002057671" w-pub-number="0006729" ID="I3f45d9878e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">[2002] O.J. No. 489 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175884" w-seq-number="00019" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027253060" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3f45d9898e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>GasTOPS Ltd. v. Forsyth</ital>, 2012 CarswellOnt 2539, 2012 ONCA 134</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4c938028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>5</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>Jones v. Klassen</ital> (2006), 55 Alta. L.R. (4th) 354 (Q.B.).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4c938038e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>6</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175884" w-seq-number="00020" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2011192292" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I3f4739118e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>RBC Dominion Securities Inc. v. Merrill Lynch Canada Inc.</ital></cite.query> (2003), 55 C.C.E.L. (3d) 179 (B.C.S.C.), supp. reasons 55 C.C.E.L. (3d) 208 (B.C.S.C.), appeal allowed in part <cite.query w-src-number="0492175884" w-seq-number="00021" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2011192292" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I3f4739128e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">275 D.L.R. (4th) 385 (B.C.C.A.)</cite.query>, <case.history>appeal allowed in part</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175884" w-seq-number="00022" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017227608" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I3f4739148e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">298 D.L.R. (4th) 1 (S.C.C.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4c938048e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>7</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175884" w-seq-number="00023" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2000551071" w-pub-number="0006698" ID="I3f4760208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>CIBC World Markets Inc. v. MacDonald</ital>, [2000] B.C.J. No. 1560 (S.C.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4c95f108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>8</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175884" w-seq-number="00024" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2008062525" w-pub-number="0005628" ID="I3f4787308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Unified Freight Services Ltd. v. Therriault</ital>, 2006 C.L.L.C. ¶ 210-010 (Alta. Q.B.)</cite.query>, at paras. 63-64.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4c95f118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>9</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>57134 Manitoba Ltd. v. Palmer</ital> (1989), 37 B.C.L.R. (2d) 50 at p. 56, 44 B.L.R. 94 (C.A.).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4c95f128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>10</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175884" w-seq-number="00025" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1993382959" w-pub-number="0005628" ID="I3f48bfb18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sure-Grip Fasteners Ltd v. Allgrade Bolt &amp; Chain Inc.</ital></cite.query> (1993), 45 C.C.E.L. 276 at p. 288, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175884" w-seq-number="00026" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1993382959" w-pub-number="0005628" ID="I3f48bfb28e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">93 C.L.L.C. ¶ 14,021</cite.query> (Ont. Ct. (Gen. Div.)).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4c95f138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>11</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175884" w-seq-number="00027" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225421" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3f48e6c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Embedia Technologies Corporation v. Blumell</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 594, 2018 ABQB 222</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4ca97908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>12</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175884" w-seq-number="00028" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225421" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3f4934e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Embedia Technologies Corporation v. Blumell</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 594, 2018 ABQB 222</cite.query>, at paras. 1 and 10.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4cb0cc08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>13</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175884" w-seq-number="00029" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225421" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3f495bf08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Embedia Technologies Corporation v. Blumell</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 594, 2018 ABQB 222</cite.query>, at paras. 2-3.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4cb0cc18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>14</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175884" w-seq-number="00030" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225421" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3f4983008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Embedia Technologies Corporation v. Blumell</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 594, 2018 ABQB 222</cite.query>, at paras. 8-9.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4cb33d08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>15</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175884" w-seq-number="00031" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225421" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3f49aa108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Embedia Technologies Corporation v. Blumell</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 594, 2018 ABQB 222, at para. 11</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4cb33d18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>16</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175884" w-seq-number="00032" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225421" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3f49d1208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Embedia Technologies Corporation v. Blumell</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 594, 2018 ABQB 222</cite.query>, at paras. 12-14.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4cb33d28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>17</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175884" w-seq-number="00033" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225421" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3f49f8308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Embedia Technologies Corporation v. Blumell</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 594, 2018 ABQB 222</cite.query>, at paras. 18-19.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4cb33d38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>18</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175884" w-seq-number="00034" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225421" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3f4a1f408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Embedia Technologies Corporation v. Blumell</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 594, 2018 ABQB 222, at para. 20</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 4:30<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
