<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 7:3<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I56d26460411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>7.</label.designator><headtext>Remedies for Breach of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I56dbb330411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>II.</label.designator><headtext>Equitable Relief</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I56dc0150411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>A.</label.designator><headtext>Interim and Interlocutory Injunctions</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f6fb8f6ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>7:3.</label.designator><headtext>Prima Facie Test</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Where the <ital>prima facie</ital> test is used, the moving party must show that there is a likelihood that he or she will succeed at trial.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82beb008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>] In an action for breach of confidential business information, this means that the moving party must show that the information is, in fact, confidential.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82beb018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>] The only exception to this is where the information has been published and the courts, for public policy reasons, order that the wrongdoer not be entitled to continue to benefit from the wrongdoing. <eos/><bos/>However, even in such a case, the moving party must establish that the information was confidential and would have remained so but for the wrongdoing of the responding party.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82beb028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">3</footnote.reference>] The <ital>prima facie</ital> test involves a higher duty than when the test is whether there is a serious issue to be tried.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82beb038e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">4</footnote.reference>] Further, the moving party must establish that it would be unjust not to grant the injunction.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82beb048e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">5</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Dialadex Communications Inc. v. Crammond</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id82beb058e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">6</footnote.reference>] the plaintiff sought an injunction to restrain the defendants from publishing a telefax directory. <eos/><bos/>The facts were not substantially in dispute. <eos/><bos/>Dialadex claimed that there had been a breach of fiduciary duty, appropriation of a corporate opportunity (unjust enrichment), and breach of confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The court held that since the plaintiff did not establish a fiduciary duty, the corporate opportunity was still just an idea, and since the information was also publicly available, it was doubtful the plaintiff would succeed at trial. <eos/><bos/>The court refused to grant an interlocutory injunction because the moving party had failed to establish a <ital>prima facie</ital> case.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82beb068e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">7</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Where a party seeks to enforce a restrictive covenant, that party must establish a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case regardless of whether the facts of the matter are in dispute because, normally, the de facto rights of the parties are determined by the injunction.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82c12108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">8</footnote.reference>] Of note, the English Court of Appeal rejected the argument that special rules apply with regard to injunctions in restraint of trade cases and held that the appropriate test in such a case is whether there is a serious issue to be tried.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82c12118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">9</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Where the moving party establishes a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case, then an injunction may be granted with less regard to the balance of conveniece and irreparable harm.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82c12128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">10</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id82c12138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">11</footnote.reference>] the applicants alleged that Good, a former employee and director of the applicant EMW and a shareholder of the applicant Employee Co. had breached a Non-Disclosure Agreement with EMW [2016 Agreement] and a Non-Disclosure/Non-Competition/Non-Solicitation Agreement with EMW [2017 Agreement] through his employment by Confidence. <eos/><bos/>They also alleged that Good breached fiduciary obligations he owed to EMW resulting from his employment in a fiduciary capacity and to Employee Co. as a director. <eos/><bos/>The application for an interim injunction requiring that Good&apos;s employment with Confidence and any other corporate entity associated with FWS be terminated and restraining the continuation of the alleged breaches was dismissed.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82c12148e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">12</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>EMW was in the business of providing maintenance, repair and construction services to clients in the agriculture and mining industries. <eos/><bos/>Good was, but for a period of seven months, employed by EMW from 2001 until he resigned October 26, 2017. <eos/><bos/>He began as a welder, advancing to senior crew leader in 2006 and Project Manager in 2008. <eos/><bos/>In 2011, It was alleged that Good was again promoted and became one of four department managers in the Ag Division. <eos/><bos/>Good disagreed and alleged that his title and formal position did not change and that he was a Project Manager until he left EMW. <eos/><bos/>Whatever his title, Good&apos;s responsibilities after 2008 related almost exclusively to Richardson, a major EMW client, generating 12.14% of Ag Division revenue in 2015 and 16.4% in 2016. <eos/><bos/>There was conflicting evidence as to Good&apos;s duties. <eos/><bos/>Good deposed that from 2008, he worked almost exclusively on Richardson fertilizer site expansions, which he described as small new capital builds. <eos/><bos/>He said there were 70 such projects, and in addition, two repair and maintenance calls and one grain facility upgrade for Richardson. <eos/><bos/>He described his duties as including business development; ensuring the department met safety standards and followed EMW procedures; corresponding with clients and customers; overseeing project invoicing, job costing and product status and scheduling; and performing estimate reviews. <eos/><bos/>Good deposed that his sole contact with Richardson was with the engineering group in Winnipeg. <eos/><bos/>Richardson maintenance work was managed by another EMW employee based in Regina. <eos/><bos/>He did not have an office at EMW, working from his home in Souris, Manitoba. <eos/><bos/>He claimed he was not invited to any department meetings where policy and decision-making took place and did not contribute to the development of strategy relating to sales, pricing, business development or other high-level policy issues.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82c12158e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">13</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>EMW alleged that Good had broader responsibilities as one of four Ag Division managers. <eos/><bos/>An Ag Department Manager was described as being <begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>“responsible for all activities of the respective department”<end.quote refid="QT_0001"/>, assigning project roles within the department, creating and implementing a marketing plan, and assisting in the coordination of project resources and in the hiring process. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence Good received that job description or carried out all those duties.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82c39208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">14</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>There was evidence that Good attended Ag Department Manager meetings until January 2017, when those meetings were replaced by one-on-one meetings with Morrison, who had become the Ag Division Manager. <eos/><bos/>There was also evidence Good had online access to EMW client accounts, pricing, suppliers and procedures relating to construction and maintenance and repair projects. <eos/><bos/>There was little evidence as to the extent to which he exercised that access. <eos/><bos/>Good also received weekly “batting orders” which showed contact information and schedules for EMW employees.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82c39218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">15</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Morrison and his wife were the sole shareholders of EMW until 2007. <eos/><bos/>In August 2007, they sold 15 key EMW employees 48% of EMW&apos;s common shares at a value of $1 per share. <eos/><bos/>Good, who was one of those key employees, acquired 3000 shares. <eos/><bos/>All the minority shareholders also became directors of EMW until October 2015.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82c39228e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">16</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In 2016, the minority shareholders froze the value of their shares at $107.95 per share, to enable new key employees the opportunity to become minority shareholders in EMW at a nominal cost. <eos/><bos/>To carry out that transaction, Good and the other minority shareholders transferred their shares to Employee Co. Each received one common share in Employee Co. and was to receive preferred shares equal to the value of the shares they held in EMW. <eos/><bos/>On March 13, 2017, Good, all other EMW shareholders, Employee Co. and EMW entered into an EMW Unanimous Shareholders Agreement which contained the following provision relating to the 2017 Agreement: 20. <eos/><bos/>The Parties agree that all shareholders of [Employee Co.] as well as Ewen shall sign Non-Competition/Non-Disclosure/Non-Solicitation Agreements in a form as determined acceptable to the Board Directors of the Corporation. <eos/><bos/>They also entered into an Employee Co. Unanimous Shareholders Agreement. <eos/><bos/>That agreement provided that Good and the other minority shareholders would be the directors and specified the process for shareholders to terminate their participation in Employee Co. The 2017 Agreement contained broad non-disclosure, non-competition and non-solicitation obligations.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82c39238e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">17</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>On October 6, 2017, Good sent a <begin.quote ID="QT_0003"/>“letter of resignation from EMW Industrial, and its subsidiary company or companies”<end.quote refid="QT_0003"/>, effective October 27, 2017. <eos/><bos/>His resignation letter referred to his shares in Employee Co., stating that he had “no clue on this stuff” and that he wanted to <begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>“just to ‘rip off the band-aid’ and hopefully clear everything up as soon as possible, and move on”<end.quote refid="QT_0002"/>. <eos/><bos/>Good was negotiating with FWS. He received a written offer of employment October 13, 2017 and began work October 30, 2017 in the position of “Business Development”.<eos/><bos/> The services specified in the job description included participating in project development and the preparation of proposal documents, identifying and managing risks to FWS when searching for new markets, working with clients to develop project concepts and determining if projects are realistic and suited to FWS.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82c39248e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">18</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Richardson was an existing FWS client. <eos/><bos/>Good&apos;s evidence was that EMW&apos;s work for Richardson was smaller scale and was typically in the repair and maintenance sector. <eos/><bos/>That evidence did not appear to be consistent with his evidence that he worked on 70 small capital projects for Richardson while with EMW. <eos/><bos/>Good also said that he was not involved in any way with servicing Richardson&apos;s account for FWS, and that his only participation in a Richardson project since joining FWS was taking pictures on one project site. <eos/><bos/>He said he was involved in a project bid involving both FWS and EMW relating to a Cargill project. <eos/><bos/>He said he turned over or destroyed all EMW information when he left the company and had not shared any confidential or proprietary information. <eos/><bos/>He also denied any involvement in the solicitation of EMW employees, customers or suppliers.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82c39258e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">19</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>EMW presented a different picture of the competition between FWS and EMW. <eos/><bos/>Morrison described FWS as EMW&apos;s largest competitor in the grain and fertilizer industry. <eos/><bos/>He said that FWS was not particularly involved in maintenance and repair, a significant component of EMW&apos;s work where EMW believes it had a competitive advantage, but that FWS wished to expand in that area. <eos/><bos/>He alleged that Good could harm EMW, adversely affecting its competitive advantage and the value of shares in Employee Co., because of the knowledge and relationships he had from working at EMW. <eos/><bos/>Morrison deposed that Good had been involved in tenders on behalf of FWS where EMW was asked to bid. <eos/><bos/>He alleged that FWS and EMW frequently compete for work from Cargill, which was also a large EMW client. <eos/><bos/>He deposed that EMW does significant work other than maintenance and repair, including bidding on larger projects, and provided a list of such bids. <eos/><bos/>He deposed that FWS probably competed with EMW on all of those bids. <eos/><bos/>Morrison also deposed that Good was having a significant detrimental effect on the share value of Employee Co. by providing FWS with a competitive advantage, as he knows EMW&apos;s bidding process. <eos/><bos/>He said that the grain and fertilizer industry has a very secretive bidding process and that billing information is confidential. <eos/><bos/>There was, however, no evidence Employee Co. shares were valued or sold after Good joined FWS. Morrison also alleged the information in the batting orders had potential strategic significance.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82c60308e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">20</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The parties agreed that the strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case standard applied in relation to both the restrictive covenant and the fiduciary obligation. <eos/><bos/>That standard is a significant hurdle for the applicant. <eos/><bos/>In undertaking the preliminary review, the court must consider not only the applicants&apos; evidence, but the conflicting evidence of the respondents.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82c60318e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">21</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The applicants alleged that Good was employed in a fiduciary capacity. <eos/><bos/>A departing employee who was so employed is subject to different obligations than one who was not. <eos/><bos/>The court is concerned with the scope of the employee&apos;s powers, their ability to unilaterally exercise that power or discretion so as to affect the beneficiaries&apos; interests, and whether the beneficiary is peculiarly vulnerable or at the mercy of the fiduciary. <eos/><bos/>Matters such as level of responsibility, degree of contact with customers, and knowledge of customer and pricing information may be significant.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82c60328e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">22</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motions judge observed that the obligations owed by a fiduciary employee are limited, and their term and content—as in relation to every fiduciary duty—turns on the facts. <eos/><bos/>Key employees who are not senior managers may be found to be fiduciaries. <eos/><bos/>A fiduciary may compete with their former employer, as long as they do not do so unfairly. <eos/><bos/>It is for that reason that they may be precluded from soliciting clients, but not from competing in general, and then only for a reasonable time after leaving their employment. <eos/><bos/>That temporal limit results reflects the purpose of the non-solicitation obligation.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82c60338e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">23</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Finally, the applicants submitted that Good was a director of Employee Co., and as such, continued to be subject to the fiduciary duties. <eos/><bos/>They say he breached that duty by taking employment with FWS and competing directly with EMW. <eos/><bos/>The respondents alleged that Good was not a director, as he resigned.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82c60348e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">24</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Turning to the application of the law to the facts, the motion judge dealt first with the allegation that Good had continuing fiduciary duties as a director of Employee Co., and was breaching those duties. <eos/><bos/>Good expressly stated that his resignation letter was intended to relate to <begin.quote ID="QT_0004"/>“all of his roles and capacities”<end.quote refid="QT_0004"/>. <eos/><bos/>The respondents did not claim they did not understand he wished to resign Further, there was no evidence the applicants continued to treat him as a director or that he has acted as such since his resignation. <eos/><bos/>In these circumstances, the applicants had not made out a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that they did not receive effective notice of Good&apos;s resignation, and accordingly, that he was still a director.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82c60358e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">25</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Further, and even if there was a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that Good was a director of Employee Co., the motion judge would not exercise a discretion to grant an injunction on that ground. <eos/><bos/>The application for an equitable remedy should not turn on whether Good managed to extricate himself as a minority shareholder or director of Employee Co. At this stage, it should turn on the former employment relationship between EMW and Good. <eos/><bos/>That primary relationship should drive the analysis. <eos/><bos/>As such, the issue was whether there was strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that Good breached the 2016 Agreement, the 2017 Agreement or fiduciary obligations which arose from his employment in a fiduciary capacity by EMW. <eos/><bos/>The applicants had not made out a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that the non-competition and non-solicitation provisions of the 2017 Agreement were enforceable. <eos/><bos/>There was a strong argument they were unreasonably restrictive and aimed against competition generally. <eos/><bos/>EMW failed to make out a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case the 2016 Agreement continued in force.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82c87408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">26</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motion judge observed that there were substantial conflicts between the evidence of the applicants and the evidence of the respondents as to the scope of Good&apos;s powers when he was employed by EMW, his ability to unilaterally exercise that power or discretion so as to affect EMW&apos;s interests, and whether EMW was peculiarly vulnerable or at the mercy of Good as a result of his employment by EMW. <eos/><bos/>There was also conflicting evidence as to his duties with FWS, and the relationship between those duties and his work with EMW and the confidential information he obtained while employed by EMW.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82c87418e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">27</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>There were certain matters that appeared to be clear. <eos/><bos/>Good worked almost exclusively with Richardson during his last eight years with EMW, in only two provinces, within the limits of his comfort zone. <eos/><bos/>He did not do large projects and had very little to do with the maintenance and repair business which was of particular importance to EMW and in relation to which EMW claimed a particular advantage and exposure to particular risks. <eos/><bos/>Although there was evidence he was involved in some bidding, there was limited evidence as to the timing and extent of that involvement. <eos/><bos/>Although Good had significant responsibilities for a very important client, it appeared that he did not participate in senior management functions such as determining the strategy relating to sales, pricing, business development or other high-level policy issues. <eos/><bos/>There was evidence Good had online access to a broad range of proprietary information. <eos/><bos/>However, there was no evidence that he used that access in relation to much of that information or that he took any information in electronic or written form when he left EMW. <eos/><bos/>The motion judge concluded that, taken as a whole, the evidence suggested Good was a middle manager focused almost exclusively on one aspect of the business of one client. <eos/><bos/>However, middle managers can be fiduciaries. <eos/><bos/>In the motion judge&apos;s view, there was a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that Good was a fiduciary. <eos/><bos/>He had major responsibilities, including serving as a key contact, for a very significant client, and had knowledge of some confidential matters such as pricing and supplier information. <eos/><bos/>There was sufficient evidence as to EMW&apos;s vulnerability. <eos/><bos/>The question, accordingly, was the nature and extent of his fiduciary obligations. <eos/><bos/>A fiduciary is not precluded from competing with the former employer. <eos/><bos/>He or she is precluded from unfairly competing, and in particular, from soliciting clients of the former employer for a limited time. <eos/><bos/>The scope and temporal limits of that prohibition depend on the facts. <eos/><bos/>In these circumstances, there was a sound argument that Good was not obliged to avoid soliciting all clients for all kinds of business. <eos/><bos/>The key issue was Richardson. <eos/><bos/>Good was not the only or the most senior EMW employee responsible for the relationship with Richardson. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence that transitioning his project management, marketing, relationship and other responsibilities with Richardson to another employee presented unusual difficulties or would have taken EMW much time. <eos/><bos/>The ability to effect that transition was relevant to EMW&apos;s vulnerability.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82c87428e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">28</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The evidence as to the competition between FWS and EMW was also an important consideration. <eos/><bos/>While it appeared that the applicants overstated the extent of that competition, it appeared the respondents understated it. <eos/><bos/>There was evidence FWS and EMW were competitors in relation to a significant number of projects and that competition would increase. <eos/><bos/>Good could have been employed in a manner that engaged the concern with unfair competition, particularly in relation to Richardson.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82c87438e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">29</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>However, the evidence suggested that Good had done very little that constituted competition with EMW in relation to any client. <eos/><bos/>He played some role in two bids for Cargill business that involved both EMW and FWS. He had not provided services in relation to Richardson, other than taking photographs on one occasion. <eos/><bos/>There was no other evidence that Good&apos;s employment with FWS has impacted EMW&apos;s business or the value of Employee Co.[<footnote.reference refid="Id82c87448e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">30</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motion judge observed that it was also significant that the application was heard more than six months after Good joined FWS. There was a strong argument Good was no longer subject to an obligation to avoid soliciting EMW clients, at least other than Richardson, when the application was heard. <eos/><bos/>Additional time had now passed. <eos/><bos/>Further, the passage of time meant that confidential information that depends on its currency—such as information about the allocation of specific staff in the batting orders, or information as to then current projects or bids that are now complete was no longer an issue.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82c87458e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">31</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motion judge was not satisfied there was a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that Good had used or shared confidential information so as to engage the concern with unfair competition by a fiduciary. <eos/><bos/>Nor was there a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that he had otherwise competed unfairly by soliciting EMW&apos;s clients. <eos/><bos/>The mere fact that FWS competes with EMW did not mean that Good could not work for FWS in any capacity. <eos/><bos/>The motion judge disagreed with the submission by EMW that employment by a competitor will inevitably result in sharing confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The question as to whether to draw that inference is a question of fact.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82c87468e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">32</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In the result, the applicants had not made out a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that Good has breached a fiduciary obligation to EMW or any other applicant. <eos/><bos/>Further, the motion judge was not satisfied that EMW would suffer irreparable harm, whether as a result of erosion of EMW&apos;s market share, the disclosure of confidential information, the erosion of the value of Employee Co. shares or otherwise, if an interim injunction was not granted.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82cae508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">33</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id82cae518e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">34</footnote.reference>] the plaintiff, Capital Direct, which was in the business of providing home equity and residential mortgage financing to individuals, applied for an interim injunction restraining the defendant Blanchette, a former employee of Capital Direct and a licensed mortgage broker, from <begin.quote ID="QT_0005"/>“soliciting, serving, referring, directing, receiving business from, contacting or continuing any form of communication with any clients or active prospect of Capital Direct with whom she had contact or knowledge of during her employment with Capital Direct.”<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0005"/> Blanchette was hired and employed as a “Mortgage Salesperson” pursuant to a written employment agreement in 2005. <eos/><bos/>During her employment with Capital Direct she was also described and held out to the public as a “Mortgage Planner” or “Mortgage Advisor”.<eos/><bos/> The Original Employment Agreement contained a one-year non-competition clause, limited geographically to the <begin.quote ID="QT_0006"/>“City of Vancouver and the Lower Mainland”<end.quote refid="QT_0006"/>, and with respect to any business involving the business of private mortgage lending or private mortgage brokering. <eos/><bos/>The Original Employment Agreement contained a confidentiality clause that required Blanchette to keep all information provided to her by Capital Direct confidential, including information relating to any customer, and not to release, use, or disclose the information unless she obtained the prior written permission of Capital Direct. <eos/><bos/>The Original Employment Agreement expired on February 24, 2006. <eos/><bos/>Clause 3.2 of the Original Employment Agreement stated that the initial term could be extended for a further one-year period, on a recurring basis, upon the written agreement of both parties. <eos/><bos/>However, the Original Employment Agreement was never extended or renewed. <eos/><bos/>The parties agreed that from February 25, 2006 until her departure from Capital Direct, Blanchette&apos;s employment was not governed by a written employment agreement, nor was it subject to any express restrictive covenants or confidentiality provisions.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82cae528e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">35</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Capital Direct&apos;s business development efforts involved significant advertising across a wide range of media. <eos/><bos/>Blanchette was never the face of Capital Direct. <eos/><bos/>Capital Direct never used or displayed her name, contact information, picture, or bio in any of its advertising or on its website. <eos/><bos/>Blanchette did not engage in any networking activities for Capital Direct, nor was she required to do so. <eos/><bos/>Rather, potential clients who contacted Capital Direct were distributed on a rotating basis to all of the mortgage brokers.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82cae538e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">36</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In late 2017, Blanchette took a three-month medical leave of absence. <eos/><bos/>When she commenced her leave, she was one of three mortgage brokers. <eos/><bos/>Following her return, Blanchette&apos;s authority and discretion were significantly decreased by Capital Direct, including that she was only referred new phone leads/clients from outside the Metro Vancouver area; her authority to approve mortgages up to $500,000 was decreased to only lower value mortgages; she could no longer contact an investor directly to deal with changes to the Loan to Value ratio or the funding amount after a mortgage was approved and prior to funding; whereas she could previously initial the change without question; she no longer had authority to negotiate a repayment program; she could no longer waive or reduce NSF fees unless she had approval; she could no longer approve holds on a client&apos;s payments without approval; she needed approval before allowing clients to send and sign mortgage package documents outside the Capital Direct office; and her time/schedule was managed by the Capital Direct administrative staff and manager whereas she previously had autonomy to set her own schedule. <eos/><bos/>By the time of her return, Capital Direct had employed three new brokers, bringing the total number of active brokers to six. <eos/><bos/>The three new junior brokers were assigned to work with and train under the other two senior brokers. <eos/><bos/>Blanchette was not provided with any assistance from these new employees.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82cae548e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">37</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>On July 13, 2018, Capital Direct provided one year&apos;s working notice of termination to Blanchette. <eos/><bos/>Settlement negotiations continued until February 12, 2019, when they broke down for the final time. <eos/><bos/>Capital Direct directed Blanchette to report to work on February 13, 2019. <eos/><bos/>Blanchette did not report to work. <eos/><bos/>Capital Direct treated Blanchette&apos;s employment as having been ended by her.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82cae558e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">38</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Capital Direct discovered that Blanchette had referred a client of Capital Direct to her son. <eos/><bos/>Blanchette sent an email to this client stating that she was transferring her mortgage broker license to work independently of Capital Direct, and would be working with her son going forward. <eos/><bos/>The client later received an approval through her son but did not go ahead with that financing as the client received a better offer from Capital Direct.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82cae568e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">39</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Blanchette said that from this point until the end of February 2019, she did not initiate contact with any clients, former clients, or active prospects of Capital Direct, as she needed to wait until her Mortgage Sub Broker license had been officially transferred. <eos/><bos/>The clients she had any contact with during this period were either ones who contacted her directly or who were close friends or associates. <eos/><bos/>Once her Mortgage Sub Broker license was officially transferred to a new brokerage, Blanchette did begin contacting certain former clients she had personally serviced at Capital Direct. <eos/><bos/>She provided her new contact information, advised them that she had made a switch from working for Capital Direct, and reassured them that she was available to answer any questions or concerns they had going forward.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82cd5608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">40</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Blanchette acknowledged that she had the names, phone numbers and email addresses of some of her former clients at Capital Direct, information she personally collected over many years. <eos/><bos/>She collected this information to help her do her job better, to stay in touch and maintain relationships with her clients, and to reconcile commissions. <eos/><bos/>She collected this information on her own initiative and was not directed to do so by Capital Direct as part of her job duties. <eos/><bos/>Blanchette did not download or take any customer lists compiled by Capital Direct, nor did she possess a list of Capital Direct clients with whom she did not personally deal. <eos/><bos/>Blanchette did not take or possess any documents of Capital Direct containing detailed customer information relating to their needs or preferences, the rates they paid, their credit rating, or their income, assets or debt.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82cd5618e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">41</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Blanchette said that to date she had not benefitted financially from any of her initiated contacts with former clients. <eos/><bos/>The only amount she has been paid arising from a former client was from one person who called her to arrange financing to pay out an existing Capital Direct mortgage.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82cd5628e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">42</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Branch concluded that the heightened standard of strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case should be applied for the following reasons: the request for injunctive relief at trial would likely become moot by the time the matter reached that stage, as any duties Blanchette might owe to Capital Direct not to solicit former clients, even at a fiduciary level, would likely have expired; an injunction would clearly affect Blanchette&apos;s ability to earn a living. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff was almost 64 years old. <eos/><bos/>An injunction against any communication with individuals with whom she has worked over many years would clearly be detrimental to her ability to earn a living.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82cd5638e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">43</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Branch observed that Capital Direct initially had non-competition and confidentiality clauses in place, but those fell away as its relationship with Blanchette continued. <eos/><bos/>Absent contractual duties governing the conduct of a former employee, Capital Direct must rely on common law principles. <eos/><bos/>It first placed reliance on the concept of fiduciary duty. <eos/><bos/>Capital Direct alleged that by virtue of the trust, confidence and broad discretion possessed by Blanchette, Capital Direct was subject to a peculiar vulnerability to the exercise of her powers. <eos/><bos/>Justice Branch concluded that there was not a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that Blanchette would be found to be a fiduciary given that: she was not the general manager or broker on record, even in name only; she was no longer subjected to any restrictive covenants; she was not in management at all, having no employees under her; she was not identified on marketing materials; she did not have access to all of Capital Direct&apos;s confidential information; she was not the primary point of contact for Capital Direct&apos;s major client or group of clients; she was only one of eight brokers; she did not supervise any other employees; the defendant&apos;s reputation did not rest in Blanchette&apos;s hands; she was not the first point of contact with any clients, who were simply referred to her randomly; her client list had diminished such that she was not an integral part of the financial success of the office. <eos/><bos/>Her commissions had reduced to approximately one-half of what the other senior mortgage brokers were achieving; even according to the defendant, she had no power to make referrals to other companies without management approval; and, particularly after she was given her one-year notice, her rights and responsibilities were greatly reduced. <eos/><bos/>This showed a lack of trust, rather than to her being a repository of trust.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82cd5648e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">44</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Based on her limited discretion and authority, Justice Branch concluded that Capital Direct was not particularly vulnerable to loss, harm, and damage if Blanchette failed to perform her duties.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82cd5658e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">45</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Even if there was no fiduciary duty, there may still be other common law duties applicable to departing employees. <eos/><bos/>There was support for Capital Direct&apos;s position that there was at least a more limited duty on the part of the former employee not to misuse confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The improper use of confidential client information by an employee constitutes a breach of the employee&apos;s duty of confidence. <eos/><bos/>However, Justice Branch concluded that there was not a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that Blanchette misused confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The information that Blanchette retained was not a client list as that term is properly understood. <eos/><bos/>She did not download, take, print off or extract a client list from the plaintiff&apos;s systems. <eos/><bos/>Rather, she simply had a list of persons with whom she had had previous contact on her phone. <eos/><bos/>Further, it was only basic name, phone number or email information, and not more material information such as mortgage renewal dates, interest rates charged, current banking profiles, or other personal characteristics. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence that the defendant extracted information “in fraud of” Capital Direct or that it was intentionally <begin.quote ID="QT_0008"/>“acquired to advance his own business”<end.quote refid="QT_0008"/>. <eos/><bos/>Rather, the information was simply gathered in her phone over the many years of her employment. <eos/><bos/>Capital Direct did not assert that Blanchette took a copy of any client list, nor that she emailed a list of customer names to her personal email account. <eos/><bos/>Nor was there evidence that she made a special effort to duplicate or imprint any formal client lists or sheets into her memory or her phone. <eos/><bos/>Nor did the information include <begin.quote ID="QT_0007"/>“the clients&apos; needs, the clients&apos; preferences, and the rates that the clients were willing to pay”<end.quote refid="QT_0007"/>. <eos/><bos/>Rather, it was simply contact information already on her phone. <eos/><bos/>Hence, the relatively passive retention of name of contact information on her phone gathered over the course of her employment did not amount to the misuse of confidential information on the facts.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82cd5668e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">46</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2048208806" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I603da3718e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">ADT Security Services Canada, Inc. v. Fluent Home</cite.query> Ltd.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id82cfc708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">47</footnote.reference>] the plaintiffs motion for an interlocutory injunction to prohibit certain behaviour in the security alarm market by the defendant Fluent was granted in part. <eos/><bos/>The relief sought fell into two general categories: a. Prohibiting solicitation by Fluent of customers of the plaintiff ADT Canada pursuant to a contractual restrictive covenant; and b. Prohibiting certain unlawful conduct, including impersonating ADT and making false statements about ADT. <eos/><bos/>ADT alleged that the impugned conduct by Fluent was not a few “one-off” events by rogue door-to-door salespeople, but rather was a “top-down” strategy for unlawfully increasing Fluent&apos;s market share at ADT Canada&apos;s expense. <eos/><bos/>Fluent conceded that it had solicited some ADT Canada customers in breach of the Restrictive Covenant. <eos/><bos/>It also conceded that there had been some isolated examples of improper conduct by Fluent sales personnel. <eos/><bos/>It defended the interlocutory injunction on the following bases: the Restrictive Covenant was unenforceable on its face; in the alternative, events since the Restrictive Covenant was agreed to had rendered it unenforceable; in any event, there was no irreparable harm to ADT Canada because damages were an adequate remedy; the balance of convenience lay with refusing the injunction, since the effect of any injunction would create a benefit to ADT Canada Inc. far greater than the benefit conferred by the Restrictive Covenant.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82cfc718e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">48</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Corbett agreed that the Restrictive Covenant was unenforceable because of subsequent events. <eos/><bos/>The original obligation arose under a “Dealership Agreement” between Fluent and Protectron. <eos/><bos/>The terms may have been reasonable in the context of that contract: Fluent sold security services for Protectron, received compensation for its sales, and was required not to compete with Protectron, for Protectron customers, for five years after the dealership contract ended. <eos/><bos/>ADT was a competitor of both Protectron and Fluent. <eos/><bos/>It bought Protectron and took an assignment of the Dealership Agreement, and was thereby entitled to the benefit of that agreement. <eos/><bos/>However, the agreement did not preclude Fluent from competing with ADT for non-Protectron customers. <eos/><bos/>ADT and Fluent ended the Dealership Agreement and ADT insisted that Fluent return all information it had about ADT customers to ADT. <eos/><bos/>Thereafter ADT rebranded Protectron as ADT. <eos/><bos/>The net result was that compliance with the Restrictive Covenant, with no list of customers not to solicit, would be difficult and would seriously compromise Fluent&apos;s ability to compete legitimately in the marketplace. <eos/><bos/>ADT&apos;s actions, in acquiring Protectron, refusing Fluent information about the customers for which Fluent was not permitted to compete, and rebranding Protectron as ADT, cumulatively rendered compliance with the Restrictive Covenant far more onerous. <eos/><bos/>Even if it turned out that the Restrictive Covenant was still enforceable, the changed circumstances rendered it impossible to tailor an injunction to enforce the Restrictive Covenant without unduly impeding Fluent&apos;s legitimate activities. <eos/><bos/>In these circumstances, it was fair to restrict ADT to a remedy in damages.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82cfc728e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">49</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>ADT proposed a third-party verification protocol to enable Fluent to check whether a proposed customer was one to which the Restrictive Covenant applied. <eos/><bos/>Justice Corbett rejected this as an unreasonable method for securing compliance with the Restrictive Covenant. <eos/><bos/>Alarm security services are sold door-to-door, generally by a seasonal sales force during fair-weather months. <eos/><bos/>Sales are sought at the front door, and the goal of a sales person is to make it as easy and fast as possible for a customer to sign up for security services. <eos/><bos/>Adding layers of due diligence to a simple consumer purchase creates an impediment to sales that impacts a competitor&apos;s ability to compete in the marketplace. <eos/><bos/>It is also difficult to explain to customers and creates a form of promotion for ADT.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82e5c008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">50</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Corbett explained that Fluent&apos;s misconduct in the marketplace was another matter. <eos/><bos/>There were examples of Fluent personnel using ADT identification to pass themselves off as ADT personnel in order to make sales for Fluent. <eos/><bos/>There were also examples of Fluent personnel telling lies to potential customers such as <begin.quote ID="QT_0009"/>“Protectron has gone out of business”<end.quote refid="QT_0009"/> and <begin.quote ID="QT_0010"/>“Protectron is going out of business”<end.quote refid="QT_0010"/>. <eos/><bos/>It was difficult, however, to see more than isolated incidents of this conduct. <eos/><bos/>The passing off conduct was so serious that an injunction was justified to restrain it. <eos/><bos/>The motion was dismissed as regards the request for an injunction to enforce the Restrictive Covenant. <eos/><bos/>The motion was granted to restrain Fluent from passing itself off as ADT or as authorized by ADT.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82e5c018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">51</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Pursuant to a dealer agreement, Fluent was an authorized dealer for Protectron. <eos/><bos/>Under the dealer agreement, Fluent sold alarm protection services on behalf of Protectron. <eos/><bos/>Fluent was paid a fee for these sales. <eos/><bos/>Protectron thereafter provided the home security services and collected fees for those services from the customers to whom those services had been sold by Fluent. <eos/><bos/>The dealer agreement provided that, upon termination of the agreement, Fluent may not solicit or enter into security agreements with any customers of Protectron for a five-year period. <eos/><bos/>In particular, section 17.2 of the Dealer Agreement stated:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0011"/>Non-solicitation and non-acceptance. <eos/><bos/>Neither the Dealer nor the Principal(s), nor any officer, director, or employee of the Dealer shall, for a period of five (5) years from the termination of this Agreement or from the termination of their employment with the Dealer, whichever comes first, directly or indirectly solicit the Security Service Business of an existing Customer or past Customer nor act in any way that could induce a Customer to cease doing business with Protectron.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0011"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0012"/>“Customer” is defined in the Dealer Agreement as:<end.quote refid="QT_0012"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0013"/>… any person, business, corporation or other entity that has entered into a Protectron Monitoring Agreement wherein the Customer will be billed and the Customer&apos;s security alarm system will be monitored by Protectron and wherein the Customer will be serviced by either Protectron or the Dealer.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0013"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id82e83108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">52</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Corbett observed that facially, this provision may have been commercially reasonable at the time it was agreed. <eos/><bos/>Fluent was paid an amount for each customer that would require Protectron to retain the customer and receive payment from the customer for services for roughly three years in order to break-even on the cost of providing its services and the payment it made to Fluent for signing the customer up for home security services. <eos/><bos/>Agreements with customers were generally for an initial term of five years.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82e83118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">53</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Protectron was acquired by the ADT Corporation in July 2014. <eos/><bos/>In July 2015, Protectron&apos;s name was changed to ADT Canada. <eos/><bos/>It continued using the Protectron name in connection with its business after the corporate name change, but then changed the name under which it was dealing with its customers to ADT Canada. <eos/><bos/>It was not clear precisely when the rebranding began, but that rebranding in the marketplace took place after Fluent ceased to be a dealer. <eos/><bos/>At the time ADT acquired Protectron, ADT and Protectron had roughly equal market share in the Canadian alarm security market.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82e83128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">54</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Issues arose after ADT acquired Protectron about solicitation of ADT Security accounts by Fluent. <eos/><bos/>These solicitations were not precluded by the Restrictive Covenant but, obviously ADT did not want to be paying Fluent to recruit customers away from ADT Security for Protectron. <eos/><bos/>In July 2015, by letter from its solicitors, ADT Canada confirmed its position to Fluent that Protectron did not take the position that Fluent was prohibited from doing ADT takeovers but rather that, pursuant to the terms of the Agreement, Protectron would no longer purchase those underlying accounts, effective January 1, 2015.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82e83138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">55</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Fluent decided that it wished to terminate the Dealer Agreement. <eos/><bos/>Fluent and ADT Canada negotiated a termination agreement, which they executed effective October 20, 2015. <eos/><bos/>Pursuant to the Termination Agreement, Fluent was obliged to deliver all Protectron customer files and information relating to Protectron customer accounts to ADT Canada. <eos/><bos/>Fluent was not permitted to retain any information relating to these Protectron customers. <eos/><bos/>In the Termination Agreement, Fluent acknowledged its obligation to observe the Restrictive Covenant. <eos/><bos/>It would not have been apparent to Fluent at the time it entered into the Termination Agreement that Protectron would be rebranded ADT for the customers it was bound not to solicit pursuant to the Restrictive Covenant.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82e83148e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">56</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>ADT Canada tracked the attrition or “churn” rates for its authorized dealers. <eos/><bos/>The “churn rate” is the number of customers that cease to be customers in a given period. <eos/><bos/>There is a “natural” churn rate. <eos/><bos/>ADT Canada saw that it experienced an abnormally high churn rate for customers in western Canada, where Fluent had been its authorized dealer. <eos/><bos/>In April 2016, as the season started, the churn rates skyrocketed. <eos/><bos/>Upon investigation, ADT Canada found that the excessive churn rate was attributable to an unusual rate of cancellations by customers who had been sold services by Fluent, at a rate more than fivefold over historic cancellation rates. <eos/><bos/>These high churn rates continued over the summer of 2016, dipped somewhat in the fall, only to climb back up again in April and May 2017. <eos/><bos/>ADT Canada investigated the abnormally high churn rate for its Fluent accounts. <eos/><bos/>The investigation revealed more than 140 ADT Canada customers who had Fluent representatives visit their homes to try to convince them to terminate their contracts with ADT. <eos/><bos/>More than 20 Fluent sales representatives were involved in this conduct. <eos/><bos/>The sales tactics took place in multiple locations across western Canada, throughout the 2016 and 2017 sales seasons.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82e83158e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">57</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>ADT Canada argued that the test is “modified” where the moving party shows a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case to enforce a restrictive covenant. <eos/><bos/>Justice Corbett explained that in a negotiated commercial agreement, rather than an employment agreement, the courts tend to favour enforcement of commercial obligations of this kind. <eos/><bos/>Justice Corbett concluded that the “employment” cases are also followed in the context of some “independent contractor” cases. <eos/><bos/>The more closely an independent contractor arrangement resembles an employment contract, the more likely that a court will look to all three branches of the general injunction test. <eos/><bos/>The more it can be said that the independent contractor arrangement reflects payment for goodwill, the less likely that the court will place great weight on irreparable harm or balance of convenience. <eos/><bos/>Justice Corbett observed that in this case, there were factors tending both ways. <eos/><bos/>The consideration paid to Fluent for recruiting customers for Protectron was premised on retention of those customers for several years. <eos/><bos/>The financial structure of the dealer agreement would be defeated if Fluent could terminate the contract and recruit away all of the customers it had signed up. <eos/><bos/>On the other hand, customers sign term contracts that contain penalty provisions if they terminate their agreements early. <eos/><bos/>The nature of the interest protected by the restrictive covenant must be considered on the basis of a reading of the entire agreement, and Justice Corbett was not convinced that the agreement should not be considered as closer to an employment contract than an asset purchase agreement.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82eaa208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">58</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Jutstice Corbett accepted that the unreasonableness of the agreement was magnified by ADT&apos;s conduct in refusing to leave a customer list with Fluent and in rebranding Protectron as ADT. <eos/><bos/>ADT&apos;s motion to enforce the Restrictive Covenant did not meet the test for a <ital>prima facie</ital> case for an injunction because conduct by ADT had rendered the burden of compliance to be much heavier than it was at the time that it was agreed to by Fluent. <eos/><bos/>ADT sought to ameliorate the prejudice of its conduct by proposing a third-party verification process but such a process would unduly hamper Fluent&apos;s legitimate activities in the marketplace and would be impractical in the context of a business where sales are made through door-to-door solicitation. <eos/><bos/>If the dealer agreement was terminated, Fluent would have had two ways to know which customers it could not solicit during the period of the Restrictive Covenant: signage on customer homes showing they were secured by Protectron and customer information about Protectron customers. <eos/><bos/>Thus it would be relatively straightforward for Fluent to instruct its sales force not to solicit Protectron customers. <eos/><bos/>When Fluent and ADT Canada entered into the Termination Agreement, Fluent agreed to return customer information to ADT Canada, and to destroy copies of this information in its possession. <eos/><bos/>At the same time, it confirmed its continuing obligations under the Restrictive Covenant. <eos/><bos/>There did not appear to be any terms in the Termination Agreement that addressed how Fluent was to observe the Restrictive Covenant without having a list of the customers to which those obligations applied. <eos/><bos/>In the summer of 2015, Protectron changed its name to ADT Canada. <eos/><bos/>This change of name was known to Fluent on termination. <eos/><bos/>However, aside from the change of name of the company, ADT Canada had not begun to re-brand “Protectron” with the “ADT” name. <eos/><bos/>It had since done so.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82eaa218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">59</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>On the face of the Restrictive Covenant, Fluent was precluded from soliciting Protectron customers, as of termination, for a period of five years. <eos/><bos/>Without a list of these customers, Fluent now had no way of knowing who these people were. <eos/><bos/>Existing customers of ADT Canada may have become new customers since October 2015. <eos/><bos/>Fluent was not precluded from soliciting these people. <eos/><bos/>Fluent was not and never had been precluded from soliciting customers of ADT Security Services Canada. <eos/><bos/>After the rebranding, when customers would believe themselves doing business with “ADT”, Fluent had no practical way to positively identify customers covered by the Restrictive Covenant. <eos/><bos/>This situation had only become even more difficult: effective January 1, 2018, the plaintiffs amalgamated: there was now only one ADT company offering these services in Canada. <eos/><bos/>The Restrictive Covenant would only apply to some, but not all, of its customers.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82eaa228e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">60</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Corbett rejected the suggestion by ADT that Fluent should submit to a process of vetting every customer it sought to solicit through a process of third party verification. <eos/><bos/>This was not agreed in the Dealer Agreement or the Termination Agreement. <eos/><bos/>It was a cumbersome additional step in soliciting a customer and would disadvantage Fluent in its sales efforts. <eos/><bos/>It would also require Fluent to trust, without verification, that the list of protected customers provided to a third party verification service was accurate.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82eaa238e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">61</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The onus was on ADT to show that the restrictive covenant was reasonable, and in particular, that: ADT had a proprietary interest entitled to protection; b. the temporal and geographic terms of the restrictive covenant were reasonable to protect the proprietary interests; and the restrictive covenant was not against competition generally.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82eaa248e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">62</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Corbett concluded that there was a serious issue to be tried as to whether the Restrictive Covenant was enforceable from the outset. <eos/><bos/>However, ADT had not established a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case for its initial enforceability. <eos/><bos/>Complying with the Restrictive Covenant was rendered impractical by decisions made by ADT. <eos/><bos/>This impracticality cannot fairly be redressed by a third-party verification system, which would impose unreasonable compliance requirements on Fluent. <eos/><bos/>There is a serious issue to be tried whether ADT&apos;s conduct has rendered the restrictive Covenant completely unenforceable, or whether ADT should be restricted to a remedy in damages.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82eaa258e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">63</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>At issue in <ital>2158124 Ontario Inc. v. Pitton</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id82ed1308e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">64</footnote.reference>] was whether Pitton had breached his non-solicitation and confidentiality obligations under an employment agreement. <eos/><bos/>StoneRidge carried on business as an insurance brokerage. <eos/><bos/>Glenny carried on business as an insurance brokerage. <eos/><bos/>It was a family-run business whose principals included Brian and Scott. <eos/><bos/>Pitton was a long-time family friend of the principals of Glenny. <eos/><bos/>Pitton was a licensed insurance broker. <eos/><bos/>Up to April 2011, Pitton was employed as a broker with Brokerlink managing a book of business consisting of commercial and personal clients. <eos/><bos/>Pitton approached StoneRidge&apos;s principal Puccini, advising that he wished to leave Brokerlink to join StoneRidge. <eos/><bos/>Pitton proposed that StoneRidge approach Brokerlink with an offer to purchase the book of business managed by him so that he could commence his StoneRidge employment with a ready client base. <eos/><bos/>Puccini eventually purchased the book of business from Brokerlink. <eos/><bos/>The book of business was assigned to StoneRidge. <eos/><bos/>Pitton was hired by StoneRidge as a senior account executive managing the Brokerlink book of business. <eos/><bos/>Pitton signed an Employment Agreement and was employed by StoneRidge until his abrupt resignation. <eos/><bos/>Without prior notice, Pitton delivered a letter of resignation and advised Puccini that he had accepted a position as a broker with Glenny, now operating under the name Erion. <eos/><bos/>Unbeknownst to Puccini or to anyone else at StoneRidge, Pitton began to contact StoneRidge clients to advise that he was leaving. <eos/><bos/>Puccini became aware of the solicitation because StoneRidge was contacted subsequently by several clients requesting clarification of Pitton&apos;s situation.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82ed1318e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">65</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Pitton&apos;s book of business at the time of termination consisted of 183 commercial client lines and 92 personal client lines. <eos/><bos/>The defendants alleged that Pitton sent an email to a small selection of his former clients. <eos/><bos/>Most of the clients who received the email had followed Pitton from Brokerlink and included close personal friends and family, the vast majority of whom resulted from relationships that pre-dated his employment with the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>The defendants alleged that Pitton restricted the email to 50 individuals and had only spoken to approximately 35 former clients. <eos/><bos/>The defendants argued that the purpose of the email was not to be a solicitation of the plaintiff&apos;s clients.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82ed1328e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">66</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>There was no dispute that a brokerage&apos;s primary asset is its customer base, including names, addresses, contact information, occupation, business and insurance requirements, information that would be extremely beneficial to another brokerage.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82ed1338e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">67</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Goodman observed that several things flowing from the email clearly indicated a solicitation of business. <eos/><bos/>The email from Pitton was sent two days before Puccini&apos;s discussion with Scott regarding a potential purchase of the book of business and his confirmation that the Agreement would be honoured. <eos/><bos/>The email was sent on a Saturday, indicating that Pitton was losing no time in approaching certain of StoneRidge&apos;s clients. <eos/><bos/>Before even apparently commencing his new employment, Pitton had a Glenny email address, office address and telephone number. <eos/><bos/>StoneRidge was in touch with most clients serviced by Pitton and was advised by almost all of them that they had been contacted by Pitton either by email, letter or telephone call. <eos/><bos/>Justice Goodman was satisfied that Pitton knew who his StoneRidge clients were, had their contact information on his personal cell phone, was aware of the products they had purchased, the type of insurance coverage they had and general knowledge of when client policy renewals came due. <eos/><bos/>It was somewhat self-serving to justify this conduct by claiming that certain clients would have followed Pitton in any event. <eos/><bos/>The email went far beyond simply advising clients that Pitton had left StoneRidge. <eos/><bos/>The email referenced “my clients” and clearly stated that Pitton would provide <begin.quote ID="QT_0015"/>“the best service at competitive pricing at Erion…”<end.quote refid="QT_0015"/>. <eos/><bos/>He opined that his position at Glenny as operations manager would have a <begin.quote ID="QT_0014"/>“positive effect on client relations and insurance options”<end.quote refid="QT_0014"/>. <eos/><bos/>Finally, he stated that he hoped <begin.quote ID="QT_0016"/>“to continue working with you in the future”<end.quote refid="QT_0016"/>. <eos/><bos/>Justice Goodman concluded that Pitton solicited former clients of StoneRidge immediately after his resignation from the plaintiff&apos;s business.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82ed1348e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">68</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>With respect to the interpretation of the clauses found in the Agreement and restrictive covenants in employment agreements generally, Justice Goodman observed that the case law in Ontario is divided as to whether the standard to be applied ought to be the lower “serious question to be tried” or the higher “strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case” test. <eos/><bos/>The majority of reported cases that applied the higher standard of a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case dealt with restrictive non-competition clauses, as opposed to mere non-solicitation clauses. <eos/><bos/>One line of cases in Ontario has found that the higher standard of a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case should be met where parties are seeking to enforce restrictive covenants. <eos/><bos/>In these cases, if the higher standard is met, less emphasis is placed on the second and third parts of the injunction test. <eos/><bos/>Still, other jurisprudence provides that a court need not choose between a higher or a lower threshold but, depending on the strength of a plaintiff&apos;s case, irreparable harm and the balance of convenience will be given either more or less weight; less if a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case, more if it is simply a serious issue to be tried. <eos/><bos/>Whether the “serious question to be tried” test or the higher standard of a “strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case” is to be applied must be met in relation to certain aspects of the plaintiff&apos;s claim. <eos/><bos/>The authorities suggest that where the interlocutory injunction will interfere with the defendant&apos;s ability to make a living, the threshold should be the higher one of “strong <ital>prima facie</ital>” case.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82ed1358e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">69</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Goodman agreed with the application of the general test and weight to be placed on the various factors for injunctive relief in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2014814397" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60763fa08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Van Wagner Communications Co., Canada v. Penex Metropolis Ltd</ital>., 2008 CarswellOnt 218 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>, wherein Justice Pattillo stated:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0017"/>… Each of those respected judges are saying, in my view, that in the case of an interlocutory injunction to restrain a breach of a negative covenant, irreparable harm and the balance of convenience need to be still considered. <eos/><bos/>The extent of the consideration, however, will be directly influenced by the strength of a plaintiff&apos;s case. <eos/><bos/>Even where there is a clear breach of a negative covenant which is reasonable on its face, the issues of irreparable harm and balance of convenience cannot be ignored. <eos/><bos/>They may, however, become less of a factor in reaching the final determination of the issue depending on the strength of the plaintiff&apos;s case.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0017"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id82ef8408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">70</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><paratext>Justice Goodman explained that a restrictive covenant in an employment contract akin to a restraint of trade is voidable and will not be enforced unless justified as reasonable between the parties or in the public interest. <eos/><bos/>The onus is on the employer trying to enforce the restrictive covenant to justify it as being no more than is reasonably required to protect its valid proprietary interests between the parties. <eos/><bos/>If it is a non-solicitation clause, it is more likely to be enforced. <eos/><bos/>The difference between a non-solicitation clause and a non-competition clause was described by the Court of Appeal in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2016711239" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6076dbe08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>H.L. Staebler Co. v. Allan</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 4650 (C.A.)</cite.query>, at para. 38, as follows:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0018"/>… A restrictive covenant may restrain either competition or solicitation. <eos/><bos/>A non-competition clause restrains the departing employee from conducting business with former clients and customers whereas a non-solicitation clause merely prohibits the departing employee from soliciting their business.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0018"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id82ef8418e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">71</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Goodman observed that the Agreement employed the words <begin.quote ID="QT_0019"/>“solicit, interfere with or endeavour to entice away”<end.quote refid="QT_0019"/>. <eos/><bos/>This was very clearly language of solicitation. <eos/><bos/>The provisions of the Agreement did not curtail Pitton&apos;s right or ability to carry on a livelihood or business as an insurance broker. <eos/><bos/>Justice Goodman was persuaded that the Agreement was limited to customers of the Ancaster office alone. <eos/><bos/>Nothing in the Agreement prohibited solicitation or competition for clients of any other StoneRidge affiliated office. <eos/><bos/>The two-year limitation clause appeared to be reasonable and in-line with industry norms. <eos/><bos/>The language in the Agreement was clearly in the realm of a non-solicitation prohibition and did not constrain Pitton&apos;s ability to work in the insurance field. <eos/><bos/>Nonetheless, Justice Goodman was satisfied that the plaintiff met the higher burden, if indeed that burden applied to all or any part of this segment of the claim.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82ef8428e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">72</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Clarke Road Transport Inc. v. O&apos;Toole</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id82ef8438e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">73</footnote.reference>] Clarke sought an interim injunction against Dinham, O&apos;Toole and Day &amp; Ross to prevent what Clarke alleged was use of confidential information and solicitation of customers, employees and independent contractors. <eos/><bos/>Dinham and O&apos;Toole were employed at Clarke until July 2017. <eos/><bos/>Both were now employed at Day &amp; Ross, a competitor of Clarke. <eos/><bos/>Prior to their resignations, Dinham and O&apos;Toole worked in Clarke&apos;s Flatbed Division. <eos/><bos/>Upon resigning from Clarke, both were hired at the Flatbed Division of Day &amp; Ross, a company providing a variety of transportation services across Canada through four divisions.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82ef8448e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">74</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Initially, Clarke argued that a “Code of Conduct” was allegedly part of the employment contracts of Dinham and O&apos;Toole. <eos/><bos/>Clarke abandoned these arguments and instead focused on the argument that, as key employees, Dinham and O&apos;Toole owed fiduciary duties to Clarke and argued there was a serious issue raised that those duties had been breached.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82ef8458e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">75</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Clarke argued that it need only demonstrate a serious issue to be tried in relation to the questions: (1) were Dinham and O&apos;Toole key employees who owed fiduciary duties to their former employer and (2) did they breach those duties? <eos/><bos/>Justice Brothers concluded that the proper test to meet was a <ital>prima facie</ital> case.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82f1f508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">76</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Dinham began employment at Clarke in April 2013, after leaving his employment at Day &amp; Ross. <eos/><bos/>On April 26, 2013, Dinham signed a revised employment agreement with Clarke. <eos/><bos/>The revised employment agreement did not contain a non-competition clause. <eos/><bos/>During negotiations, Dinham refused to enter into an agreement with Clarke containing a non-competition clause, consequently, Clarke acquiesced and removed the non-competition clause from the proposed agreement. <eos/><bos/>On April 9, 2015, Dinham was promoted to General Manager, Atlantic Region, Flatbed Division, with Clarke and acknowledged that he made decisions with respect to the operations within the flatbed division. <eos/><bos/>Both Dinham and O&apos;Toole reported to upper management about financial and operational matters.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82f1f518e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">77</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>O&apos;Toole commenced employment with Clarke in January 2001 as a dispatch load coordinator. <eos/><bos/>Prior to being promoted to the position of Operations Manager, Atlantic Region, on April 9, 2015, O&apos;Toole considered leaving Clarke to accept an offer from Jardine. <eos/><bos/>All other members of the Clarke senior management team left for the employ of Jardine at that time. <eos/><bos/>O&apos;Toole, as the Operations Manager, Atlantic Region, Flatbed Division, reported to and assisted Dinham, the then General Manager, Atlantic Region, Flatbed Division.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82f1f528e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">78</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Brothers was of the view concluded that there was a <ital>prima facie</ital> case that Dinham and O&apos;Toole owed fiduciary duties to Clarke. <eos/><bos/>Both Dinham and O&apos;Toole had extensive knowledge of Clarke&apos;s operation and customers. <eos/><bos/>While O&apos;Toole reported to Dinham, both had extensive managerial responsibilities and both had many individuals reporting to them. <eos/><bos/>There was a prima facie case that they were both responsible for managing existing business, customer relations, hiring, setting rates for revenue, negotiating with third-parties, and were responsible for advancing the business. <eos/><bos/>The evidence demonstrated they had a lot of personal contact with and responsibility for a vast proportion of Clarke&apos;s customers in the Flatbed Division.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82f1f538e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">79</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Brothers observed that this was not to say that every employee, who has knowledge of and contact with any employer&apos;s customers would be a fiduciary. <eos/><bos/>However, both individuals held very senior managerial positions and the evidence made out a <ital>prima facie</ital> case that they had knowledge and control over Clarke&apos;s operations. <eos/><bos/>While Dinham and O&apos;Toole both reported to others at Clarke concerning certain company matters, the evidence, at this interim stage, did satisfy, on a <ital>prima facie</ital> basis a level of knowledge of: (1) customers and ability to influence, (2) business and market opportunity and development, (3) confidential information. <eos/><bos/>Both employees “exerted significant autonomy.” <eos/><bos/>Justice Brothers concluded that the evidence provided was largely based on conjecture and suspicion that Dinham and O&apos;Toole had taken confidential information and were using it to solicit customers and owner/operators from Clarke. <eos/><bos/>The affidavit evidence of the defendants categorically disputed these allegations. <eos/><bos/>Justice Brothers concluded that there was very little evidence that demonstrated a <ital>prima facie</ital> case or even raised a serious issue that the defendants were soliciting employees, customers or owner/operators, or using confidential information. <eos/><bos/>Some customers and owner/operators followed Dinham and O&apos;Toole to Day &amp; Ross; however, this alone does not support the imposition of an injunction. <eos/><bos/>The circumstances did not support the extraordinary and rare remedy of an injunction.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82f1f548e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">80</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Brothers further concluded that even if Clarke could demonstrate a <ital>prima facie</ital> case that the defendants breached fiduciary duties, Clarke failed to demonstrate that without an injunction it would suffer irreparable harm that could not be compensated for by way of damages. <eos/><bos/>Clarke&apos;s Flatbed Division was a subsidiary of a larger company which in turn was a subsidiary of a larger organization. <eos/><bos/>The reference to Mathers, United Rentals, ACL, and Atlas, representing 18.3% of Clarke&apos;s revenue in 2016 was only in relation to the Flatbed Division. <eos/><bos/>This did not reflect the larger operation. <eos/><bos/>The applicant&apos; affidavit evidence also suggested that if there was increased loss, in the future, then the business would be at risk. <eos/><bos/>The risk was not alleged to be present currently, consequently there was no irreparable harm. <eos/><bos/>The argument that Clarke would suffer irreparable harm was based on conjecture.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82f1f558e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">81</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Furthermore, if damages are proven at trial, the damages are capable of monetary quantification. <eos/><bos/>There was no suggestion that Clarke would be put out of business without an injunction and there was no evidence of a permanent market loss. <eos/><bos/>If Clarke was successful at trial, any losses were calculable based on revenue earned based on historical performance and any increase in Day &amp; Ross&apos; business based on the prior year. <eos/><bos/>Quantification of loss in these circumstances is routinely done by accountants, actuaries and business valuators.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82f1f568e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">82</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Also, Clarke did not say its business was at risk, only that it would be if a larger market share and more owner/operators left. <eos/><bos/>This alone demonstrated no irreparable harm. <eos/><bos/>There was no suggestion that damages at the end of a trial would not compensate Clarke if their case was made out. <eos/><bos/>Damages are an adequate remedy. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence Clarke would be put out of business or there would be irreversible damage. <eos/><bos/>There was some evidence of loss of market share, but that alone is not enough.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82f46608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">83</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Doors on Demand v. Wierenga</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id82f46618e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">84</footnote.reference>] the defendants were granted an order setting aside a without notice interim injunction restraining Wierenga, for a period of one year, from having contact or contracting for overhead door services with persons known to be clients of DOD. <eos/><bos/>Wierenga was employed by DOD from January 2015 to August 2017. <eos/><bos/>Wierenga gave DOD a month&apos;s notice of his resignation. <eos/><bos/>He advised that he wanted to start his own business. <eos/><bos/>DOD responded by terminating Wierenga&apos;s employment immediately. <eos/><bos/>Teerling asked Wierenga to sign a “non-compete and non-solicitation agreement” but Wierenga declined to do so.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82f46628e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">85</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Where the injunction sought would limit a former employee&apos;s ability to earn a livelihood, the bar is set higher. <eos/><bos/>The applicant must show a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that by competing with DOD, Wierenga was in breach of some legal obligation he had toward DOD. <eos/><bos/>On the without notice application, DOD&apos;s position was that an interim injunction should be granted either because a. Wierenga was a fiduciary of DOD and the business he intended to start would involve, at least potentially, his breaching his fiduciary obligations to DOD, or the terms of Wierenga&apos;s employment were at least partially set out in an employee handbook, which, among other things, required Wierenga to protect and not disclose DOD&apos;s confidential and proprietary information to third parties.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82f46638e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">86</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Burrows observed that there was very little merit to the second of these positions. <eos/><bos/>Though the employee handbook discussed DOD&apos;s expectation that employees would protect the confidentiality and propriety of DOD information, there was an express statement that this was not a contractual obligation. <eos/><bos/>The suggestion of a contractual obligation to maintain confidentiality cannot live with that express contrary acknowledgement.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82f46648e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">87</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Wierenga&apos;s duties, at their highest, involved some degree of supervision of the work of DOD&apos;s other employees, interfacing with customers on whose property he was installing or servicing overhead door equipment, maintaining DOD&apos;s work quality standards, coordinating the scheduling of work with Teerling, monitoring site safety, training employees, and providing feedback regarding employees to management. <eos/><bos/>In order to carry out his day-to-day work, Wierenga would have learned the identity of at least some, probably many, of DOD&apos;s customers. <eos/><bos/>He would have had knowledge of some of their suppliers. <eos/><bos/>He would have known about their prices. <eos/><bos/>And he would know about their methods of carrying out the work of installing and maintaining overhead doors.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82f46658e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">88</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The question was whether Wierenga&apos;s relationship with DOD was a fiduciary relationship. <eos/><bos/>Justice Burrows queried whether Wierenga had discretion or power in his position which he could unilaterally exercise so as to affect DOD&apos;s legal or practical interests; whether DOD was peculiarly vulnerable to Wierenga&apos;s discretion or power; and whether Wierenga undertook to act in the best interest of DOD. <eos/><bos/>Justice Burrows concluded that it was not likely that Wierenga was a fiduciary. <eos/><bos/>Justice Burrows accepted that he was an important and valued employee of this small business. <eos/><bos/>The fact that he did high quality work on individual job sites, that he interacted well with clients, that he provided leadership and guidance to other employees were all important. <eos/><bos/>However, these things could be said of any employee, especially in a small business which serves consumers. <eos/><bos/>Justice Burrows observed that an employee can be highly trusted, valued, and important to the success of a business though he is not a fiduciary. <eos/><bos/>Those features of Wierenga&apos;s employment and relationship with DOD did not elevate his position to that of a fiduciary. <eos/><bos/>DOD had not made out a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case to support its claim to an injunction.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82f46668e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">89</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In considering whether a former employee was a “key employee” for the purpose of attracting a fiduciary duty, the court will look at a former employee&apos;s job duties; the extent or frequency of contact between the employee and customers and/or suppliers; whether the employee was the primary contact with customers and/or suppliers; to what extent the employee had access and made use of knowledge of the former employee&apos;s customers, their accounts, pricing practices and the pricing of product and services; and to what extent the former employee&apos;s information was confidential. <eos/><bos/>In <ital>Canadian Hedge Watch Inc. v. Street</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id82f6d708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">90</footnote.reference>] the plaintiff was granted an interlocutory order prohibiting the defendants from using the plaintiff&apos;s confidential information; soliciting or accepting business from the current and prospective sponsors, clients, and attendees of the plaintiff&apos;s conference; usurping, taking, or converting any corporate assets or opportunities belonging to the plaintiff; unfairly competing with the plaintiff; interfering with the plaintiff&apos;s contractual relations with third parties; misrepresenting that they are associated with the plaintiff or its conferences; and, from arranging, presenting, promoting, sponsoring, or hosting The Alliance for Institutional Dialogue&apos;s “Annual Symposium” in Niagara-on-the-Lake, or elsewhere, and/or any conference of the same or a similar nature in southern Ontario.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82f6d718e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">91</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff was a commercial entity that ran conferences as a revenue-generating business activity. <eos/><bos/>It had established goodwill in its conference. <eos/><bos/>The defendant, Street, had been the Vice President of Sales of the plaintiff since 2009. <eos/><bos/>She became the Chief Operating Officer of the NID Conference upon its creation in 2010. <eos/><bos/>Street resigned from the plaintiff&apos;s employ in 2013 in order to spend more time with her husband and possibly to help him produce practice management conferences in his business. <eos/><bos/>However, she agreed to continue to consult to the plaintiff on a part-time basis under the terms of a written consulting agreement in relation to the NID Conference. <eos/><bos/>As COO of the NID Conference Street was also a member of the Advisory Board. <eos/><bos/>She was the representative of the plaintiff with principal responsibility for running the conference. <eos/><bos/>Together with the defendants Lett and Holt, Street was very successful in developing the NID Conference to its premier place in the industry. <eos/><bos/>There was a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that under a veil of secrecy the defendants agreed to and proceeded to unlawfully take the plaintiff&apos;s corporate assets and its corporate opportunities associated with those assets. <eos/><bos/>At a time when the defendant Street was contractually bound to diligently and faithfully serve the plaintiff, she and the other defendants agreed to take the plaintiff&apos;s conference goodwill and opportunity. <eos/><bos/>Rather than competing openly and honestly, there was a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case, from the defendants&apos; own evidence, that the defendants surreptitiously carried out overt acts to implement their agreement to take the plaintiff&apos;s conference.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82f6d728e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">92</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motions judge concluded that there was at least one serious issue to be tried as to whether Street was a fiduciary in light of her acknowledged significance as the face of the plaintiff in respect of the NID Conference. <eos/><bos/>She had “encyclopedic knowledge” of the plaintiff&apos;s business, market opportunity, customers, and suppliers. <eos/><bos/>If Street was a fiduciary, then she fell under the prohibition against unfair post-employment competition. <eos/><bos/>An important factor in deciding whether a fiduciary&apos;s competition is unfair is whether it is infected by improper conduct prior to the time that the fiduciary left her role with the employer. <eos/><bos/>The defendants had met, agreed to their plan, took the hotel reservations, and prepared to commence sales as if they were the NID Conference before Street even left the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>They incorporated the corporate defendant one week later with Street as a director. <eos/><bos/>Under cross-examination the defendants agreed that Street&apos;s appointment to the board was intentionally done but was reversed later purportedly at Street&apos;s request. <eos/><bos/>The motions judge observed that her appointment was an “error” only in the sense that Street realized that she should not have done it. <eos/><bos/>It was not accidental.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82f6d738e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">93</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The other defendants all knew and participated in Street&apos;s conduct. <eos/><bos/>The motions judge noted that a subordinate who participates in a fiduciary&apos;s breach of duty is liable with the fiduciary. <eos/><bos/>In this case, arguably, it was the other defendants who were the seniors members of the new entity who wished to create a business and induced a subordinate who had duties to the plaintiff to join them and to breach her duties in doing so. <eos/><bos/>Holt and Lett never resigned from the plaintiff&apos;s Advisory Board. <eos/><bos/>While there was no doubt that Holt and Lett were free to compete with the plaintiff generally, there was at least a serious issue to be tried as to whether in agreeing to sit on the plaintiff&apos;s Advisory Board for consideration there was an implied duty that Holt and Lett would act in the best interests of the plaintiff and avoid conflicts of interest vis-à-vis the subject matter of their appointment and not try to usurp the conference for themselves. <eos/><bos/>The defendants Holt and Lett argued that they could not be fiduciaries because they never undertook to sacrifice their interests to protect those of the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>The question of whether by agreeing to join the plaintiff&apos;s Advisory Board, the defendants undertook such duties to the plaintiff in relation to the NID Conference was a serious issue to be tried.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82f6d748e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">94</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Innersolutions Ltd. v. Hooper</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id82f6d758e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">95</footnote.reference>] the Applicant sought injunctive relief to prohibit the Respondents from operating a directly competing business, soliciting and using the Applicant&apos;s trade connections, soliciting and providing services to any of the Applicant&apos;s clients, and disclosing and using the Applicant&apos;s confidential information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82f6d768e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">96</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Applicant provided a specialized counselling program that included psychotherapy and education services to individuals suffering from severe mental illnesses, as well as to their families. <eos/><bos/>The Respondents Hooper and Woolsey were former employees or independent contractors of the Applicant. <eos/><bos/>Woolsey and Hooper incorporated Inspired Minds Inc. while they were working for the Applicant. <eos/><bos/>The Applicant hired Woolsey in April 2007 and Hooper in April 2012. <eos/><bos/>The Applicant required Woolsey and Hooper to sign agreements, which stated that they would learn the design and operation of the Applicant&apos;s DBT program, they would provide treatment using that program, and the Applicant had interests that it wanted to protect. <eos/><bos/>Each agreement required that they not compete for business, clients, or professional services during their employment and that they provide three months&apos; notice of termination. <eos/><bos/>Hooper&apos;s agreement included additional express terms that all patients were to remain with the Applicant in the event of her termination and she would not offer or advertise private practice services in the specialized nature of the Applicant within a four hundred kilometer radius of Calgary for twenty-four months from the date of termination. <eos/><bos/>Woolsey&apos;s agreement also required that all clients were to have the first option to remain with the Applicant in the event of her termination. <eos/><bos/>In June 2012, Woolsey and her husband wanted to explore the possibility of purchasing the Applicant&apos;s business. <eos/><bos/>To facilitate this exploration, they signed a confidentiality/non-competition agreement.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82f94808e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">97</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The modified first branch of the test for an interlocutory injunction required the Court to consider whether the Applicant had established a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that the restrictions were enforceable against the Respondents. <eos/><bos/>This was the Applicant&apos;s onus and the Court found that although the Applicant had a proprietary interest that was worthy of protection, there was insufficient evidence that would allow the Court fully to assess the reasonableness of the restrictive covenant it was seeking against the Respondents. <eos/><bos/>That was not to say that such evidence was not available. <eos/><bos/>It simply meant that the Applicant had not met its onus on the motion.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82f94818e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">98</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motions judge found that the agreements that bound the respondents were too broad or ambiguous which pointed to their unreasonableness. <eos/><bos/>The Applicant argued that either or both of Hooper and Woolsey had fiduciary duties towards the Applicant. <eos/><bos/>The motions judge observed that there is no doubt that a director and officer of corporation acts in a fiduciary capacity towards the corporation. <eos/><bos/>Fiduciary obligations can extend beyond those roles. <eos/><bos/>Although the Applicant provided the respondents with certain confidential information, they did not have the authority to affect the Applicant&apos;s “legal and economic interests”.<eos/><bos/> They did, however, have exclusive access to certain of the Applicant&apos;s clients. <eos/><bos/>The motions judge stated:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0020"/>But does that place them in a fiduciary relationship vis-à-vis the Applicant? <eos/><bos/>In <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1981177092" w-pub-number="0005150" w-pinpoint-page="477" ID="I609bf0108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>WJ Christie &amp; Co v Greer</ital> (1981), 121 DLR (3d) 472 at 477 (Man CA)</cite.query>, the Manitoba Court of Appeal said the following:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext>There is nothing to prevent an ordinary employee from terminating his employment, and normally that employee is free to compete with his former employer. <eos/><bos/>The right to compete freely may be constrained by contract….<eos/><bos/> But it is different for a director/officer/key management person who occupies a fiduciary position. <eos/><bos/>Upon his resignation and departure, that person is entitled to accept business from former client, but direct solicitation of that business is not permissible. <eos/><bos/>Having accepted a position of trust, the individual is not entitled to allow his own self-interest to collide and conflict with fiduciary responsibilities. <eos/><bos/>The direct solicitation of former clients traverses the boundary of acceptable conduct….<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0020"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id82f94828e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">99</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motions judge concluded that it did not appear that the respondents were “key employees” or “key management”.<eos/><bos/> At best, they were “ordinary employees”.<eos/><bos/> Thus, they were <begin.quote ID="QT_0021"/>“free to compete with the Applicant. <eos/><bos/>That was not to say that with more evidence a court might find that they were key employees. <eos/><bos/>That issue would be left to the trial judge.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0021"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id82f94838e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">100</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>With respect to a duty of fidelity and good faith to his employer, a duty much narrower in scope than the duty owed by a departing employee who stands in the position of a fiduciary, the respondents gave the clients an option to stay with the Applicant. <eos/><bos/>Further, on their departure from the Applicant&apos;s employ, they shredded their patient lists and left the patient files with the Applicant. <eos/><bos/>Again, further evidence might be extracted during the trial that might provide more information concerning a breach of their duty of fidelity and good faith, but such information was simply not before the motions judge.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82f94848e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">101</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The length of time that fiduciary obligations may extend beyond the termination of the relationship will be governed by the particular circumstances. <eos/><bos/>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2034610279" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60a035d18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Benayoune &amp; Associates FZE v. Kanata Chemical Technologies</cite.query> Inc.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id82f94858e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">102</footnote.reference>] in the course of the KCT receivership, certain assets, including intellectual property, were conveyed to the moving party Kanata. <eos/><bos/>Choses in action were also assigned to Kanata. <eos/><bos/>Kanata brought a motion for an interlocutory injunction against Kamal and Muhammad, former senior executives of KCT, and their new company, Kamal, a competing business. <eos/><bos/>The respondents were brothers. <eos/><bos/>Both were directors of KCT. Because of the receivership, Kamal and Muhammad were notified that their employment was terminated. <eos/><bos/>However, both of them were given an offer to continue to assist the Receiver on a temporary basis. <eos/><bos/>Muhammad did so until August 27, 2013. <eos/><bos/>Kamal did so until October 7, 2013. <eos/><bos/>Both Kamal and Muhammad were left with substantial unpaid employee remuneration after the receivership. <eos/><bos/>Benayoune put together a bid on KCT&apos;s assets and entered into an agreement with the Receiver through a company that became Kanata. <eos/><bos/>An Asset Purchase Agreement was approved by the court and the asset sale closed on October 18, 2013. <eos/><bos/>Kanata then initiated its business with a view to marketing the same proprietary technologies previously sold by KCT. On September 26, 2013, Kamal and Muhammad each tendered their resignation as KCT directors and registered a URL for a new website. <eos/><bos/>A new company was incorporated shortly thereafter.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82fbb908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">103</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Injunctive relief was sought on the basis that the Agreements with Kamal and Muhammad were effectively assigned to Kanata under the APA, and that KCT&apos;s cause of action for breach of fiduciary duty by Kamal and Muhammad was effectively assigned by the Receiver as provided for in the APA. <eos/><bos/>The motions judge concluded that Kanata must show a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case. <eos/><bos/>The motions judge observed that judicial consensus has imposed the requirement of a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case in cases that involved restrictive covenants and employment contracts, and in actions against former employees. <eos/><bos/>The strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case threshold means that the moving party must show that the claim is almost certain to succeed.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82fbb918e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">104</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motions judge also observed that Kamal and Muhammad obviously owed fiduciary duties to KCT. They were both directors and very senior officers. <eos/><bos/>However, the business of KCT came to an end when it was assigned into bankruptcy by the Receiver in October 2013. <eos/><bos/>As of that time, all or substantially all of its assets had been sold. <eos/><bos/>Kamal and Muhammad had resigned as directors and their employment had been terminated. <eos/><bos/>Nonetheless, their fiduciary duties to KCT may have continued to some degree.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82fbb928e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">105</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Kanata submitted that Kamal and Muhammad should have told the Receiver of their plans to set up a competing business, and if they had done so the transaction captured in the APA would have “cratered”.<eos/><bos/> If so, the motions judge noted there might be a remedy. <eos/><bos/>However, the issue on the motion was the availability of an interlocutory injunction now, as opposed to at that time, rather than a claim for damages. <eos/><bos/>Whatever might have happened at the time, it remained the case that shortly thereafter the APA closed, KCT was assigned into bankruptcy and it had ceased all business. <eos/><bos/>The opportunity for KCT to negotiate a different deal could not be recreated now using the proposed interlocutory injunction.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82fbb938e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">106</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Kanata also alleged improper solicitation of customers and misuse of confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The proposed injunction regarding customer solicitation may have been relevant to KCT in 2013, but a fiduciary duty regarding non-solicitation ordinarily only continues post-termination in order to give the company time to solidify its relationships with customers before the former employee begins competition. <eos/><bos/>That purpose did not support the continuation of the fiduciary duties to KCT.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82fbb948e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">107</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Finally, with respect to confidential information, there was the possibility of a direct claim by Kanata for breach of confidence but it had not been pleaded. <eos/><bos/>There was also the possibility of that given the sale of the intellectual property and goodwill, the fiduciary duty to protect confidential information formerly of KCT continued for a reasonable time post-closing and post-bankruptcy. <eos/><bos/>However, the court did not find the requisite strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case of breach of such a fiduciary duty. <eos/><bos/>There was some evidence, which was flatly denied, and it did not meet the required threshold.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82fbb958e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">108</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Edgetch HVAC Services Ltd. v. Ubhi</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id82fbb968e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">109</footnote.reference>] the plaintiffs sought an interim injunction restraining the defendants from competing against Edgetch and from soliciting clients and employees of Edgetch. <eos/><bos/>The defendants fell into three categories. <eos/><bos/>Jesse was a one-third owner of Edgetch. <eos/><bos/>Jesse founded Edgetch with the plaintiffs Randy and Thomas. <eos/><bos/>Edgetch was an authorized sales and service distributor for gas detection products manufactured by Honeywell. <eos/><bos/>From 2008 to 2014, Edgetch was solely in Jesse&apos;s name, as Randy and Thomas continued to work at Honeywell. <eos/><bos/>In January 2014, after Randy and Thomas were laid off from Honeywell, the three of them engaged in a corporate reorganization of Edgetch and executed a unanimous shareholder agreement. <eos/><bos/>James and Extreme were independent contractors for Edgetch. <eos/><bos/>The remaining defendants were former employees of Edgetch. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs alleged that Jesse orchestrated the resignation of the former employees, the incorporation of Extreme and the possession and control of Edgetch&apos;s confidential information for the purpose of competing against Edgetch with Extreme.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82fe2a08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">110</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiffs&apos; narrative was one of being the victim to Jesse&apos;s plan to direct the other defendants to use proprietary information to solicit clients and compete against Edgetch in a way that did not overtly offend his obligations as set out in the USA. <eos/><bos/>Jesse&apos;s narrative was one of the victim as well. <eos/><bos/>He stated that he was the victim of exclusion by the plaintiffs who purposely denied him his rights under the USA and were now relying on it to prevent him from earning a livelihood with his recently formed company. <eos/><bos/>Jesse submitted that the plaintiffs could not seek to enforce the restrictive covenants in the USA, as the plaintiffs effectively repudiated the agreement and excluded him from the business improperly. <eos/><bos/>The former employees&apos; narrative was one of good, honest people with no choice but to leave Edgetch to join Extreme in order to earn a livelihood, given the stresses created by nepotism and racism at Edgetch.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82fe2a18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">111</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motions judge was of the view that it was the plaintiffs&apos; narrative that was supported and demonstrated by the evidentiary record. <eos/><bos/>The motions judge did not accept that Jesse was a victim of exclusion by Randy and Thomas. <eos/><bos/>The exclusion efforts were conduct reactive to Jesse&apos;s efforts to defeat Edgetch by soliciting its clients and competing against it with the assistance of former employees. <eos/><bos/>The motions judge did not accept that the former employees left Edgetch <ital>en masse</ital> without notice or transition because of nepotism or racism. <eos/><bos/>The timing of the resignations coincided too conveniently with Jesse&apos;s efforts to have the restrictive covenants in the USA waived, and none of the letters of resignation detailed nepotism or racism as the reason for leaving Edgetch. <eos/><bos/>The former employees left to assist Jesse with his efforts to compete against Edgetch through Extreme. <eos/><bos/>Finally, the motions judge did not accept that James decided to rebrand and expand his business around the same time that Jesse was negotiating a way out of his restrictive covenants and the former employees resigned without notice. <eos/><bos/>The only conclusion that failed to defy common sense was that Jesse took intentional and covert steps to coordinate with James and Edgetch employees in order to compete with Edgetch through Extreme.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82fe2a28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">112</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The defendants argued that there were no proprietary marketing or business techniques that Edgetch used to solicit customers on the basis that Edgetch&apos;s start up and service reports contain information that was easily obtained directly from customers and was generally offered by customers, upon request, to any service providers, especially competitive service providers who requested it, as this facilitated customers&apos; efforts to secure competitive quotes from different service providers before awarding the work. <eos/><bos/>The motions judge disagreed with this submission. <eos/><bos/>Edgetch recorded their clients&apos; specific products, pricing and servicing requirements. <eos/><bos/>This was information critical to the company, permitting it to know the clients&apos; needs and when these needs must be addressed. <eos/><bos/>It was not sufficient to say that the remaining shareholders could have called their clients to ask about products, pricing or when servicing was due. <eos/><bos/>The defendant Neha had the database of all clients, which included all upcoming scheduling for servicing, and she would update the database every evening. <eos/><bos/>The documentary evidence reflected the use of this information, including service reports, start-up reports and the excel service database to solicit business on behalf of Extreme. <eos/><bos/>The documentary evidence reflected the use by the defendants of Edgetch&apos;s proprietary information to solicit Edgetch&apos;s clients and compete with its business. <eos/><bos/>It put them in a position to harm the business of Edgetch as it gave them the opportunity to reach out and schedule the service required in accordance with the information retained.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82fe2a38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">113</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motions judge observed that the cases focus on the result of the enforcement of the covenant when adopting the strong <ital>prima facie</ital> test. <eos/><bos/>It is the result, interfering with an individual&apos;s ability to earn a livelihood that properly informs the analysis. <eos/><bos/>In this case, the restrictive covenant was agreed to by shareholders of equal bargaining power in a commercial context and not by an employee as a condition of employment or in the context of a sale of business. <eos/><bos/>The motions judge concluded nonetheless that the strong <ital>prima facie</ital> test still applied as the consequence remained consistent in that the shareholder was restricted in his ability to make a living. <eos/><bos/>Therefore, the higher threshold of a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case was applicable to the first branch of the <ital>RJR-MacDonald</ital> test.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82fe2a48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">114</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Jesse was the only defendant that was contractually prohibited from soliciting Edgetch&apos;s clients or employees. <eos/><bos/>He was the president and director of Edgetch. <eos/><bos/>Jesse breached the USA and his fiduciary duties as shareholder and director by soliciting clients and employees of Edgetch and using confidential information to compete directly against Edgetch. <eos/><bos/>While the evidence remained in its early stages and there had been some reliance on hearsay, the plaintiffs established a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case as against Jesse. <eos/><bos/>This conclusion was reached in the context of reasonable restrictive covenants in the USA. <eos/><bos/>The USA was a commercial contract amongst business partners of equal bargaining power bringing different and complimenting skills to the relationship. <eos/><bos/>At the commencement of their relationship, the partners negotiated and agreed to the terms therein. <eos/><bos/>It must be presumed that they did so with knowledge of the industry and in a manner that reasonably reflected the risks inherent in their business. <eos/><bos/>The court ought not to impose its views on reasonableness years later upon the breakdown of the relationship, unless the contract was entered into unfairly or circumstances occurred in the interim that could not have been reasonably foreseen at the time of the contract. <eos/><bos/>Further, the territorial scope was limited and did not extend to all territories within which Edgetch did business.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id82fe2a58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">115</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>None of the remaining defendants were contractually prohibited from soliciting Edgetch&apos;s clients or employees or prohibited from competing with Edgetch upon leaving the company. <eos/><bos/>However, as they assisted Jesse in the breach of his fiduciary duties, they too were liable for the breach.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id83009b08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">116</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The remaining defendants denied possessing or misusing any information belonging to Edgetch and submitted that the information at issue was neither confidential nor proprietary. <eos/><bos/>The motions judge disagreed with this submission. <eos/><bos/>The documentary evidence demonstrated a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that Neha, Arjun, Vic and Rovind misused confidential information for the benefit of Extreme. <eos/><bos/>Aman, Vic and Micky resigned their positions without notice, in order to work for Extreme. <eos/><bos/>James incorporated Extreme. <eos/><bos/>Extreme&apos;s business was founded, at least in part, on the misuse of confidential information. <eos/><bos/>By their very employment with Extreme, therefore, the former employees could be said to have misused confidential information for the benefit of a competitor. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs established a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that the defendants misused confidential information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id83009b18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">117</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff in <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2039182032" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60b8c6e18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">FLS Transportation Services Inc. v. Charger Logistics</cite.query> Inc.</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id83009b28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">118</footnote.reference>] provided logistic and freight brokerage services. <eos/><bos/>Its contracts with clients were generally short-term. <eos/><bos/>As a result, the business between third party logistics companies and their clients is easily transferrable. <eos/><bos/>The Defendant Spalding had worked in the trucking, logistics and transport industry for over 20 years. <eos/><bos/>He had developed a good relationship with a significant number of clients which he brought with him when he was recruited to join FLS in 2009. <eos/><bos/>He understood from the terms of his employment contract that he could take his own book of business with him if he left FLS. Spalding opened a branch office for FLS in Milton, Ontario in 2012. <eos/><bos/>At the time of Spalding&apos;s departure, FLS Milton had eight employees, including three salespersons. <eos/><bos/>FLS Milton generated annual revenue of about $300,000 to $400,000. <eos/><bos/>On February 26, 2016, Spalding was told that FLS had been purchased by a private equity firm. <eos/><bos/>Spalding understood from this conversation that the new owners would likely close FLS Milton in the near future and transfer those operations to their larger office in Oakville. <eos/><bos/>Spalding had no interest in moving to the Oakville office. <eos/><bos/>At that point, Spalding decided to look for other employment. <eos/><bos/>On February 29, 2016, Spalding resigned from FLS. The Defendants Burchatzki, Russell, Natt, and Miehm also resigned on February 29, 2016. <eos/><bos/>The Defendants McIntyre and Costa resigned on March 1, 2016. <eos/><bos/>Prior to their resignation, the former employees held the following positions at FLS Milton: Spalding was the Senior Branch Director; Burchatzki and Russell were Sales Executives; Natt was a Customer Service Representative; Miehm was a Logistic Support Representative; McIntyre and Costa were Logistics Coordinators. <eos/><bos/>The Former Employees were hired by the Defendant, Charger on March 1, 2016 to work at its office in Mississauga, Ontario. <eos/><bos/>Since the resignation of the Former Employees, FLS had seen about a 90 percent decline in the number of orders placed by the clients serviced out of FLS Milton.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id83009b38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">119</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>FLS alleged that the Former Employees removed confidential information related to all aspects of its business and clients. <eos/><bos/>FLS alleged that the Former Employees used that information to solicit business, on behalf of Charger, from FLS&apos; clients. <eos/><bos/>FLS sought an interim injunction pending the hearing of a motion for an interlocutory injunction.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id83009b48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">120</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Where an employer seeks to place restrictions on a person&apos;s ability to engage in their chosen vocation and to earn a livelihood, then a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case must be shown. <eos/><bos/>In such cases, the moving party must show that its claim is almost certain to succeed. <eos/><bos/>The strong <ital>prima facie</ital> standard applies regardless of whether the basis for the restriction on an employee is based on a contract or a common law cause of action such as breach of fiduciary duty or breach of confidence.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id83009b58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">121</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>FLS submitted that the Former Employees breached the restrictive covenants found in their employment contracts related to retaining and disclosing confidential information as well as soliciting employees and customers. <eos/><bos/>FLS also submitted that the Former Employees were liable at common law for breach of fiduciary duty and breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>The reasonableness of the covenants was questionable. <eos/><bos/>First, FLS, in earlier proceedings, stated that for this type of business there is no proprietary interest in customers nor is there “confidential information” entitled to protection given that its client lists, rates and related business information are almost entirely publicly available. <eos/><bos/>The evidence of FLS&apos; own executives in other proceedings undermined its position on this motion that the business information was confidential and proprietary. <eos/><bos/>In any event, even if the covenants were found to be reasonable, evidence did not support a finding that there was a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that these covenants had been breached by the Former Employees.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id83009b68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">122</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>FLS had also not established a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> claim for breach of confidence given that the information did not possess the quality of confidence.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id83030c08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">123</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00007" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2028290296" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60c263d18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Maudore Minerals Ltd. v. Harbour Foundation,</ital></cite.query>[<footnote.reference refid="Id83030c18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">124</footnote.reference>] Maudore brought a motion to enjoin Harbour Foundation and City Securities from voting their shares and from soliciting proxies on the grounds that Dr. Howard Carr, who was Harbour Foundation&apos;s and City Securities Limited&apos;s nominee as a director on the proposed board of directors, breached a confidentiality agreement signed by him while acting on behalf of Harbour Foundation and City Securities. <eos/><bos/>Alternatively, Maudore sought an injunction on the basis that the defendants perpetrated a breach of confidence by misusing confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The Harbour Foundation and City Securities Limited together owned 18.4% of the shares of Maudore, a Canadian mining corporation, and together were its single-largest shareholder. <eos/><bos/>With the support of the second-largest shareholder, Harbour Foundation and City Securities nominated and planned to vote for a new slate of directors at the annual and special meeting of the shareholders. <eos/><bos/>On either theory of liability, the alleged breach was that Harbour Foundation and City Securities were using confidential information to obtain proxies with the aim of replacing the current board of directors with a new board.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In 2011, Harbour began to have doubts about the competency of Maudore&apos;s management. <eos/><bos/>Harbour asked Howard Carr, to investigate Maudore. <eos/><bos/>Dr. Carr analyzed the publicly available documentation about Maudore. <eos/><bos/>He also reviewed public documents on the geology of the Comtois gold project and about volcanogenic massive sulphide deposits in the area of the project. <eos/><bos/>Dr. Carr reported to Harbour that there was a good prospect that Maudore Mineral&apos;s property did contain an economically-feasible gold deposit as had been reported, but that the company&apos;s management seemed to be functioning at a very low level technically. <eos/><bos/>Harbour decided to send his son along with Dr. Carr to visit the Comtois gold project site on behalf of the Harbour Foundation to verify the accuracy of the public disclosures and to assess the competence of the current management. <eos/><bos/>Harbour contacted Mr. Shorr and asked about the possibility of his son visiting the project. <eos/><bos/>Harbour did not mention that Dr. Carr would accompany his son. <eos/><bos/>There was no advance notice of plans to replace or displace the management team. <eos/><bos/>There was no disclosure that the agenda would be to assess management, Maudore&apos;s business plan, and general matters. <eos/><bos/>None of these threatening prospects was ever communicated to Maudore. <eos/><bos/>After learning that Dr. Carr would be attending, Maudore protected itself with a confidentiality agreement.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id83030c28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">125</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>There was a great deal of technical information discussed by Doctors Jourdan and Carr. <eos/><bos/>Dr. Carr appeared to be extraordinarily well prepared for the meeting, and his questioning was substantive, detailed, and not superficial. <eos/><bos/>Dr. Jourdan provided detailed and elaborate answers. <eos/><bos/>Dr. Carr was provided with drill core sections and associated sections as requested. <eos/><bos/>Dr. Carr&apos;s evidence was that the tour resumed and the group went to one of Maudore&apos;s drill sites. <eos/><bos/>Shortly thereafter, they returned to the core shed and viewed more sections, which are physical samples and also cross-sections, which are data sheets or charts of information derived from physical sources. <eos/><bos/>Dr. Carr saw between 20 and 50 of the approximately 100 cross-sections. <eos/><bos/>The cross-sections would have included data that had been assembled from information learned after the 43–101 Report. <eos/><bos/>Some or all of the information from cross-sections may have been disclosed in press releases or public disclosure documents after the 43–101 Report or information that would be disclosed in future press releases.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id83030c38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">126</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Dr. Carr reported on the visit to Mr. Harbour. <eos/><bos/>Dr. Carr prepared an outline of the steps he would take if he became Maudore&apos;s CEO, which he called the “100 Day Action Plan.” <eos/><bos/>He presented the plan to a committee of Maudore&apos;s board, formed to consider new nominees to Maudore&apos;s board and management. <eos/><bos/>Maudore alleged that Dr. Carr prepared his action plan using confidential information acquired by his visit to the Comtois site. <eos/><bos/>Harbour Foundation and City Securities issued their Dissident Proxy Circular, which included as an appendix the “100-day plan” that had been prepared by Dr. Carr.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id83030c48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">127</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The court was of the view that Maudore must show a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case because granting or refusing the injunction would be determinative of the underlying dispute that concerned the election of competing slates of directors. <eos/><bos/>With a possibly viable claim for breach of confidence in play, Maudore must simply show a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that (1) the defendants received confidential information pursuant to the Confidentiality Agreement or in circumstances governed by the law of breach of confidence; and (2) they made an unauthorized use of the confidential information (be that unauthorized use a breach of contract or be it a breach of confidence).<eos/><bos/> Maudore had shown a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that the defendants received confidential information from Maudore. <eos/><bos/>However, Maudore had shown only a weak case that there was a misuse of the confidential information. <eos/><bos/>It followed that Maudore&apos;s request for an interlocutory injunction should be dismissed.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id83030c58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">128</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The court observed that a misuse of confidential information requires a use of confidential information. <eos/><bos/>Two uses were identified. <eos/><bos/>First, the confidential information was used to motivate or to give Harbour Foundation and City Securities the comfort it needed to undertake a proxy fight, which it did not need permission to do but apparently required some measure of self-confidence to undertake. <eos/><bos/>Second, the confidential information was used to prepare the proxy fight material. <eos/><bos/>However, the Court did not regard these two uses of the information obtained by Dr. Carr as showing a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case of misuse of confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The first alleged misuse of the information lacked substance because the information obtained from the site visit was no more than a motivational catalyst and it was difficult to say whether the motivation came from confidential information or from the fact that the confidential information was consistent with the extensive public information that Dr. Carr had ascertained. <eos/><bos/>The second alleged misuse of the information to prepare the dissident proxy circular, lacked substance because Maudore could not actually identify confidential information in the dissent proxy circular. <eos/><bos/>Both alleged misuses arguably fell within the expressly permitted uses of assisting Dr. Carr in his review of Maudore&apos;s properties and projects for Harbour Foundation and evaluating Maudore&apos;s properties and projects on behalf of Harbour Foundation. <eos/><bos/>It was arguable that using the information for the purpose of deciding to exercise shareholder&apos;s rights was not a misuse of confidential information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id83057d08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">129</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The balance of convenience did not favour the granting of an injunction. <eos/><bos/>Assuming a breach of confidence, it seems not to have genuinely perturbed Maudore&apos;s management and there was something to be said for the suggestion that the discomfort or inconvenience was not genuine but rather a cover for a tactical device in the proxy fight. <eos/><bos/>The parties were to be left to win or lose the proxy fight on the merits.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id83057d18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">130</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>For the purposes of a motion for an interlocutory injunction, the court in <ital>GDI Solutions Inc. v. Walker</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id83057d28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">131</footnote.reference>] did not need to consider whether there was a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that the other named defendants were fiduciaries of GDL, as there was a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that Walker was a fiduciary of GDL and the other named defendants were impressed with fiduciary duties by joining Walker at Hudson in a competing business. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff GDL discovered that the defendant Walker, the individual from whom it purchased the GDL business, had, with several of his former subordinates and employees at GDL, joined a newly established direct competitor that was actively soliciting GDL clients. <eos/><bos/>Walker had started the information technology business in 2003. <eos/><bos/>GDL purchased the business, including its goodwill, technology, and book of business, from Walker in early 2010. <eos/><bos/>As a condition of the purchase, Walker became general manager of GDL, and expressly covenanted not to compete with GDL, solicit or accept business from its clients, solicit or employ its employees, or misuse its confidential information during his employment and for a period thereafter. <eos/><bos/>In June 2011, Walker was introduced to Evershed and Jankovic, a former employee of GDL. Evershed was planning to expand his IT business to Ottawa. <eos/><bos/>He incorporated Hudson on October 24, 2011. <eos/><bos/>Jankovic helped to set up Hudson. <eos/><bos/>In November of 2011, Walker and Mears both left GDL. Walker advised GDL that he was going to do consulting work and Mears advised that he was going to work for his father, an IT consultant. <eos/><bos/>Both joined Hudson. <eos/><bos/>Hudson then began to offer a CPR-like service for data recovery. <eos/><bos/>There were only two companies other than GDL and Hudson offering such a service. <eos/><bos/>Other employees also joined Hudson.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id83057d38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">132</footnote.reference>] There was no evidence that any of the defendants other than Walker had an employment agreement or a non-compete/non-solicitation agreement with the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>Fiduciary obligations attach to employees who depart with fiduciaries to work with competitive businesses. <eos/><bos/>Were it otherwise, the fiduciary would be permitted to do indirectly what he or she cannot do directly. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff met the tests, that there was a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case made out, that misappropriation of GDL&apos;s data and use of confidential information gave rise to the probability of irreparable harm and that the balance of convenience favoured the plaintiff in this regard.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id83057d48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">133</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Polar Wireless Corp. v. Roberts</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id83057d58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">134</footnote.reference>] Polar alleged that four individual defendants had recently occupied key positions at Polar and had started competing directly with Polar through Go To. <eos/><bos/>Polar also sought the return of any confidential and/or proprietary information of Polar by the defendants and an order preserving all information, documents and data in any format, electronic or otherwise, in the possession and or control of the defendants and relating to Polar, its technology, business and/or operations. <eos/><bos/>The defendants did not have contractual non-competition agreements or non-solicitation agreements.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id83057d68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">135</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The court noted that some courts in Ontario have held that the higher standard of a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case should apply where parties are seeking to enforce restrictive covenants, both in the context of an employment agreement and the sale of a business. <eos/><bos/>In other decisions, the courts have not insisted that the parties seeking to enforce a restrictive covenant make out a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case. <eos/><bos/>They have found that where a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case can be made out, there is no need to examine the second and third parts of the injunction test. <eos/><bos/>Where only a serious issue to be tried can be established, there is more emphasis on the second and third parts of the injunction test. <eos/><bos/>Here, the court agreed with the approach of Justice Pattillo in <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00008" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2014814397" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60db6a118e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Van Wagner Communications Co., Canada v. Penex Metropolis</cite.query> Ltd.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id83057d78e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">136</footnote.reference>] that even if a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case of a breach of a restrictive covenant by the defendants is evident, the issues of irreparable harm and balance of convenience must be examined, but may become less of a factor depending on the strength of the plaintiff&apos;s case.<eos/><bos/></paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0022"/>Each of those respected judges are saying, in my view, that in the case of an interlocutory injunction to restrain a breach of a negative covenant, irreparable harm and the balance of convenience need to be still considered. <eos/><bos/>The extent of the consideration, however, will be directly influenced by the strength of the plaintiff&apos;s case. <eos/><bos/>Even where there is a clear breach of a negative covenant which is reasonable on its face, the issues of irreparable harm and balance of convenience cannot be ignored. <eos/><bos/>They may, however, become less of a factor in reaching the final determination of the issue depending on the strength of the plaintiff&apos;s case.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0022"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id8307ee08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">137</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motions judge concluded that there was a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that Roberts was a fiduciary and that those fiduciary duties had been breached by him and that there had been a breach of confidence by him. <eos/><bos/>Roberts understood that after his termination he could advise his contacts of his termination and that was the extent of what he was permitted to do. <eos/><bos/>He understood that he owed a fiduciary obligation to Polar. <eos/><bos/>However, within 7 days of Roberts&apos; departure, he was engaged in business on behalf of Go To and appeared to be soliciting Polar&apos;s business opportunities. <eos/><bos/>There was also a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that the other defendants were impressed with fiduciary duties having joined Mr. Roberts at Go To which was a company that was clearly competing with Polar in the alternative roaming solutions industry. <eos/><bos/>Fiduciary duties can apply to employee, and independent contractors, who leave with fiduciaries to work in a competing business. <eos/><bos/>If the court were to grant injunctive relief, it must be granted against all of the defendants as their positions and responsibilities were essential to Polar&apos;s business and it appeared that they all had access to confidential information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8307ee18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">138</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Id82beb008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00009" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1986268204" w-pub-number="0005653" ID="I60df3aa08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Drake International Inc. v. Tennenbaum</ital> (1986), 10 C.P.R. (3d) 119 (Ont. H.C.J.), at p. 120</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82beb018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00010" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1976147414" w-pub-number="0005652" ID="I60dffdf18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Amer-Can Development Corp. v. Tele Time Saver Inc.</ital></cite.query> (1976), 1 C.P.C. 230, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00011" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1976147414" w-pub-number="0005652" ID="I60dffdf28e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">29 C.P.R. (2d) 272 (Ont. H.C.J.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00012" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2031914048" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60dffdf48e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Planit Search Inc. v. Mann</ital>, 2013 CarswellOnt 15233, 2013 ONSC 6847</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82beb028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00013" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1985031070" w-pub-number="0004891" ID="I60e491d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Speed Seal Products Ltd. v. Paddington</ital>, [1985] 1 W.L.R. 1327 (C.A.), at p. 1332</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82beb038e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>4</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00014" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1974027100" w-pub-number="0004651" ID="I60e4b8e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>American Cyanamid Co. v. Ethicon Ltd.</ital>, [1975] A.C. 396 (H.L.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00015" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1967017749" w-pub-number="0004891" ID="I60e4b8e28e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Harman Pictures N.V. v. Osborne</ital>, [1967] 1 W.L.R. 723 (Ch.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82beb048e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>5</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00016" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1984033735" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I60e507008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cayne v. Global Natural Resources plc</ital>, [1984] 1 All E.R. 225 (C.A.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00017" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1968018312" w-pub-number="0004831" ID="I60e507028e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Coco v. A.N. Clark (Engineers) Ltd.</ital>, [1969] R.P.C. 41 (Ch.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00018" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1976025195" w-pub-number="0004728" ID="I60e507048e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Belfast Ropework Co. v. Pixdane Ltd.</ital>, [1976] F.S.R. 337 (C.A.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82beb058e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>6</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00019" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1987290159" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I60e52e108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Dialadex Communications Inc. v. Crammond</ital> (1987), 34 D.L.R. (4th) 392, 57 O.R. (2d) 746 (H.C.J.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82beb068e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>7</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00020" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1987290159" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I60e778008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Dialadex Communications Inc. v. Crammond</ital> (1987), 34 D.L.R. (4th) 392, 57 O.R. (2d) 746 (H.C.J.), at pp. 396 and 403</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00021" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2030642293" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I60e778038e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jardine Lloyd Thompson Canada Inc. v. Harke-Hunt</ital>, 2013 CarswellAlta 861, 2013 ABQB 313</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82c12108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>8</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00022" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1986192083" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I60e925b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Mercury Marine Ltd. v. Dillon</ital> (1986), 30 D.L.R. (4th) 627, 56 O.R. (2d) 266 (H.C.J.)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>See also <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00023" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1975027181" w-pub-number="0003898" ID="I60e925b38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Fellowes &amp; Son v. Fisher</ital>, [1976] 1 Q.B. 122 (C.A.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00024" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1976025421" w-pub-number="0004728" ID="I60e925b58e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Office Overload Ltd. v. Gunn</ital>, [1977] F.S.R. 39 (C.A.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00025" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2002453768" w-pub-number="0003986" ID="I60e925b78e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Windship Aviation Ltd. v. DeMeulles,</ital> [2003] 1 W.W.R. 393, 5</cite.query> Alta. L.R. (4th) 133 (Q.B.); <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00026" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2000671032" w-pub-number="0006458" ID="I60e925b98e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Merrill Lynch Canada Inc. v. Pastro</ital>, 2000 BCCA 243</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00027" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2018889038" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I60e925bb8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Dynamex Canada Franchise Holdings Inc. v. P&amp;D Investments Ltd.</ital> (2009), 177 A.C.W.S. (3d) 794 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00028" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2005575994" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I60e925bd8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Hobbs v. TDI Canada Ltd.</ital> (2004), 246 D.L.R. (4th) 43, [2004] O.J. No. 4876 (C.A.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00029" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017937542" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I60e925c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Shafron v. KRG Insurance Brokers (Western) Inc.</ital> (2009), 301 D.L.R. (4th) 522, 2009 SCC 6</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00030" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2021951177" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I60e925c38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>MD Management Ltd. v. Campbell</ital> (2010), 188 A.C.W.S. (3d) 1145, 2010 ONSC 2315</cite.query>, leave to appeal to Ont. C.A. <eos/><bos/><case.history>granted</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00031" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2022792348" w-pub-number="0007659" ID="I60e925c68e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2010 ONSC 4217 (Div. Ct.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00032" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028350994" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60e925c88e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Altus Group Ltd. v. Yeoman</ital>, 2012 CarswellOnt 9503, 2012 ONSC 4406</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00033" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027654193" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I60e925cb8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Fuller Western Rubber Linings Ltd. v. Spence Corrosion Services Ltd</ital>., 2012 CarswellAlta 777, 2012 ABCA 137</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00034" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027180487" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I60e925ce8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>6180 Fraser Holdings Inc. v. Ali</ital>, 2012 CarswellBC 495, 2012 BCSC 247</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00035" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2021358352" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I60e94cc28e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>F &amp; G Delivery Ltd. v. MacKenzie</ital>, 2010 CarswellBC 318, 2010 BCSC 195</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00036" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2015925450" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I60e94cc58e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Corporate Images Holdings Partnership v. Satchell</ital>, 2008 CarswellBC 844, 2008 BCSC 525</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82c12118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>9</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00037" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1989190393" w-pub-number="0004740" ID="I60ea10108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Dairy Crest Ltd. v. Piggott</ital>, [1989] I.C.R. 92 (C.A.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00038" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1988182950" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I60ea10128e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Lawrence David Ltd. v. Ashton</ital>, [1991] 1 All E.R. 385 (C.A.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82c12128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>10</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>See <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00039" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2002513740" w-pub-number="0003986" ID="I60ea5e308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Netsmart Inc. v. Poelzer</ital>, [2003] 1 W.W.R. 698 (Alta. Q.B.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82c12138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>11</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00040" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I60ea85408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82c12148e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>12</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00041" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I60eaac508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47</cite.query>, at paras. 2–3.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82c12158e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>13</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00042" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I60ead3608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47</cite.query>, at paras. 4–8.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82c39208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>14</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00043" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I60eafa708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47, at para. 9</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82c39218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>15</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00044" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I60eb21808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47, at para. 10</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82c39228e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>16</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00045" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I60eb48908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47, at para. 11</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82c39238e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>17</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00046" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I60eb6fa08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47</cite.query>, at paras. 12–14.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82c39248e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>18</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00047" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I60ebbdc08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47</cite.query>, at paras. 16–18.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82c39258e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>19</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00048" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I60ebe4d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47</cite.query>, at paras. 19–20.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82c60308e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>20</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00049" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I60ec0be08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47</cite.query>, at paras. 21–22.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82c60318e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>21</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00050" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I60ec32f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47</cite.query>, at paras. 27–28.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82c60328e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>22</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00051" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I60ec81108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47</cite.query>, at paras. 33–35.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82c60338e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>23</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00052" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I60eca8208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47</cite.query>, at paras. 36–37.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82c60348e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>24</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00053" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I60eccf308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47, at para. 40</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82c60358e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>25</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00054" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I60ecf6408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47</cite.query>, at paras. 41–42.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82c87408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>26</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00055" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I60ed44608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47</cite.query>, at paras. 43–44, and 47–48.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82c87418e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>27</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00056" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I60ed6b708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47, at para. 56</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82c87428e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>28</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00057" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I60ed92808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47</cite.query>, at paras. 57–61.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82c87438e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>29</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00058" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I60edb9908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47, at para. 62</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82c87448e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>30</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00059" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I60ede0a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47, at para. 63</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82c87458e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>31</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00060" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I60ee07b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47, at para. 64</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82c87468e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>32</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00061" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I60ee2ec08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47, at para. 66</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82cae508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>33</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00062" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I60ee2ec38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47, at para. 67</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82cae518e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>34</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00063" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048642413" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I60ee55d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 1906, 2019 BCSC 1068</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82cae528e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>35</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00064" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048642413" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I60eea3f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 1906, 2019 BCSC 1068</cite.query>, at paras. 1–4.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82cae538e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>36</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00065" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048642413" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I60eecb008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 1906, 2019 BCSC 1068</cite.query>, at paras. 6–7.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82cae548e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>37</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00066" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048642413" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I60ef19208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 1906, 2019 BCSC 1068</cite.query>, at paras. 8–10.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82cae558e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>38</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00067" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048642413" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I60ef40308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 1906, 2019 BCSC 1068, at para. 21</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82cae568e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>39</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00068" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048642413" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I60ef67408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 1906, 2019 BCSC 1068, at para. 22</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82cd5608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>40</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00069" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048642413" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I60ef8e508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 1906, 2019 BCSC 1068</cite.query>, at paras. 23–24.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82cd5618e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>41</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00070" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048642413" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I60efb5608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 1906, 2019 BCSC 1068, at para. 25</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82cd5628e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>42</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00071" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048642413" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I60efdc708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 1906, 2019 BCSC 1068, at para. 26</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82cd5638e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>43</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00072" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048642413" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I60f003808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 1906, 2019 BCSC 1068, at para. 27</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82cd5648e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>44</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00073" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048642413" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I60f02a908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 1906, 2019 BCSC 1068</cite.query>, at paras. 38–43.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82cd5658e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>45</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00074" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048642413" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I60f051a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 1906, 2019 BCSC 1068, at para. 44</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82cd5668e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>46</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00075" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048642413" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I60f078b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 1906, 2019 BCSC 1068</cite.query>, at paras. 45–49, 52, and 54.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82cfc708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>47</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00076" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048208806" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60f09fc08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>ADT Security Services Canada, Inc. v. Fluent Home Ltd.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 6880, 2019 ONSC 2804</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82cfc718e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>48</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00077" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048208806" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60f0ede08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>ADT Security Services Canada, Inc. v. Fluent Home Ltd.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 6880, 2019 ONSC 2804</cite.query>, at paras. 1–3.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82cfc728e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>49</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00078" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048208806" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60f114f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>ADT Security Services Canada, Inc. v. Fluent Home Ltd.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 6880, 2019 ONSC 2804</cite.query>, at paras. 5–7.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82e5c008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>50</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00079" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048208806" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60f13c008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>ADT Security Services Canada, Inc. v. Fluent Home Ltd.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 6880, 2019 ONSC 2804, at para. 8</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82e5c018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>51</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00080" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048208806" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60f163108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>ADT Security Services Canada, Inc. v. Fluent Home Ltd.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 6880, 2019 ONSC 2804, at para. 9</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82e83108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>52</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00081" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048208806" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60f18a208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>ADT Security Services Canada, Inc. v. Fluent Home Ltd.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 6880, 2019 ONSC 2804, at para. 12</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82e83118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>53</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00082" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048208806" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60f1b1308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>ADT Security Services Canada, Inc. v. Fluent Home Ltd.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 6880, 2019 ONSC 2804, at para. 15</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82e83128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>54</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00083" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048208806" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60f1d8408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>ADT Security Services Canada, Inc. v. Fluent Home Ltd.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 6880, 2019 ONSC 2804</cite.query>, at paras. 16–17.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82e83138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>55</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00084" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048208806" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60f1ff508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>ADT Security Services Canada, Inc. v. Fluent Home Ltd.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 6880, 2019 ONSC 2804, at para. 18</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82e83148e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>56</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00085" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048208806" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60f226608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>ADT Security Services Canada, Inc. v. Fluent Home Ltd.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 6880, 2019 ONSC 2804</cite.query>, at paras. 19–21.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82e83158e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>57</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00086" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048208806" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60f274808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>ADT Security Services Canada, Inc. v. Fluent Home Ltd.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 6880, 2019 ONSC 2804</cite.query>, at paras. 22–26.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82eaa208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>58</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00087" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048208806" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60f29b908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>ADT Security Services Canada, Inc. v. Fluent Home Ltd.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 6880, 2019 ONSC 2804</cite.query>, at paras. 33–36.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82eaa218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>59</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00088" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048208806" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60f2c2a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>ADT Security Services Canada, Inc. v. Fluent Home Ltd.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 6880, 2019 ONSC 2804</cite.query>, at paras. 37–43.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82eaa228e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>60</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00089" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048208806" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60f2e9b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>ADT Security Services Canada, Inc. v. Fluent Home Ltd.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 6880, 2019 ONSC 2804, at para. 44</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82eaa238e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>61</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00090" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048208806" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60f310c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>ADT Security Services Canada, Inc. v. Fluent Home Ltd.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 6880, 2019 ONSC 2804, at para. 46</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82eaa248e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>62</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00091" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048208806" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60f337d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>ADT Security Services Canada, Inc. v. Fluent Home Ltd.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 6880, 2019 ONSC 2804, at para. 47</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82eaa258e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>63</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00092" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048208806" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60f385f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>ADT Security Services Canada, Inc. v. Fluent Home Ltd.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 6880, 2019 ONSC 2804, at para. 48</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82ed1308e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>64</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00093" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040845729" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60f3ad008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2158124 Ontario Inc. v. Pitton</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 1023, 2017 ONSC 411</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82ed1318e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>65</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00094" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040845729" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60f3d4108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2158124 Ontario Inc. v. Pitton</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 1023, 2017 ONSC 411</cite.query>, at paras. 2–8, and 13.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82ed1328e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>66</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00095" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040845729" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60f3fb208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2158124 Ontario Inc. v. Pitton</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 1023, 2017 ONSC 411, at para. 20</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82ed1338e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>67</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00096" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040845729" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60f422308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2158124 Ontario Inc. v. Pitton</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 1023, 2017 ONSC 411, at para. 24</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82ed1348e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>68</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00097" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040845729" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60f449408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2158124 Ontario Inc. v. Pitton</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 1023, 2017 ONSC 411</cite.query>, at paras. 26–28.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82ed1358e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>69</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00098" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040845729" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60f497608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2158124 Ontario Inc. v. Pitton</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 1023, 2017 ONSC 411</cite.query>, at paras. 31–33.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82ef8408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>70</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00099" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040845729" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60f4be708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2158124 Ontario Inc. v. Pitton</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 1023, 2017 ONSC 411</cite.query>, at paras. 34–35.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82ef8418e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>71</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00100" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040845729" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60f4e5808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2158124 Ontario Inc. v. Pitton</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 1023, 2017 ONSC 411, at para. 36</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82ef8428e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>72</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00101" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040845729" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60f50c908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2158124 Ontario Inc. v. Pitton</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 1023, 2017 ONSC 411</cite.query>, at paras. 38, 40, and 42.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82ef8438e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>73</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00102" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043398085" w-pub-number="0005475" ID="I60f533a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Clarke Road Transport Inc. v. O&apos;Toole</ital>, 2017 CarswellNS 911, 2017 NSSC 319 (N.S. S.C.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82ef8448e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>74</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00103" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043398085" w-pub-number="0005475" ID="I60f55ab08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Clarke Road Transport Inc. v. O&apos;Toole</ital>, 2017 CarswellNS 911, 2017 NSSC 319 (N.S. S.C.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 1 and 3.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82ef8458e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>75</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00104" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043398085" w-pub-number="0005475" ID="I60f5a8d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Clarke Road Transport Inc. v. O&apos;Toole</ital>, 2017 CarswellNS 911, 2017 NSSC 319 (N.S. S.C.)</cite.query>, at paragraph 19.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82f1f508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>76</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00105" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043398085" w-pub-number="0005475" ID="I60f5cfe08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Clarke Road Transport Inc. v. O&apos;Toole</ital>, 2017 CarswellNS 911, 2017 NSSC 319 (N.S. S.C.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 24 and 30.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82f1f518e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>77</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00106" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043398085" w-pub-number="0005475" ID="I60f61e008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Clarke Road Transport Inc. v. O&apos;Toole</ital>, 2017 CarswellNS 911, 2017 NSSC 319 (N.S. S.C.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 36–37, and 39.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82f1f528e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>78</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00107" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043398085" w-pub-number="0005475" ID="I60f645108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Clarke Road Transport Inc. v. O&apos;Toole</ital>, 2017 CarswellNS 911, 2017 NSSC 319 (N.S. S.C.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 40 and 43.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82f1f538e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>79</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00108" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043398085" w-pub-number="0005475" ID="I60f66c208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Clarke Road Transport Inc. v. O&apos;Toole</ital>, 2017 CarswellNS 911, 2017 NSSC 319 (N.S. S.C.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 51 and 55.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82f1f548e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>80</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00109" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043398085" w-pub-number="0005475" ID="I60f6ba408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Clarke Road Transport Inc. v. O&apos;Toole</ital>, 2017 CarswellNS 911, 2017 NSSC 319 (N.S. S.C.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 56–58, 61, and 96.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82f1f558e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>81</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00110" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043398085" w-pub-number="0005475" ID="I60f6e1508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Clarke Road Transport Inc. v. O&apos;Toole</ital>, 2017 CarswellNS 911, 2017 NSSC 319 (N.S. S.C.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 98 and 100.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82f1f568e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>82</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00111" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043398085" w-pub-number="0005475" ID="I60f708608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Clarke Road Transport Inc. v. O&apos;Toole</ital>, 2017 CarswellNS 911, 2017 NSSC 319 (N.S. S.C.)</cite.query>, at paragraph 101.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82f46608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>83</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00112" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043398085" w-pub-number="0005475" ID="I60f756808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Clarke Road Transport Inc. v. O&apos;Toole</ital>, 2017 CarswellNS 911, 2017 NSSC 319 (N.S. S.C.)</cite.query>, at paragraph 102.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82f46618e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>84</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00113" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043666780" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I60f77d908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Doors on Demand v. Wierenga</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 101, 2018 ABQB 60 (Alta. Q.B.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82f46628e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>85</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00114" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043666780" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I60f7a4a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Doors on Demand v. Wierenga</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 101, 2018 ABQB 60 (Alta. Q.B.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 1, and 3–4.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82f46638e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>86</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00115" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043666780" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I60f7cbb08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Doors on Demand v. Wierenga</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 101, 2018 ABQB 60 (Alta. Q.B.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 5–6.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82f46648e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>87</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00116" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043666780" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I60f819d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Doors on Demand v. Wierenga</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 101, 2018 ABQB 60 (Alta. Q.B.)</cite.query>, at paragraph 7.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82f46658e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>88</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00117" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043666780" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I60f840e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Doors on Demand v. Wierenga</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 101, 2018 ABQB 60 (Alta. Q.B.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 8–9.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82f46668e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>89</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00118" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043666780" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I60f867f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Doors on Demand v. Wierenga</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 101, 2018 ABQB 60 (Alta. Q.B.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 10–12.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82f6d708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>90</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00119" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035342984" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60f88f008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Canadian Hedge Watch Inc. v. Street</ital>, 2015 CarswellOnt 881, 2015 ONSC 454</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82f6d718e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>91</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00120" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035342984" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60f8dd208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Canadian Hedge Watch Inc. v. Street</ital>, 2015 CarswellOnt 881, 2015 ONSC 454</cite.query>, at paras. 1–2.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82f6d728e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>92</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00121" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035342984" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60f904308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Canadian Hedge Watch Inc. v. Street</ital>, 2015 CarswellOnt 881, 2015 ONSC 454</cite.query>, at paras. 8–9, and 29.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82f6d738e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>93</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00122" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035342984" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60f92b408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Canadian Hedge Watch Inc. v. Street</ital>, 2015 CarswellOnt 881, 2015 ONSC 454</cite.query>, at paras. 30–31.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82f6d748e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>94</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00123" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035342984" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60f952508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Canadian Hedge Watch Inc. v. Street</ital>, 2015 CarswellOnt 881, 2015 ONSC 454</cite.query>, at paras. 32–34.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82f6d758e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>95</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00124" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036173265" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I60f979608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Innersolutions Ltd. v. Hooper</ital>, 2015 CarswellAlta 722, 2015 ABQB 258</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82f6d768e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>96</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00125" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036173265" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I60f9a0708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Innersolutions Ltd. v. Hooper</ital>, 2015 CarswellAlta 722, 2015 ABQB 258, at para. 1</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82f94808e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>97</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00126" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036173265" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I60f9ee908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Innersolutions Ltd. v. Hooper</ital>, 2015 CarswellAlta 722, 2015 ABQB 258</cite.query>, at paras. 4–6, 10–13, and 16–18.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82f94818e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>98</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00127" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036173265" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I60f9ee938e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Innersolutions Ltd. v. Hooper</ital>, 2015 CarswellAlta 722, 2015 ABQB 258, at para. 68</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82f94828e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>99</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00128" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036173265" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I60fa15a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Innersolutions Ltd. v. Hooper</ital>, 2015 CarswellAlta 722, 2015 ABQB 258, at para. 63</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82f94838e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>100</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00129" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036173265" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I60fa3cb08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Innersolutions Ltd. v. Hooper</ital>, 2015 CarswellAlta 722, 2015 ABQB 258, at para. 64</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82f94848e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>101</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00130" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036173265" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I60fa63c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Innersolutions Ltd. v. Hooper</ital>, 2015 CarswellAlta 722, 2015 ABQB 258, at para. 66</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82f94858e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>102</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00131" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034610279" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60fa8ad08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Benayoune &amp; Associates FZE v. Kanata Chemical Technologies Inc.</ital>, 2014 CarswellOnt 14194, 2014 ONSC 5874 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00132" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034742157" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60fa8ad38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2014 CarswellOnt 15647, 2014 ONSC 6415 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82fbb908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>103</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00133" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034610279" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60fad8f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Benayoune &amp; Associates FZE v. Kanata Chemical Technologies Inc.</ital>, 2014 CarswellOnt 14194, 2014 ONSC 5874 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00134" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034742157" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60fad8f38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2014 CarswellOnt 15647, 2014 ONSC 6415 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>, at paras. 2, 6–11, and 55.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82fbb918e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>104</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00135" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034610279" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60fb27108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Benayoune &amp; Associates FZE v. Kanata Chemical Technologies Inc.</ital>, 2014 CarswellOnt 14194, 2014 ONSC 5874 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00136" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034742157" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60fb27138e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2014 CarswellOnt 15647, 2014 ONSC 6415 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>, at paras. 39–40.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82fbb928e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>105</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00137" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034610279" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60fb4e208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Benayoune &amp; Associates FZE v. Kanata Chemical Technologies Inc.</ital>, 2014 CarswellOnt 14194, 2014 ONSC 5874 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00138" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034742157" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60fb4e238e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2014 CarswellOnt 15647, 2014 ONSC 6415 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>, at para. 55.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82fbb938e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>106</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00139" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034610279" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60fb9c408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Benayoune &amp; Associates FZE v. Kanata Chemical Technologies Inc.</ital>, 2014 CarswellOnt 14194, 2014 ONSC 5874 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00140" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034742157" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60fb9c438e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2014 CarswellOnt 15647, 2014 ONSC 6415 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>, at para. 56.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82fbb948e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>107</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00141" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034610279" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60fbc3508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Benayoune &amp; Associates FZE v. Kanata Chemical Technologies Inc.</ital>, 2014 CarswellOnt 14194, 2014 ONSC 5874 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00142" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034742157" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60fbc3538e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2014 CarswellOnt 15647, 2014 ONSC 6415 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>, at para. 57.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82fbb958e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>108</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00143" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034610279" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60fc11708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Benayoune &amp; Associates FZE v. Kanata Chemical Technologies Inc.</ital>, 2014 CarswellOnt 14194, 2014 ONSC 5874 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00144" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034742157" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60fc11738e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2014 CarswellOnt 15647, 2014 ONSC 6415 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>, at para. 58.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82fbb968e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>109</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00145" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040515325" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60fc38808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgetch HVAC Services Ltd. v. Ubhi</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 19341, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 103, 2016 ONSC 7564 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00146" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040956173" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60fc38848e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellOnt 1753, 275 A.C.W.S. (3d) 706, 2017 ONSC 1004 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82fe2a08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>110</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00147" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040515325" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60fc86a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgetch HVAC Services Ltd. v. Ubhi</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 19341, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 103, 2016 ONSC 7564 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00148" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040956173" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60fc86a48e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellOnt 1753, 275 A.C.W.S. (3d) 706, 2017 ONSC 1004 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 1–6.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82fe2a18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>111</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00149" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040515325" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60fcd4c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgetch HVAC Services Ltd. v. Ubhi</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 19341, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 103, 2016 ONSC 7564 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00150" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040956173" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60fcd4c48e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellOnt 1753, 275 A.C.W.S. (3d) 706, 2017 ONSC 1004 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at para. 7.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82fe2a28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>112</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00151" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040515325" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60fcfbd08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgetch HVAC Services Ltd. v. Ubhi</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 19341, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 103, 2016 ONSC 7564 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00152" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040956173" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60fcfbd48e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellOnt 1753, 275 A.C.W.S. (3d) 706, 2017 ONSC 1004 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 9–10.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82fe2a38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>113</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00153" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040515325" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60fd49f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgetch HVAC Services Ltd. v. Ubhi</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 19341, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 103, 2016 ONSC 7564 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00154" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040956173" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60fd49f48e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellOnt 1753, 275 A.C.W.S. (3d) 706, 2017 ONSC 1004 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 14–16.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82fe2a48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>114</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00155" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040515325" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60fd98108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgetch HVAC Services Ltd. v. Ubhi</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 19341, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 103, 2016 ONSC 7564 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00156" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040956173" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60fd98148e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellOnt 1753, 275 A.C.W.S. (3d) 706, 2017 ONSC 1004 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at para. 28.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id82fe2a58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>115</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00157" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040515325" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60fde6308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgetch HVAC Services Ltd. v. Ubhi</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 19341, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 103, 2016 ONSC 7564 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00158" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040956173" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60fde6348e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellOnt 1753, 275 A.C.W.S. (3d) 706, 2017 ONSC 1004 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 30–31, and 33.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id83009b08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>116</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00159" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040515325" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60fe0d408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgetch HVAC Services Ltd. v. Ubhi</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 19341, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 103, 2016 ONSC 7564 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00160" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040956173" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60fe0d448e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellOnt 1753, 275 A.C.W.S. (3d) 706, 2017 ONSC 1004 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at para. 34.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id83009b18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>117</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00161" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040515325" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60fe5b608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgetch HVAC Services Ltd. v. Ubhi</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 19341, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 103, 2016 ONSC 7564 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00162" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040956173" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60fe5b648e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellOnt 1753, 275 A.C.W.S. (3d) 706, 2017 ONSC 1004 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at para. 35.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id83009b28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>118</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00163" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039182032" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60fe82708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>FLS Transportation Services Inc. v. Charger Logistics Inc.</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 9633, 2016 ONSC 3652</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id83009b38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>119</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00164" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039182032" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60fea9808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>FLS Transportation Services Inc. v. Charger Logistics Inc.</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 9633, 2016 ONSC 3652</cite.query>, at paras. 1–6, and 8.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id83009b48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>120</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00165" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039182032" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60fef7a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>FLS Transportation Services Inc. v. Charger Logistics Inc.</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 9633, 2016 ONSC 3652</cite.query>, at paras. 9–10.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id83009b58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>121</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00166" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039182032" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60ff1eb08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>FLS Transportation Services Inc. v. Charger Logistics Inc.</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 9633, 2016 ONSC 3652, at para. 18</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id83009b68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>122</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00167" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039182032" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60ff45c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>FLS Transportation Services Inc. v. Charger Logistics Inc.</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 9633, 2016 ONSC 3652</cite.query>, at paras. 19, 23–24, and 27.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id83030c08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>123</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00168" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039182032" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60ff6cd08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>FLS Transportation Services Inc. v. Charger Logistics Inc.</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 9633, 2016 ONSC 3652, at para. 49</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id83030c18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>124</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00169" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028290296" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60ff93e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Maudore Minerals Ltd. v. Harbour Foundation,</ital> 2012 CarswellOnt 9332, 2012 ONSC 4255</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id83030c28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>125</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00170" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028290296" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60ffbaf08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Maudore Minerals Ltd. v. Harbour Foundation,</ital> 2012 CarswellOnt 9332, 2012 ONSC 4255</cite.query>, at paras. 15–20.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id83030c38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>126</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00171" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028290296" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I60ffe2008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Maudore Minerals Ltd. v. Harbour Foundation,</ital> 2012 CarswellOnt 9332, 2012 ONSC 4255</cite.query>, at paras. 29–33.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id83030c48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>127</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00172" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028290296" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I610030208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Maudore Minerals Ltd. v. Harbour Foundation,</ital> 2012 CarswellOnt 9332, 2012 ONSC 4255</cite.query>, at paras. 38, 68 and 71.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id83030c58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>128</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00173" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028290296" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I610057308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Maudore Minerals Ltd. v. Harbour Foundation,</ital> 2012 CarswellOnt 9332, 2012 ONSC 4255</cite.query>, at paras. 85 and 88–89.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id83057d08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>129</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00174" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028290296" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6100a5508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Maudore Minerals Ltd. v. Harbour Foundation,</ital> 2012 CarswellOnt 9332, 2012 ONSC 4255</cite.query>, at paras. 90–91.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id83057d18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>130</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00175" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028290296" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6100cc608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Maudore Minerals Ltd. v. Harbour Foundation,</ital> 2012 CarswellOnt 9332, 2012 ONSC 4255, at para. 97</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id83057d28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>131</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00176" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028418359" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6100f3708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>GDI Solutions Inc. v. Walker</ital>, 2012 CarswellOnt 9889, 2012 ONSC 4378</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id83057d38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>132</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00177" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028418359" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I61011a808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>GDI Solutions Inc. v. Walker</ital>, 2012 CarswellOnt 9889, 2012 ONSC 4378</cite.query>, at paras. 1, 6 and 12–14.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id83057d48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>133</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00178" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028418359" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I610141908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>GDI Solutions Inc. v. Walker</ital>, 2012 CarswellOnt 9889, 2012 ONSC 4378</cite.query>, at paras. 81–82, 93 and 96.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id83057d58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>134</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00179" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2029280753" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I610168a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Polar Wireless Corp. v. Roberts</ital>, 2012 CarswellOnt 14742, 2012 ONSC 6482 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, leave to appeal refused <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00180" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2030096328" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I610168a38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2013 CarswellOnt 2513, 2013 ONSC 1155 (Ont. Div. Ct.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id83057d68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>135</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00181" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2029280753" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6101b6c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Polar Wireless Corp. v. Roberts</ital>, 2012 CarswellOnt 14742, 2012 ONSC 6482 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, leave to appeal refused <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00182" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2030096328" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6101b6c38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2013 CarswellOnt 2513, 2013 ONSC 1155 (Ont. Div. Ct.)</cite.query>, at paras. 2, 4 and 18.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id83057d78e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>136</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00183" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2014814397" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6101ddd08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Van Wagner Communications Co., Canada v. Penex Metropolis Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 218 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, leave to appeal refused <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00184" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2016464042" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6101ddd28e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2008 CarswellOnt 3899, [2008] O.J. No. 1707 (Ont. Div. Ct.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8307ee08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>137</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00185" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2014814397" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I61022bf08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Van Wagner Communications Co., Canada v. Penex Metropolis Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 218 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, leave to appeal refused <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00186" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2016464042" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I61022bf28e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2008 CarswellOnt 3899, [2008] O.J. No. 1707 (Ont. Div. Ct.)</cite.query>, at paras. 21–25.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8307ee18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>138</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00187" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2014814397" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I610253008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Van Wagner Communications Co., Canada v. Penex Metropolis Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 218 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, leave to appeal refused <cite.query w-src-number="0492175956" w-seq-number="00188" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2016464042" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I610253028e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2008 CarswellOnt 3899, [2008] O.J. No. 1707 (Ont. Div. Ct.)</cite.query>, at paras. 44–45 and 50.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 7:3<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
