<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 1:7<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I4d7849c0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>1.</label.designator><headtext>Confidential Business Information in Historical Context</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I4d790d10411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>I.</label.designator><headtext>Origins of Intellectual Property</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f59bef6ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>1:7.</label.designator><headtext>Summary</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The sources of wealth in a given society are central to the structure and organization of that society. <eos/><bos/>In Roman times, the central resource was labour; in feudal times, it was land; in the Commercial Age, it was commerce and trade; and during the Industrial Revolution, it was the development of machinery and the corresponding need for a vast labour force. <eos/><bos/>In the Information Age, the central resource is information.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The legal system is often used as a means to regulate entitlement to a central resource and to legitimize the right of those who have access to that resource. <eos/><bos/>Roman laws reinforced the right of masters to control the slave; feudal laws reflected the hierarchical system; the Commercial Age legitimized the rights of two parties to bargain in good faith; the Industrial Age created a more difficult situation. <eos/><bos/>Encouragement of the manufacturing sector favoured the enactment of laissez-faire individualist laws while workers fought to enact laws which would enable them to be seen as a group, thus strengthening their position.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Information Age creates an even more difficult situation for courts and legislators as there is an inherent conflict between society&apos;s desire for free access to information and its aim of encouraging the development of new business information by protecting private property rights to that information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Icde91e108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>] Furthermore, as socio-economic change has accelerated and communications have improved, the courts must provide a legal response which will reflect the increased pace of social change. <eos/><bos/>However, due to its precedential approach, the judiciary has often trailed the general public and the legislature in establishing a legal system that reflects the socio-economic values of the times. <eos/><bos/>There have as yet been no major legislative or doctrinal changes in the common law.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Icde91e108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>G. Klueck, <begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>“The Coming Jurisprudence of the Information Age: Examinations of the Three Past Socio-Economic Ages Suggest the Future”<end.quote refid="QT_0001"/> (1984), 21 San Diego L. Rev. 1077 at p. 1110.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 1:7<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
