<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 3:19<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I4ed25b80411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>3.</label.designator><headtext>Defining Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I4eeaec90411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>II.</label.designator><headtext>Information Capable of Protection</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I5044d740411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>B.</label.designator><headtext>The “Business” Nature of the Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f611116ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>3:19.</label.designator><headtext>Introduction</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The courts have considered a number of factors in evaluating whether information should be classed as “commercial”, <ital>i.e.</ital>, offering value or advantage to its “owner”.<eos/><bos/> Such value or advantage may exist due to the fact that the information is “secret” or because resources have been expended to bring the information into existence. <eos/><bos/>Here too, the courts have made use of a number of phrases in analyzing whether information can be classed as being of a business nature, including:</paratext><list><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(a)</label.designator></head><paratext>economic value (whether actual or potential);</paratext></para></list.item><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(b)</label.designator></head><paratext>value to the business;</paratext></para></list.item><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(c)</label.designator></head><paratext>value to competitors;</paratext></para></list.item><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(d)</label.designator></head><paratext>use in a trade or business;</paratext></para></list.item><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(e)</label.designator></head><paratext>providing an advantage over competitors; and</paratext></para></list.item><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(f)</label.designator></head><paratext>expenditure of independent effort and resources, including work, money, time, or brain-power, to protect the information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id33e79508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></list.item></list><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175850" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2038152801" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2143cff18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Jane Doe 464533 v. D.</cite.query> (N.)</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id33ea0608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>] the plaintiff&apos;s ex-boyfriend posted an intimate video of her on a pornography website without her knowledge or consent. <eos/><bos/>In early December 2011, the plaintiff learned that the defendant had posted the video she sent him on an Internet pornography website under the “user submissions” section of the website. <eos/><bos/>As posted by the defendant, the video was titled <begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>“college girl pleasures herself for ex boyfriends (<ital>sic</ital>) delight.”<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0002"/> She further learned that the defendant had been showing it to some of the young men with whom they had attended high school. <eos/><bos/>She later learned that the video had been posted online on the same day she had sent it to him, and that its existence had become known among some of her friends. <eos/><bos/>The video was available online for approximately three weeks, before it was “removed”.<eos/><bos/> There was no way to know how many times it was viewed or downloaded or if and how many times it may have been copied onto other media storage devices or recirculated. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff&apos;s lawyer sent a demand letter to the defendant in February 2012. <eos/><bos/>The defendant admitted having posted the video, but advised that it had been removed and that he did not consider that the plaintiff&apos;s claims for compensation had any merit. <eos/><bos/>The defendant failed to serve a statement of defence and had been noted in default.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id33ea0618e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">3</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The consequences for the plaintiff arising from the defendant&apos;s conduct had been significant and long-lasting. <eos/><bos/>She saw a counsellor at her school for over a year and a half to deal with the emotional fallout from the posting of the video. <eos/><bos/>She experienced serious depression and emotional upset. <eos/><bos/>On the occasions since the incident when she has encountered the defendant she has become emotionally distraught and unable to cope, sometimes collapsing. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff remains conscious of the fact that the video was viewed by acquaintances of the defendant, that its existence is known to other members of her former social circle and has caused harm to her reputation. <eos/><bos/>Even today, more than four years after the incident, she is emotionally fragile and worried about the possibility that the video may someday resurface and have an adverse impact on her employment, her career, or her future relationships. <eos/><bos/>She continues to be distraught about the incident and afraid that these feelings will haunt her for a long time to come. <eos/><bos/>Despite these challenges, she finished her undergraduate studies and was attending a graduate program that would enable her to become a health care professional when she graduated. <eos/><bos/>She remained worried, however, that the defendant&apos;s actions had put her future career in jeopardy should news of these events surface again.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id33ea0628e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">4</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The judge concluded that there are both established and developing legal grounds that support the proposition that the courts can and should provide civil recourse for individuals who suffer harm arising from this misconduct and should intervene to prevent its repetition. <eos/><bos/>There can be little doubt that the decision by the plaintiff to provide the defendant with an intimate video of herself engages issues of confidentiality and privacy. <eos/><bos/>They had a close personal and romantic relationship of some duration. <eos/><bos/>It was on the basis of that relationship that she agreed to provide him with private images of her. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff&apos;s decision to send the video was premised upon the defendant&apos;s assurance that he alone would view it. <eos/><bos/>His decision to share it publicly was a clear breach of the terms upon which it was communicated to him.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id33ea0638e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">5</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff has made out a cause of action for breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>The elements required to make out the tort of breach of confidence are: a) that the information must have the necessary quality of confidence about it; b) that the information must have been imparted in circumstances importing an obligation of confidence; and c) that there must be unauthorized use of that information to the detriment of the party communicating it. <eos/><bos/>The video created by the plaintiff met the first test, being confidential information. <eos/><bos/>It had <begin.quote ID="QT_0003"/>“the necessary quality of confidence about it”<end.quote refid="QT_0003"/>. <eos/><bos/>It was private and personal to the plaintiff and was not (until it was shared on the Internet and otherwise by the defendant) publicly available. <eos/><bos/>The circumstances that led to the creation and communication of the video clearly demonstrated that it was communicated to the defendant on the express basis that he would treat it as confidential. <eos/><bos/>Thus the second element was met. <eos/><bos/>The third element of the tort, use of the information to the detriment of the party communicating it, is ordinarily considered in commercial circumstances, where the recipient has misused the confidential information for commercial advantage, at the expense or to the detriment of the other party. <eos/><bos/>An essential element in any tort is harm to the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>There is no rational basis to distinguish between economic harm and psychological, emotional and physical harm, such as was experienced by the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>In any event, the possible future adverse impact on the plaintiff&apos;s career and employment prospects arising from the possibility that the video may someday resurface, also demonstrated actionable harm.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id33ec7708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">6</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Id33e79508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>For the American position, see <cite.query w-src-number="0492175850" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="ER" w-normalized-cite="199FS202" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="205" ID="I2144e1608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Forest Laboratories Inc. v. Formulations Inc.,</ital> 199 F. Supp. 202, 205 (E.D. Wisc. 1967)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175850" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="RP" w-serial-number="1908019507" w-pub-number="0000550" ID="I2144e1628e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Witkop &amp; Holmes Co. v. Boyce</ital>, 61 Misc. 126</cite.query>. 131, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175850" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="RP" w-serial-number="1908019507" w-pub-number="0000601" ID="I2144e1648e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">112 N.Y.S. 874 (1908)</cite.query>, <case.history>affd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175850" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="RP" w-serial-number="1909024171" w-pub-number="0000601" ID="I2144e1678e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">131 A.D. 922, 115 N.Y.S. 1150 (1909)</cite.query>, which held, in the context of information relating to customer names, that information which has <begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>“been secured by years of business effort and advertising, and the expenditure of time and money, constituting a part of the good will of a business which enterprise and foresight have built up, should be deemed just as sacred and entitled to the same protection as a secret of compounding some article of manufacture and commerce”<end.quote refid="QT_0001"/>. <eos/><bos/>Of course, the corollary to this concept is the general refusal to prevent a party from making use of information gained through independent invention, accidental disclosure or reverse engineering: see the United States Supreme Court&apos;s leading decision of <cite.query w-src-number="0492175850" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="RP" w-serial-number="1974127179" w-pub-number="0000780" w-pinpoint-page="476" ID="I2144e1698e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Kewanee Oil co. v. Bicron Corp.</ital>, 416 U.S. 470, 476 (1974)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id33ea0608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175850" w-seq-number="00007" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038152801" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I21452f808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jane Doe 464533 v. D. (N.)</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 911, 2016 ONSC 541</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id33ea0618e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175850" w-seq-number="00008" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038152801" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I21457da08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jane Doe 464533 v. D. (N.)</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 911, 2016 ONSC 541</cite.query>, at paras. 1-2, 8, and 10.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id33ea0628e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>4</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175850" w-seq-number="00009" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038152801" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2145a4b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jane Doe 464533 v. D. (N.)</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 911, 2016 ONSC 541</cite.query>, at paras. 11-14.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id33ea0638e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>5</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175850" w-seq-number="00010" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038152801" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2145cbc08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jane Doe 464533 v. D. (N.)</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 911, 2016 ONSC 541</cite.query>, at paras. 19-20.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id33ec7708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>6</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175850" w-seq-number="00011" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038152801" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I214619e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jane Doe 464533 v. D. (N.)</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 911, 2016 ONSC 541</cite.query>, at paras. 21-25.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 3:19<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
