<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 7:4<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I56d26460411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>7.</label.designator><headtext>Remedies for Breach of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I56dbb330411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>II.</label.designator><headtext>Equitable Relief</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I56dc0150411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>A.</label.designator><headtext>Interim and Interlocutory Injunctions</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f6fb926ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>7:4.</label.designator><headtext>Serious Issue to Be Tried Test</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Where affidavits and other evidence before the court contain conflicting evidence, the courts have often accepted the less onerous test of establishing that there is a serious issue to be tried.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84566708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>] The courts have also adopted the serious question threshold where there is no clear public interest at stake; see <ital>4064143 Manitoba Ltd. v. Wawryk</ital>.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84566718e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>] In such cases, the moving party must demonstrate that the claim is neither frivolous nor vexatious.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84566728e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">3</footnote.reference>] Then, unless the court finds that the moving party has no real prospect of succeeding at trial in a claim for a permanent injunction, the court should go on to consider whether the balance of convenience lies in favour of granting or refusing the interim injunction.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84566738e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">4</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>2298679 <cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I633fbfe18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc.</cite.query> et al</ital>.,[<footnote.reference refid="Id8458d808e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">5</footnote.reference>] the Plaintiff 229 moved, without notice, for an <ital>Anton Piller</ital> Order to search and seize electronic devices from the headquarters of the Defendant Northern Homecare and from the residence of the Defendant Goldkind, who was one of the principals of Northern Homecare. <eos/><bos/>Aurum Property also requested an injunction restraining Northern Homecare, Goldkind and the other Defendants, prohibiting them from possessing or transmitting Aurum&apos;s confidential customer information in any form or through any medium whatsoever. <eos/><bos/>Justice Perell dismissed the motion for an <ital>Anton Piller</ital> Order, and granted an interim injunction and mandatory order that was to terminate ten days after the release of the Reasons for Decision.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8458d818e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">6</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Aurum was an industry leader in commercial window cleaning and property maintenance servicing government buildings, commercial high-rise buildings, condominium towers, hotels and hospitals across North America. <eos/><bos/>It also serviced residences and had a customer list of residential customers and leads numbering 35,000 contacts. <eos/><bos/>Aurum maintains a customer list that included: customer names, customer addresses, customer email addresses and details of past services including dates and prices.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8458d828e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">7</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Northern Homecare&apos;s executive included Goldkind and Goldman. <eos/><bos/>Goldkind was the CEO and Goldman was the COO. <eos/><bos/>Northern Homecare carried on a residential window cleaning and property maintenance business.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8458d838e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">8</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Arous, Edward, and Hyde were former employees of Aurum. <eos/><bos/>Arous was employed as field business development representative from April 1, 2018 to July 6, 2018, when his employment was terminated. <eos/><bos/>Edwards was first employed as a field business development representative and was promoted to outbound business development representative. <eos/><bos/>He was employed from April 1, 2018 to August 2, 2018, when his employment was terminated. <eos/><bos/>Hyde was employed as a field business manager from May 1, 2017 to August 25, 2018 when he was terminated. <eos/><bos/>Arous, Edward, and Hyde signed employment agreements. <eos/><bos/>The agreements contained the confidentiality and non-disclosure provisions. <eos/><bos/>During their employment, Arous, Edward, and Hyde had access to Aurum&apos;s residential customer lists.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8458d848e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">9</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Although Aurum was not aware of it at the time: (a) after Arous was terminated, he logged into Aurum&apos;s management software, which contains Aurum&apos;s customer list, on six occasions; (b) after Edwards was terminated, he logged into Aurum&apos;s management software twice on two occasions; and (c) after Hyde was terminated he logged into Aurum&apos;s management software on at least thirty occasions. <eos/><bos/>Aurum did not know: (a) the extent of information that was obtained by Arous, Edward, and Hyde; (b) how the information was used; and (c) with whom the information was shared. <eos/><bos/>Aurum conceded that the extent of the confidential information allegedly misappropriated by the Defendants would be an important facet of Aurum&apos;s damages claim.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8458d858e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">10</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Up until eight months after it had terminated the employment of Arous, Edward, and Hyde, Aurum had no knowledge of these intrusions on its computer system. <eos/><bos/>In March and April 2019, however, there were a series of events that prompted Aurum to investigate: a. Customers DD, OA, ED, and AS cancelled appointments because they had already been contacted by persons presenting themselves as being Aurum. <eos/><bos/>Based on the information provided by these customers; b. Customer ND advised Arum that she had been contacted by persons presenting themselves as being Aurum. <eos/><bos/>She did not cancel her contract with Aurum. <eos/><bos/>Aurum inferred that Northern Homecare was using information provided by Arous, Edward, and Hyde to contact ND. c. Customer DS advised Aurum that he had been contacted by Goldkind who misrepresented himself as representing a reorganized Aurum. <eos/><bos/>Goldkind disparaged Arum as it had formerly existed. <eos/><bos/>DS advised Aurum of the contact. <eos/><bos/>Goldkind was lying and Aurum inferred that the wrongdoing of Goldkind was a spinoff of Arous, Edward, and Hydes&apos; disclosing confidential information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8458d868e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">11</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Aurum suspected but did not actually know that Arous, Edward, and Hyde provided confidential information to Northern Homecare because Aurum customers reported that when solicited by Northern Homecare, the Northern Homecare representative had knowledge of past services provided to the customer.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id845b4908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">12</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>It was not clear, however, what the precise relationship or connection was between Northern Homecare and the three former employees, who might have a connection as employees, independent contractors, dependent contractors, sales agents, or intermediators.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id845b4918e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">13</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Perell concluded that while there appeared to have been wrongdoing, most likely by Goldkind and Goldman, it was not clear whether the harm they caused was trivial or substantial. <eos/><bos/>It appeared that it was only an inference that the three former employees stole the whole data base of customer information. <eos/><bos/>However, it was not clear whether the three former employees did anything more than inform Northern Homecare of a few contacts and that Northern Homecare used those few contacts to compete for business in a wrongful way when they should and could have competed for the customers in a lawful way. <eos/><bos/>On the other hand, it was not known whether more than a few of Aurum&apos;s customers were contacted and whether Northern Homecare was more than a minor nuisance and a major threat to Aurum&apos;s residential business. <eos/><bos/>In any event, at this juncture, there was no evidence to suggest that Northern Homecare or Goldkind had Aurum&apos;s customer list on its computers or that there was reason to believe that they would destroy that evidence.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id845b4928e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">14</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Perell noted that under their employment contracts, Arous, Edward, and Hydes&apos; obligations with respect to Confidential Information did not apply to information that they could demonstrate was generally available to or known by the public other than as a result of improper disclosure to them. <eos/><bos/>At this juncture, it was impossible to say that they had no defence to a breach of contract claim for the conduct of passing on information to Northern Homecare if that was what they did.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id845b4938e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">15</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Perell was satisfied that Aurum had presented a serious issue to be tried about whether the Arous, Edward, and Hyde and whether the Defendants committed the tort of breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>Although Aurum established a <ital>prima facie</ital> case for breach of confidence with an associated claim of breach of contract, it remained to be seen whether this was a case of former employees attempting to use the knowledge and experience they gained in their former employment for the purpose of earning a living with a new employer. <eos/><bos/>There was, in any event, a serious issue to be tried.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id845b4948e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">16</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>An application for an interlocutory injunction preventing the Defendants from holding bull riding events in July 2019 and 2020 was dismissed in <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I634983e18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos;</cite.query> Inc</ital>.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id845b4958e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">17</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Plaintiffs owned and operated the Ranchman&apos;s, a restaurant, bar, cookhouse and dancehall. <eos/><bos/>Each year in early July the Plaintiffs host, at the Ranchman&apos;s, a successful event known as the Ranchman&apos;s Rodeo. <eos/><bos/>The Ranchman&apos;s Rodeo was a festival event which included high-quality professional bull riding taking place in a temporary arena adjacent to the Ranchman&apos;s building. <eos/><bos/>The Defendant BBI began producing the bull riding event for Ranchman&apos;s in 2000, and did so annually through July 2018. <eos/><bos/>Although the Snyders produced a bullbustin&apos; event for Ranchman&apos;s for many years, they were not contractually committed to produce them in future. <eos/><bos/>BBI and Ranchman&apos;s did not reach contractual terms for the 2019 Stampede season and the Snyder Defendants decided to produce a bull riding event elsewhere.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id845b4968e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">18</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Plaintiffs advanced numerous claims in support of the injunctions including breach of duty of confidence relating to Ranchman&apos;s information and know-how, and breach of fiduciary duty by Cody Snyder and Rhonda Snyder.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id845b4978e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">19</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Eamon concluded that the serious issue standard should apply to most of the relief claimed on the application. <eos/><bos/>The assertion of delay was somewhat conclusory. <eos/><bos/>The parties had not addressed a litigation plan nor the possibility of seeing the Associate Chief Justice for an expedited trial. <eos/><bos/>Therefore, Justice Eamon was not prepared to find that the application would effectively determine the entire action. <eos/><bos/>Justice Eamon concluded that the serious issue standard should apply to most of the relief claimed on the application. <eos/><bos/>The assertion of delay was somewhat conclusory. <eos/><bos/>The parties had not addressed a litigation plan nor the possibility of seeing the Associate Chief Justice for an expedited trial. <eos/><bos/>Therefore, Justice Eamon was not prepared to find that the application would effectively determine the entire action. <eos/><bos/>However, Justice Eamon would apply the higher standard (<ital>prima facie</ital> case) to the request for an order that the Snyder Defendants destroy information in their possession. <eos/><bos/>It is well established that such a mandatory injunction attracts the higher standard.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id845dba08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">20</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Plaintiffs&apos; claims on the application included a request for an order prohibiting the Defendants from using their trademarks, intellectual property and key information. <eos/><bos/>The Ranchman&apos;s intellectual property was claimed to consist of intellectual property and trade secrets including but not limited to “key information”, marketing strategies, copyrights, the Ranchman&apos;s trademarks, know-how, confidential information and instructions regarding the operation of the Ranchman&apos;s Rodeo. <eos/><bos/>There was almost no detail in Ranchman&apos;s affidavit evidence of what was contained in this generic description. <eos/><bos/>Know-how was described as Ranchman&apos;s secrets on how they successfully run their business. <eos/><bos/>The Ranchman&apos;s key information was claimed to be all data, and records relating to the customers of Ranchman&apos;s including customer lists and email lists for customers, supplier lists and other data with respect to third parties. <eos/><bos/>There was almost no detail of what was contained in this description apart from a list of past ticket buyers and sponsors including their name, contact particulars, and past bleacher assignment.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id845dba18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">21</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Under the new 2018 agreement, the parties agreed to a revised fee structure. <eos/><bos/>BBI was to receive a fixed fee and a fee based on a fixed percentage of net profit. <eos/><bos/>This revenue flow through was accomplished by creating and inserting a numbered Alberta company 207, equally owned by the Snyders through Snyco (as to 50%) and by business associates of Raspberry, the Plaintiff&apos;s witness, through the Plaintiff CUBI (as to 50%).<eos/><bos/> The objective, rationale, and reason for being of 207 was to provide a corporate vehicle under which costs and revenues could be calculated with respect to Ranchman&apos;s Rodeo. <eos/><bos/>On paper, 207 was to produce an entertainment function including three days of bull riding and a Dallas Smith concert, 207 was to handle ticket sales, and Ranchmans 2017 Ltd. was to handle alcohol sales and secure the parking lot on which to host the event.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id845dba28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">22</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Plaintiffs learned that the Snyders had sent an email to all the bulk bleacher purchasers. <eos/><bos/>Ranchman&apos;s maintained a database containing its customer email names, contact particulars and ticket purchase information for the bull riding event. <eos/><bos/>There was no dispute that the Snyder Defendants accessed this information and used it to email the customers. <eos/><bos/>The Snyder Defendants created the website codysnyderbullbustin.com, describing their 2019 event. <eos/><bos/>This site included the statement that <begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>“Cody Snyder has decided to move the event”<end.quote refid="QT_0001"/> and contains pictures from the 2018 event. <eos/><bos/>These pictures were focused on the action in the arena, though one was an overhead photo of the Ranchman&apos;s cookhouse and arena set up.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id845dba38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">23</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>On November 21, 2018 the Snyder Defendants again emailed the customers on the list. <eos/><bos/>They stated the Snyders were not producing a 2019 bull riding event at Ranchman&apos;s, and the event Ranchman&apos;s were producing was not the same event as the Snyders had produced for the last 19 years. <eos/><bos/>Further, the Snyders had decided to move their charity bullbustin&apos; to a new location and would continue to deliver to fans, sponsors and charity partners the same amazing event they were accustomed to.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id845dba48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">24</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Plaintiffs&apos; claimed that the event database containing particulars of ticket purchasers and sponsors was confidential. <eos/><bos/>Ranchman&apos;s compiled the list and kept it private on a password secured database. <eos/><bos/>The evidence was somewhat conflicting but there was enough evidence to suggest a serious issue that the Snyders were only given access to the database to discharge their functions in connection with the arrangements created under the February 2018 memorandum of agreement. <eos/><bos/>That was arguably sufficient to satisfy the requirement of circumstances importing an obligation of confidentiality.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id845dba58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">25</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>However, Justice Eamon observed that the fact the list was confidential did not mean that all of the information in it was confidential. <eos/><bos/>Substantial parts were publicly disseminated by Ranchman&apos;s in or around the arena during the event, and some was already known to the Snyders from other sources. <eos/><bos/>There was no serious issue that the identity of the corporate purchasers or their locations in the bleachers was confidential information. <eos/><bos/>Each year, Ranchman&apos;s compiled “day sheets” for each day of the event, listing the names of the corporate bleacher purchasers, sponsors and key event suppliers. <eos/><bos/>These were handed out or made available to the 2950 individuals who would attend the bull riding event each day. <eos/><bos/>Also, each corporate bleacher purchaser and sponsor was recognized during the event by the live announcers. <eos/><bos/>Maps showing the location of the corporate bleacher purchasers were posted in the facility at places accessible to members of the public attending the bull riding event. <eos/><bos/>Event scripts, provided to announcers, the Snyders, and others, also included the bleacher assignments—a list of the 59 bleachers and the name of each corporate purchaser for each bleacher for each day, reflecting the publicly accessible bleacher maps. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence that Ranchman&apos;s secured these sources of information when the event was completed; for example by taking copies of day sheets back from members of the public or others for destruction. <eos/><bos/>To the extent the Snyders knew or had records of that information, they could use it. <eos/><bos/>The Snyders had the day sheets and bleacher assignments for 2018 in their possession. <eos/><bos/>Further, the Snyders said they personally knew many of the corporate bleacher purchasers, sponsors and suppliers from their involvement in bull riding events since 1993, and had sourced them as potential purchasers of the bull riding events at Ranchman&apos;s. <eos/><bos/>In such cases, it was likely the Snyders also had contact information for these customers. <eos/><bos/>There were even cases where the Snyders acted as the interface between Ranchman&apos;s and the customer, and declined to provide Ranchman&apos;s with direct contact information. <eos/><bos/>To the extent the Snyders knew or had records of that information, they could use it.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id845dba68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">26</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>There was no evidence that any of the supplies necessary to stage the show, including to build the arena or provide seating for the show, were so specialized as to be unknown to the event producers. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence that suppliers kept their identities, wares or services confidential, or that it was not generally known in the community where one might source bleachers or other supplies. <eos/><bos/>The day sheets also named key event suppliers.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84602b08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">27</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Accordingly, there was a serious issue to be tried that the spreadsheet compilation itself was confidential and that the Snyders used some confidential information of the Plaintiffs which was not otherwise available to or known by them. <eos/><bos/>That information would mainly be: (a) Contact information of specific customers which may not have been known to the Snyders through their networking efforts or was lost from their memories. (b) The identity of customers or sponsors and bleacher assignments, for those who did not attend in 2018 and therefore would not be disclosed on the 2018 records, to the extent that information was not otherwise available to or known by the Snyders.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84602b18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">28</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Plaintiffs further suggested that various aspects of “know-how” was confidential. <eos/><bos/>This included key information, marketing strategies, know-how and instructions regarding the operation of the rodeo. <eos/><bos/>Justice Eamon was not provided many particulars of this claimed confidential information, which would allow the Court to meaningfully assess what was confidential, how or why it was confidential, or how it was imparted in a way that maintained confidentiality.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84602b28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">29</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Snyders were present in meetings where they would have learned of Ranchman&apos;s marketing strategies. <eos/><bos/>These strategies were reflected in public marketing activities, and the ones described (e.g., emailing customers and sending them brochures, making radio commercials or handing out flyers) were generic.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84602b38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">30</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>There was no evidence to suggest, or plausibility in the suggestion that, experienced professional rodeo event organizers like the Defendants were not aware of how to organize a Stampede event or of the identity of suppliers of goods or services for such events.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84602b48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">31</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Generally, Justice Eamon observed that it was counter-intuitive to think that the Snyders, given their experience, would be using secret information developed by Ranchman&apos;s. <eos/><bos/>If anything, it would be the other way round with Ranchman&apos;s benefitting from the Snyder&apos;s knowledge, expertise, contacts and network in this area. <eos/><bos/>Justice Eamon was not satisfied that there is a serious issue in relation to claims concerning “know-how”.<eos/><bos/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id84602b58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">32</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Eamon observed that the law of fiduciary relations does not ordinarily apply to parties dealing at arm&apos;s length in commercial transactions. <eos/><bos/>The mere receipt of confidential business information does not necessarily give rise to a fiduciary obligation.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84602b68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">33</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Snyder Defendants were providing a commercial production service to an experienced entertainment operator. <eos/><bos/>That did not give rise to a fiduciary relationship. <eos/><bos/>The fact they may have received confidential information did not of itself impress Snyder with a fiduciary obligation. <eos/><bos/>The 2018 memorandum of agreement removed all previous limitations on hosting other events. <eos/><bos/>There was no serious issue that Snyder was in a fiduciary relationship with the Plaintiffs or owed them a fiduciary duty.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84602b78e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">34</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Plaintiffs argued in the alternative that the Snyder Defendants owed fiduciary duties to 207 as directors thereof. <eos/><bos/>They submitted that the initiation and production of an annual bull riding event shortly before the Calgary Stampede was a corporate opportunity belonging to 207 which the Snyders could not usurp for themselves. <eos/><bos/>Justice Eamon agreed with the Plaintiffs that a corporate director is not permitted to appropriate for themselves a maturing business opportunity of the company. <eos/><bos/>However, there was no merit to the application of this principle in this case. <eos/><bos/>First, 207 was not a Plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiffs should not be permitted to bolster their position by relying on 207&apos;s rights, if any. <eos/><bos/>Moreover, if the Plaintiffs really had ceded their Ranchman&apos;s Rodeo opportunity or future bull riding opportunities to 207, one would wonder why they were plaintiffs in the action at all. <eos/><bos/>Yet, as Plaintiffs they claimed the opportunities belonged to them. <eos/><bos/>The name of 207 appeared nowhere in their original or amended statement of claim. <eos/><bos/>No one pleaded the Snyders owed fiduciary duties to 207 or were directors of 207. <eos/><bos/>No one asked to further amend the pleadings.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84629c08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">35</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Each production contract was a separate deal and limited to providing specific services—producing a bull riding event. <eos/><bos/>The parties&apos; historical practice was to periodically negotiate for the production of a bull riding event resulting in limited term contracts. <eos/><bos/>The memorandum of agreement for 2018, which was the first to mention 207, was made among BBI, 207, CUBI and Ranchmans 2017 Ltd. There was nothing in the memorandum or elsewhere to suggest as a triable issue that the Plaintiffs ceded any entertainment opportunities associated with their businesses to 207 in future. <eos/><bos/>There was no serious issue to be tried that the Snyders owed or breached fiduciary obligations in relation to 207 or anyone else in respect of the 2019 Stampede season or thereafter.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84629c18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">36</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>SkyCope Technologies Inc. v. Jia</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id84629c28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">37</footnote.reference>] the Plaintiff sought an interlocutory injunction to restrain the Defendants from various forms of activity and, in particular, from making use of its confidential information. <eos/><bos/>Specifically, the Plaintiff sought to enjoin the Defendants from making use of the source codes it had developed in the area of anti-drone technology. <eos/><bos/>The individual Defendants were all persons who formally worked for the Plaintiff in various capacities and now worked for the corporate defendant.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84629c38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">38</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The founder and Chief Executive Officer of the Plaintiff was Liu. <eos/><bos/>Liu was also the sole director and shareholder of the company. <eos/><bos/>The corporate defendant was incorporated in March 2018 by the Defendant Jia. <eos/><bos/>The corporate defendant also developed and marketed anti-drone technology. <eos/><bos/>Liu and Jia had known each other for more than a decade and had worked together at different companies. <eos/><bos/>In the first six months of 2016, Liu wanted to assemble a team of engineers and researchers to help develop a prototype for an anti-drone defence system. <eos/><bos/>One of the individuals that Liu reached out to was Jia who, in September 2016, joined the Plaintiff and became its Chief Technology Officer. <eos/><bos/>In the time period that followed, each of the other individual Defendants joined the Plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>Each of the individual Defendants signed identical employment contracts. <eos/><bos/>Each of these employment contracts had various confidentiality, non-solicitation, and non-competition clauses.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84629c48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">39</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In December 2017, Liu and Jia had a falling out and Jia left the Plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>In early January 2018, the Defendant Pan announced that he was leaving the company. <eos/><bos/>In February 2018, both the Defendants Zhang and Zhuang left the Plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>Zhang left because the company had closed down the hardware development branch of its business in which he had been engaged.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84629c58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">40</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In June 2018, Liu travelled to China and learned that what appeared to be the Plaintiff&apos;s technology was being marketed to consumers. <eos/><bos/>He learned that Jia was the vice president of a Chinese company that had been formed on March 9, 2018 and that was marketing anti-drone technology. <eos/><bos/>He subsequently learned that Jia had formed the corporate defendant. <eos/><bos/>Liu learned through one of the Plaintiff&apos;s software engineers that Jia had reached out to another software engineer, Zarei, to gauge his potential interest in a new job. <eos/><bos/>Zarei has filed an affidavit in the proceedings on behalf of the Plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>He has deposed that, on June 10, 2018, he met briefly with. <eos/><bos/>Jia and, for a more extended period of time, with Pan to discuss his joining their new company, the corporate defendant. <eos/><bos/>That company, he was told, was developing anti-drone technology. <eos/><bos/>Zarei was also told that the corporate defendant had shipped its first product to a customer in April 2018. <eos/><bos/>The Defendants, in their response materials, asserted that that statement was not true, but was simply puffery. <eos/><bos/>This information caused Liu, in late July 2018, to hire a private investigation firm. <eos/><bos/>The investigators were advised that the corporate defendant would be in a position to deliver an anti-drone system to them by mid-October 2018. <eos/><bos/>They thereafter exchanged several emails and, on August 30, 2018, they arranged for a demonstration of the corporate defendant&apos;s anti-drone technology. <eos/><bos/>That demonstration occurred with Pan and two other individuals who the investigators had seen at the corporate defendant&apos;s offices. <eos/><bos/>The investigators openly photographed and video-recorded aspects of the presentation and of the equipment that was being used.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84629c68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">41</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A witness for the Plaintiff explained that he took a screenshot from the video that the investigators took during the demonstration. <eos/><bos/>That screenshot revealed a portion of the source code that the corporate defendant relied on for its technology. <eos/><bos/>The witness deposed that there was virtually no possibility that two people, or groups of people, working separately, would code their entries in an identical fashion, with the same capitalization and order of letters and numerical figures.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84650d08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">42</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Plaintiff&apos;s Notice of Civil Claim alleged that each of the individual Defendants breached their respective employment contracts, that each of them was liable for a breach of confidence, and that Jia, by virtue of his senior position in the Plaintiff company, breached the fiduciary obligations that he owed to the Plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiff also alleged that the corporate defendant was liable for knowing receipt of confidential information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84650d18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">43</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Chambers judge observed that the threshold for whether there is a serious question to be tried is a low one. <eos/><bos/>The Court must only undertake a preliminary assessment of the merits of the case and be satisfied that the application is neither vexatious nor frivolous. <eos/><bos/>The Chambers judge was satisfied that the Plaintiff had established a serious question in relation to each of the elements of the cause of action for breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>Liu had deposed that the Plaintiff spent in excess of $1.5 million in developing its technology. <eos/><bos/>Furthermore, the employment contracts signed by each of the individual Defendants contained an acknowledgment that the work product they were generating for the Plaintiff was confidential. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiff&apos;s technology, or aspects of it, was confidential. <eos/><bos/>The evidence further indicated that aspects of the Plaintiff&apos;s promotional materials, its hardware and, in particular, its source code had been used without the Plaintiff&apos;s authority. <eos/><bos/>This arose directly from the evidence filed by the Plaintiff and also inferentially from the fact that the corporate defendant appeared to have somehow been able to develop, and to have, products available for delivery to market in about six months.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84650d28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">44</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Chambers judge recognized that the Defendants denied that the Plaintiff&apos;s information was confidential or, alternatively, denied having made any use of the Plaintiff&apos;s confidential information. <eos/><bos/>Jia, for example, deposed that the corporate defendant developed its own technology “from scratch”.<eos/><bos/> However, the Chambers judge&apos;s role at this stage, however, was not to make any determinations in respect of these issues or even to weigh the evidence. <eos/><bos/>It was simply to determine whether the Plaintiff had raised a serious issue to be tried and the Chambers judge was satisfied that it had in respect of the breach of confidence claim.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84650d38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">45</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Chambers judge made the following orders: 1. The Defendants were to deliver the source code that they were relying on in connection with their anti-drone technology to counsel for the Plaintiff within 48 hours. <eos/><bos/>They were to do so in sealed form. 2. The Defendants, and each of them, were enjoined until December 14, 2018 from: (a) contacting and/or soliciting any employee of the Plaintiff; and (b) engaging in any activity or in any undertaking or business in any capacity that develops, manufactures, or markets anti-drone technology. <eos/><bos/>The Chambers judge used December 14, 2018 because this was one year from when Jia left the Plaintiff and the one-year period aligned with the prohibition in his employment contract. 3. The Defendants, and each of them, were enjoined until the trial of the action from using or developing any anti-drone source code or software that is based on, or derived from, the source code of the Plaintiff.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84650d48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">46</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I6369b6118e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading</cite.query> Ltd.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id84650d58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">47</footnote.reference>] the plaintiffs, Natural Trade and Global Forest were closely held “sister” companies involved in lumber trading. <eos/><bos/>Natural Trade exported lumber products from North America, South America and Europe to Mexico where Global Forest sold the products to local customers. <eos/><bos/>The defendants, Mizrach and Quintana, were former employees of Natural Trade. <eos/><bos/>Mizrach&apos;s responsibilities initially consisted of accounting and trading lumber. <eos/><bos/>Mizrach soon became an important trader and was promoted to CFO. <eos/><bos/>While he was CFO, continued to have an important sales role. <eos/><bos/>Throughout his time with Natural Trade, Quintana worked as a lumber trader. <eos/><bos/>The defendant, MYL Trading was a partnership formed by Mizrach and his spouse while Mizrach was employed by Natural Trade. <eos/><bos/>It was subsequently incorporated and now competed with Natural Trade and Global Forest. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs believed that MYL Trading was formed to directly compete with them and was a corporate vehicle through which Mizrach and Quintana misused confidential information obtained during their employment with Natural Trade. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs sought an interlocutory injunction to restrain the Mizrach defendants from using confidential information obtained in violation of duties owed to the plaintiffs; an order for recovery by the plaintiffs of its confidential information and other property from the Mizrach defendants; and orders requiring Mizrach and Quintana to attest to their eventual return of the plaintiffs&apos; property and to answer questions about their use of the plaintiffs&apos; confidential information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84650d68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">48</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Mizrach and Quintana signed written employment agreements with Natural Trade. <eos/><bos/>In 2016, they also signed written confidentiality and non-disclosure agreements. <eos/><bos/>The employment agreements, and/or confidentiality and non-disclosure agreements included terms relating to non-disclosure of confidential information, return of company property, non-competition and non-solicitation.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84650d78e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">49</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>During their employment with Natural Trade, Mizrach and, to a lesser extent, Quintana had access to, and acquired knowledge of nearly every aspect of Natural Trade&apos;s business and operations. <eos/><bos/>This included access to gross margin reports, which included the customers, suppliers, freight and insurance providers, costs, discounts, profits and profit margins for each sale. <eos/><bos/>Collectively, this information outlined which combinations of customers, suppliers and logistics providers were the most profitable. <eos/><bos/>In performing their duties for Natural Trade, Mizrach and Quintana developed relationships with various customers.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84677e08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">50</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiffs believed that before November 2016, and perhaps as early as the spring of 2015, Mizrach developed a plan to use their confidential information to take their customers for himself. <eos/><bos/>To support their beliefs, the plaintiffs produced documents recovered from Mizrach&apos;s Natural Trade computer. <eos/><bos/>These documents appeared to show that Mizrach, Niron and MYL Trading were, for their own benefit, utilizing one of Natural Trade&apos;s suppliers in Brazil to transact business directly with Proterey and Valley Lumber in December 2016. <eos/><bos/>Mizrach was still employed as Natural Trade&apos;s CFO at the time. <eos/><bos/>The defendants offered no explanation of these records in their affidavits. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs adduced evidence that Mizrach made a copy of Natural Trade&apos;s “ERP system”, which listed all of Natural Trade&apos;s suppliers and customers together with contact information for each. <eos/><bos/>The implication of the plaintiffs&apos; evidence is that Mizrach took a copy of the information for his own benefit to compete with the plaintiffs.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84677e18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">51</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiffs adduced evidence that, prior to their departures, Mizrach and Quintana either copied or tried to copy their entire work email contents for their personal use. <eos/><bos/>Both Mizrach and Quitana acknowledged having or having had several months&apos; worth of work emails on their cell phones after leaving Natural Trade. <eos/><bos/>Further, Mizrach acknowledged having copies of certain of Natural Trade&apos;s gross margin reports.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84677e28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">52</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Mizrach and Mr. Quintana offered explanations as to why they had possession of confidential information of the plaintiffs. <eos/><bos/>They explained that they copied or tried to copy the content of their work email accounts to capture personal emails. <eos/><bos/>They explained having several months&apos; worth of work emails on their cell phones as a mere consequence of their departures. <eos/><bos/>Mizrach explained his possession of gross margin reports as being to enable him to ensure he was paid for commissions he earned before his departure.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84677e38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">53</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Since the departure of Mizrach and Quintana, the plaintiffs experienced a decline in sales to some of the plaintiffs&apos; customers which was offset by sales to these same customers by MYL Trading.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84677e48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">54</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Marchand explained that generally, the court does not embark on a prolonged examination of the merits of the case. <eos/><bos/>However, where the result of an interlocutory injunction would effectively amount to a final determination of the case between the parties, the applicant is required to establish a “strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case”.<eos/><bos/> The test for the return of property, including electronic documents, prior to judgment is essentially the same as the test for the granting of an interlocutory injunction.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84677e58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">55</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiffs acknowledged that the non-compete clauses in the employment contracts of Mizrach and Quintana had expired and the plaintiffs did not seek an order prohibiting the Mizrach defendants from competing against them.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84677e68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">56</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Marchand observed it was incongruous for the Mizrach defendants to say on the one hand that they were not using any confidential information and to say on the other hand that if they were enjoined from using confidential information they would be driven out of business. <eos/><bos/>The real concern of the Mizrach defendants appeared to be the breadth of the injunction sought by the plaintiffs. <eos/><bos/>That concern could be addressed through a properly tailored order. <eos/><bos/>Justice Marchand was unable to conclude that a properly tailored injunction would drive the defendants out of business and/or effectively amount to a final order. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, the plaintiffs did not have to establish that they had a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case. <eos/><bos/>They needed only to establish that there was a serious issue to be tried.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84677e78e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">57</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>There was no serious contest that Mizrach and Quintana owed duties of confidence, loyalty, fidelity and/or good faith to at least Natural Trade, as a result of their employment and/or confidentiality and non-disclosure agreements, at common law and/or in equity. <eos/><bos/>There was also no serious issue that a third party, such as MYL Trading, who is aware that it received confidential information through a breach of confidence may also be held liable for that breach.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8469ef08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">58</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>While the Mizrach defendants maintained that a great deal of information about the international trade of lumber into Mexico is publicly available, there was also no serious issue that the Mizrach defendants had at least some confidential information of the plaintiffs, in particular certain gross margin reports.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8469ef18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">59</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>There was unexplained evidence that the Mizrach defendants transacted business for their own benefit in competition with the plaintiffs while still employed by Natural Trade. <eos/><bos/>There was also evidence of the Mizrach defendants transacting business with the plaintiffs&apos; customers, which corresponded with a decline in the plaintiffs&apos; business with these customers.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8469ef28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">60</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>It might well be that the employment, and confidentiality and non-disclosure agreements are unenforceable; that there is an explanation for the business apparently transacted by the Mizrach defendants for their own benefit in December 2016; that the Mizrach defendants used only publicly available information to build their business; and that the Mizrach defendants were simply outcompeting the plaintiffs through their general know-how and perseverance. <eos/><bos/>Nevertheless, the evidence easily satisfied Justice Marchand that there were a number of serious issues to be tried.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8469ef38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">61</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I637527c18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity</cite.query> Corp.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id8469ef48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">62</footnote.reference>] the plaintiff sought an interlocutory injunction restraining the defendants from disclosing or making use of client information and/or soliciting the plaintiff&apos;s clients. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff also sought an order requiring the defendants to return to it all copies of information related to clients of the plaintiff when the employment of the defendant Mann was terminated by the plaintiff; provide an affidavit setting out any uses to which the defendants have put the information; and refrain from disclosing or otherwise making use of the information, including for the purpose of soliciting the plaintiff&apos;s clients.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8469ef58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">63</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff was a full service brokerage firm and investment dealer. <eos/><bos/>Mann moved to the plaintiff&apos;s Vancouver Branch from another brokerage firm and signed an employment agreement. <eos/><bos/>That agreement did not contain any non-solicitation clause or make reference to a code of conduct. <eos/><bos/>A few days after signing the employment agreement and commencing his employment with the plaintiff, Mann signed a document indicating that he would “accept to read” the plaintiff&apos;s Code of Conduct and Ethics. <eos/><bos/>When he joined the plaintiff, he had 100 clients and was managing $50 million in investment assets.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8469ef68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">64</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The defendants, James and Ilia Nizker became employees of the plaintiff, the latter as a “cold caller”.<eos/><bos/> Like Mann, James&apos; employment contract did not contain a non-solicitation provision and did not refer to the Code of Conduct. <eos/><bos/>Nizker signed an employment contract one month after having qualified and becoming employed as an investment advisor. <eos/><bos/>His employment contract contained a non-solicitation provision.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8469ef78e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">65</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>By April 18, 2018, Mann held the position of Senior Vice President, Portfolio Manager, and oversaw a group of investment advisors and other employees who were known within the plaintiff as the “Mann Group”.<eos/><bos/> At that time the Mann Group serviced 2,500 clients with investment assets totaling $725,000,000. <eos/><bos/>James and Nizker were part of the Mann Group. <eos/><bos/>The growth of the Mann Group&apos;s client base over the years came about as the result of the individual efforts of the Mann Group. <eos/><bos/>The Mann Group had its own website and marketed its services through various means such as newsletters, emails, cold calls and referrals.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id846c6008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">66</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In 2010, Mann purchased computer software called “Salesforce”, a third-party customer relationship platform. <eos/><bos/>It is a cloud-based database into which the Mann Group input the names, addresses, phone numbers and email addresses of clients as well as general notes of discussions they had with clients and prospects. <eos/><bos/>It did not include any information such as account numbers, holdings or rates of return. <eos/><bos/>Mann paid all of the licencing fees for the Salesforce software. <eos/><bos/>The Mann Group did not use the plaintiff&apos;s database to retrieve information used to communicate to clients. <eos/><bos/>It used Salesforce. <eos/><bos/>The only people who had access to the Salesforce database were members of the Mann Group.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id846c6018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">67</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In 2016, Mann contemplated leaving the employ of the plaintiff and moving to the defendant, Canaccord. <eos/><bos/>He copied and provided to Canaccord, via flash drives, confidential and private information regarding the Mann Group&apos;s clients. <eos/><bos/>This information comprised up to 23,768 reports containing “Know Your Client” forms and other client documents. <eos/><bos/>In early 2018, Mann again copied onto flash drives a substantial amount of confidential and private information regarding clients, comprising up to 27,088 records.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id846c6028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">68</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>On April 18, 2018, Mann&apos;s employment was terminated by the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff now alleged that Mann was terminated for cause, in that he engaged in misconduct that was in breach of securities regulations, IIROC rules and the plaintiff&apos;s internal policies.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id846c6038e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">69</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Immediately after Mann&apos;s termination, James changed the Salesforce password, which cut off the plaintiff&apos;s temporary access to the Salesforce account. <eos/><bos/>Thereafter, the only contact information available to the plaintiff for the clients that had been managed by the Mann Group was that contained in its own database. <eos/><bos/>On April 20, 2018, James tendered his resignation to the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>On April 23, 2018, Mann and James commenced employment with Canaccord. <eos/><bos/>Also on April 23, 2018, Nizker and four other members of the Mann Group tendered their respective resignations and joined Mann and James at Canaccord. <eos/><bos/>The Mann team immediately began to solicit the business of the clients whose assets they had managed while employed by the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>They provided information regarding why they had left the plaintiff and moved to Canaccord that was, at the very least, a failure of full disclosure as to the true reason they had left the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff was unable to correspond with or contact many of the recipients of these emails because it did not have current contact information for them.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id846c6048e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">70</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The defendants had possession of seven categories of documents that fell within the plaintiff&apos;s definition of Confidential Documents: a) the 2016 USB Keys; b) documents from the 2016 USB Keys downloaded to the desktop of Canaccord&apos;s Assistant Branch Manager; c) hard copies of documents printed from the 2016 USB Keys; d) data from the hard copies used to populate Canaccord transfer forms which were kept on USB drives; e) data from the hard copies of documents loaded into a database used by Canaccord known as Dataphile; f) the 2018 USB Keys; and g) a client list, separate from that contained on Salesforce, printed by Mann shortly before his termination from the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>The defendants returned to the plaintiff the 2016 USB Keys, the hard copies of documents from the 2016 USB Keys, the Transfer Form USB Keys, the 2018 USB Keys and the client list printed by Mann in 2018. <eos/><bos/>No copies were kept of any of these documents, electronically or otherwise. <eos/><bos/>The data that was loaded to Dataphile remained there. <eos/><bos/>Dataphile is a database owned by an external vendor and Canaccord does not have the ability, on its own, to permanently remove the data.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id846c6058e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">71</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The first requirement for an injunction to enjoin the use of confidential information is the establishment of a serious issue to be tried as to whether the defendants remain in possession of confidential information belonging to the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>Justice Weatherill observed that the court&apos;s consideration as to whether information is sufficiently confidential so as to warrant the court&apos;s protection includes: a) the extent to which the information is known outside of the owner&apos;s business; b) the extent to which it is known by the employees and others involved in the owner&apos;s business; c) the extent of measures taken by the company to guard the secrecy of the information; d) the value of the information to the company and its competitors; e) the amount of money or effort expended by the company in developing the information; and f) the ease or difficulty with which the information could properly be acquired or duplicated by others.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id846c6068e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">72</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The defendants conceded that there was a serious issue to be tried in respect of the documents that were loaded to Dataphile but alleged that the plaintiff failed to demonstrate a proprietary interest in the Salesforce information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id846ed108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">73</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Weatherill observed that in the context of clients being served by investment advisors who move firms, the interests of the clients must be put ahead of those of the firm. <eos/><bos/>Investment advisors are entitled to maintain client information so as to enable them to immediately contact the client after the move, citing Justice Southin in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2011192292" w-pub-number="0006458" ID="I637a30d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>RBC Dominion Securities Inc. v. Merrill Lynch Canada Inc.</ital>, 2007 BCCA 22</cite.query>, <case.history>revd in part on other grounds</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017227608" w-pub-number="0006489" ID="I637a30d28e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2008 SCC 54</cite.query>:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>[81] In my opinion, a client is entitled to know immediately upon his advisor leaving one firm for another where that advisor has gone so that he or she can decide whether to change to the new firm or remain with the old.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0002"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0003"/>[82] Because of the important interest of the client, an advisor should be able, without fear of litigation, to prepare a list of his own book of business from the records of the brokerage house. <eos/><bos/>To hold in the 21st century that an advisor, who usually, by considerable personal diligence, has built up a book of business, must rely on his memory for the full names, addresses, telephone numbers and e-mail addresses of his clients, is not, in my opinion, in the interests of the clients and, therefore, is not in the public interest. <eos/><bos/>I emphasise “his own book of business”.<eos/><bos/> He is not entitled to take a list of other advisors&apos; clients. <eos/><bos/>To put it another way, the interests of the brokerage house should not be put ahead of the interests of the clients.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0003"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id846ed118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">74</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Salesforce database contained only information in respect of the clients who were advised and serviced by the Mann Group. <eos/><bos/>The Mann Group&apos;s Book of Business was generated by the Mann Group through cold calling, ground work and other of their own initiatives.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id846ed128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">75</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Weatherill noted that the plaintiff did not take steps to assiduously protect the information of the clients being managed by the Mann Group. <eos/><bos/>Indeed, the plaintiff did not take any steps consistent with an assertion of exclusive ownership over that information. <eos/><bos/>Moreover, at the time the plaintiff terminated Mann, it offered to purchase the “management rights” with respect to Mann Group&apos;s Book of Business, which demonstrated a recognition on the plaintiff&apos;s part that it did not have a proprietary interest in that book of business.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id846ed138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">76</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Weatherill further observed that there is also a public interest factor to consider. <eos/><bos/>Brokerage houses do not “own” their clients. <eos/><bos/>Clients should be free to receive information from all competitive sources and to have the ability to decide if they wish to follow their investment advisor to the new brokerage house or stay with the old one. <eos/><bos/>In addition, employee mobility and the ability to compete and earn a livelihood in a chosen field are in the public interest and should not be lightly restrained.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id846ed148e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">77</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Weatherill concluded that the plaintiff failed to demonstrate a serious issue to be tried in respect of the Salesforce information being proprietary to the plaintiff such that it was entitled to injunctive relief. <eos/><bos/>However, as the defendants conceded that there was a serious question to be tried regarding the documents loaded to Dataphile, the threshold had been met with respect to those documents.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id846ed158e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">78</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Quick Pass Master Tutorial School Ltd. v. Zhao</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id846ed168e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">79</footnote.reference>] Quick Pass sought an interlocutory injunction to prohibit Zhao from competing with it, from soliciting its students, and from using what it alleged was Quick Pass&apos;s confidential or proprietary information. <eos/><bos/>Quick Pass offered real estate-related tutorial programs in various Lower Mainland locations to assist Mandarin speakers in taking British Columbia&apos;s real estate licencing examinations. <eos/><bos/>It hired real estate agents who were fluent in Mandarin as instructors. <eos/><bos/>The owner of Quick Pass hired Zhao under a two-year contract as a real estate program instructor. <eos/><bos/>The contractual terms prohibited Zhao from soliciting Quick Pass&apos;s students and from competing with it for specified periods. <eos/><bos/>It also provided that Quick Pass owned all material relating to its business, including any material created by Zhao while under contract to Quick Pass, whether or not he created it at Quick Pass&apos;s direction.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84714208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">80</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The day after Zhao terminated his contract, he opened a competing tutorial school in Burnaby. <eos/><bos/>He advertised and marketed his school to the Mandarin-speaking community, including to students of Quick Pass. <eos/><bos/>He used materials that he alleged he developed for use in his own program, but which he must have developed while working for Quick Pass since he opened his school the next day.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84714218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">81</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Iyer observed that since Zhao opened his school the day after he left Quick Pass, and the Confidential Information Clause deemed any such material created by Zhao during the term of the Contracts to be the proprietary and confidential information of Quick Pass, it was more likely than not that the material he created for the Zhao School was created while Zhao was under contract to Quick Pass. <eos/><bos/>This meant that if the Confidential Information Clause was enforceable, Zhao breached it.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84714228e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">82</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Confidential Information Clause was not a restrictive covenant. <eos/><bos/>Rather, Justice Iyer observed that it was <begin.quote ID="QT_0004"/>“intended to protect the right of a business to keep confidential the information it hopes will help it to compete so the usual relatively low threshold applies to it”<end.quote refid="QT_0004"/>, citing <cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00007" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034063927" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I638bbd008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Phoenix Restorations Ltd. v. Drisdelle</ital>, 2014 CarswellBC 2348, 2014 BCSC 1497</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>This meant that Quick Pass need only prove that its claim with respect to this clause was not frivolous or vexatious and the court need not engage in an extensive review of the merits of the claim.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84714238e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">83</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Zhao argued that the information in dispute is not capable of being confidential information. <eos/><bos/>Justice Iyer observed that the contractual prohibition applied to <begin.quote ID="QT_0005"/>“teaching materials, examination, teaching methods, marketing plans, proposals, contracts, technical and/or financial information, databases, software and know-how”<end.quote refid="QT_0005"/>. <eos/><bos/>Justice Iyer was satisfied that some of the described information could be confidential information. <eos/><bos/>That was all that is necessary for Quick Pass to establish that there was a serious issue to be tried.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84714248e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">84</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff in <ital>Claim Analytics Inc. v. Polon</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id84714258e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">85</footnote.reference>] was granted an interim and interlocutory injunction against the defendants to prevent the disclosure of confidential information, being the “Diagnosis Database”, a predictive model that the plaintiff used in its core business to serve a narrow area of demand within the insurance market.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84714268e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">86</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff corporation was founded by the defendant, Jonathan Polon and Senensky. <eos/><bos/>In March, 2014, after Senensky triggered a buy/sell provision in the Shareholders Agreement entered into by their respective shareholder corporations, Polon sold his interest in the plaintiff to Senensky and left Claim Analytics.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84714278e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">87</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Diagnosis Database was a key part of the plaintiff&apos;s confidential information. <eos/><bos/>In addition to creating and offering predictive models in respect of long-term and short-term disability claim scoring, another core part of the plaintiff&apos;s business was to provide services in relation to “Benchmarking Studies”, which provide a claim recovery comparison to various insurers. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff and Munich Re co-sponsored two Benchmarking Studies in relation to group long-term disability claims experience for Canadian insurers in 2011 and 2014. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff and Munich Re had discussed co-sponsorship of a new study to take place in 2016 and had planned to offer it to the Canadian insurers who participated in the previous study and to others. <eos/><bos/>However, when the plaintiff insisted upon looking for some kind of guaranteed revenue from Munich Re, Munich Re advised the plaintiff that it was not acceptable and minimum revenues did not fit with Munich Re&apos;s objectives. <eos/><bos/>Munich Re then sought out Polon and agreed to conduct its 2016 Benchmarking Study with him rather than with the plaintiff, mainly because Polon was willing to do the study for the same financial structure as had been charged in the past.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8473b308e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">88</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The dispute centered around the confidentiality of the concept and technique to create a Diagnosis Database. <eos/><bos/>Polon submitted that the predictive models were unique 10 years ago but that is no longer the case. <eos/><bos/>He stated that all material confidential information and trade secrets had already been disclosed into the public domain by the plaintiff itself. <eos/><bos/>This included both a) information disseminated by the plaintiff in papers, articles and presentations as well as b) concepts developed by persons with no affiliation to the plaintiff inclusive of works published in text books, scholarly articles and conveyed to the public during presentations. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, qualified individuals are capable of building their own predictive models, including insurance claim scoring.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8473b318e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">89</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>However, the motions judge observed with respect to the Diagnosis Database that (a) the Confidential Information related to specific novel methods, processes and compilations of information created and developed by the plaintiff; (b) the plaintiff had consistently treated this information as confidential: (i) although the general concept has been disclosed outside of the business, important elements of the Diagnosis Database remained secret; (ii) the plaintiff was a closely-knit business with few employees; (iii) the plaintiff required third parties, employees, and even its shareholders to agree to the confidentiality of its information; (iv) the Diagnosis Database represented an important data transformation which distinguished the plaintiff&apos;s predictive models; (v) the Diagnosis Database had been evolving and growing since 2003; (vi) Without specific knowledge of the seven variables for each of the diagnosis codes, the manner in which scores were assigned to the variables, and particularly the eighth element of the Diagnosis Database, it could not be easily duplicated. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff had mapped each medical diagnosis it encountered in its customers&apos; data into a set of variables which were rated 0 or 1 to 10. <eos/><bos/>As of March 2014, there were seven variables scored for each of the hundreds of diagnosis codes. <eos/><bos/>Of the seven variables, five had been disclosed in presentations or academic papers. <eos/><bos/>Two of the variables remained confidential.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8473b328e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">90</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motions judge observed that even when all of the information becomes public, if an ex-employee is able, by information provided by or developed for the previous employer to gain an advantage that he or she would not have had, it would provide a spring board for an unfair advantage over others. <eos/><bos/>What is really being protected in situations of this nature is the original process of mind. <eos/><bos/>The protection is enforced against persons who wish to use the confidential information without spending time, trouble and expense of going through the same process to prevent them from getting an unfair start. <eos/><bos/>In any event, the full Diagnosis Database had not been disclosed publicly and the plaintiff had taken protective measures to ensure its confidentiality. <eos/><bos/>A misappropriation of trade secrets by a former employee will give rise to liability for which there is injunctive relief. <eos/><bos/>There was sufficient evidence to establish that there was a serious issue to be tried with respect to the imminent threat of breach of confidence and fiduciary duty by Polon.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8473b338e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">91</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Cambridge Mercantile Corp. v. Cook</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id8473b348e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">92</footnote.reference>] the plaintiff sought an order that the Defendant be restrained and enjoined until the hearing of the matter, or until further Order of this Court from using, reproducing or disclosing the confidential information of the Plaintiff, which information includes customer files, customer lists, costing manuals, costing procedures or cost amounts and all such information, either in electronic, printed, or verbal form. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff also sought an order that the defendant be required to immediately return to the Plaintiff all Confidential Information, documents, electronic information and tangible items which belong to the Plaintiff or any customer of the Plaintiff or which contain or refer to any Confidential Information in relation to the Plaintiff or any customer of the Plaintiff in the Defendant&apos;s possession or under his control.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8473b358e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">93</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff was in the business of providing specialized foreign exchange services to assist business enterprises in conducting business globally. <eos/><bos/>The defendant began working for the plaintiff in 2003. <eos/><bos/>He resigned on July 31, 2015 and left the plaintiff&apos;s employ on September 30, 2015. <eos/><bos/>He started work for a competitor EncoreFX in October 2015. <eos/><bos/>The relationship of the parties was governed by an employment agreement that provided, among other things, for confidentiality, and included non-competition and non-solicitation clauses. <eos/><bos/>In the course of his employment, the defendant was privy to confidential and proprietary information. <eos/><bos/>The defendant had been in communication with EncoreFX during the spring of April 2015. <eos/><bos/>On June 11, 2015 the defendant emailed a list of 1738 customer names, addresses, and revenue figures to his personal email account. <eos/><bos/>On July 27, 2015 the defendant emailed a list of the plaintiff&apos;s customers including names, address, sales history revenue, and other information to his personal email account. <eos/><bos/>The defendant acknowledged that he did this. <eos/><bos/>He said it was a foolish decision and that he never used this information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8473b368e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">94</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The application judge observed that there was another case before the courts involving the plaintiff and another employee who departed for EncoreFX, <ital>Cambridge Mercantile Corp. v. Sean Parks</ital> (July 29, 2015), Vancouver S155672 (B.C. S.C.).<eos/><bos/> There, the court had addressed the situation of an employee who was not a trader. <eos/><bos/>He had acknowledged the breach of confidentiality in his dealings with EncoreFX. <eos/><bos/>He also had training and marketing materials in hard copies and on a computer in his possession. <eos/><bos/>There was some issue as to whether this material had all been returned or whether it was used in relation to EncoreFX. <eos/><bos/>The application judge observed that the court had stated as follows:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0006"/>[38] By the Notice of Civil Claim that was placed before the court, the plaintiff claims that the defendant breached its contractual duty, including a duty not to disclose the plaintiff&apos;s confidential information to any person without its authorization <ital>inter alia</ital>.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0006"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0007"/>[39] In addition to the Employment Agreement and the confidentiality clause, the plaintiff submits that every employee owes a duty of fidelity or good faith to his employer and should not retain or use documents, client lists or other confidential information: <cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00008" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2009692908" w-pub-number="0006459" ID="I639448808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>C.B. Constantini Ltd. v. Slozka</ital>, 2006 BCSC 1210, at para. 29</cite.query>:<end.quote refid="QT_0007"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0008"/>[29] With respect to breach of fiduciary duty, the principles to be applied in the context of the departing employee were summarized by Madam Justice Holmes in the <ital>BBC </ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00009" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2011192292" w-pub-number="0006458" ID="I639532e18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Dominion Securities Inc. v. Merrill Lynch Canada Inc</ital>.</cite.query> (2003), 44 B.L.R. (3d) 72 at paras. 35–36, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00010" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2003873390" w-pub-number="0006459" ID="I639532e28e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2003 BCSC 1773</cite.query>:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext>Every employee, whether or not in a fiduciary relationship to the employer, owes a duty of fidelity or good faith to the employer which is not limited to current employment. <eos/><bos/>This general duty includes a duty not to compete unfairly against the employer during or after the employment arrangement, and in turn a duty not to make use of the employer&apos;s confidential information and material to compete with the employer: <cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00011" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1999482256" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I6395cf208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Barton Insurance Brokers Ltd. v. Irwin</ital> (1999) 170 D.L.R. (4th) 69, 1999 BCCA 73 (B.C.C.A.)</cite.query> at [paragraph] 17–18 and [paragraph] 29, <ital>Delta Play Co. v. International Play Co</ital>. <eos/><bos/>May 4, 1999 Doc. <eos/><bos/>Vancouver C991871 (B.C.S.C.).<eos/><bos/> However, unless bound by a non-competition clause in the employment contract, an employee is entitled to compete fairly with the employer.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0008"/></paratext></para></display.quote></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0009"/>A former employee is more restricted if he or she stands in a fiduciary relationship to the employer. <eos/><bos/>Like a non-fiduciary employee, he or she may compete fairly against the former employer. <eos/><bos/>However, he or she must not directly solicit the former employers&apos; clients:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext>Absent an enforceable contractual restriction to the contrary, a fiduciary may compete with its former employer. <eos/><bos/>However, a fiduciary may not make unfair use of confidential information, directly solicit the business of customers or suppliers, or take any business advantage or opportunities belonging to the employer. (<eos/><bos/><ital>Delta Play, supra</ital>, at [paragraph] 20).<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0009"/></paratext></para></display.quote></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0010"/>Accordingly, even in the absence of a fiduciary relationship, every employee still owes a duty of good faith to the employer.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0010"/></paratext></para><head style="l" parent="display.quote"><headtext><bold>(i) The fair question to be tried</bold></headtext></head><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0011"/>[41] Here, I find that legal threshold for the serious issue to be tried has been met. <eos/><bos/>As there is only a preliminary assessment of the merits to be determined and as the threshold is low, and I find the facts deposed to disclose a serious issue to be tried.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0011"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><bold><begin.quote ID="QT_0012"/>(ii) The applicant has demonstrated it will suffer irreparable harm if the injunction not granted …<end.quote refid="QT_0012"/></bold></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0013"/>[45] I have found in the present case that there is a serious issue to be tried with respect to whether the defendant remains in possession of the property and the confidential information. <eos/><bos/>Given the defendant&apos;s admission that he discussed at least one client of the plaintiff with his now present employer, I do not accept that the name of the client is not a part of the confidential information warranting an order from this court.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0013"/></paratext></para><head parent="display.quote"><headtext>…</headtext></head><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0014"/>[50] Here, the parties have an agreement providing for confidentiality as embodied in the Employment Agreement and that any violation will give rise to injury. <eos/><bos/>Claims for privilege and confidentiality in many instances are to be determined at trial after an order for an interim injunction has been granted, particularly in circumstances where there are written agreements respecting confidentiality. <eos/><bos/>Otherwise, the claim could be moot if the terms were not respected pending trial: see <cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00012" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2003061858" w-pub-number="0006459" ID="I6396b9808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Fording Coal Ltd. v. United Steelworkers of America, Local No. 7884</ital>, 2003 BCSC 977</cite.query>.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0014"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0015"/>[51] The defendant says that he could suffer irreparable harm if an interim injunction is ordered as a consequence of this application. <eos/><bos/>He submits that an order may in some way affect his future employment if others learn that he is the subject of an interim injunction. <eos/><bos/>I find this claim to be speculative and I am unable to accede to this argument.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0015"/></paratext></para><head style="l" parent="display.quote"><headtext><bold>(iii) The balance of convenience</bold></headtext></head><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0016"/>[52] I find the balance of convenience favours the granting of an injunction, it favours return of the information and does not prejudice the defendant in any manner. <eos/><bos/>If the defendant does have the plaintiff&apos;s property in violation of the terms of the Employment Agreement, that cannot be a prejudice to him if he is ordered to return and cease using that information: <cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00013" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2016634847" w-pub-number="0006459" ID="I639707a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>QuIC Financial Technologies Inc. v. Chang</ital>, 2008 BCSC 989, at para. 43</cite.query>, nor is there harm in being ordered to return information in his possession and disclose what information he has disclosed to date.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0016"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id84762408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">95</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The application judge concluded that the above-expressed principles applied and the question, if anything, was whether the facts were materially different and would lead to a different outcome. <eos/><bos/>In the present case, like that of <ital>Parks</ital>, there was a serious question as to whether the defendant Cook remained in possession of the plaintiff&apos;s information and whether he has been using that information in contravention of the employment agreement. <eos/><bos/>The indications that the defendant breached the agreement beyond his admissions, included the evidence given by other employees of the defendant&apos;s efforts to leave the plaintiff for EncoreFX, and evidence that customers have been contacted by the defendant for business purposes. <eos/><bos/>Apart from saying that he did not use the material he took from Cambridge, the defendant denied the assertion that he defendant told a fellow employee that he had photographed confidential material. <eos/><bos/>He acknowledged speaking to some of the plaintiff&apos;s customers, but said that even when he initiated the calls he did not solicit them. <eos/><bos/>He had, however, given them quotes for his services at EncoreFX.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84762418e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">96</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Much of what the defendant submitted respecting the employment contract would be of more interest if this were a trial on the broader terms of the contract. <eos/><bos/>While it may be important to know, in some contexts, that the contract underlying the application is thoroughly bad, the application judge would not go so far as to say so here. <eos/><bos/>Even if the contract was deficient, in its absence an employer may still seek to protect proprietary information from being taken by former employees. <eos/><bos/>In the context of an interlocutory injunction, where the objective is to adjust the positions of the parties to best preserve the subject matter of the claim, and to protect the rights of the parties pending a final determination, it is unwise to embark on more than the provisional weighing of the merits necessary to meet the tests set out in <ital>Parks</ital>. <eos/><bos/>Applying that law at this stage of the proceedings there was a fair issue to be tried, and the balance of convenience here, as in <ital>Parks</ital>, favoured the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>The inchoate nature of the harm that may potentially be inflicted will be difficult to quantify and that damages may not be an adequate remedy. <eos/><bos/>The damages the defendant suggests may come to EncoreFX from an injunction altering <begin.quote ID="QT_0017"/>“the competitive landscape between it and [the plaintiff]”<end.quote refid="QT_0017"/> pales in comparison to the interests of the plaintiff in seeing that it keeps what it had, and EncoreFX does not get it until the limits of each entity&apos;s rights are addressed in light of the defendant&apos;s responsibility. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, the case for an interlocutory injunction had been established.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84789508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">97</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Enviro Trace Ltd. v. Sheichuk</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id84789518e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">98</footnote.reference>] the applicant was granted a continuation of an interlocutory injunction previously granted on an interim interim basis against the defendant former employees of the plaintiff and the company which they set up. <eos/><bos/>The applicant requested only an order preventing the respondents from using the applicant&apos;s trade secrets and confidential information rather than one which prevented them from carrying on business. <eos/><bos/>In the circumstances, this was not a situation where the “strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case” standard replaced the “serious issue to be tried” standard. <eos/><bos/>The motions judge did not accept the respondents&apos; argument that, because they were former employees, the higher threshold test of “strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case” applied. <eos/><bos/>The motions judge did agree that where facts are not in dispute, perhaps because questioning has made the underlying fact situation clear, a higher standard might be appropriate. <eos/><bos/>However, most of the defendants had not yet been questioned, and the time lines were too tight to have completed undertakings and dealt with challenges to refused undertakings. <eos/><bos/>The higher standard did not come into play because the underlying facts were still very much in dispute.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84789528e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">99</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motions judge concluded that the applicant had met the usual standard. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff maintained that it kept its trade secrets in a binder in a locked office within its premises and that the defendant, and former employee, Hess had the responsibility of guarding the confidentiality of that material. <eos/><bos/>The applicant also asserted that the binder in question went missing at some time after the defendant Hess left the plaintiff&apos;s employ and had never been found. <eos/><bos/>The applicant also asserted that one of its former employees, the defendant Montgomery, was responsible for a data management software program developed for the applicant and in which tanks owned by various clients were identified by location, and by the date of last servicing, thereby providing to the applicant specific information about when specific tanks had to be re-tested. <eos/><bos/>The applicant claimed that this was confidential information that would not be available to persons involved in the oil and gas industry generally. <eos/><bos/>The applicant stated that one of its clients was approached by the respondents at precisely the time when some of that client&apos;s specific tanks had to be tested and that such approach could not have been mere co-incidence. <eos/><bos/>Since the date of the interim, interim injunction, none of the defendants had provided sworn evidence that they were not involved in a conspiracy to steal the applicant&apos;s trade secrets and none of them had provided affidavit evidence stating that they have returned to their former employer all corporate material f that was in their possession. <eos/><bos/>In the circumstances, the applicant established that its fear of a breach of its rights was well founded. <eos/><bos/>The respondents acted suspiciously throughout by failing to respond in a forthright manner to the plaintiff&apos;s allegations.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84789538e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">100</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motions judge cautioned that the tri-partite test should be just that and should not become a three step process in which the first test is a threshold. <eos/><bos/>Rather, the court should examine, perhaps in the context of the third prong of the test (balance of convenience) the strength of the applicant&apos;s case. <eos/><bos/>In the result, the appropriate standard to be applied was the “serious issue to be tried” standard.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84789548e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">101</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>RBC Dominion Securities Inc. v. Macdonald</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id84789558e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">102</footnote.reference>] the plaintiff RBCDS carried on business as a registered investment dealer with a branch office in Kelowna. <eos/><bos/>The defendant was employed as an associate investment advisor at the RBCDS Kelowna branch until he resigned. <eos/><bos/>The employee worked as an assistant to I, a senior investment advisor. <eos/><bos/>Over time, he became the primary contact and service provider for some clients for whom I was the designated RBCDS advisor. <eos/><bos/>Shortly after he left RBCDS, the employee commenced new employment with the NBF, an RBCDS competitor. <eos/><bos/>He began immediately to contact I&apos;s RBCDS clients to solicit their investment business. <eos/><bos/>In so doing, the employee apparently relied in part on RBCDS records of client names and contact information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id84789568e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">103</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The court concluded that the identities and contact particulars of RBCDS clients was, <ital>prima facie</ital>, confidential information that the employee acquired in the course of his employment. <eos/><bos/>Pursuant to the terms of his employment contract it was also information he was obliged, <ital>prima facie</ital>, not to disclosure or use following his departure. <eos/><bos/>This was so regardless of whether the employment contract included a non-solicitation or non-competition clause. <eos/><bos/>The court was of the view that the extent to which a departing investment advisor may properly use information regarding the identities and contact particulars of clients where there is a contractual term did not need to be resolved because the alleged misuse of confidential information extended beyond the Primary Contact Clients to whom the employee provided services while he was employed by RBCDS. Rather, since departing, the employee had solicited a range of RBCDS clients in a targeted manner using a range of contact methods. <eos/><bos/>Some of those solicited were not Primary Contact Clients. <eos/><bos/>In addition, some of the addresses or telephone numbers through which contact was made are not publicly available. <eos/><bos/>In these circumstances, there was a serious question to be tried.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id847b0608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">104</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Id84566708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00014" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1977149578" w-pub-number="0005150" ID="I639c10b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Yule Inc. v. Atlantic Pizza Delight Franchise (1968) Ltd.</ital> (1977), 80 D.L.R. (3d) 725, 17 O.R. (2d) 505 (Div. Ct.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00015" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1983169154" w-pub-number="0005652" ID="I639c10b48e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>C-Cure Chemical Co. v. Olympia &amp; York Developments Ltd.</ital></cite.query> (1983), 33 C.P.C. 192 at pp. 199–200, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00016" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1983169154" w-pub-number="0005652" ID="I639c10b58e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">71 C.P.R. (2d) 153 (Ont. Div. Ct.)</cite.query>, leave to appeal to Ont. C.A. refused 33 C.P.C. 192<ital>n</ital>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00017" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2002453516" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I639c10b78e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>911887 Ontario Ltd. v. LeBlanc</ital> (2002), 115 A.C.W.S. (3d) 868 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00018" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2030642918" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I639c10b98e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Brett Young Seeds Limited Partnership v. Dyck</ital>, 2013 CarswellAlta 900, 2013 ABQB 319</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84566718e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00019" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2002454643" w-pub-number="0003986" ID="I639c85e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>4064143 Manitoba Ltd. v. Wawryk</ital>, [2002] 10 W.W.R. 703, 222 Sask. R. 153 (Q.B.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84566728e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00020" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1977149578" w-pub-number="0005150" ID="I639cacf08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Yule Inc. v. Atlantic Pizza Delight Franchise (1968) Ltd.</ital> (1977), 80 D.L.R. (3d) 725, 17 O.R. (2d) 505 (Div. Ct.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00021" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1974148959" w-pub-number="0005652" ID="I639cacf38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Champion International Corp. v. Merrill &amp; Wagner Ltd.</ital> (1974), 15 C.P.R. (2d) 190 (B.C.C.A.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00022" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1985196523" w-pub-number="0005459" ID="I639cacf58e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Haessler-DeWay Ltd. v. Color Tech Inc.</ital> (1985), 4 C.I.P.R. 77, 49</cite.query> C.P.C. 156 (Ont. Dist. Ct.).<eos/><bos/> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00023" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2000551071" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I639cacf78e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">In <ital>C.I.B.C. World Markets Inc. v. MacDonald</ital> (2000), 99 A.C.W.S. (3d) 678 (B.C.S.C.)</cite.query> the court <case.history>granted</case.history> an injunction for a fixed period during which time the plaintiff was to determine what, if anything, the defendants were doing.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84566738e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>4</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00024" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1974027100" w-pub-number="0004651" ID="I639cfb108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>American Cyanamid Co. v. Ethicon Ltd.</ital>, [1975] A.C. 396 (H.L.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00025" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1967017749" w-pub-number="0004891" ID="I639cfb128e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Harman Pictures N.V. v. Osborne</ital>, [1967] 1 W.L.R. 723 (Ch.)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>See also <cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00026" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2009642838" w-pub-number="0005160" ID="I639cfb148e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Diversified Metal Engineering Ltd. v. Trivett</ital> (2006), 258 Nfld. &amp; P.E.I.R. 13 (P.E.I.C.A.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8458d808e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>5</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00027" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I639d22208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al</ital>., 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8458d818e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>6</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00028" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I639d49308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al</ital>., 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055</cite.query>, at paras. 1–2.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8458d828e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>7</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00029" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I639d70408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al</ital>., 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055</cite.query>, at paras. 8–9.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8458d838e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>8</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00030" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I639d97508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al</ital>., 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055, at para. 10</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8458d848e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>9</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00031" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I639dbe608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al</ital>., 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055</cite.query>, at paras. 11–13.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8458d858e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>10</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00032" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I639e0c808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al</ital>., 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055</cite.query>, at paras. 14–15.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8458d868e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>11</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00033" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I639e33908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al</ital>., 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055, at para. 16</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id845b4908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>12</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00034" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I639e33938e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al</ital>., 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055, at para. 17</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id845b4918e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>13</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00035" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I639e5aa08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al</ital>., 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055, at para. 19</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id845b4928e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>14</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00036" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I639ea8c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al</ital>., 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055</cite.query>, at paras. 3–6.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id845b4938e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>15</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00037" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I639ea8c38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al</ital>., 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055, at para. 21</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id845b4948e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>16</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00038" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I639ef6e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al</ital>., 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055</cite.query>, at paras. 27–30.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id845b4958e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>17</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00039" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I639f1df08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc</ital>., 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id845b4968e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>18</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00040" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I639f45008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc</ital>., 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220</cite.query>, at paras. 2–4, and 8.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id845b4978e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>19</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00041" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I639f6c108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc</ital>., 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220, at para. 11</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id845dba08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>20</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00042" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I639f93208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc</ital>., 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220</cite.query>, at paras. 20 and 24.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id845dba18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>21</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00043" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I639fba308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc</ital>., 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220</cite.query>, at paras. 53, and 55–56.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id845dba28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>22</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00044" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I639fe1408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc</ital>., 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220, at para. 57</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id845dba38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>23</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00045" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I63a008508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc</ital>., 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220</cite.query>, at paras. 62–63.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id845dba48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>24</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00046" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I63a02f608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc</ital>., 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220, at para. 71</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id845dba58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>25</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00047" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I63a056708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc</ital>., 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220, at para. 85</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id845dba68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>26</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00048" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I63a07d808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc</ital>., 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220</cite.query>, at paras. 86–88.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84602b08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>27</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00049" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I63a0a4908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc</ital>., 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220, at para. 90</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84602b18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>28</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00050" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I63a0cba08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc</ital>., 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220, at para. 91</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84602b28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>29</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00051" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I63a0f2b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc</ital>., 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220, at para. 92</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84602b38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>30</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00052" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I63a0f2b38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc</ital>., 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220, at para. 93</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84602b48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>31</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00053" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I63a119c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc</ital>., 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220, at para. 94</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84602b58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>32</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00054" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I63a167e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc</ital>., 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220</cite.query>, at paras. 95–96.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84602b68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>33</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00055" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I63a167e38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc</ital>., 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220, at para. 98</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84602b78e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>34</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00056" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I63a18ef08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc</ital>., 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220, at para. 100</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84629c08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>35</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00057" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I63a1dd108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc</ital>., 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220</cite.query>, at paras. 102–105.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84629c18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>36</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00058" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I63a204208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc</ital>., 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220</cite.query>, at paras. 108 and 115.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84629c28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>37</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00059" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047090766" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a22b308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>SkyCope Technologies Inc. v. Jia</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 3343, 2018 BCSC 2204</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84629c38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>38</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00060" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047090766" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a252408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>SkyCope Technologies Inc. v. Jia</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 3343, 2018 BCSC 2204, at para. 1</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84629c48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>39</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00061" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047090766" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a279508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>SkyCope Technologies Inc. v. Jia</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 3343, 2018 BCSC 2204</cite.query>, at paras. 2–4.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84629c58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>40</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00062" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047090766" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a2a0608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>SkyCope Technologies Inc. v. Jia</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 3343, 2018 BCSC 2204, at para. 5</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84629c68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>41</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00063" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047090766" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a2c7708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>SkyCope Technologies Inc. v. Jia</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 3343, 2018 BCSC 2204</cite.query>, at paras. 6–8.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84650d08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>42</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00064" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047090766" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a315908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>SkyCope Technologies Inc. v. Jia</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 3343, 2018 BCSC 2204, at para. 10</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84650d18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>43</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00065" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047090766" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a33ca08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>SkyCope Technologies Inc. v. Jia</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 3343, 2018 BCSC 2204, at para. 12</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84650d28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>44</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00066" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047090766" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a38ac08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>SkyCope Technologies Inc. v. Jia</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 3343, 2018 BCSC 2204</cite.query>, at paras. 16–18.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84650d38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>45</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00067" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047090766" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a3b1d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>SkyCope Technologies Inc. v. Jia</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 3343, 2018 BCSC 2204, at para. 19</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84650d48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>46</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00068" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047090766" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a3d8e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>SkyCope Technologies Inc. v. Jia</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 3343, 2018 BCSC 2204, at para. 39</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84650d58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>47</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00069" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a3d8e38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84650d68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>48</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00070" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a427008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176</cite.query>, at paras. 1–3, 5–6, and 18.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84650d78e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>49</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00071" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a44e108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176</cite.query>, at paras. 20–21.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84677e08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>50</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00072" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a475208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176</cite.query>, at paras. 22–23.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84677e18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>51</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00073" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a49c308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176</cite.query>, at paras. 24–26.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84677e28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>52</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00074" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a4c3408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176, at para. 31</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84677e38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>53</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00075" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a4ea508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176, at para. 32</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84677e48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>54</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00076" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a511608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176, at para. 33</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84677e58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>55</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00077" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a538708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176</cite.query>, at paras. 37–38.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84677e68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>56</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00078" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a55f808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176, at para. 39</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84677e78e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>57</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00079" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a586908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176</cite.query>, at paras. 41–43.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8469ef08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>58</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00080" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a5ada08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176</cite.query>, at paras. 46–47.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8469ef18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>59</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00081" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a5d4b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176, at para. 48</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8469ef28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>60</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00082" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a5fbc08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176, at para. 49</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8469ef38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>61</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00083" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a622d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176, at para. 50</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8469ef48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>62</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00084" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a649e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity Corp.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1309, 2018 BCSC 857</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8469ef58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>63</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00085" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a649e38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity Corp.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1309, 2018 BCSC 857, at para. 1</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8469ef68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>64</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00086" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a698008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity Corp.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1309, 2018 BCSC 857</cite.query>, at paras. 3, and 5–6.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8469ef78e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>65</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00087" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a698038e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity Corp.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1309, 2018 BCSC 857, at para. 7</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id846c6008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>66</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00088" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a6e6208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity Corp.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1309, 2018 BCSC 857</cite.query>, at paras. 11–12.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id846c6018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>67</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00089" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a70d308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity Corp.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1309, 2018 BCSC 857</cite.query>, at paras. 13–14, and 17–18.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id846c6028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>68</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00090" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a734408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity Corp.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1309, 2018 BCSC 857</cite.query>, at paras. 19–20.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id846c6038e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>69</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00091" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a75b508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity Corp.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1309, 2018 BCSC 857</cite.query>, at paras. 21 and 23.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id846c6048e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>70</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00092" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a782608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity Corp.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1309, 2018 BCSC 857</cite.query>, at paras. 25–29.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id846c6058e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>71</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00093" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a7d0808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity Corp.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1309, 2018 BCSC 857</cite.query>, at paras. 34–35, and 37.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id846c6068e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>72</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00094" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a7f7908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity Corp.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1309, 2018 BCSC 857</cite.query>, at paras. 44–45.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id846ed108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>73</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00095" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a81ea08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity Corp.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1309, 2018 BCSC 857, at para. 48</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id846ed118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>74</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00096" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a81ea38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity Corp.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1309, 2018 BCSC 857, at para. 49</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id846ed128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>75</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00097" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a845b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity Corp.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1309, 2018 BCSC 857, at para. 51</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id846ed138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>76</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00098" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a86cc08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity Corp.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1309, 2018 BCSC 857, at para. 53</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id846ed148e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>77</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00099" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a893d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity Corp.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1309, 2018 BCSC 857</cite.query>, at paras. 54–55.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id846ed158e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>78</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00100" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a8bae08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity Corp.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1309, 2018 BCSC 857, at para. 56</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id846ed168e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>79</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00101" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044476992" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a8e1f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Quick Pass Master Tutorial School Ltd. v. Zhao</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1038, 2018 BCSC 683</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84714208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>80</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00102" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044476992" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a909008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Quick Pass Master Tutorial School Ltd. v. Zhao</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1038, 2018 BCSC 683</cite.query>, at paras. 1 and 3.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84714218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>81</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00103" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044476992" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a930108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Quick Pass Master Tutorial School Ltd. v. Zhao</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1038, 2018 BCSC 683, at para. 5</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84714228e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>82</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00104" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044476992" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a957208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Quick Pass Master Tutorial School Ltd. v. Zhao</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1038, 2018 BCSC 683, at para. 25</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84714238e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>83</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00105" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044476992" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a97e308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Quick Pass Master Tutorial School Ltd. v. Zhao</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1038, 2018 BCSC 683, at para. 30</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84714248e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>84</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00106" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044476992" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63a9a5408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Quick Pass Master Tutorial School Ltd. v. Zhao</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1038, 2018 BCSC 683, at para. 31</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84714258e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>85</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00107" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038788031" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I63a9cc508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Claim Analytics Inc. v. Polon</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 6964, 2016 ONSC 2235</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00108" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039236900" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I63a9cc538e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 10206, 2016 ONSC 3800</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84714268e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>86</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00109" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038788031" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I63a9f3608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Claim Analytics Inc. v. Polon</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 6964, 2016 ONSC 2235</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00110" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039236900" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I63a9f3638e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 10206, 2016 ONSC 3800, at para. 1</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84714278e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>87</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00111" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038788031" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I63aa1a708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Claim Analytics Inc. v. Polon</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 6964, 2016 ONSC 2235</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00112" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039236900" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I63aa1a738e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 10206, 2016 ONSC 3800</cite.query>, at paras. 2, 4, and 6.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8473b308e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>88</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00113" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038788031" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I63aa68908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Claim Analytics Inc. v. Polon</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 6964, 2016 ONSC 2235</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00114" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039236900" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I63aa68938e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 10206, 2016 ONSC 3800</cite.query>, at paras. 7–11.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8473b318e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>89</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00115" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038788031" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I63aa8fa08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Claim Analytics Inc. v. Polon</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 6964, 2016 ONSC 2235</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00116" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039236900" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I63aa8fa38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 10206, 2016 ONSC 3800, at para. 15</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8473b328e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>90</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00117" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038788031" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I63aaddc08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Claim Analytics Inc. v. Polon</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 6964, 2016 ONSC 2235</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00118" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039236900" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I63aaddc38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 10206, 2016 ONSC 3800</cite.query>, at paras. 16–17.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8473b338e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>91</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00119" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038788031" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I63ab04d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Claim Analytics Inc. v. Polon</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 6964, 2016 ONSC 2235</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00120" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039236900" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I63ab04d38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 10206, 2016 ONSC 3800</cite.query>, at paras. 21–24.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8473b348e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>92</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00121" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037953884" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63ab2be08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cambridge Mercantile Corp. v. Cook</ital>, 2016 CarswellBC 11, 2016 BCSC 11</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8473b358e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>93</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00122" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037953884" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63ab52f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cambridge Mercantile Corp. v. Cook</ital>, 2016 CarswellBC 11, 2016 BCSC 11, at para. 1</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8473b368e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>94</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00123" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037953884" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63ab7a008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cambridge Mercantile Corp. v. Cook</ital>, 2016 CarswellBC 11, 2016 BCSC 11</cite.query>, at paras. 2–8.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84762408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>95</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00124" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037953884" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63aba1108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cambridge Mercantile Corp. v. Cook</ital>, 2016 CarswellBC 11, 2016 BCSC 11</cite.query>, at paras. 14–15.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84762418e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>96</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00125" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037953884" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63abef308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cambridge Mercantile Corp. v. Cook</ital>, 2016 CarswellBC 11, 2016 BCSC 11</cite.query>, at paras. 16–18, and 21.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84789508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>97</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00126" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037953884" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63ac16408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cambridge Mercantile Corp. v. Cook</ital>, 2016 CarswellBC 11, 2016 BCSC 11</cite.query>, at paras. 27–29, and 32.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84789518e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>98</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00127" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2033737736" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I63ac3d508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Enviro Trace Ltd. v. Sheichuk</ital>, 2014 CarswellAlta 1073, 2014 ABQB 381</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00128" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035261741" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I63ac3d538e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2015 CarswellAlta 35, 2015 ABQB 28</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84789528e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>99</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00129" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2033737736" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I63ac64608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Enviro Trace Ltd. v. Sheichuk</ital>, 2014 CarswellAlta 1073, 2014 ABQB 381</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00130" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035261741" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I63ac64638e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2015 CarswellAlta 35, 2015 ABQB 28</cite.query>, at paras. 1, 3–7, and 26–27.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84789538e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>100</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00131" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2033737736" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I63acb2808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Enviro Trace Ltd. v. Sheichuk</ital>, 2014 CarswellAlta 1073, 2014 ABQB 381</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00132" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035261741" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I63acb2838e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2015 CarswellAlta 35, 2015 ABQB 28</cite.query>, at paras. 14, 18, 22 and 24.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84789548e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>101</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00133" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2033737736" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I63ad00a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Enviro Trace Ltd. v. Sheichuk</ital>, 2014 CarswellAlta 1073, 2014 ABQB 381</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00134" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035261741" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I63ad00a38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2015 CarswellAlta 35, 2015 ABQB 28</cite.query>, at paras. 28–29.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84789558e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>102</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00135" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2030681325" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63ad27b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>RBC Dominion Securities Inc. v. Macdonald</ital>, 2013 CarswellBC 1669, 2013 BCSC 992</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id84789568e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>103</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00136" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2030681325" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63ad4ec08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>RBC Dominion Securities Inc. v. Macdonald</ital>, 2013 CarswellBC 1669, 2013 BCSC 992</cite.query>, at paras. 1–2 and 4.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id847b0608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>104</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175957" w-seq-number="00137" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2030681325" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I63ad9ce08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>RBC Dominion Securities Inc. v. Macdonald</ital>, 2013 CarswellBC 1669, 2013 BCSC 992</cite.query>, at paras. 48–51.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 7:4<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
