<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 7:8<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I56d26460411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>7.</label.designator><headtext>Remedies for Breach of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I56dbb330411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>II.</label.designator><headtext>Equitable Relief</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I56dc0150411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>A.</label.designator><headtext>Interim and Interlocutory Injunctions</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f722876ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>7:8.</label.designator><headtext>Related Relief</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Progressive Conservative Party of Ontario v. Karahlios</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id87f3b208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>] the applicant political party sought an interlocutory injunction. <eos/><bos/>In its application, the Party sought a declaration that the respondents unlawfully used the Party&apos;s confidential membership list, a tracing order and disgorgement of the respondent&apos;s earnings from the misappropriation of the confidential information; and an interim injunction preventing the respondents from using address information obtained through their work on behalf of the Party or any of its associations, candidates, or leadership campaigns derived from data in the Party&apos;s confidential membership registry or other confidential membership list, in order to contact Party members or former members. <eos/><bos/>The respondents resisted the motion for an injunction and sought an order dismissing the application on the basis that the application arose from communications relating to matters of public interest. <eos/><bos/>Justice Perell granted the respondents&apos; motion and dismissed the Party&apos;s action.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id87f3b218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>PC Ontario maintained a registry of its members in an electronic database. <eos/><bos/>The registry contains personal contact information. <eos/><bos/>The registry is governed by Article 8 of the PC Ontario Constitution. <eos/><bos/>Article 8.8(j) of the Constitution authorizes the executive to make rules governing the use of the registry. <eos/><bos/>Section 8.7 of the Constitution states: <begin.quote ID="QT_0003"/>“As a confidential asset of the Party, the Registry shall not be sold or made available to any person or organization outside of the Party.”<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0003"/> The information in the Registry was compiled from the personal information of members as part of their membership applications. <eos/><bos/>The Party periodically updates the information, using, among other things, membership renewal applications, address change notifications, contribution solicitations, convention and event registrations, and voting registrations at Party meetings, nominations, and policy conferences. <eos/><bos/>Section 1.7 of the Membership Registry Rules states that a purpose of the registry is: <begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>“To protect the confidentiality of data of members listed on the Registry, and to ensure that the Registry is used only for Party purposes, and not for any other or improper purpose…”<end.quote refid="QT_0001"/> Section 11 states: <begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>“The Registry, and any portion thereof, may not be used or disclosed for any other purpose without the prior written approval of the Party Executive.”<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0002"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id87f3b228e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">3</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The respondent Karahalios was formerly a member of PC Ontario. <eos/><bos/>He was a political activist involved in provincial and federal politics. <eos/><bos/>He was the organizer of “Axe the Carbon Tax,” which was a non-profit political national lobbying organization. <eos/><bos/>Karahalios&apos;s involvement in politics began in 2005, when he volunteered to help the federal PC party in organizing riding associations. <eos/><bos/>In the years that followed, Karahalios ran nomination and general election campaigns, served as president of riding associations, volunteered on leadership campaigns, fundraised, and served on a candidate identification committee. <eos/><bos/>In 2014–2015, there was a campaign to elect a new leader of PC Ontario, and Karahalios volunteered to campaign for McNaughton. <eos/><bos/>With respect to the leadership race, Karahalios signed a Confidentiality Agreement. <eos/><bos/>After the leadership race was over, Karahalios continued his activities as a member of the Party, but in early 2017, he decided not to run for the nomination for Cambridge riding because he did not support Brown&apos;s leadership, and instead Karahalios established the national political campaign “Axe the Carbon Tax.” <eos/><bos/>In late May 2017, Karahalios and Axe the Carbon Tax sent an email in which he argued that Brown was supporting a carbon tax similar to that proposed by the Liberal Party of Canada.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8809ab08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">4</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>PC Ontario alleged that in sending the email, Karahalios unlawfully used a mailing list that he had obtained because of his involvement in the 2015 leadership race. <eos/><bos/>On November 7, 2017, Karahalios sent a mailer from Axe the Carbon Tax, in which he argued that the Party executive had failed to abide by the Party Constitution&apos;s requirement for a properly constituted policy conference. <eos/><bos/>He submitted that the executive was deliberating evading pushback against Brown&apos;s carbon tax policy. <eos/><bos/>On November 8, 2017, Karahalios sent a mailer from Take Back our PC Party, and he argued that Brown and the Executive had usurped essential democratic processes as mandated by the Party Constitution and had deceived Party members as to PwC&apos;s role at nomination meetings. <eos/><bos/>The Party submitted that it did not give its prior written approval to Karahalios, Axe the Carbon Tax or Take Back Our PC Party, to disclose any part of the confidential membership list or to use the information for the purpose of communicating with members by email or letter in respect of the matters contained in the May 2017 email or the November 2017 letter from Karahalios. <eos/><bos/>Karahalios acknowledged having the list provided for the 2015 leadership race, but denied that he used that list to compile his Nation Builder list. <eos/><bos/>He admitted that he had received Party membership lists from others that may have contained information that the others had taken from the Party&apos;s registry and that information from those lists may have added to his own database.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8809ab18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">5</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Sections 137.1 to 137.5 of the <ital>Courts of Justice Act</ital>, Ontario&apos;s version of an anti-SLAPP statute are designed to discourage the use of litigation as a means of unduly limiting expression on matters of public interest. <eos/><bos/>Under the anti-SLAPP statute, a defendant or respondent may bring a motion to have a proceeding dismissed, if the court is satisfied that the proceeding arises from an expression made by the defendant or respondent that relates to a matter of public interest. <eos/><bos/>The anti-SLAPP provisions provide that on motion by a person against whom a proceeding is brought, a judge shall dismiss the proceeding against the person if the person satisfies the judge that the proceeding arises from an expression made by the person that relates to a matter of public interest. <eos/><bos/>On a motion under the anti-SLAPP provisions, the moving party bears the initial onus of satisfying the court that the other party&apos;s proceeding arises from an expression made by the moving party that relates to a matter of public interest. <eos/><bos/>Karahalios met the onus of showing that the proceeding against the respondents arose from an expression by him that related to a matter of public interest.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id880c1c08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">6</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Perell did not agree that the Party&apos;s application was about the manner or means used by the respondents to express their views, which the Party alleged was an unlawful means. <eos/><bos/>The facts revealed that at its heart or essence, the Party&apos;s application was designed to discourage the respondents from expressing themselves on matters of public interest and to discourage participation in debates on matters of public interest. <eos/><bos/>The application used litigation as a means of limiting expression on matters of public interest. <eos/><bos/>The respondents met the onus of showing a communication on a matter of public interest.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id880c1c18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">7</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>If the moving party meets the onus of showing a communication on a matter of public interest, under the anti-SLAPP provisions, the onus of proof shifts to the other party, and his or her proceeding will be dismissed, unless it is shown that: (1) the proceeding has substantial merit, (2) the moving party has no valid defence in the proceeding, and (3) the harm likely to be or have been suffered by the other party as a result of the moving party&apos;s expression is sufficiently serious that the public interest in permitting the proceeding to continue outweighs the public interest in protecting that expression. <eos/><bos/>The anti-SLAPP provisions do not dismiss claims simply because their subject matter is one of public interest, but rather scrutinizes such claims and imposes a burden on the plaintiff to show more than that the claim is not frivolous or vexatious, and rather the plaintiff must show there are reasonable grounds to believe that the proceeding has substantial merit and that the defendant has no valid defence to the proceeding.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id880c1c28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">8</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Perell concluded that, giving the Party the benefit of the doubt and assuming that the breach of contract and breach of confidence claims had substantial merit, the Party had not met the onus of showing that Karahalios had no valid defence to these claims. <eos/><bos/>Rather, it appeared that he had reasonably strong factual and legal defences. <eos/><bos/>It was reasonably arguable that the information alleged to have been misappropriated from the leadership race list was not confidential, and it was reasonably arguable that the information was not imparted in circumstances with an obligation of confidentiality. <eos/><bos/>The Party members would have anticipated that the information was for the private use of the Party and its members but that is different than imparting some aura of confidentiality. <eos/><bos/>The address information was meant to be used much in the way that Karaholios used it for the purposes of debate within the party. <eos/><bos/>In any event, it was reasonably arguable that Karahalios did not disclose any confidential information but rather gathered his own information from non-confidential sources, some of which were in the public domain. <eos/><bos/>For similar reasons, it was reasonably arguable that he did not breach the Constitution of the Party with respect to the use of information found in the registry. <eos/><bos/>Assuming that the information was confidential, which was debatable, and that Karahalios used the information without the permission of the Party executive, it was reasonably arguable that he did not misuse the information. <eos/><bos/>Karahalios did not sell the information for commercial purposes and he did not use it for personal gain. <eos/><bos/>He used the information for purposes for which it was intended; i.e., in order to communicate with Party members about the Party&apos;s policies, politics, and governance. <eos/><bos/>Justice Perell therefore concluded that the Party had not met the onus of showing that Karahalios had no valid defence to the claims.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id880c1c38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">9</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A motion by the plaintiff for an interim injunction and forensic inspection was dismissed in <ital>Altus Group Ltd. v. Yeoman</ital>.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id880c1c48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">10</footnote.reference>] Altus alleged that a former employee copied highly confidential and sensitive files and documents onto a USB key weeks before he resigned his employment and weeks after he was asked by a co-worker whether he had copied all of his files.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id880c1c58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">11</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The court was not prepared to grant the order sought by Altus. <eos/><bos/>At this point, there was no evidence that Tom inappropriately copied highly confidential and sensitive files and documents onto the USB device. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence that Tom had taken confidential information belonging to Altus. <eos/><bos/>He admitted that he used a USB device while working at Altus, but there was no evidence that he had any confidential or proprietary information of Altus in his possession. <eos/><bos/>Tom deposed that the USB device referred to was used to copy his personal files prior to the end of his employment with Altus. <eos/><bos/>He stated that these personal files included educational materials for completed and ongoing courses he was taking, and some tax impact information that he copied for a meeting with Hydro One. <eos/><bos/>This meeting was scheduled to take place while he was still employed by Altus. <eos/><bos/>He also indicated that the information that he copied to the key for the meeting with Hydro One had previously been forwarded to clients and peers in the industry when requested. <eos/><bos/>This extraordinary remedy did not appear to be justified.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id880c1c68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">12</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Id87f3b208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175961" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043459965" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6a41b9b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Progressive Conservative Party of Ontario v. Karahlios</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 20501, 2017 ONSC 7696, 287 A.C.W.S. (3d) 146 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id87f3b218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175961" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043459965" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6a464d908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Progressive Conservative Party of Ontario v. Karahlios</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 20501, 2017 ONSC 7696, 287 A.C.W.S. (3d) 146 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 1–3.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id87f3b228e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175961" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043459965" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6a469bb08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Progressive Conservative Party of Ontario v. Karahlios</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 20501, 2017 ONSC 7696, 287 A.C.W.S. (3d) 146 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 6–8.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8809ab08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>4</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175961" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043459965" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6a46c2c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Progressive Conservative Party of Ontario v. Karahlios</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 20501, 2017 ONSC 7696, 287 A.C.W.S. (3d) 146 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 9, 11–12, 15, and 17.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8809ab18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>5</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175961" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043459965" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6a46e9d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Progressive Conservative Party of Ontario v. Karahlios</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 20501, 2017 ONSC 7696, 287 A.C.W.S. (3d) 146 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 18 23, 29, and 33.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id880c1c08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>6</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175961" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043459965" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6a4710e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Progressive Conservative Party of Ontario v. Karahlios</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 20501, 2017 ONSC 7696, 287 A.C.W.S. (3d) 146 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 35, and 38–39.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id880c1c18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>7</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175961" w-seq-number="00007" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043459965" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6a475f008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Progressive Conservative Party of Ontario v. Karahlios</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 20501, 2017 ONSC 7696, 287 A.C.W.S. (3d) 146 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 46–47.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id880c1c28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>8</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175961" w-seq-number="00008" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043459965" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6a4786108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Progressive Conservative Party of Ontario v. Karahlios</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 20501, 2017 ONSC 7696, 287 A.C.W.S. (3d) 146 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paragraph 48.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id880c1c38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>9</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175961" w-seq-number="00009" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043459965" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6a47ad208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Progressive Conservative Party of Ontario v. Karahlios</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 20501, 2017 ONSC 7696, 287 A.C.W.S. (3d) 146 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 55, and 61–63.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id880c1c48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>10</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175961" w-seq-number="00010" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028350994" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6a47d4308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Altus Group Ltd. v. Yeoman</ital>, 2012 CarswellOnt 9503, 2012 ONSC 4406</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id880c1c58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>11</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175961" w-seq-number="00011" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028350994" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6a4822508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Altus Group Ltd. v. Yeoman</ital>, 2012 CarswellOnt 9503, 2012 ONSC 4406</cite.query>, at paras. 44–45.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id880c1c68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>12</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175961" w-seq-number="00012" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028350994" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6a4849608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Altus Group Ltd. v. Yeoman</ital>, 2012 CarswellOnt 9503, 2012 ONSC 4406</cite.query>, at paras. 48–49 and 54.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 7:8<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
