<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 4:44<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I5089a870411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>4.</label.designator><headtext>Confidential Business Information and the Employment Relationship</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I52517020411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>V.</label.designator><headtext>Fiduciary Duty</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I53a16fc0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>B.</label.designator><headtext>Remedies Table—Employment Relationship—Breach of Fiduciary Duty</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f65f5b6ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>4:44.</label.designator><headtext>Canadian Premier Life Insurance Co. v. Ho</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><ital>Canadian Premier Life Insurance Co. v. Ho</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 652, 2016 ONSC 496</headtext><eos/><eop/></head><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Award</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Order as follows: a. The plaintiff is entitled to judgment in the amount of $866,498.52 plus prejudgment interest as asked; b. The plaintiff is entitled to an award of punitive damages in the amount of $50,000 (not subject to prejudgment interest); c. All amounts held in the three accounts: at Branch of CIBC (estimated $263,478.41), at Branch 06232 of CIBC (estimated $2,194.56); and at Branch 1923 of TD (estimated $12,502.66) are declared to be proceeds of the defendant&apos;s fraud upon the plaintiff and are forthwith vested in the plaintiff as beneficial owner thereof notwithstanding the existing Mareva orders (and, upon receipt, shall reduce the indebtedness of the defendant under the judgment to the extent of payments received); d. The plaintiff is entitled to a vesting order and immediate possession of the 2014 Audi Automobile registered in the plaintiff&apos;s name the net proceeds of the eventual sale of which shall be credited towards the judgment; e. The plaintiff shall be entitled to move, upon further evidence, for a declaration that the Investia RRSP account is proceeds of the defendant&apos;s fraud upon the plaintiff and that the plaintiff is entitled to an order vesting such assets in its name as beneficial owner thereof; f. No order shall be made under s. 178(1) of the BIA; g. The Mareva injunctions made herein are continued and extended until February 29, 2016 (subject to the orders transferring proceeds made herein) without prejudice to the plaintiff&apos;s right to seek the appointment of a receiver or further orders in aid of execution; and h. The plaintiff is entitled to full indemnity costs of this action which I fix at $110,761.00.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Summary of Facts:</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>This was a motion for default judgment and ancillary relief arising from a fraud perpetrated by the defendant over a period of over two years. <eos/><bos/>While an employee claims adjuster of the plaintiff, the defendant fraudulently processed insurance claims payable to himself, via a thinly disguised pseudonym, in increments just within his claims authority with the result that $866,498.52 was fraudulently paid to him.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The defendant was engaged by the plaintiff Canadian Premier Life Insurance Company as a claims examiner in May 2009 and he continued in that capacity until he was dismissed for cause on October 13, 2015. <eos/><bos/>CPLIC was in the business of providing insurance products for credit cards. <eos/><bos/>Canadian Imperial Bank of Commerce entered into a group credit insurance policy with the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>The policy permitted the bank to offer to holders of the Bank&apos;s credit card products insurance in respect of critical illness, disability or unemployment. <eos/><bos/>Beginning in May, 2013 the defendant began processing claims for a claimant known as Chong Z. Ho having a date of birth of September 9, 1986. <eos/><bos/>The pseudonym used to process these claims amounted to little more than dropping his first name and using a different birthdate.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The disguise was a thin one but it served the intended purpose well enough for a while. <eos/><bos/>The defendant&apos;s claims payable to himself eluded immediate detection by his employer while enabling him to receive and deal with the proceeds of his fraud at financial accounts established in his own name. <eos/><bos/>While initiating the scheme with a claim in respect of a single alleged case of cancer, the scheme evolved quickly into one of making almost weekly claims for unemployment benefits in the amount of $9,000 under ever-changing claim numbers. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff&apos;s investigation revealed a total of $866,498.52 in claims paid in this fashion between June 3, 2013 and September 23, 2013. <eos/><bos/>A total of 100 separate payments were made under 49 different claim numbers. <eos/><bos/>All of the payments were made to the same CIBC Dividend Visa account of the defendant. <eos/><bos/>While the plaintiff&apos;s internal auditors may not have been the fleetest of foot in this case, they did eventually tumble to this scheme. <eos/><bos/>A claims examiner flagged as suspicious the original payment made in respect of cancer claim and one of the 48 unemployment claims due to the lack of appropriate documentation in the file. <eos/><bos/>These two irregularities initially discovered led to a more general review of the defendant&apos;s activities.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Reasons Given by Court for Award:</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff established its claim to the liquidated sum claimed of $866,498.52 and established that certain identified assets were indeed proceeds of the fraud of which the plaintiff was victim. <eos/><bos/>This was also an appropriate case to award punitive damages of $50,000.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The evidence supported the damages as claimed in the Statement of Claim being $866,498.52. <eos/><bos/>The defendant misused his position of trust as an employee of the plaintiff and authorized these payments to himself in furtherance of his fraudulent scheme. <eos/><bos/>He had no lawful authority to do so and breached his duties to his employer in so doing. <eos/><bos/>As regards the exercise by him of the discretionary settlement vested in him by the plaintiff, the defendant exercised the powers of a fiduciary of his employer even if his relatively low employment status might not have qualified him as a fiduciary in other regards. <eos/><bos/>By exercising that authority to accept and direct payment of his own fraudulent claims, the defendant was in breach of those fiduciary duties. <eos/><bos/>This scheme amounted to theft pure and simple.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff was entitled to judgment in the claimed amount of $866,498.52.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>An award of punitive damages in the amount of $50,000 was appropriate. <eos/><bos/>The defendant&apos;s actions amounted to a gross abuse of the trust vested in him by his employer and called out for a clear statement of condemnation that would serve the dual purposes of punishing and deterring.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></section.body></section><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 4:44<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
