<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 2:16<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I4e5fc390411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>2.</label.designator><headtext>Legal Bases Used by the Courts for the Protection of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I4ecd0450411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>VI.</label.designator><headtext>Conclusion</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f5ea0d6ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>2:16.</label.designator><headtext>Generally</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The basis of the right to confidential business information may be characterized in many different ways, including either as a property right in the information itself, a duty of good faith, an agreement between two contracting parties, or an independent wrong based on the recognition by society of the inherent value of protecting confidential business information. <eos/><bos/>The method of protecting confidential information has become increasingly important as information has become the greatest source of wealth in the 20th century.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The conceptualization of confidential business information as property would make it easier to resolve problems regarding sales and licences, to use both criminal and civil sanctions to protect information from espionage and theft, and to fit information into existing taxation schemes.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id18d46e08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>On the other hand, a new body of law or a statute created specifically to govern confidential information could include the necessary incentives to create new ideas by upholding business ethics and prohibiting the wrongful use of confidential information, while allowing for the dissemination of new ideas for the benefit of society as a whole when it is in the public interest to do so. <eos/><bos/>There would be no requirement to remain within the confines of existing bodies of law.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id18d46e18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Id18d46e08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>S. Cheung, “Property Rights and Trade Secrets”, <ital>Economic Inquiry</ital>, vol. xx (January 1982).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id18d46e18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175831" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1977023749" w-pub-number="0004651" ID="I155c7ac08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>United Scientific Holdings Ltd. v. Burnley Borough Council</ital>, [1978] A.C. 904 (H.L.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 2:16<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
