<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 4:52<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I5089a870411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>4.</label.designator><headtext>Confidential Business Information and the Employment Relationship</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I52517020411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>V.</label.designator><headtext>Fiduciary Duty</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I53a16fc0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>B.</label.designator><headtext>Remedies Table—Employment Relationship—Breach of Fiduciary Duty</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f686516ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>4:52.</label.designator><headtext>Beyer-Brown &amp; Associates Ltd. v. S &amp; R Interiors Ltd.</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><ital>Beyer-Brown &amp; Associates Ltd. v. S &amp; R Interiors Ltd</ital>., 2007 CarswellBC 522, 2007 BCSC 327</headtext><eos/><eop/></head><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Award</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Judgment awarded against Mason in the amount of $105,000 plus interest, which was the amount of the profit he enjoyed.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Judgment awarded against S &amp; R in the amount of $139,868 plus interest, this being the remaining balance of the profit for which it was responsible as a constructive trustee</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Summary of Facts:</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>For 16 years, the Defendant Mason was employed by the Plaintiff as a commission salesman in the wholesale furniture supply business. <eos/><bos/>Throughout this employment, Mason secured and serviced furniture supply contracts for Canadian Citizenship and Immigration. <eos/><bos/>In 2004, while still in the Plaintiff&apos;s employ, Mason failed to notify the Plaintiff that he would not be tendering a bid on its behalf for the upcoming CIC contract in time for the Plaintiff to tender a bid of its own. <eos/><bos/>Rather, Mason tendered a bid on behalf of the Defendant, S &amp; R, a company in which he had recently acquired a 50% interest. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiff did not become aware that Mason failed to tender a bid for the CIC contract on its behalf until after he had left its employ to join S &amp; R. At that time, it was too late for the Plaintiff to submit a bid of its own. <eos/><bos/>S &amp; R was subsequently awarded the CIC contract. <eos/><bos/>It was the only bid tendered. <eos/><bos/>S &amp; R fulfilled the terms of this contract. <eos/><bos/>From this CIC contract, S &amp; R derived a gross profit of $346,738. <eos/><bos/>From these gross profits, S &amp; R paid $105,000 to Mason for management fees; $129,299 to a principal of S &amp; R and the other 50% shareholder for management fees; and $101,870 for overhead and operating costs. <eos/><bos/>The remaining $10,569 was designated as profits. <eos/><bos/>S &amp; R was no longer in business and had declared bankruptcy.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Reasons Given by Court for Award:</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Mason&apos;s tortious conduct was his failure to provide the Plaintiff with sufficient notice that he would not be tendering a bid on its behalf in time for the Plaintiff to tender a bid of its own. <eos/><bos/>As a result of the pattern of behaviour, the Plaintiff came to rely upon Mason to tender this bid for it. <eos/><bos/>This pattern of reliance on the Plaintiff&apos;s part gave rise to a corresponding obligation on Mason&apos;s part to notify the Plaintiff if he was not going to do the task for which it was relying upon him. <eos/><bos/>That notification had to be made in sufficient time to provide the Plaintiff with the opportunity to tender a bid on its own behalf. <eos/><bos/>A fiduciary relationship existed between Mason and the Plaintiff with respect to tendering the CIC bid on its behalf. <eos/><bos/>For the 16 years he was employed by the Plaintiff, Mason acted as its agent with respect to the CIC contract. <eos/><bos/>That is, he had scope for the exercise of some discretion or power because he had assumed the responsibility of preparing and tendering the Plaintiff&apos;s bid for the CIC contract throughout. <eos/><bos/>He could unilaterally exercise that power or discretion so as to affect the Plaintiff&apos;s practical interests because the Plaintiff left it up to him to tender its bid. <eos/><bos/>That is, the Plaintiff did not check with Mason each time to ensure that he was preparing its bid. <eos/><bos/>Lastly, because the Plaintiff relied on Mason to tender its bid, it was vulnerable to, or at the mercy of Mason. <eos/><bos/>If he failed to notify the Plaintiff that he was not tendering a bid on its behalf, the Plaintiff would be unaware of that fact and would lose the opportunity to submit a bid of its own. <eos/><bos/>Though tendering a competing bid while still employed may be a breach of contract rather than a breach of fiduciary duty, in the circumstances, it was appropriate to consider it as being incidental to the breach of the fiduciary duty. <eos/><bos/>That is, the conduct that resulted in the greatest harm to the Plaintiff was the loss of the opportunity to bid on the CIC contract.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>As far as the measure of damages is concerned, generally speaking the measure of damages for the breach of a fiduciary obligation are the profits resulting from that breach. <eos/><bos/>The policy underlying this principle is that the law of fiduciary duty has always contained within it an element of deterrence. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, this remedy does not depend on any proof that the claimant suffered any loss. <eos/><bos/>It is of no consequence that the party seeking redress could not its/her/himself have taken advantage of the benefit “improperly” gained. <eos/><bos/>However, if the profits enjoyed by the defendant are less than the losses proven by the plaintiff, for reasons of fairness the Court will order restitution rather than a disgorgement of profits. <eos/><bos/>In other words, if the disgorgement of profits is an inadequate remedy (because the plaintiff has proven that their losses are greater than the defendant&apos;s ill-gotten profits), the measure of damages is the loss proven by the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>It is only in cases in which the plaintiff&apos;s proven losses are greater than the defendant&apos;s profits that the Court will adopt a <begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>“but for the breach of the fiduciary duty”<end.quote refid="QT_0002"/> analysis and award damages commensurate with the plaintiff&apos;s proven loss. <eos/><bos/>Otherwise, the measure of damages is the defendant&apos;s profits. <eos/><bos/>The court was satisfied that the plaintiff&apos;s loss would have been considerably less than the profits enjoyed by the Defendants. <eos/><bos/>The <begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>“but for the breach of the fiduciary obligation”<end.quote refid="QT_0001"/> analysis results in very modest damages to the Plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>That is, if Mason had provided the Plaintiff with sufficient notice, it is very unlikely that the Plaintiff would have been awarded the bid. <eos/><bos/>The likelihood of the Plaintiff securing the CIC contract was no greater than 10%. <eos/><bos/>The “but for” analysis results in a loss to the Plaintiff in the range of $17,500-$20,000. <eos/><bos/>The profit analysis for the measure of damages, on the other hand, results in a substantially larger award. <eos/><bos/>The profit of the Defendants was $244,868. <eos/><bos/>This is the balance remaining after the deduction of operating/overhead expenses, excluding the $234,299 in management fees paid to Mason and Sehmbey.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></section.body></section><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 4:52<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
