<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 4:47<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I5089a870411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>4.</label.designator><headtext>Confidential Business Information and the Employment Relationship</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I52517020411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>V.</label.designator><headtext>Fiduciary Duty</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I53a16fc0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>B.</label.designator><headtext>Remedies Table—Employment Relationship—Breach of Fiduciary Duty</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f686426ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>4:47.</label.designator><headtext>Frydman v. Pelletier</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><ital>Frydman v. Pelletier</ital>, 2015 CarswellAlta 819, 2015 ABQB 289</headtext><eos/><eop/></head><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Award</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Plaintiffs were entitled to the following damages: (a) The amount of $1,392,000 based on funds which were credited to the Vialta Loan. (b) The amount of $128,000 based on funds which were credited to the PCR Credit. (c) The amount of $14,153.82 which was duplicate payment for reimbursable cash expenses already paid by Aries. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiffs were granted a judgment against the Defendant Pelletier for: $1,455,693.82 plus prejudgment interest</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Summary of Facts:</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Plaintiffs alleged that the Defendants wrongfully and fraudulently converted the Plaintiffs&apos; funds to their own use and benefit through a series of inter-related fraudulent activities. <eos/><bos/>Pelletier was the son-in-law of Frydman. <eos/><bos/>He had been involved for about 40 years in businesses owned primarily by Frydman. <eos/><bos/>PCR was owned 20 percent by Frydman, 50 percent by Davonne Establishment, and, 30 percent by Janden Trust, which was owned and controlled by Frydman. <eos/><bos/>Pelletier was the sole shareholder of Baythorne. <eos/><bos/>Pelletier incorporated Baythorne for the purpose of managing his investments. <eos/><bos/>The facts of the alleged fraudulent scheme perpetrated by Pelletier were as follows: 1. In May 1998, Pelletier orchestrated a land transfer for PCR as a result of which a shareholder loan of $1,392,000 was credited to him by Vialta and a credit of $128,000 was created for him by PCR. The Vialta Loan and the PCR Credit resulted from the transfer of funds from Frydman through Pelletier to PCR and were credits beneficially belonging to Frydman, not Pelletier. 2. In 1994, PCR recorded an advance/loan alleged to have been received from Baythorne on March 13, 1991, in the amount of $500,000, for which in fact Baythorne never advanced monies. <eos/><bos/>Baythorne was directly paid $169,128 in purported reimbursement of this loan. <eos/><bos/>Pelletier also charged $295,395 in personal expenses against the Baythorne Credit. 3. From 1995 to 2010, Pelletier charged personal expenses to PCR and took money from PCR in the form of cash and credit card cash advances. <eos/><bos/>Amounts were properly recorded as due from Pelletier, but then were offset annually against a “Due to Pelletier” account in PCR, and a “Due To Shareholders” account in Vialta, resulting in $2,238,705 of his personal expenses being paid by the Plaintiffs. 4. Between 2004 and 2011, Pelletier obtained duplicate reimbursement for expenses totalling approximately $25,289.61</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Reasons Given by Court for Award:</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge observed that Courts have cautioned against finding ordinary employees as subject to such a continuing duty. <eos/><bos/>Although courts are sometimes reluctant to impose fiduciary obligations in a commercial setting, a “peculiar vulnerability” could be established. <eos/><bos/>By virtue of Pelletier&apos;s position with the plaintiff&apos;s companies, Pelletier owed a fiduciary duty to safeguard the interests of the Plaintiff companies. <eos/><bos/>He was in a senior position and he exploited this position for his own benefit. <eos/><bos/>The evidence illustrated that Pelletier had direction over the activities of the plaintiff&apos;s companies in Canada and he used this position for his own gain an advantage. <eos/><bos/>Although the transactions were all recorded, the scheme was elaborate and was difficult even for trained accountants to detect.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>While the trial judge concluded that the Defendant in breach of a fiduciary duty, this was not a situation where a constructive trust should be imposed. <eos/><bos/>The remedy of constructive trust is discretionary. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiffs had not shown a legitimate reason for seeking this remedy. <eos/><bos/>A monetary award alone was a satisfactory and appropriate remedy for the losses that have been suffered by the Plaintiffs. <eos/><bos/>Therefore, the Plaintiffs were entitled to the following damages: (a) The amount of $1,392,000 based on funds which were credited to the Vialta Loan. (b) The amount of $128,000 based on funds which were credited to the PCR Credit. (c) The amount of $14,153.82 which was duplicate payment for reimbursable cash expenses already paid by Aries. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiffs were granted a judgment against the Defendant Pelletier for: $1,455,693.82 plus prejudgment interest.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></section.body></section><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 4:47<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
