<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 6:6<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I55e174b0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>6.</label.designator><headtext>Defences to Claims for Breach of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I560c0720411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>III.</label.designator><headtext>Person Suing Must be Someone to Whom a Duty of Confidence is Owed)</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f6d47c6ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>6:6.</label.designator><headtext>Generally</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Fraser v. Evans</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id79d8db08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>] the plaintiff prepared a confidential report for the Greek government. <eos/><bos/>A copy of the report was leaked to a newspaper, and the plaintiff sought an injunction to prevent publication or use of its contents. <eos/><bos/>The court held that the plaintiff had no standing to complain. <eos/><bos/>Lord Denning held that:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>The jurisdiction is based not so much on property or on contract as on the duty to be of good faith … But the party complaining must be the person who is entitled to the confidence and to have it respected. <eos/><bos/>He must be a person to whom the duty of good faith is owed … There is no doubt that Mr. Fraser himself was under an obligation of confidence to the Greek Government … The Greek Government entered into no contract with Mr. Fraser to keep it secret … They were the people to say aye or no whether it should be communicated elsewhere, or be published generally. <eos/><bos/>It follows that they alone have any standing to complain if anyone obtains the information surreptitiously or proposes to publish it.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0001"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id79d8db18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In the Australian decision of <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="U4" w-serial-number="1982167114" w-pub-number="0005542" ID="I53f6f0318e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Moorgate Tobacco Co. v. Philip Morris</cite.query> Ltd.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id79d8db28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">3</footnote.reference>] Hope J. of the Supreme Court of New South Wales held that the assignor of confidential information cannot pass to the assignee a personal right to have the information treated as confidential. <eos/><bos/>Therefore the assignee cannot sue to enforce a duty of confidence, but has, at most, a right to compel the assignor to take action.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In the British case of <ital>Morison v. Moat</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id79d8db38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">4</footnote.reference>] Turner V.C. stressed that <begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>“what we have to deal with here is, not the right of the Plaintiffs against the world, but their right against the Defendant”<end.quote refid="QT_0002"/>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Finally, there is no obligation of confidence where the party asserting the right had no part in creating the information, but merely summarized information made public by a third party.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79d8db48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">5</footnote.reference>] In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2000545513" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I53f828b18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Visagie v. TVX Gold</cite.query> Inc.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id79d8db58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">6</footnote.reference>] the court held that, where a party had gained all his knowledge and insight from a third party, the third party had standing to sue to enforce a confidential agreement even though that party held the confidential information with no express consent from its owner.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2030642272" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I53f988418e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Scott &amp; Associates Engineering Ltd. v. Finavera Renewables</cite.query> Inc.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id79db4c08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">7</footnote.reference>] a property was offered for sale in a bid system where many were invited to participate. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff conducted research on the project, was accepted as a qualified bidder, submitted four offers in its own name and eventually became the only entity with which Penn West was still negotiating. <eos/><bos/>Penn West acknowledged that the plaintiff had become the preferred potential purchaser of the project. <eos/><bos/>However, the plaintiff did not have the required funds or necessary financing and Scott actively sought monies from numerous sources. <eos/><bos/>Eventually, the plaintiff and the defendant were brought together and they moved quickly to acquire the project, with the defendant providing the money. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff and the defendant shared information, worked together, and submitted a bid in the name of the defendant in the same amount as in prior offers by the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>This final bid was eventually accepted by Penn West. <eos/><bos/>Differences of opinion arose and the tensions were such that when the purchase and sale transaction closed with Penn West, the defendant purported to have acquired the wind project on its own account. <eos/><bos/>The defendant subsequently developed the project alone, hired another engineering firm to work on the project, and eventually sold the project to a third party, all without any further involvement of the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>People who came to this existing opportunity were provided with extensive materials compiled and owned by Penn West. <eos/><bos/>Potential purchasers were expected to make their own evaluations and/or further enquire and satisfy themselves in the manner of their choice about the attractiveness, economics and viability of the project.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79db4c18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">8</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A party alleging a breach of confidence only has a right over information which he or she has created with some measure of his or her own time, skill and effort. <eos/><bos/>There is no obligation of confidence where the party asserting the right had no part in creating the information but merely summarized the information made public by a third party.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79db4c28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">9</footnote.reference>] The great majority of the information provided to the defendant was the confidential information of Penn West and was not created by the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff merely passed it along or summarized it. <eos/><bos/>Therefore, there was no obligation of confidence owed by the defendant to the plaintiff for Penn West&apos;s information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79db4c38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">10</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2030642272" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I53fb35f18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Scott &amp; Associates Engineering Ltd. v. Finavera Renewables</cite.query> Inc</ital>.,[<footnote.reference refid="Id79db4c48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">11</footnote.reference>] the plaintiff appealed only the trial judge&apos;s conclusion that damages and not the proprietary remedy of a constructive trust were the appropriate remedy for the defendant&apos;s unjust enrichment. <eos/><bos/>The focus in oral submissions on the appeal was on the “moral quality” of the defendant&apos;s conduct. <eos/><bos/>That is, the plaintiff argued that moral culpability was a factor in determining whether a constructive trust was available. <eos/><bos/>However, the Court of Appeal observed that in the absence of a fiduciary relationship or a relationship giving rise to confidence or a contractual relationship, it was doubtful that moral culpability becomes a factor. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge expressly found no fiduciary duty to engage the duty of loyalty. <eos/><bos/>This eliminated <ital>Soulos</ital> and the cases awarding constructive trusts for a breach of a fiduciary duty. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge also expressly found no breach of confidence, which eliminated the <ital>Lac Minerals</ital> breach of confidence line of cases that considered moral quality, and on which the appellant relied. <eos/><bos/>The circumstances considered in awarding a constructive trust in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2000545513" w-pub-number="0005506" ID="I53fb35f38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Visagie v. TVX Gold Inc</ital>. (2000), 49 O.R. (3d) 198, 132 O.A.C. 231 (Ont. C.A.)</cite.query>, were also distinguishable. <eos/><bos/>There were critical differences which made that case entirely inapplicable. <eos/><bos/>The remedy upheld by the Court of Appeal of Ontario was based on the successful claim of breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2000545513" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I53fb35f78e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>TVX Gold</ital></cite.query> was distinguishable, the trial judge here having expressly found that there was no breach of confidence.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79db4c58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">12</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00007" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2042921205" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I540017f18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Scott &amp; Associates Engineering Ltd. v. Ghost Pine Windfarm</cite.query>, LP</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id79db4c68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">13</footnote.reference>] the application judge granted Ghost Pine&apos;s summary dismissal application and dismissed Scott&apos;s claim in its entirety. <eos/><bos/>Scott and Finavera worked together on a bid for a wind farm project. <eos/><bos/>Ultimately, Finavera was the successful bidder and developed the project. <eos/><bos/>Finavera did not include Scott in the final bid, nor did it hire Scott as the engineer for the project. <eos/><bos/>Scott sued Finavera alleging that Finavera had misused confidential information Scott had provided as part of the joint bid process; misappropriated Scott&apos;s business opportunity; and been unjustly enriched by Scott&apos;s efforts in relation to the purchase of the project.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79ddbd08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">14</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Finavera sold part of the project to Ghost Pine. <eos/><bos/>Scott then sued Ghost Pine. <eos/><bos/>Scott alleged that Ghost Pine made the purchase with full knowledge of Scott&apos;s lawsuit against Finavera, including its allegations that Finavera held the project in trust for Scott. <eos/><bos/>It argued that as a result of this knowledge when making the purchase, Ghost Pine now held the project and the associated lands for Scott as constructive trustee. <eos/><bos/>Scott also alleged that Ghost Pine knowingly received confidential information from Finavera and benefitted from this information. <eos/><bos/>It sought a constructive trust in its favour over Ghost Pine&apos;s interests in the project and associated lands, an accounting of profits or damages in the alternative.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79ddbd18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">15</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Ghost Pine brought an application for summary dismissal on the grounds that section 203 of the <ital>Land Titles Act</ital> was a bar to Scott&apos;s claims against the lands. <eos/><bos/>Ghost Pine also argued that the application judge should dismiss Scott&apos;s claims for knowing receipt, breach of confidence and unjust enrichment.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The completed Finavera litigation resolved a number of issues. <eos/><bos/>In particular, Justice Martin concluded at trial that Scott had no interest in the lands. <eos/><bos/>Furthermore, since Justice Martin refused to impose a constructive trust as remedy, the motions judge dismissed Scott&apos;s claim for knowing receipt of trust property, as there never was a trust interest. <eos/><bos/>The only remaining issues included whether the application judge should summarily dismiss Scott&apos;s breach of confidence claim.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79ddbd28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">16</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In the Finavera litigation, Justice Martin dismissed Scott&apos;s claim for breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>She found that Finavera properly used the limited amount of confidential information Scott supplied to acquire the project. <eos/><bos/>Scott did not appeal this finding, nor was it addressed in its leave application before the Supreme Court of Canada. <eos/><bos/>The application judge observed that Justice Martin had explained that Canadian courts have rejected the view that confidential information should be treated as property. <eos/><bos/>Rather, an action for breach of confidence is rooted in the relationship of confidence rather than the legal characteristics of the information confided. <eos/><bos/>Ghost Pine acquired the project from Finavera in an arm&apos;s length transaction in which Scott had no involvement. <eos/><bos/>Ghost Pine had no relationship with Scott until Scott sued Ghost Pine in this litigation. <eos/><bos/>Scott did not convey any confidential information to Ghost Pine; in fact, Scott did not communicate with Ghost Pine at all. <eos/><bos/>Furthermore, there was no evidence to suggest that Ghost Pine misused any information to Scott&apos;s detriment. <eos/><bos/>Justice Martin concluded there was no misuse of Scott&apos;s confidential information by Finavera. <eos/><bos/>There was no basis for Scott to argue that Ghost Pine, a party with whom it had no dealings, misused its confidential information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79ddbd38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">17</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The appellant&apos;s appeal of the summary dismissal of its claim for breach of confidence against the respondents was dismissed in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00008" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2042921205" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I541267718e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Scott &amp; Associates Engineering Ltd v. Ghost Pine Windfarm LP</ital></cite.query>.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79ddbd48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">18</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In 2007 Scott and Finavera worked together on a bid to purchase a wind farm. <eos/><bos/>Scott did significant upfront work on the deal and shared this information with Finavera, who proceeded to close the purchase without involving Scott or hiring Scott for the project. <eos/><bos/>In 2008, Finavera sold part of the project to Ghost Pine. <eos/><bos/>Scott then sued Ghost Pine in this action, alleging that Ghost Pine made the purchase with full knowledge of Scott&apos;s lawsuit against Finavera, and claiming that Ghost Pine held the project as constructive trustee and that Ghost Pine knowingly received Scott&apos;s confidential information from Finavera and benefitted from that information. <eos/><bos/>Ghost Pine applied in 2010 for summary dismissal of the Action. <eos/><bos/>At the trial in the Finavera Action, Scott&apos;s claim for unjust enrichment was granted and Scott was awarded $600,000. <eos/><bos/>The balance of Scott&apos;s claims against Finavera were dismissed. <eos/><bos/>The Finavera trial judge concluded that most of the information provided to Finavera by Scott was not its own confidential information, stating:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0003"/>There is therefore only a small amount of Scott&apos;s information that has any quality of confidence about it that can be enforced by Scott. <eos/><bos/>This includes the amount Scott bid in its offers; the few terms Scott had negotiated with Penn West outside its proposed Purchase and Sale Agreement; and information Scott requested and received from Golder Associates Ltd (“Golder”) on wildlife and other issues.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0003"/></paratext></para></display.quote><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Finavera trial judge found that, while the information had been communicated in confidence, Finavera had not misused Scott&apos;s confidential information because it had been used with Scott&apos;s authorization to acquire the assets. <eos/><bos/>An appeal of the Finavera trial decision was dismissed. <eos/><bos/>After the Supreme Court of Canada dismissed the Finavera leave application in October 2015, the parties provided further submissions to the chambers judge on the summary dismissal application. <eos/><bos/>In October 2017, the chambers judge dismissed Scott&apos;s entire claim.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79ddbd58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">19</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Both the Finavera trial judge and the chambers judge correctly identified the three-step test for a breach of confidence claim: the information conveyed must be confidential; the information must have been communicated in confidence; and, the party to whom it was communicated must have misused the information to the detriment of the party who confided it. <eos/><bos/>The Chambers judge noted that the Finavera trial judge dismissed Scott&apos;s claim against Finavera for breach of confidence because, <begin.quote ID="QT_0004"/>“Finavera properly used the limited amount of confidential information Scott supplied to acquire the project”<end.quote refid="QT_0004"/> In addressing Scott&apos;s claim for breach of confidence against Ghost Pine, the Chambers judge stated that Scott did not convey any confidential information to Ghost Pine; in fact, Scott did not communicate with Ghost Pine at all. <eos/><bos/>Furthermore, there was no evidence to suggest that Ghost Pine misused any information to Scott&apos;s detriment. <eos/><bos/>The Chambers judge concluded there was no misuse of Scott&apos;s confidential information by Finavera. <eos/><bos/>There was no basis for Scott to argue that Ghost Pine, a party with whom it had no dealings, misused its confidential information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79e02e08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">20</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Scott submitted that the chambers judge erred because it was not fatal to its claim for breach of confidence that Scott did not have any direct dealings with Ghost Pine. <eos/><bos/>Scott submitted that third party recipients of confidential information may be liable where they had actual or constructive knowledge of the impropriety. <eos/><bos/>The chambers judge did not address this issue despite evidence from Ghost Pine that it had notice of Scott&apos;s claim against Finavera. <eos/><bos/>Scott pointed to the Asset Purchase Agreement between Finavera and Ghost Pine, which required Finavera to deliver to Ghost Pine all documents relating to the Ghost Pine Project, and contained a $1 million holdback in relation to the Scott litigation. <eos/><bos/>As well, Scott submitted that Ghost Pine provided no direct evidence on the summary judgment application that addressed whether it received any of Scott&apos;s confidential information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79e02e18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">21</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In the Court of Appeal&apos;s view, the chambers judge erred in dismissing Scott&apos;s breach of confidence action on the basis that there had been no direct dealings between Scott and Ghost Pine. <eos/><bos/>Scott could still have a claim against Ghost Pine if it knowingly received Scott&apos;s confidential information from Finavera and used that information in a manner not authorized by Scott. <eos/><bos/>The finding by the Finavera trial judge that Finavera did not misuse Scott&apos;s confidential information was not an answer to Scott&apos;s claim against Ghost Pine. <eos/><bos/>Whether any of Scott&apos;s confidential information was misused by Ghost Pine was a different issue.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79e02e28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">22</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>However, that did not end the matter. <eos/><bos/>Before the Chambers judge, Ghost Pine also submitted that the Finavera trial judge had found that very little information provided by Scott to Finavera was actually confidential information of Scott, and that there was no evidence that any of the identified confidential information had been received by Ghost Pine. <eos/><bos/>The Chambers judge did not address these submissions, as he had dismissed Scott&apos;s breach of confidence claim for other reasons. <eos/><bos/>At the appeal hearing, Scott conceded that its claim for breach of confidence was limited to the confidential information identified by the Finavera trial judge, essentially the information from Golder regarding wildlife and other issues. <eos/><bos/>Scott submitted, however, that even had the chambers judge addressed these submissions, the evidentiary record was not sufficient to summarily dismiss the breach of confidence claim on the basis that Ghost Pine did not receive the confidential information. <eos/><bos/>Scott pointed out that the onus is on the applicant for summary dismissal to establish that there is “no merit” to a claim.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79e02e38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">23</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Court of Appeal observed that due, in part, to the way the summary dismissal application unfolded, there was no affidavit evidence from Ghost Pine that directly addressed whether it received any of Scott&apos;s confidential information, beyond the fact that no such information was included in Ghost Pine&apos;s affidavit of records. <eos/><bos/>Ghost Pine submitted that this was sufficient to ground a summary dismissal application. <eos/><bos/>Its officer had sworn that Ghost Pine had produced all of the relevant and material records relating to the action that it had in its possession, custody or power, and identified all the relevant and material records that it once had, but no longer had, in its power. <eos/><bos/>Moreover, when that officer was cross-examined on the affidavit of records, she confirmed that all documents received from Finavera had been provided to their counsel, and counsel confirmed that all documents from Finavera had been included in the affidavit of records. <eos/><bos/>The Court of Appeal was satisfied there was evidence on the record before the Chambers judge that Ghost Pine never possessed any of Scott&apos;s confidential information. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, the appeal of the summary dismissal of Scott&apos;s claim for breach of confidence was dismissed.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79e02e48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">24</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00009" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2028075473" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I543de4418e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Barrick Gold Corp. v. Goldcorp</cite.query> Inc</ital>.,[<footnote.reference refid="Id79e02e58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">25</footnote.reference>] the trial judge concluded that the plaintiff had no standing to assert its common law claims for breach of confidence based on misuse of information because neither defendant owed a duty of confidence to it, stating:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0005"/>First, while I accept that equity is to be applied flexibly to render justice, there is no authority for imposing a duty of confidence in favour of a third party to a contract who is neither the owner of the confidential information nor a confider of the confidential information.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0005"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0006"/>In particular, I am not persuaded that either Minera Aquiline or Cadbury Schweppes support Barrick&apos;s position on this issue. <eos/><bos/>In Cadbury Schweppes, the plaintiff was the legal successor-in-interest to the original confider of the confidential information. <eos/><bos/>Minera Aquiline was decided on the basis of a contractual claim. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff was a contracting party to the confidentiality agreement by its terms so the issue in the present circumstances did not present itself. <eos/><bos/>Neither the trial decision nor the appellate decision addressed the issue in the present action directly and the comments of the trial judge in Minera Aquiline respecting the common law claim are entirely obiter dicta. <eos/><bos/>I am therefore of the opinion that there is nothing in that decision that can be relied on to find that a duty of confidence could be owed to an unrelated third party, i.e., a party who neither owns the confidential information nor provides it to a party in circumstances establishing a duty of confidence.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0006"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id79e29f08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">26</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00010" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I54418dc18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course</cite.query> Ltd.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id79e29f18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">27</footnote.reference>] a motion for summary judgment brought by the defendant Derrydale asking that the action by the plaintiff, Endplex be dismissed was granted. <eos/><bos/>Derrydale received an unsolicited offer from Endplex to purchase the property owned by Derrydale. <eos/><bos/>The shareholders of Derrydale decided to sell the East and West portions of Derrydale&apos;s property to Endplex for its development purposes and to retain the central portion of the property. <eos/><bos/>Derrydale wanted to retain ownership of the central portion of the property for continued use as a 9-hole executive golf course enabling Endplex to take ownership of the East and West parcels for development.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79e29f28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">28</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The agreement with Endplex was conditional upon obtaining the consent of the City of Mississauga Committee of Adjustment to sever the two parcels of Derrydale&apos;s property and to permit Derrydale to retain lands which would be redeveloped for the nine-hole golf course. <eos/><bos/>The agreement provided that Endplex would pay the costs of Derrydale&apos;s application for severance to the Committee of Adjustment. <eos/><bos/>The agreement also required Derrydale and Endplex to work together in using best efforts to obtain approval for the severance of the property from the Committee of Adjustment. <eos/><bos/>In furtherance of this objective, Derrydale retained a consultant to assist in providing planning advice to Derrydale as owner/applicant. <eos/><bos/>Subsequently Endplex, and Derrydale, appointed the consultant to be responsible for the preparation of severance applications for submission to the City of Mississauga Committee of Adjustment. <eos/><bos/>At the direction of Derrydale and Endplex, the consultant submitted the Applications to the Committee of Adjustment seeking consent to sever the two parcels. <eos/><bos/>Both severances were approved subject to conditions that were to be fulfilled within one year from the date of the decision, namely, by August 12, 2005. <eos/><bos/>The consultant, acting at the direction of both Endplex and Derrydale, retained consultants for the purpose of obtaining expert reports for submission to the Region of Peel, the Committee of Adjustment, the City of Mississauga and the Credit Valley Conservation in order to satisfy the conditions for severance required by the Committee of Adjustment. <eos/><bos/>The conditions required, that a number of technical matters be addressed through the submission of expert reports to be reviewed and approved by the City and Credit Valley Conservation. <eos/><bos/>Thereafter, at the direction of both Derrydale and Endplex, the consultant coordinated the retainer of consultants for the preparation of expert reports required to satisfy the Region of Peel, the City of Mississauga and the Credit Valley Conservation. <eos/><bos/>At the direction of Derrydale and Endplex, and without any constraints on the release of such expert reports, the consultant submitted three expert reports provided to the City of Mississauga and to the Credit Valley Conservation for purposes of satisfying the conditions of the severances established by the Committee of Adjustment. <eos/><bos/>The submission of the expert reports was part of the public approval process provided for under the <ital>Planning Act</ital>.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79e29f38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">29</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>At or about the same time as the consultants&apos; reports were being filed with the City of Mississauga and the Credit Valley Conservation, Endplex, entered into discussions with the consultant with respect to potential retainer of Glenn Schnarr and Associates by Endplex to obtain land-use planning approvals related to Endplex&apos;s development plans for the West parcel. <eos/><bos/>The consultant gave Endplex an opinion that there was a low prospect for the development for residential uses of the West parcel because of existing land-use planning constraints.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79e29f48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">30</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Agreement of Purchase and Sale provided that if Endplex was not satisfied that the lands could be zoned with a zoning designation satisfactory to it, Endplex had the right to terminate the Agreement to purchase the two parcels of property. <eos/><bos/>Before making its second deposit, Endplex terminated the Agreement of Purchase and Sale and requested the return of its initial deposit pursuant to the terms of the agreement. <eos/><bos/>The initial deposit of $250,000 was returned to Endplex by Derrydale.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79e29f58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">31</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Endplex wrote to the consultant and requested all the reports that had been prepared by consultants, including the originals and copies of all reports which were prepared and filed with the City of Mississauga or distributed to any other third party, be collected and turned over to Endplex. <eos/><bos/>Endplex asserted that the reports were the property of Endplex and further that such reports were not to be disseminated or used in any fashion without the consent of Endplex. <eos/><bos/>Endplex&apos;s assertion of an entitlement to ownership and possession of all reports was contrary to the provisions of the Agreement of Purchase and Sale. <eos/><bos/>Notwithstanding the Agreement, the consultant collected the reports and forwarded them to Endplex. <eos/><bos/>Derrydale&apos;s solicitor, immediately denied Endplex&apos;s claim to ownership of the reports prepared by the consultants. <eos/><bos/>The “First” reports were never returned to Derrydale.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79e29f68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">32</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>After the termination of the agreement by Endplex, Derrydale sought a new purchaser for the two parcels of land. <eos/><bos/>Derrydale entered into an Agreement of Purchase and Sale with GWL for the East parcel. <eos/><bos/>GWL was not interested in purchasing the West parcel. <eos/><bos/>The parcel which is the subject of the agreement between GWL and Derrydale is a slightly modified version of the East parcel that Derrydale had originally agreed to sell to Endplex. <eos/><bos/>As a result, Derrydale and GWL were required to satisfy the conditions of the approved severance relating to the East parcel.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79e51008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">33</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The initial agreement between Derrydale and GWL provided that GWL would not pursue the existing applications for severances and would make a new application for a severance to the Committee of Adjustment notwithstanding that the existing severances for the East and West parcels had already been approved by the Committee of Adjustment subject to conditions. <eos/><bos/>The purpose of this agreement between Derrydale and GWL to make a new application for severance was to accommodate concerns being expressed by Endplex as to its “property” rights in the consultants&apos; reports and the existing severance applications.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79e51018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">34</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Secretary-Treasurer of the Committee of Adjustment denied a request by Endplex to close or suspend the operation of the approved severance applications, stating that the applications were still active and available to the owner of the property before lapsing on August 12, 2005.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79e51028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">35</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In May of 2005, a number of terms of the GWL Agreement were amended by the parties. <eos/><bos/>One of the terms of the GWL contract, which was amended, was the provision that GWL pursue a new severance application to permit sale by Derrydale of the East parcel. <eos/><bos/>This amendment reflected the fact that the Committee of Adjustment had confirmed that the existing severances and applications were approved, subject to the conditions stipulated, and that such approval could not be withdrawn. <eos/><bos/>Further, the Committee of Adjustment confirmed that Derrydale, as owner of the property, was in a position to satisfy the conditions prior to the severance collapsing on August 12, 2005.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79e51038e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">36</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>As the conditions for severance of the East parcel had not yet been fulfilled, through its planning consultants GWL retained its own consultants to prepare and file expert reports (hereinafter, the “Second” reports) in order to satisfy the conditions for the severance of the East parcel.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79e51048e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">37</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Endplex claimed that it held a copyright interest in the “First” reports generated in support of the applications for severance of the East and West parcels, that it owned such reports and that the defendant Derrydale breached an obligation to hold in confidence and not to use information in relation to the applications for severance. <eos/><bos/>With respect to this latter allegation, it was alleged by the plaintiffs that GWL in their acquisition of the East parcel from Derrydale were provided by Derrydale with copies of various reports, information and documents that were confidential and that this is a breach of the defendant&apos;s obligation to the plaintiff.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79e51058e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">38</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Murray concluded that there was no merit to these claims. <eos/><bos/>Section 7.3 of Schedule “A” to the Agreement of Purchase and Sale between Endplex and Derrydale was a complete answer to the plaintiff&apos;s claim. <eos/><bos/>Section 7.3 states as follows:</paratext><display.quote><head style="l" parent="display.quote"><headtext><bold>7.3 Confidentiality</bold></headtext></head><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0007"/>The Purchaser and Vendor shall keep in strict confidence all information obtained with respect to the Lands (save and except that the vendor will be able to disclose that an Agreement of Purchase and Sale has been reached) until such time as the closing is completed. <eos/><bos/>The Purchaser and Vendor agree to instruct its agents, advisors and consultants to comply with the provisions of this section. <eos/><bos/><ital>If the purchase and sale of the Lands is not completed for any reason, the Purchaser shall promptly deliver to the Vendor all documents, information and material relating to the lands delivered by or on behalf of the Vendor and all reports and information and all copies thereof and shall keep in confidence all such information and all discussions between the Vendor and the Purchaser with respect to the Lands. (<eos/><bos/>Emphasis added)</ital><end.quote refid="QT_0007"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id79e51068e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">39</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The contract provided for confidentiality of information in two circumstances: firstly, where the purchase and sale of the property was completed and, secondly, in circumstances where the purchase and sale was not completed. <eos/><bos/>The Agreement of Purchase and Sale of the lands between Derrydale and Endplex was not completed as a result of the unilateral termination of the contract by Endplex, the purchaser. <eos/><bos/>Therefore, the last sentence of s. 7.3 of Schedule “A” to the contract applied. <eos/><bos/>This provision of the contract put an obligation to maintain confidentiality on the purchaser not on the vendor. <eos/><bos/>Section 7.3 provided that if the purchase and sale of the lands was not completed for any reason, the purchaser shall: 1) promptly deliver all documents, information and material relating to the lands delivered by or on behalf of the vendor and all reports and information and all copies thereof; and 2) shall keep in confidence all such information and all discussions between the vendor and purchaser with respect to the lands.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79e78108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">40</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The obligation of the purchaser to <begin.quote ID="QT_0008"/>“deliver all documents, information and material relating to the lands delivered by or on behalf of the vendor and all reports and information and all copies thereof”<end.quote refid="QT_0008"/> made it abundantly clear that the contract contemplated that the purchaser had no on-going interest in any information or reports related to the property or related to the applications for severance once the Agreement was terminated.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79e78118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">41</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Endplex&apos;s claim that it owned the consultant&apos;s reports and all other information related to the ill-fated real estate transaction flied in the face of the provision of section 7.3 of the contract which made it clear that Endplex had no proprietary interest in any of the information that it claimed to own and no right to insist that the vendor keep such information confidential.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79e78128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">42</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The obligation to keep information related to the purchase and sale confidential after termination of the Agreement was imposed by s. 7.3 of the Agreement on the purchaser. <eos/><bos/>The vendor had no contractual obligation imposed it to keep information related to the transaction. <eos/><bos/>Indeed, the contractual obligation was for Endplex to return all information to the vendor, Derrydale. <eos/><bos/>The absence of any contractual obligation on Derrydale to keep any information confidential and the contractual obligation on Endplex to return all information to Derrydale, confirmed that the parties to the agreement intended that Derrydale could do what it wanted with the information after the termination of the agreement.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79e78138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">43</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Murray observed that the obligation of confidentiality was on the purchaser Endplex (and not on the vendor) also made good business sense. <eos/><bos/>Derrydale, the vendor, did not want its ability to sell the property in the future to be impaired in any way by disclosure by Endplex of any of the details of the agreement between Endplex and Derrydale to a subsequent potential purchaser. <eos/><bos/>For example, if a subsequent purchaser was prepared to pay more than Endplex, Derrydale would not likely want the subsequent purchaser to be informed by Endplex of the details of the contract between Derrydale and Endplex. <eos/><bos/>It would have made no sense for the vendor to have contracted with Endplex that all information related to the property including any consultants&apos; reports obtained for purposes of furthering the applications for severance would be treated as confidential by the vendor after termination of the agreement. <eos/><bos/>If the vendor were to wish to sell to another purchaser, it would have made no sense for the vendor to be constrained from using any information or consultants&apos; reports generated in support of the applications for severance once the Endplex contract was terminated. <eos/><bos/>Consent for severance(s) is required regardless of who purchases the property.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79e78148e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">44</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff asserted that, if the defendant Derrydale was not obliged by contract to hold in confidence and not use information in relation to the applications for severance, the obligations were implied terms of the agreement. <eos/><bos/>Justice Murray would not imply such a contractual restriction. <eos/><bos/>Over a month before the termination of the agreement by Endplex, various consultants&apos; reports, the “First” reports were submitted to the City of Mississauga, and to the CVC for purposes of clearing the conditions of the severances. <eos/><bos/>These reports were filed with public authorities to satisfy conditions for severance of the parcels of land which Endplex had agreed to purchase and to be available for public scrutiny in what is a public process. <eos/><bos/>There was no objection by Endplex to the filing of these reports. <eos/><bos/>Even if Endplex held a bona fide belief that Derrydale had an obligation to maintain the confidentiality of the reports, the joint filing of such reports with various public authorities in order to meet the conditions for severance imposed by the Committee of Adjustment was, by necessary implication, a waiver of any claim to confidentiality of those reports by Endplex. <eos/><bos/>Indeed, if Derrydale had prevented the filing of the reports with the authorities, it would have been in breach of the agreement with Endplex to <begin.quote ID="QT_0009"/>“cooperate in the processing of the applications and the execution of any documents required as part of the application.”<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0009"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id79e78158e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">45</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Finally, the “First” reports were not used by the defendant in satisfying the conditions for severance necessary for the sale of the East parcel to GWL. Endplex maintained possession of the “First” reports after it terminated the agreement of purchase and sale. <eos/><bos/>Derrydale did not retain possession of the first reports. <eos/><bos/>After the termination by Endplex of the Agreement of Purchase and Sale, Derrydale neither directly or indirectly employed the “First” reports for any further use or purpose. <eos/><bos/>Such reports were not used for purposes of obtaining the severance of the East parcel for purposes of sale to GWL.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79e9f208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">46</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Derrydale had every right to use any information in its possession, including the “First” consultants&apos; reports, to further its application for severance and to achieve its objective of selling the East parcel to GWL. However, at it did not use such information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79e9f218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">47</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Murray concluded that there was no factual or legal basis for the claim by Endplex that Derrydale improperly used confidential information. <eos/><bos/>There were no material facts alleged in any affidavit material filed by the plaintiffs or by the defendant which supported a conclusion that the plaintiff could raise a triable issue in a claim for breach of confidence.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79e9f228e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">48</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff asserted that the misuse of confidential information by Derrydale was also a breach of a fiduciary duty owed by Derrydale to Endplex. <eos/><bos/>As a result, the plaintiff asserted that it was entitled to any profits made by Derrydale including any profits from the sale of the East parcel to GWL. This claim was also completely without foundation. <eos/><bos/>The relationship between the parties was contractual and was terminated when Endplex terminated the Agreement of Purchase and Sale. <eos/><bos/>After the termination of the contract by Endplex, Derrydale had no duty to forsake its own interest to act for the benefit of the plaintiff.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79e9f238e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">49</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00011" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2010279811" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5464a6218e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Free Trade Medical Network Inc. v. RBC Travel Insurance</cite.query> Co.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id79e9f248e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">50</footnote.reference>] Free Trade sought to set aside the judgment dismissing its action for damages and for breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>The appellant submitted that the trial judge failed properly to apply the three part test enunciated by the Supreme Court of Canada in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00012" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1989312320" w-pub-number="0005156" ID="I5464a6238e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>International Corona Resources Ltd. v. Lac Minerals Ltd</ital>., [1989] 2 S.C.R. 574, 1989 CarswellOnt 126 (S.C.C.)</cite.query>.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79e9f258e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">51</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Free Trade had an agreement with CCN entitling it to market CCN services. <eos/><bos/>It was not an exclusive agreement. <eos/><bos/>CCN was a Preferred Provider Organization that provided access to discounted medical and hospital services throughout the United States. <eos/><bos/>These services are important to companies like the defendant RBC which was in the business of providing travel insurance to tourists and others travelling abroad. <eos/><bos/>RBC had had a contractual relationship with a predecessor of CCN through an intermediary but that contract had ended and RBC was seeking a new arrangement with a PPO on a direct contractual basis. <eos/><bos/>It was interested in continuing with CCN.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79e9f268e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">52</footnote.reference>] Hitchlock, the principal of the appellant, arranged the meeting on October 31, 1997, with representatives of RBC, a representative of CCN and himself, in order to pitch CCN&apos;s services. <eos/><bos/>Nothing was said at that meeting about the relationship between Free Trade and CCN. In the course of the meeting, Hitchlock provided RBC with, amongst other things, a directory containing confidential information about CCN&apos;s discounts. <eos/><bos/>This was important information and it enabled RBC to satisfy itself through a test analysis that CCN&apos;s services met their needs. <eos/><bos/>On November 6, RBC entered into a contract directly with CCN.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79e9f278e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">53</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge found that the information in the directory was confidential and that it had been provided to RBC in confidence. <eos/><bos/>She concluded, however, that Free Trade was not entitled to claim breach of confidence because it was not the “owner” of the confidential information. <eos/><bos/>Rather, CCN was. <eos/><bos/>She also found that there had been no misuse of the information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79ec6308e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">54</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The November 6 agreement did not involve Free Trade and was made at a meeting to which Hitchlock was not invited, even though he had had some further involvement in the test process. <eos/><bos/>In short, Free Trade was cut out of the deal.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79ec6318e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">55</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The appellant argued that the trial judge made a fundamental error in applying the test for a claim for breach of confidence by failing to consider the third element and, more particularly, by concluding that a party asserting breach of confidence is not entitled to rely upon a misuse of confidential information unless it is the “owner” of that information. <eos/><bos/>The Court of Appeal concluded that there was no reversible error.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79ec6328e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">56</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge relied upon the decision of Lord Denning M. R. in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00013" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1968017805" w-pub-number="0003898" ID="I546ac0a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Fraser v. Evans</ital> (1968), [1969] 1 Q.B. 349 (Eng. C.A.)</cite.query> and the decision of Nordheimer J. in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00014" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2009640412" w-pub-number="0006729" ID="I546ac0a28e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Air Canada v. WestJet Airlines Ltd</ital>., [2004] O.J. No. 5627 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>The Court of Appeal accepted that it may not be accurate in all cases of breach of confidence to say that the person seeking to rely upon a confidence must be the owner of the confidential information. <eos/><bos/>However, as Lord Denning said in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00015" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1968017805" w-pub-number="0003898" ID="I546ac0a58e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Fraser v. Evans</ital></cite.query>:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0010"/>… the party complaining must be the person who is entitled to the confidence and to have it respected. <eos/><bos/>He must be a person to whom the duty of good faith is owed.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0010"/></paratext></para></display.quote><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>RBC had no relationship with Free Trade other than in its capacity as a representative of CCN. The confidential information in the directory was CCN&apos;s confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The information was being provided by, or on behalf of CCN, to assist RBC in deciding whether to contract with CCN as its PPO. <eos/><bos/>There was nothing on the record that would support an argument that Free Trade was the person who was entitled to the confidence and to have it respected or that RBC owed a duty of good faith to Free Trade in a fashion sought to be established by the appellant.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79ec6338e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">57</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In any event, the Court of Appeal concluded that there was no misuse of the confidential information. <eos/><bos/>In this regard, the trial judge did not fail to apply the third element of the <ital>Lac Minerals</ital> test. <eos/><bos/>She made a finding that the confidential information had not been misused. <eos/><bos/>The discounted information in the directory was used for exactly the purpose intended, namely, to facilitate the negotiation of a contract with CCN. Any disclosure to Hodosy was justified because he was RBC&apos;s agent and was entitled to deal with CCN on RBC&apos;s behalf. <eos/><bos/>Neither he nor RBC used the information for any other purpose.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id79ec6348e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">58</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Id79d8db08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00016" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1968017805" w-pub-number="0003898" ID="I546e6a208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Fraser v. Evans</ital>, [1969] 1 Q.B. 349</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79d8db18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00017" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1968017805" w-pub-number="0003898" w-pinpoint-page="361" ID="I546e91308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Fraser v. Evans</ital>, [1969] 1 Q.B. 349, at p. 361</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79d8db28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00018" w-ref-type="U2" w-serial-number="1982167114" w-pub-number="0005542" ID="I546eb8408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Moorgate Tobacco Co. v. Philip Morris Ltd.</ital> (1982), 64 F.L.R. 387 (S.C., N.S.W.)</cite.query>, at p. 404.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79d8db38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>4</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00019" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1851042779" w-pub-number="0005000" ID="I546f06608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Morison v. Moat</ital> (1851), 9 Hare. 241, 68 E.R. 492 (Ch.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79d8db48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>5</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00020" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1982172671" w-pub-number="0004655" w-pinpoint-page="497" ID="I546f2d708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ridgewood Resources Ltd. v. Henuset</ital> (1982), 35 A.R. 493 at pp. 497–8</cite.query>, 18 Alta. L.R. (2d) 68 (<cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00021" w-ref-type="ER" w-normalized-cite="36ARCA450n" w-pub-number="0004655" ID="I546f2d728e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">C.A.), leave to appeal to S.C.C. refused 36 A.R. 450<ital>n</ital>, 43 N.R. 90<ital>n</ital></cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79d8db58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>6</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00022" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2000545513" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I546fc9b18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Visagie v. TVX Gold Inc.</ital></cite.query> (1998), 142 B.L.R. (2d) 53 (Ont. Ct. (Gen. Div.)), affd <cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00023" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2000545513" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I546fc9b48e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">187 D.L.R. (4th) 193, 132 O.A.C. 231 (C.A.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79db4c08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>7</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00024" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2030642272" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I547017d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Scott &amp; Associates Engineering Ltd. v. Finavera Renewables Inc.</ital>, 2013 CarswellAlta 873, 2013 ABQB 273</cite.query>, <case.history>affd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00025" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035428008" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I547017d38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2015 CarswellAlta 182, 2015 ABCA 51</cite.query>, leave to appeal refused <cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00026" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037505168" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I547017d68e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2015 CarswellAlta 2009</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79db4c18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>8</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00027" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2030642272" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I547065f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Scott &amp; Associates Engineering Ltd. v. Finavera Renewables Inc.</ital>, 2013 CarswellAlta 873, 2013 ABQB 273</cite.query>, <case.history>affd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00028" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035428008" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I547065f38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2015 CarswellAlta 182, 2015 ABCA 51</cite.query>, leave to appeal refused <cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00029" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037505168" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I547065f68e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2015 CarswellAlta 2009</cite.query>, at paras. 2–3.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79db4c28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>9</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00030" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2030642272" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I54708d008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Scott &amp; Associates Engineering Ltd. v. Finavera Renewables Inc.</ital>, 2013 CarswellAlta 873, 2013 ABQB 273</cite.query>, <case.history>affd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00031" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035428008" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I54708d038e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2015 CarswellAlta 182, 2015 ABCA 51</cite.query>, leave to appeal refused <cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00032" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037505168" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I54708d068e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2015 CarswellAlta 2009, at para. 100</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79db4c38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>10</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00033" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2030642272" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I547102308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Scott &amp; Associates Engineering Ltd. v. Finavera Renewables Inc.</ital>, 2013 CarswellAlta 873, 2013 ABQB 273</cite.query>, <case.history>affd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00034" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035428008" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I547102338e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2015 CarswellAlta 182, 2015 ABCA 51</cite.query>, leave to appeal refused <cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00035" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037505168" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I547102368e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2015 CarswellAlta 2009</cite.query>, at paras. 104–105.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79db4c48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>11</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00036" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035428008" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I547129408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Scott &amp; Associates Engineering Ltd. v. Finavera Renewables Inc</ital>., 2015 CarswellAlta 182, 2015 ABCA 51</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79db4c58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>12</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00037" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035428008" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I547150508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Scott &amp; Associates Engineering Ltd. v. Finavera Renewables Inc</ital>., 2015 CarswellAlta 182, 2015 ABCA 51</cite.query>, at paras. 1, 17, 27–28, 30, and 39–41.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79db4c68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>13</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00038" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042921205" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I547177628e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Scott &amp; Associates Engineering Ltd. v. Ghost Pine Windfarm, LP</ital>, 2017 CarswellAlta 1870, 2017 ABQB 626</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00039" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2045328691" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I547177658e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2018 CarswellAlta 1664, 2018 ABQB 616</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79ddbd08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>14</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00040" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042921205" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I5471c5808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Scott &amp; Associates Engineering Ltd. v. Ghost Pine Windfarm, LP</ital>, 2017 CarswellAlta 1870, 2017 ABQB 626</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00041" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2045328691" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I5471c5838e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2018 CarswellAlta 1664, 2018 ABQB 616</cite.query>, at paras. 1–2.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79ddbd18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>15</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00042" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042921205" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I547213a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Scott &amp; Associates Engineering Ltd. v. Ghost Pine Windfarm, LP</ital>, 2017 CarswellAlta 1870, 2017 ABQB 626</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00043" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2045328691" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I547213a38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2018 CarswellAlta 1664, 2018 ABQB 616</cite.query>, at paras. 3–4.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79ddbd28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>16</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00044" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042921205" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I54723ab08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Scott &amp; Associates Engineering Ltd. v. Ghost Pine Windfarm, LP</ital>, 2017 CarswellAlta 1870, 2017 ABQB 626</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00045" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2045328691" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I54723ab38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2018 CarswellAlta 1664, 2018 ABQB 616</cite.query>, at paras. 7–9.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79ddbd38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>17</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00046" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042921205" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I547288d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Scott &amp; Associates Engineering Ltd. v. Ghost Pine Windfarm, LP</ital>, 2017 CarswellAlta 1870, 2017 ABQB 626</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00047" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2045328691" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I547288d38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2018 CarswellAlta 1664, 2018 ABQB 616</cite.query>, at paras. 21–22, and 24.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79ddbd48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>18</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00048" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047290416" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I5472afe08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Scott &amp; Associates Engineering Ltd v. Ghost Pine Windfarm LP</ital>, 2019 CarswellAlta 9, 2019 ABCA 2</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79ddbd58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>19</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00049" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047290416" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I5472d6f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Scott &amp; Associates Engineering Ltd v. Ghost Pine Windfarm LP</ital>, 2019 CarswellAlta 9, 2019 ABCA 2</cite.query>, at paras. 2–8.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79e02e08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>20</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00050" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047290416" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I5472fe008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Scott &amp; Associates Engineering Ltd v. Ghost Pine Windfarm LP</ital>, 2019 CarswellAlta 9, 2019 ABCA 2</cite.query>, at paras. 10–11.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79e02e18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>21</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00051" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047290416" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I547325108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Scott &amp; Associates Engineering Ltd v. Ghost Pine Windfarm LP</ital>, 2019 CarswellAlta 9, 2019 ABCA 2, at para. 12</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79e02e28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>22</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00052" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047290416" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I54734c208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Scott &amp; Associates Engineering Ltd v. Ghost Pine Windfarm LP</ital>, 2019 CarswellAlta 9, 2019 ABCA 2, at para. 13</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79e02e38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>23</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00053" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047290416" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I547373308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Scott &amp; Associates Engineering Ltd v. Ghost Pine Windfarm LP</ital>, 2019 CarswellAlta 9, 2019 ABCA 2</cite.query>, at paras. 14–15.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79e02e48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>24</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00054" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047290416" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I54739a408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Scott &amp; Associates Engineering Ltd v. Ghost Pine Windfarm LP</ital>, 2019 CarswellAlta 9, 2019 ABCA 2, at para. 16</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79e02e58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>25</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00055" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028075473" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5473c1508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Barrick Gold Corp. v. Goldcorp Inc</ital>., 2012 CarswellOnt 8085, 2012 ONSC 3725</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79e29f08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>26</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00056" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028075473" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5473e8608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Barrick Gold Corp. v. Goldcorp Inc</ital>., 2012 CarswellOnt 8085, 2012 ONSC 3725</cite.query>, at paras. 787–789 and 792.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79e29f18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>27</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00057" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I54740f708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 5851 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79e29f28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>28</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00058" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I547436808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 5851 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 1, and 5–6.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79e29f38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>29</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00059" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I54745d908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 5851 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 9–13.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79e29f48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>30</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00060" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I547484a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 5851 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at para. 15.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79e29f58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>31</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00061" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5474d2c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 5851 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 17–18.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79e29f68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>32</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00062" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5474f9d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 5851 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 19–20.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79e51008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>33</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00063" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I547520e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 5851 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 22 and 25.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79e51018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>34</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00064" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I547547f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 5851 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at para. 26.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79e51028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>35</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00065" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I54756f008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 5851 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at para. 27.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79e51038e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>36</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00066" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I547596108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 5851 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at para. 28.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79e51048e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>37</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00067" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5475e4308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 5851 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at para. 29.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79e51058e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>38</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00068" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I54760b408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 5851 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at para. 61.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79e51068e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>39</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00069" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I547632508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 5851 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 62–63.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79e78108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>40</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00070" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I547659608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 5851 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at para. 64.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79e78118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>41</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00071" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I547680708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 5851 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at para. 65.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79e78128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>42</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00072" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5476ce908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 5851 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at para. 66.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79e78138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>43</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00073" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5476f5a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 5851 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at para. 70.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79e78148e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>44</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00074" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I54771cb08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 5851 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at para. 71.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79e78158e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>45</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00075" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I547743c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 5851 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 72 and 74.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79e9f208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>46</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00076" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I54776ad08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 5851 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 75–76.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79e9f218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>47</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00077" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I547791e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 5851 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at para. 77.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79e9f228e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>48</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00078" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5477b8f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 5851 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 78 and 80.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79e9f238e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>49</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00079" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I547807108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 5851 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 81–83.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79e9f248e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>50</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00080" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2010279811" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I547807128e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Free Trade Medical Network Inc. v. RBC Travel Insurance Co.</ital>, 2006 CarswellOnt 5503, [2006] O.J. No. 3636 (Ont. C.A.)</cite.query>, leave to appeal refused <cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00081" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2011658865" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I547807158e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2007 CarswellOnt 1354 (S.C.C.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79e9f258e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>51</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00082" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2010279811" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I547855308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Free Trade Medical Network Inc. v. RBC Travel Insurance Co.</ital>, 2006 CarswellOnt 5503, [2006] O.J. No. 3636 (Ont. C.A.)</cite.query>, leave to appeal refused <cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00083" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2011658865" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I547855338e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2007 CarswellOnt 1354 (S.C.C.)</cite.query>, at para. 1.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79e9f268e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>52</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00084" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2010279811" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I54787c408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Free Trade Medical Network Inc. v. RBC Travel Insurance Co.</ital>, 2006 CarswellOnt 5503, [2006] O.J. No. 3636 (Ont. C.A.)</cite.query>, leave to appeal refused <cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00085" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2011658865" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I54787c438e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2007 CarswellOnt 1354 (S.C.C.)</cite.query>, at para. 2.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79e9f278e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>53</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00086" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2010279811" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5478ca608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Free Trade Medical Network Inc. v. RBC Travel Insurance Co.</ital>, 2006 CarswellOnt 5503, [2006] O.J. No. 3636 (Ont. C.A.)</cite.query>, leave to appeal refused <cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00087" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2011658865" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5478ca638e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2007 CarswellOnt 1354 (S.C.C.)</cite.query>, at para. 3.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79ec6308e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>54</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00088" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2010279811" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5478f1708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Free Trade Medical Network Inc. v. RBC Travel Insurance Co.</ital>, 2006 CarswellOnt 5503, [2006] O.J. No. 3636 (Ont. C.A.)</cite.query>, leave to appeal refused <cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00089" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2011658865" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5478f1738e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2007 CarswellOnt 1354 (S.C.C.)</cite.query>, at para. 4.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79ec6318e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>55</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00090" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2010279811" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I54793f908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Free Trade Medical Network Inc. v. RBC Travel Insurance Co.</ital>, 2006 CarswellOnt 5503, [2006] O.J. No. 3636 (Ont. C.A.)</cite.query>, leave to appeal refused <cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00091" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2011658865" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I54793f938e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2007 CarswellOnt 1354 (S.C.C.)</cite.query>, at para. 5.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79ec6328e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>56</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00092" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2010279811" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I547966a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Free Trade Medical Network Inc. v. RBC Travel Insurance Co.</ital>, 2006 CarswellOnt 5503, [2006] O.J. No. 3636 (Ont. C.A.)</cite.query>, leave to appeal refused <cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00093" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2011658865" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I547966a38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2007 CarswellOnt 1354 (S.C.C.)</cite.query>, at paras. 9–10.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79ec6338e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>57</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00094" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2010279811" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5479b4c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Free Trade Medical Network Inc. v. RBC Travel Insurance Co.</ital>, 2006 CarswellOnt 5503, [2006] O.J. No. 3636 (Ont. C.A.)</cite.query>, leave to appeal refused <cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00095" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2011658865" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5479b4c38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2007 CarswellOnt 1354 (S.C.C.)</cite.query>, at paras. 11–12.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id79ec6348e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>58</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00096" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2010279811" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5479dbd08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Free Trade Medical Network Inc. v. RBC Travel Insurance Co.</ital>, 2006 CarswellOnt 5503, [2006] O.J. No. 3636 (Ont. C.A.)</cite.query>, leave to appeal refused <cite.query w-src-number="0492175941" w-seq-number="00097" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2011658865" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5479dbd38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2007 CarswellOnt 1354 (S.C.C.)</cite.query>, at para. 13.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 6:6<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
