<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 4:39<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I5089a870411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>4.</label.designator><headtext>Confidential Business Information and the Employment Relationship</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I52517020411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>V.</label.designator><headtext>Fiduciary Duty</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I53a16fc0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>B.</label.designator><headtext>Remedies Table—Employment Relationship—Breach of Fiduciary Duty</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f65f4c6ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>4:39.</label.designator><headtext>WestCorp Solutions Ltd. v. Lancaster</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><ital>WestCorp Solutions Ltd. v. Lancaster</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1189, 2018 BCSC 789</headtext><eos/><eop/></head><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Award</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>PSE Defendants ordered to pay the outstanding balance of $495,619 in damages plus pre-judgment interest and post-judgement interest.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Summary of Facts</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>An action for damages against a stranger to a trust who allegedly and knowingly participated in a breach of fiduciary duty was allowed. <eos/><bos/>Collins was a director and officer of the plaintiff, WestCorp, and he admittedly breached his statutory fiduciary duty to WestCorp by successfully acquiring a contractual opportunity that WestCorp was interested in. <eos/><bos/>Collins secretly incorporated PSE with Lancaster for the purpose of accepting that corporate opportunity. <eos/><bos/>WestCorp alleged that, although Lancaster did not directly owe it a fiduciary duty, he actively participated and assisted in Collins&apos; breach of fiduciary duty. <eos/><bos/>WestCorp elected to claim equitable compensation based on its loss as opposed to claiming the return of the defendants&apos; profits.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>WestCorp contracted with Lancaster on November 12, 2011 to be WestCorp&apos;s project manager on its first large contract. <eos/><bos/>WestCorp entered into a consulting services contract with Nexen to provide services at its Long Lake refinery in relation to Nexen&apos;s large 2012 turnaround. <eos/><bos/>WestCorp also agreed to develop standard planning packages for Nexen which Nexen could use in the future when planning equipment maintenance. <eos/><bos/>In his capacity as a project manager, Lancaster arranged for experienced personnel to come to the Nexen site to assist with the Nexen Turnaround. <eos/><bos/>At the end of the Nexen Turnaround, WestCorp had no further opportunities for Lancaster. <eos/><bos/>Lancaster requested WestCorp&apos;s permission to end the consulting agreement with it so that he could become employed by Nexen as Nexen&apos;s in-house turnaround manager. <eos/><bos/>WestCorp granted permission and on December 1, 2012 Lancaster became an employee of Nexen.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Sometime before January 12, 2013, Lancaster and Collins spoke about incorporating PSE to pursue opportunities with Nexen through PSE. <eos/><bos/>One of Lancaster&apos;s roles as a turnaround manager for Nexen was to assist Nexen in finding consultants to hire. <eos/><bos/>Lancaster and Collins agreed to pursue an opportunity to bring Stollsteimer to work as a PSE consultant at Nexen. <eos/><bos/>Stollsteimer had consulted for Nexen during the Nexen Turnaround and was a senior turnaround advisor and projects advisor. <eos/><bos/>At the same time Scherzer was canvassing opportunities on behalf of WestCorp to bring on board another turnaround consultant to Nexen to work as a WestCorp consultant. <eos/><bos/>Had WestCorp known of the opportunity to bring in Stollsteimer as WestCorp&apos;s consultant to work at Nexen, it would have pursued that opportunity. <eos/><bos/>Neither Lancaster nor Collins told WestCorp that they were incorporating PSE or that they were arranging to bring Stollsteimer in to work at Nexen. <eos/><bos/>Lancaster advised Scherzer that he could no longer advocate for WestCorp at Nexen because it would be perceived as a conflict of interest given that he previously worked for WestCorp. <eos/><bos/>Lancaster did not tell Scherzer that he had incorporated PSE with Collins so that PSE could pursue opportunities with Nexen. <eos/><bos/>He also never told Scherzer that WestCorp was never going to be hired back by Nexen.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>PSE entered into a letter of understanding with Nexen to provide services to Nexen. <eos/><bos/>On behalf of PSE, Stollsteimer wrote to Lancaster who was the turnaround manager at Nexen making a proposal for PSE to support the turnaround organization at Nexen by providing a senior turnaround and project advisor. <eos/><bos/>The proposal was accepted and signed by Lancaster, Nexen&apos;s turnaround manager. <eos/><bos/>The Second Nexen Contract was a contract that WestCorp would have been interested in. <eos/><bos/>At the time it was entered into, Scherzer, on behalf of WestCorp, was actively pursuing work from Nexen. <eos/><bos/>In 2013, PSE earned $454,000 from the Second Nexen Contract. <eos/><bos/>During the business year 2013, WestCorp suffered a significant drop in revenue. <eos/><bos/>PSE was removed from the Nexen jobsite in December 2013 and did not have an opportunity to continue the Second Nexen Contract to December 2014 or to negotiate a larger contract with Nexen.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Directors are precluded from obtaining either secretly or without the approval of the company, any property or business advantage either belonging to the company or for which it has been negotiating. <eos/><bos/>If a director seeks approval of the company it must do so upon full disclosure of the facts. <eos/><bos/>Courts impose a strict ethic on directors which disqualifies a director or senior officer from usurping for himself or diverting to another person or company with whom he is associated a maturing business opportunity.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Collins was a fiduciary of WestCorp from the time of its incorporation until his resignation. <eos/><bos/>His fiduciary duties came both from the operation of common law and from s. 142 of the BCA. <eos/><bos/>If a trust or fiduciary duty is imposed by statute, then a stranger to the trust will be deemed to have known of it. <eos/><bos/>As a director of WestCorp, Collins had a statutory fiduciary duty to WestCorp. <eos/><bos/>Lancaster was deemed to have known about Collins&apos; status as WestCorp&apos;s fiduciary.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Collins pursued a business opportunity that WestCorp was interested in while he was still a director of WestCorp. <eos/><bos/>Collins acknowledged that he concealed his conduct from WestCorp. <eos/><bos/>He decided to set up a competitor company, PSE, when he was a director of WestCorp. <eos/><bos/>He placed the shares in PSE in his wife&apos;s name and appointed Ames as a dummy director of PSE. <eos/><bos/>He registered a website but after receiving notice from Scherzer&apos;s litigation lawyer, he changed the administrative, technical, and registrant contact information on the website so that it would not be associated with him. <eos/><bos/>He failed to advise WestCorp that he was attempting to divert the Nexen opportunity to PSE. <eos/><bos/>He failed to disclose his interest in PSE to WestCorp even after Scherzer&apos;s litigation counsel sent a demand pursuant to s. 153 of the BCA. <eos/><bos/>Section 153 of the BCA requires that a director disclose a conflict of interest to the company immediately.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A stranger to a trust may be liable for assisting a fiduciary in a breach of that fiduciary&apos;s duty. <eos/><bos/>Knowing assistance or accessory liability is fault based. <eos/><bos/>The knowledge requirement for knowing assistance type liability is actual knowledge, recklessness or wilful blindness. <eos/><bos/>Constructive notice is insufficient.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>If a stranger misleads another with respect to their activities that could also be evidence of or lead to an inference of knowledge. <eos/><bos/>Silence by the stranger may satisfy the knowledge requirement where, for example, the stranger did nothing to correct the view of the beneficiary. <eos/><bos/>Justice Young observed that the authorities say that a stranger should know that a fraudulent and dishonest plan was being perpetrated but the stranger need not have knowledge of the whole design. <eos/><bos/>If a stranger to the trust knew that the fiduciary was concealing information from the principal, this will support a finding that the stranger knew of the fiduciary&apos;s dishonest conduct.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>When Collins incorporated PSE and negotiated the Second Nexen Contract, he knew or ought to have known that this was a corporate opportunity of interest to WestCorp and that he owed a duty to WestCorp. <eos/><bos/>As such he was taking a risk to the prejudice of WestCorp&apos;s rights. <eos/><bos/>This was fraudulent conduct. <eos/><bos/>Lancaster was deemed to have known of the fiduciary relationship between Collins and WestCorp because it was a statutory relationship. <eos/><bos/>The next step was to determine whether Lancaster knew of Collins&apos; fraudulent and dishonest conduct. <eos/><bos/>Justice Young drew an inference from the evidence that Lancaster either knew or ought to have known of Collins&apos; fiduciary duty and his fraudulent breach or that Lancaster was reckless and willfully blind. <eos/><bos/>Lancaster knew that Scherzer and Collins had a falling out. <eos/><bos/>It was Lancaster who initiated the activities that led to Collins&apos; breach of his fiduciary duty when Lancaster offered to Collins the opportunity to bring Stollsteimer to Nexen. <eos/><bos/>Lancaster intentionally did not make that offer to WestCorp. <eos/><bos/>This was very much a joint venture and Lancaster and Collins were partners throughout. <eos/><bos/>Lancaster relied on Collins to find a solicitor and incorporate a company. <eos/><bos/>It was a joint and conscious decision to issue shares to their wives and not to themselves and to appoint a dummy director and not themselves. <eos/><bos/>Justice Young inferred from this conduct that Lancaster and Collins were hiding their involvement in PSE. <eos/><bos/>Lancaster knew WestCorp was pursuing Nexen opportunities. <eos/><bos/>Rather than flatly denying the opportunity or telling Scherzer that WestCorp did not have a chance, he led Scherzer on. <eos/><bos/>Justice Young found this conduct to be deceitful. <eos/><bos/>When Lancaster became aware in June or July 2013 that Collins had a conflict and could not openly participate in PSE, he continued to conceal that fact by agreeing to backdate share transfers to the PSE incorporation date. <eos/><bos/>Justice Young concluded that Lancaster and Collins were acting together in all these actions and trying to conceal their dishonest conduct from WestCorp. <eos/><bos/>Lancaster knew of Collins&apos; fraudulent and dishonest breach of fiduciary duty and he initiated it and continued to participate in it. <eos/><bos/>He clearly knew the opportunity was one that WestCorp was interested in because was asking him for work for WestCorp. <eos/><bos/>He ignored any conflict that Collins had as not his problem.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Reasons Given by Court for Award</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>When the gain realized by a fiduciary and his accomplice is greater than that lost by a plaintiff, the plaintiff will likely elect an accounting as opposed to damages. <eos/><bos/>On the other hand, if a fiduciary and his accomplice lose money, the plaintiff should not be penalized for the business ineptitude of the fiduciary or its accomplice. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, if the loss by the plaintiff is greater than the profit of the fiduciary, damages would be better compensation. <eos/><bos/>WestCorp alleged that its loss was greater than the profit of the fiduciary and his accomplice. <eos/><bos/>The contract obtained by PSE was terminated early in December 2013.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Damages for breach of fiduciary duty is restitutionary. <eos/><bos/>WestCorp was entitled to be put in as good a position as it would have been had the breach not occurred.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Strict liability for breach of fiduciary duty is unaffected by the fact that the party seeking redress itself could not take advantage of the benefit “improperly” gained. <eos/><bos/>WestCorp was not required to prove that it would have obtained the Nexen opportunity. <eos/><bos/>What was relevant was the perspective of WestCorp and whether it abandoned its hope of capturing the Nexen opportunity. <eos/><bos/>In the circumstances, it was irrelevant whether WestCorp could in fact have obtained further work from Nexen. <eos/><bos/>The operative principle was that in these circumstances, Collins could not divert the opportunity to PSE.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In valuing an opportunity, the Court must take into account negative contingencies even in cases of breach of fiduciary duty.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>WestCorp claimed loss of earnings for two years being the duration of the Second Nexen Contract. <eos/><bos/>If it was true that Nexen did not have favourable views of WestCorp, then the PSE Defendants could have called witnesses from Nexen to prove it. <eos/><bos/>They did not do so and Justice Young drew a negative inference. <eos/><bos/>There was no proof that Nexen was dissatisfied with WestCorp&apos;s work. <eos/><bos/>Even if the PSE Defendants did prove that Nexen was dissatisfied with WestCorp&apos;s work, a victim of a breach of fiduciary duty will not be denied a remedy simply because the opportunity was not available to them. <eos/><bos/>The focus at law is whether or not WestCorp had abandoned its hope of obtaining the opportunity. <eos/><bos/>WestCorp did not abandon its hope of obtaining the opportunity.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Young could not find that PSE lost its contract because of the conduct of Lancaster. <eos/><bos/>Rather, Justice Young accepted Lancaster&apos;s evidence that Nexen was reviewing its contracting strategy and assessing contractors on site to determine which of the four contractors on site was going to continue. <eos/><bos/>His evidence was that one company was definitely going to continue and that there was an opportunity for one other company. <eos/><bos/>There was no guarantee that WestCorp would have been the second company to continue with Nexen.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In assessing damages, Justice Young concluded that there was a certainty that an opportunity would have been available in 2013 and that the opportunity lost by WestCorp was the actual revenue earned by PSE, after expenses. <eos/><bos/>The damages for loss of business opportunity in 2014 were more speculative and a negative contingency of 25% was to be applied to the calculation of damages for the second year. <eos/><bos/>For the business year 2013, WestCorp&apos;s loss of profits were $501,107. <eos/><bos/>For the business year 2014, WestCorp&apos;s loss of profits were $592,683 but Justice Young reduced that amount by 25% to allow for the negative contingency. <eos/><bos/>That reduced the loss of profits for 2014 to $444,512. <eos/><bos/>Total damages for the breach of fiduciary duty were $945,619.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A stranger participating or assisting in a breach of fiduciary duty is jointly and severally liable with the fiduciary for the losses associated with the breach. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, Collins and the PSE Defendants were jointly and severally liable for the losses associated with the breach. <eos/><bos/>Collins had paid $450,000 in settlement. <eos/><bos/>The PSE Defendants were therefore ordered to pay the outstanding balance of $495,619 in damages plus pre-judgment interest and post-judgement interest.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></section.body></section><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 4:39<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
