<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 4:40<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I5089a870411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>4.</label.designator><headtext>Confidential Business Information and the Employment Relationship</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I52517020411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>V.</label.designator><headtext>Fiduciary Duty</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I53a16fc0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>B.</label.designator><headtext>Remedies Table—Employment Relationship—Breach of Fiduciary Duty</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f65f4f6ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>4:40.</label.designator><headtext>Atlas Copco Canada Inc. v. David Hillier</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><ital>Atlas Copco Canada Inc. v. David Hillier</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 3654, 2018 ONSC 1588 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</headtext><eos/><eop/></head><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Award</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Damages for breach of fiduciary duty to the full extent of the $20 million amount claimed, subject to an obligation to account for any recoveries from other co-defendants in future.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Summary of Facts</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Plate was convicted of defrauding his former employer and was sentenced to five years in prison. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff sought summary judgment against him relying upon the jury verdict as well as a number of findings of fact made by the sentencing judge based upon the trial evidence.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Statement of Claim advanced a number of claims seeking damages arising from a fraudulent scheme that misappropriated funds from CMT and other business units of the plaintiff employing (i) false advances and bonuses; (ii) approvals of illegitimate expense reimbursements; and (iii) inflated and/or false invoices. <eos/><bos/>The former employees were alleged to have conspired with one another to perpetrate this scheme which involved the knowing submission of invoices and claims for payment that were fraudulent misrepresentations that caused damage. <eos/><bos/>Plate was alleged to have breached his fiduciary duties to the plaintiff to act in and demonstrate good faith towards the plaintiff and by his involvement in the fraudulent scheme, Plate was alleged to have breached his fiduciary duties to the plaintiff and thereby caused the plaintiff damages.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>For the purposes of sentencing, the sentencing judge made additional findings in relation to Plate&apos;s involvement in the offence including that while Plate was not a <begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>“central or integral member of the scheme”<end.quote refid="QT_0002"/>, given his positions with Atlas Copco, <begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>“his involvement was a gross breach of his fiduciary duty.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0001"/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Dunphy observed that the fraudulent scheme pleaded in the statement of claim was the same fraudulent scheme described in the Decision on Sentencing. <eos/><bos/>The fiduciary duty of Plate towards the plaintiff pleaded in the statement of claim arose out of the same relationship as the fiduciary duty about which the sentencing judge made findings of fact. <eos/><bos/>There was clearly a very large overlap of issues between the civil and criminal proceedings even if all the issues in the one were not present in the other and vice versa. <eos/><bos/>Findings made in criminal proceedings attract the doctrine of abuse of process more strongly. <eos/><bos/>In Justice Dunphy&apos;s view, the similarity of issues, the identity of the parties and the criminal nature of the prior proceeding all suggested that the findings of the sentencing judge were not only admissible but entitled to very considerable weight in this civil proceeding. <eos/><bos/>Determining that the findings of the sentencing judge were entitled to considerable weight did not amount to a finding that they were beyond question.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Dunphy concluded that the defendant had failed to introduce evidence from which the Court might conclude that there would be an unfairness worked by the application of the doctrine of abuse of process.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The findings in the Decision on Sentencing relative to fiduciary duty specific to Plate were well within the range of findings that were open to the Sentencing Judge to make in connection with sentencing. <eos/><bos/>In addition to being required to consider the gravity of the offence and the degree of responsibility of the offender under s. 718.1 of the <ital>Criminal Code</ital>, the Sentencing Judge was also entitled to consider the degree to which the offender abused a position of trust relative to the victim (s. 718.2(a)(iii) of the <ital>Criminal Code</ital>).<eos/><bos/> All such findings based upon the evidence at trial were open to the Sentencing Judge to consider and make. <eos/><bos/>The Decision on Sentencing made specific findings that Plate was a fiduciary. <eos/><bos/>The finding was one amply supported by Plate&apos;s title during the relevant time frame (General Manager of CMT and then vice-president) and by such description as the Decision on Sentencing contained regarding his duties and the vulnerability of Atlas Copco to him. <eos/><bos/>Justice Dunphy concluded that Plate was a fiduciary of Atlas Copco from 2002 until 2007.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Decision on Sentencing found that Plate had specific knowledge of the existence of the fraud scheme and of how it worked. <eos/><bos/>It found that he was in the best position to put a stop to it. <eos/><bos/>It found that his passive acquiescence allowed the fraud to continue. <eos/><bos/>However attenuated Plate&apos;s degree of involvement in the fraud scheme may have been, the Decision on Sentencing found that Plate was involved to some degree. <eos/><bos/>Justice Dunphy concluded that Plate breached his fiduciary duty to his employer Atlas Copco. <eos/><bos/>A fiduciary does not have the option of remaining mute in the presence of an identified, known scheme that is actively harming his employer. <eos/><bos/>Still less is he entitled to accept benefits and payments that Justice Dunphy inferred were in whole or in part made in return for his silence.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Reasons Given by Court for Award</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The question of what damages flowed from that breach required Justice Dunphy to make a determination of the start and end date of Plate&apos;s liability for breach of fiduciary duty and to determine whether the evidence permitted a quantification of the damages arising. <eos/><bos/>The Decision on Sentencing was not required to be precise on the date Plate acquired knowledge of the scheme and did not do so. <eos/><bos/>However, it was clear from the findings that were made that he had knowledge of the scheme and had received some payments arising from it by 2003 at the latest. <eos/><bos/>Justice Dunphy concluded that Plate&apos;s breach of fiduciary duty occurred no later than December 31, 2003. <eos/><bos/>Plate was promoted in December 2005 and became a Vice President of Atlas. <eos/><bos/>He ceased to be at the CMT division. <eos/><bos/>While he may thereafter have played no role in actively shielding the scheme from detection or in receiving payments in consideration of his silence, his fiduciary duty to his employer had not yet been discharged and was a continuing one. <eos/><bos/>The damages continued to accrue and he continued to do nothing to stop the scheme despite having the knowledge and the duty to do so. <eos/><bos/>Justice Dunphy concluded that Plate&apos;s liability for the consequences of his breach of fiduciary duty extended up until November 2007 when the fraud scheme was stopped by the termination of the employment of all of the active participants.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Dunphy concluded that the amount of the damages attributed to the breach of fiduciary duty was all of the damages arising from the fraudulent scheme that he failed in his duty to put an end to. <eos/><bos/>Those damages began no later than 2004 and continued through to 2007 when the fraud was stopped. <eos/><bos/>The net overbilling for that time frame had been found by Decision on Sentencing to be $22,336,335.38.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The damages determined by the forensic evidence and accepted as proved by the Sentencing Judge was for the entire scheme of overbilling or fraudulent billing over those years. <eos/><bos/>This included amounts received by other co- defendants whose fraud remained unhindered and undiscovered due to Plate&apos;s breach of fiduciary duty. <eos/><bos/>Justice Dunphy concluded that Plate was entitled to a credit against the $22,336,335.38 figure for: a. The amount of all of the annuities now seized or in the process of being seized by the plaintiff (Caron&apos;s, Hillier&apos;s and Plate&apos;s) of just under $2 million; b. The $77,930 ordered repaid by the criminal court; and c. any amounts recovered or to be recovered from other co-defendants in the future. <eos/><bos/>The Statement of Claim sought only $20 million in damages. <eos/><bos/>After crediting the first two sums against the $22.3 million figure, the remaining damages figure was very close to the claimed $20 million figure but was certainly slightly higher if calculated with precision. <eos/><bos/>Justice Dunphy determined that the plaintiff had proved its damages for breach of fiduciary duty to the full extent of the $20 million amount claimed, subject to an obligation to account for any recoveries from other co-defendants in future.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></section.body></section><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 4:40<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
