<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 1:20<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I4d7849c0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>1.</label.designator><headtext>Confidential Business Information in Historical Context</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I4df6a180411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>III.</label.designator><headtext>Policy Considerations Governing the Protection of Intellectual Property</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I4e0bfe40411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>B.</label.designator><headtext>Confidential Business Information Protection v. Patent/Copyright Protection)</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f59c166ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>1:20.</label.designator><headtext>Generally</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>It has been argued that all statutory protection for inventions and ideas should be achieved through patent and copyright laws since those laws adequately compensate inventors for their efforts. <eos/><bos/>Without the incentive of being able to protect and exploit information under patent laws, certain processes and machines might not come into being or be improved over the life of the patents. <eos/><bos/>When the patents expire, a large number of corporations can compete on price and through innovation. <eos/><bos/>Innovations usually lower costs and thus, in a competitive market, lower price. <eos/><bos/>Consumers are therefore usually best off when there are several competitors making the product.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Others have suggested that it is difficult to draft a patent claim in such a way that it is registrable, and that the criteria for drafting and enforcing patent claims need to be simplified so that patent protection would be a more attractive option.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Icf426c808e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>] With respect to confidential business information, this information cannot usually be classified as a “literary or artistic work” within the meaning of the <ital>Copyright Act</ital>, nor will a pure idea without a practical application be protected by the courts. <eos/><bos/>Further, confidential business information may not always be characterized as an “invention” within the meaning of the <ital>Patent Act</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Icf426c818e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>] as this would exclude ideas involving methods of doing business and purely mental processes. <eos/><bos/>Thus, many ideas, such as compilations, letters, reports and strategy statements may not be patentable or subject to protection by copyright law. <eos/><bos/>Furthermore, there is often the need for protection other than patent protection to enable an inventor to keep information confidential during or after the process of a new invention, even if the idea is patentable, as there may be insufficient time or money to obtain a patent where the idea is the subject of ongoing research.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The protection awarded to confidential business information is in some ways more advantageous, but in other ways less advantageous than the protection awarded to patents. <eos/><bos/>The advantages of utilizing confidential business information as compared to patent or copyright laws are:</paratext><list><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(1)</label.designator></head><paratext>Access to the information may be restricted indefinitely unless the other party has independently discovered the same idea.<eos/><bos/></paratext></para></list.item><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(2)</label.designator></head><paratext>The idea itself may be protected.<eos/><bos/></paratext></para></list.item><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(3)</label.designator></head><paratext>There are no costly registration requirements.<eos/><bos/></paratext></para></list.item><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(4)</label.designator></head><paratext>There is no compulsory licensing, and the information may never be declared to be invalid.<eos/><bos/></paratext></para></list.item></list><paratext>On the other hand, the cost of ensuring that the secret remains a secret may be high, and there is no guaranteed monopoly period. <eos/><bos/>The terms and conditions in a licence of confidential business information are generally more complex than those in a patent licence and are usually accompanied by a requirement for collateral, which suggests that they are more costly to enforce.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>If an inventor relies on the protection afforded to confidential business information, a combination of “reverse engineering” (uncovering the information independently through the same or similar process), expiration of restrictive covenants with skilled former employees, and misappropriation of confidential business information might generate competition before expiration of any patents. <eos/><bos/>On the other hand, if the innovation is immune to reverse engineering, except perhaps at extreme cost, and if information can be kept from competitors through restrictive covenants, competing products may never appear.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Icf4293908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">3</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In the landmark case of <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175807" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="RS" w-serial-number="1974127179" w-pub-number="0000780" ID="I12c184918e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Kewanee Oil Co. v. Bicron</cite.query> Corp.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Icf4293918e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">4</footnote.reference>] Justice Doug-las of the United States Supreme Court, in dissent, held that processes, as opposed to the designs of marketed products, might be immune from reverse engineering for more than the existing 17 years of patent protection if confidential business information which could be protected by patents were protected by the law as confidential business information. <eos/><bos/>Two categories of patentable information would thus exist without any particular justification for differing legal protection. <eos/><bos/>However, the majority of the United States Supreme Court upheld Kewanee&apos;s right to legal protection of confidential business information even where the invention could have been protected by patent law. <eos/><bos/>The court held:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>If a State, through a system of protection, were to cause a substantial risk that holders of patentable inventions would not seek patents, but rather would rely on the state protection, we would be compelled to hold that such a system could not constitutionally continue to exist. <eos/><bos/>In the case of trade secret law no reasonable risk of deterrence from patent application by those who can reasonably expect to be granted patents exists.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0001"/></paratext></para><head parent="display.quote"><headtext>…. .</headtext></head><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>[The usual state law cause of action] provides for weaker protection in many respects from the patent law so there is little reason to fear that inventors would prefer state law protection if the information is patentable. <eos/><bos/>The relative weakness cited by the Court is that reverse engineering is not forbidden, and that there is a substantial risk that the secret will be passed on to … competitors, by theft or by breach of a confidential relationship, in a manner not easily susceptible of discovery or proof … Where patent law acts as a barrier, trade secret law functions relatively as a sieve.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0002"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Icf42baa08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">5</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>There are famous examples of confidential business information being kept secret for centuries, like the metallurgical techniques for making cymbals held in one family since 1623, and the formula for Chartreuse liqueur, kept by the Carthusian monks for 400 years.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Icf42baa18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">6</footnote.reference>] However, in the late 20th century, technology is rapidly introducing new processes which are constantly changing, and protection is required for shorter periods while research is in progress. <eos/><bos/>In these circumstances, it may be wiser to attempt to keep the confidential business information secret and risk the possibility of reverse engineering and/or breach of contractual or fiduciary obligations rather than invest the substantial time and effort required to obtain patent protection. <eos/><bos/>Existing laws which protect confidential business information may achieve the proper balance of providing some assistance to creators and developers of new information without granting the absolute protection and concomitant obligation of lengthy and costly registration of patents.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Icf426c808e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>R.M. Milgrim, <ital>Trade Secrets</ital>, vol. 1 (New York: Matthew Bender and Co., 1978); A.N. Wise, <ital>Trade Secrets and Know-How Throughout the World</ital> (New York: Clark Boardman Co., 1974).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Icf426c818e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>R.S.C. 1985, c. P-4.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Icf4293908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>S. Cheung, “Property Rights and Trade Secrets”, <ital>Economic Inquiry</ital>, vol. xx (January 1982).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Icf4293918e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>4</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175807" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="RP" w-serial-number="1974127179" w-pub-number="0000780" ID="I12c2bd108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Kewanee Oil Co. v. Bicron Corp.</ital>, 416 U.S. 470 (1974)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Icf42baa08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>5</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175807" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="RP" w-serial-number="1974127179" w-pub-number="0000780" w-pinpoint-page="489" ID="I12c2e4208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Kewanee Oil Co. v. Bicron Corp.</ital>, 416 U.S. 470, at pp. 489-90 (1974)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Icf42baa18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>6</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>See T.M. Noone, “Trade Secret versus Patent Protection”, <ital>Research Mgmt.</ital>, vol. 21(3) (May 1978).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 1:20<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
