<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 3:12<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I4ed25b80411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>3.</label.designator><headtext>Defining Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I4eeaec90411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>II.</label.designator><headtext>Information Capable of Protection</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I4eecc150411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>A.</label.designator><headtext>The “Confidential” Nature of the Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f5ea316ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>3:12.</label.designator><headtext>Kind of Information—Identifiable and distinct</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>To be capable of protection, the information must, to some extent, be specific and identifiable.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id2bdfeb08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>] Further, the party seeking to protect the information must be able to convince the court that it has adequately demonstrated these attributes.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id2bdfeb18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>] For practical purposes, and since the onus will generally be on the party alleging the breach, the information should also be capable of being traced. <eos/><bos/>Where the party alleging a breach is unable to specifically identify what information was disseminated, and the responding party denies any misuse, the court will not uphold a claim for breach of confidential information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id2bdfeb28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">3</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Nail Cartel Inc. v. Duclos</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id2bdfeb38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">4</footnote.reference>] the plaintiff sued the defendants, pleading that the defendants unlawfully used the plaintiff&apos;s confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The defendants requested that paragraphs of the amended notice of civil claim dealing with the plaintiff&apos;s general allegation of the unlawful use of its confidential information by the defendants be struck, or in the alternative, particulars ordered to be provided. <eos/><bos/>Justice Funt observed that a plaintiff should not plead a serious allegation such as breach of fiduciary duty, or unlawful use of confidential information without some evidentiary basis. <eos/><bos/>If a plaintiff has an evidentiary basis to support a serious allegation, the plaintiff should be able to plead the particulars of the material facts to delineate the issues. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff&apos;s pleadings said little in connection with the unlawful use of confidential information and did not provide more than the understanding that the plaintiff <begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>“believes confidential information was passed to [the defendants] and they were under a duty of confidence not to misuse the same”<end.quote refid="QT_0001"/>. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff defined “Confidential Information” broadly. <eos/><bos/>Without particulars, this left the defendants not knowing whether the unlawful use of confidential information referred to, say, the “buying habits of prospective customers” or, say, “toxicological data”, or both, or neither. <eos/><bos/>Justice Funt did not accept the argument along the lines that the defendants knew what they did wrong and, accordingly, particulars were not required. <eos/><bos/>Justice Funt ordered particulars to be provided to the defendants.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id2bdfeb48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">5</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In breach of confidence cases, the plaintiff ought to specifically identify the information over which it claims a proprietary right, and the circumstances in which knowledge of the information came into the possession of the defendant such that use of the information by the defendant would be unconscionable. <eos/><bos/>In <cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2011362653" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I1edfef518e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Blue Line Hockey Acquisition Co. v. Orca Bay Hockey Ltd. Partnership</ital></cite.query>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id2be25c08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">6</footnote.reference>] the action concerned the sale of the Vancouver Canucks, General Motors Place and the assets relating to both. <eos/><bos/>Blue Line alleged that Gaglardi, Beedie and Aquilini formed a partnership to pursue the acquisition of an interest in the Enterprise. <eos/><bos/>According to Blue Line, the three partners agreed they would not pursue their objective without the involvement of all partners. <eos/><bos/>It was alleged that under the Partnership, Aquilini owed a fiduciary duty to the other partners to refrain from diverting opportunities to acquire an interest in the Enterprise to himself, and to refrain from using confidential information of the Partnership for his own benefit. <eos/><bos/>The Partnership entered into negotiations with the Orca Bay Defendants in November 2003. <eos/><bos/>Blue Line alleged that Aquilini left the Partnership some months later and secretly pursued the acquisition of an interest in the Enterprise with the Orca Bay Defendants. <eos/><bos/>Blue Line alleged that Aquilini, in the course of his secret negotiations with the Orca Bay Defendants, used confidential information he obtained from the Partnership. <eos/><bos/>Negotiations between Blue Line and the Orca Bay Defendants ended on November 5, 2005. <eos/><bos/>On the same day, some of the Aquilini Defendants entered into the Investment Agreement with some of the Orca Bay Defendants to acquire a 50 per cent interest in the Enterprise.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id2be25c18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">7</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Aquilini Defendants applied for an order that Blue Line provide further and better particulars as to the individual items of confidential information obtained by the Partnership which, according to the Amended Statement of Claim, the Aquilini Defendants acquired, and when and from whom each item of confidential information was acquired by the Aquilini Defendants; when, where, and of whom the Aquilini Defendants, according to the Amended Statement of Claim, requested confidential information from other members of the Partnership at the time the Aquilini Defendants left the Partnership, and what individual items of information were provided pursuant to such requests; the individual items of confidential information obtained from the Partnership which, according to the Amended Statement of Claim, the Aquilini Defendants used when negotiating with the Orca Bay Defendants.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id2be25c28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">8</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff argued that they should not required to particularize the constituent parts. <eos/><bos/>Rather, the confidential information was, in essence, the contents of the negotiations as embodied in the various drafts of the Term Sheet and the strategies of Blue Line in respect of them. <eos/><bos/>It was not each individual piece of information that was important but the bargaining positions as a whole and the negotiating strategies behind them.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id2be25c38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">9</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motions judge did not accept this submission and concluded that the particulars must delineate both the confidential information allegedly possessed by the Aquilini Defendants and the confidential information allegedly used by them to conclude the Investment Agreement.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id2be25c48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">10</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motions judge acknowledged that particularization of the information alleged to be confidential may be more difficult in this case than in many breach of confidence or “trade secret” cases. <eos/><bos/>Nevertheless, at trial the plaintiff would be required to establish more than simply that Aquilini <begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>“knew the mind of the purchasing group”<end.quote refid="QT_0002"/>. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff would be required to identify the information that was confidential and establish the proprietary nature of that information. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff would be required to prove facts establishing that Aquilini received the proprietary information in circumstances requiring that the information remain confidential, or facts from which such an inference can reasonably be drawn. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff would also be required to establish facts which proved that the Aquilini Defendants used the information for purposes of concluding the Investment Agreement, or facts from which that inference could reasonably be drawn. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, the plaintiff must identify, by way of particulars, the information it says is confidential information, the circumstances in which the information was conveyed to the Aquilini Defendants, and the confidential information it says the Aquilini Defendants used to acquire its interest in the Enterprise. <eos/><bos/>All aspects of the breach of confidence claim must be amenable to such particularization, and the Aquilini Defendants were entitled to those particulars before trial.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id2be4cd08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">11</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>On the basis of <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1983031647" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I1ee45c218e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Fraser v. Thames Television</cite.query> Ltd.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id2be4cd18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">12</footnote.reference>] some courts have expanded on the concept that information must be clearly identifiable. <eos/><bos/>For example, the Ontario decision in <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1985263355" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I1ee45c238e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Promotivate International Inc. v. Toronto Star Newspapers</cite.query> Ltd.</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id2be4cd28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">13</footnote.reference>] turned on whether or not a promotion for a newspaper lottery suggested by the plaintiff was “original”, <ital>i.e.</ital>, not “public property and public knowledge”:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0003"/>Here we are dealing with a newspaper lottery. <eos/><bos/>Newspaper lotteries with consecutively-numbered issues are not new to the newspaper business and had been operated before in Philadelphia and Cincinnati to the knowledge of the Toronto Star. <eos/><bos/>The Toronto Star was already considering a consecutively-numbered lottery and the purchase of the necessary equipment before any approach was made by Promotivate. <eos/><bos/>The only thing new was the concept of the application of the Ontario Provincial type reduced prize to reduced numbers to a newspaper lottery, so that instead of one prizewinner there would be multiple prizewinners. <eos/><bos/><ital>The concept was very well-known</ital> <ital>and I cannot accept that the idea of applying the concept to a newspaper</ital> <ital>lottery warrants the protection of the court. <eos/><bos/>It was the sort of concept that could be and was applied to any type of lottery where there was to be more than one winner.<eos/><bos/></ital><end.quote refid="QT_0003"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id2be4cd38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">14</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2047688097" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I1ee7de918e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>CTT Pharmaceutical Holdings v. Rapid Dose Therapeutics</ital></cite.query>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id2be4cd48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">15</footnote.reference>] the Defendant moved for summary judgment on the basis that there was no evidence in support of the Plaintiff&apos;s claim. <eos/><bos/>The principals of the Plaintiff had experience with manufacturing pharmaceuticals and the principals of the Defendant had experience in marketing various products. <eos/><bos/>The parties entered an Asset Purchase Agreement pursuant to which the Defendant was to purchase the Plaintiff&apos;s assets. <eos/><bos/>These consisted primarily of two patents relating to oral thin, dissolvable strips. <eos/><bos/>The parties proposed joining efforts to market oral dissolvable strips impregnated with cannabis, which they planned to introduce as a new product on the Canadian market once the legislation legalizing the possession, sale, and consumption of cannabis came into force. <eos/><bos/>At some point during its due diligence exercise the Defendant apparently concluded that the Plaintiff&apos;s technology was ineffective for the desired use. <eos/><bos/>The parties had a mutual falling out, and the Plaintiff issued a formal notice to the Defendant terminating the Asset Purchase Agreement.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id2bf37308e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">16</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Plaintiff alleged that there were three areas of confidential information on which the claim was particularly focused: a) the identity of ODF Pharma, b) the identity of HED International, and c) patent applications prepared by the Plaintiff which had not yet been laid open to the public. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiff stressed that only someone who had been taken into the Plaintiff&apos;s confidence would know about several patent applications that the Plaintiff had prepared and drafted but not yet submitted. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiff emphasized that while approved patents are public information that anyone can access, and so there is no allegation here alleging that the Defendant had learned in confidence of the Plaintiff&apos;s two approved patents, the Plaintiff&apos;s as-yet unsubmitted patent applications were in a different category altogether.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id2bf5e408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">17</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Morgan observed that the Plaintiff, in theory, was right. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, Justice Morgan inquired what it was that was being applied for in the as-yet unsubmitted patent applications. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiff indicated that the record did not contain that information, and so there was no way of knowing what kind of device or product the Plaintiff was seeking to patent. <eos/><bos/>There was simply affidavit evidence indicating that there were several otherwise unidentified patent applications disclosed to the Defendant during the course of their contractual relationship. <eos/><bos/>Justice Morgan observed that it was self-evident that if the record contained no evidence of the nature of the patent applications, then it equally contained no evidence of the Defendant&apos;s supposed misuse of the information contained therein. <eos/><bos/>If the Plaintiff had prepared applications to patent a new device, product, chemical formula, etc., and the Defendant had appropriated that knowledge and was now using the new device, product, chemical formula, etc. for its own ends, then that device, product, chemical formula, etc. would be identified in the record. <eos/><bos/>Otherwise, the claim could not possibly succeed. <eos/><bos/>Justice Morgan noted that no one sues for appropriating confidential information without bringing evidence as to the allegedly improper use of that information, and that could not possibly be done without in some way revealing what that information was.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id2bf5e418e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">18</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Morgan noted that that parties to a summary judgment motion are required to <begin.quote ID="QT_0004"/>“put their best foot forward. <eos/><bos/>The motion judge is entitled to assume that the record contains everything that the parties have at their disposal, and that there is nothing further that they are holding back for trial. <eos/><bos/>The failure of the Plaintiff to put evidence in the record that described the nature of the information supposedly misused by the Defendant, information that was obviously within the knowledge and possession of the Plaintiff, was fatal to this claim.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0004"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id2bf5e428e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">19</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2048188720" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I1eedf9118e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Dowd et al. v. Skip the Dishes Restaurant Services Inc.</cite.query> et al</ital>.,[<footnote.reference refid="Id2bf5e438e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">20</footnote.reference>] the statement of claim sought relief against all of the defendants, jointly and severally, for twelve different alleged causes of action, including breach of confidence, for in excess of $160,000,000. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs alleged that the defendants Skip and Simair, who was at all material times the principal and directing mind of Skip, participated in conversations and discussions leading to an alleged agreement, or partnership with the plaintiffs. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs alleged that the terms of this partnership or contract, involved them sharing “confidential or proprietary information” with Skip and/or Simair to develop a delivery platform in Winnipeg. <eos/><bos/>Skip and/or Simair agreed, in exchange, that the plaintiffs would provide exclusive delivery services for Skip, would be paid for those deliveries, and/or would share in the profits of Skip. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs plead that these negotiations/discussions took place in fall of 2012, with delivery services going live in or around October 2012, and continuing to January 16, 2013. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs further plead that they did provide confidential and proprietary information to Skip, that Skip used that information to develop its delivery platform, and that Cravers provided exclusive delivery services for Skip during the material time for a fee, plus a portion of the profits of Skip. <eos/><bos/>The information in question was defined as <begin.quote ID="QT_0005"/>“a coded delivery system, driver, delivery and customer information, guidance and assistance …”<end.quote refid="QT_0005"/>. <eos/><bos/>Finally, the plaintiffs plead that, on or about January 16, 2013, Skip stopped using Cravers for the provision of delivery services and purported to terminate the agreement between them. <eos/><bos/>After that termination, the plaintiffs say that Skip and/or Simair continued to do business with third party restaurants with whom the plaintiffs had pre-existing business relationships.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id2bf85508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">21</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Master was not prepared to strike the claim against Skip. <eos/><bos/>The statement of claim, along with the particulars, contained sufficient material facts to support the allegations against Skip. <eos/><bos/>With respect to the claim for breach of confidence, Skip suggested that it must fail primarily for failure to adequately identify the proprietary or confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The Master did not agree. <eos/><bos/>Between the statement of claim and particulars, the plaintiffs identified specific information in a manner that was sufficient to provide Skip with knowledge of what the information in question was. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs specifically identified the proprietary or confidential information at issue to include a coded delivery system, driver names, delivery and customer information, and a pricing model. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs plead the information was provided in confidence, for the purpose of entering into a contract or partnership to help build the business grow. <eos/><bos/>Finally, the plaintiffs alleged the confidence was breached and damages resulted. <eos/><bos/>No further amendments or particulars were needed for Skip to respond.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id2bf85518e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">22</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>JTT Electronics Ltd. v. Farmer</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id2bf85528e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">23</footnote.reference>] the plaintiffs&apos; application for injunctive relief against two former employees, including orders prohibiting them from using the confidential information of JTT and requiring them to deliver up all confidential information of JTT in their possession suffered from the insurmountable difficulty the plaintiffs were unable to define what confidential information they sought to protect.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id2bf85538e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">24</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A significant part of the plaintiffs&apos; concerns resulted from the interactions that the employees, who both held senior positions with the JTT, had with Farmer and his two companies in December 2013. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs suspected, from some of the materials they have uncovered, that the employees dealt with Farmer and his companies in order to set up a new business that would be operated by them and that would compete with JTT. They also believed that the employees disclosed confidential information, including pricing information, to Farmer. <eos/><bos/>On March 14, 2014, each of the Personal Defendants was dismissed.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id2bf85548e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">25</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motions judge observed that enjoining the use of and compelling the delivery of confidential information required that the plaintiffs do more than establish a “serious question” that they possessed some form of confidential information and that the conduct of the employees indicated that this information might be misused. <eos/><bos/>It was also necessary that the plaintiffs identify, with some reasonable degree of precision, what the confidential information was regardless of whether the plaintiffs sought to protect JTT&apos;s confidential information in contract or as a breach of confidence or on the basis that the employees were fiduciaries or on the basis that they owed JTT a duty of good faith as employees. <eos/><bos/>No such identification was made. <eos/><bos/>Indeed, the relief sought in the notice of application was entirely generic. <eos/><bos/>The pleadings, the notice of application, the draft order, a Shareholders&apos; Agreement, an Assignment of Intellectual Property Agreement, a Non-Disclosure and Confidentiality Agreement, and a Consulting Agreement, were all devoid of any adequate description of what was confidential to JTT or to its business. <eos/><bos/>Those descriptions that included some limited expressions of what was ostensibly confidential to JTT, such as its pricing information, were lost in the morass of other generic language. <eos/><bos/>It was not the Court&apos;s role or function to try to construct a sensible order from the breadth of generic language given. <eos/><bos/>The language identified in the plaintiffs&apos; notice of application, in the draft order, and in either of the agreements is language that could pertain to virtually any business that made virtually any product. <eos/><bos/>The motions judge stated:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0006"/>The need to identify with some reasonable degree of specificity what a plaintiff asserts is confidential or proprietary serves three important and related functions. <eos/><bos/>First, it enables a defendant to respond to an application and the relief sought in the application, and to bring into question whether the purported confidential information is in fact confidential or whether it is information that is in the public domain. <eos/><bos/>Certainly that is a relevant issue in this case. <eos/><bos/>Potter deposes that much of JTT&apos;s information or processes are broadly used in the battery industry. <eos/><bos/>That assertion is not really questioned by JTT. Second, if a plaintiff can establish that specific information in its possession is confidential, and the remaining elements of an injunction are made out, the defendant is put on notice, in the form of an order, of what it is that he or she can or cannot do. <eos/><bos/>Third, in the event that there is an allegation that a defendant has not complied with the terms of an order restraining the use of specific confidential information, the court is in a position to address the alleged breach. <eos/><bos/>Absent some reasonable level of precision or definition, the issue of enforcement is rendered either more difficult or impossible.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0006"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id2bfac608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">26</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The form of order proposed by the plaintiffs lacked the clarity and specificity which is required and which would enable the employees to regulate their future conduct. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, the motions judge declined to grant the plaintiffs the relief which sought to restrain the employees from using confidential information as well as the relief which would compel them to deliver up all confidential information in their possession.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id2bfac618e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">27</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2047688100" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I1ef6f9c18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Evertz Technologies Limited v. Lawo</cite.query> AG</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id2bfac628e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">28</footnote.reference>] each group of defendants brought a motion to strike out the statement of claim in its entirety without leave to amend and to dismiss the action on the ground that Evertz, despite having been asked for particulars, failed to identify what “confidential information” was misappropriated, how the alleged confidential information was misused, and what part of the Providius products were developed using this information. <eos/><bos/>The defendants&apos; motions were granted and the statement of claim struck out. <eos/><bos/>Leave was granted to Evertz to serve an amended statement of claim.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id2bfac638e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">29</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiffs Evertz were technology companies that were in the business of providing video and audio infrastructure solutions for the television, telecommunications, and new-media industries. <eos/><bos/>The individual defendants were formerly employed by Evertz. <eos/><bos/>Evertz alleged that the individual defendants stole its confidential information to take to use at their competing business venture, Providius. <eos/><bos/>Evertz alleged that the individual defendants and Providius lacked the wherewithal to develop a competing product on their own, and they colluded with the defendants Lawo. <eos/><bos/>Evertz alleged that Lawo used the individual defendants and Providius to funnel confidential information out of Evertz and into its own products.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id2bfac648e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">30</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In the statement of claim, Evertz pleaded facts in relation to what it called the “Evertz IP Solution”:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0008"/>40. <eos/><bos/>Evertz has developed the market-leading solution for converting traditional broadcast network communication standards to IP (the “Evertz IP Solution”).<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0008"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0009"/>41. <eos/><bos/>Evertz initiated its IP strategy more than eight years ago, making annual investments in research and development. <eos/><bos/>Over the past eight years, Evertz has invested more than $450 million in research and development, a significant portion of which to develop the Evertz IP Solution.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0009"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0010"/>42. <eos/><bos/>The Evertz IP Solution includes a series of products and technologies for converting traditional broadcast networks to IP.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0010"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0011"/>43. <eos/><bos/>Evertz award-winning MViP is an IP-based, multi-image display and monitoring transmission solution to optimize broadcast speed and quality over IP-based networks. <eos/><bos/>MViP has become the gold standard among multiviewer monitoring and transport stream solutions in the broadcast industry, enabling simultaneous live broadcasting of audio and video over an IP-based transport stream.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0011"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0012"/>44. <eos/><bos/>The products and technologies that make up the Evertz IP Solution include, but are not limited to:<end.quote refid="QT_0012"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0013"/>(a) Multiviewer products, including MViP, MViP II, MVP, and VIP10G;<end.quote refid="QT_0013"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0014"/>(b) Transport stream monitor products, including 348TSM IP and 7880TSM IP;<end.quote refid="QT_0014"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0015"/>(c) IP gateway products, including 7880 IPG8-10GE2; and<end.quote refid="QT_0015"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0016"/>(d) Control, orchestration, and analytic products, including Magnum.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0016"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0017"/>45. <eos/><bos/>The proprietary elements of the Evertz IP Solution include, but are not limited to, software-defined networking, system architecture, and product solution, which together form the cornerstone of the research and development roadmap for future technological advances by Evertz.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0017"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id2bfd3708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">31</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><paratext>In the statement of claim, under the heading <begin.quote ID="QT_0007"/>“The Defendants&apos; Theft of Confidential Information”<end.quote refid="QT_0007"/>, Evertz pleaded:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0018"/>81. <eos/><bos/>Despite being a new company with few resources, Providius somehow released a product line with extremely similar attributes to the Evertz IP Solution - an accomplishment that had required many years and millions of dollars in research and development investment by Evertz.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0018"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0019"/>82. <eos/><bos/>In or about May 2016, Providius launched the BMG Solution, a product line substantially similar to the Evertz IP Solution.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0019"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0020"/>83. <eos/><bos/>On April 7-12, 2018, the National Association of Broadcasters held its NAB Show in Las Vegas. <eos/><bos/>The NAB Show was the largest trade show for media, entertainment, and technology.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0020"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0021"/>84. <eos/><bos/>Evertz attended the NAB Show and visited what Evertz had expected to be the booth for Providius. <eos/><bos/>When Evertz approached the booth, it noticed the booth was instead emblazoned with the logo for Lawo, and it was marketing the BMG Solution as Lawo&apos;s product.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0021"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0022"/>85. <eos/><bos/>As Evertz knows now, the BMG Solution was in fact an illicit copy of the Evertz IP Solution, and it had been developed and marketed through collusion by Lawo, Providius, and the Individual Defendants.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0022"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0023"/>86. <eos/><bos/>The defendants have developed and marketed additional illicit copies of the Evertz IP Solution, including the Lawo-branded smartScope and Expandable IP Multiviewer.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0023"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0024"/>87. <eos/><bos/>Unbeknownst to Evertz, while the Individual Defendants were still employed by Evertz, they stole Evertz&apos;s confidential information and used it for the benefit of themselves, Providius, and Lawo.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0024"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0025"/>88. <eos/><bos/>In particular, the Individual Defendants sought out proprietary confidential information from Evertz relating to the Evertz IP Solution and shared the information to recipients outside the Evertz organization, including Providius and Lawo.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0025"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0026"/>89. <eos/><bos/>The defendants executed the scheme in part by having the Individual Defendants send confidential aspects of the Evertz IP Solution, including information that was not relevant to their employment, to their private email.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0026"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0027"/>90. <eos/><bos/>The Individual Defendants stole confidential information from Evertz in violation of their Confidentiality Agreements, including their agreement to maintain the confidentiality over Evertz&apos;s information, and to assign to Evertz the rights to any work they created, solely or jointly conceived, or caused to be conceived during their employment.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0027"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0028"/>91. <eos/><bos/>The information the defendants stole from Evertz included confidential information about the Evertz IP solution, including, among other things, software, architecture, product solution, roadmap, materials, workflow, and pricing information.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0028"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0029"/>92. <eos/><bos/>Lawo, Providius, and the Individual Defendants acted as a single, overarching conspiracy to build their own IP-based broadcast network product line using stolen information from Evertz.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0029"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0030"/>93. <eos/><bos/>As of April 2018, Evertz learned that Providius was acquired by, merged with, or licensed use of the BMG Solution to Lawo. <eos/><bos/>Any compensation received from the arrangement between Lawo and Providius constituted ill-gotten gains resulting from the defendants&apos; wrongful conduct and theft of confidential information.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0030"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id2bffa808e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">32</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Evertz served responses to the Defendants&apos; Demand for Particulars and Request to Inspect Documents by stating that the <begin.quote ID="QT_0032"/>“confidential information of Evertz was defined at paragraphs 42 to 45 of the Statement of Claim”<end.quote refid="QT_0032"/>, and that <begin.quote ID="QT_0031"/>“the confidential information alleged to have been stolen, taken or memorized by the defendants was defined at paragraphs 42 to 45 of the Statement of Claim”<end.quote refid="QT_0031"/>. <eos/><bos/>The responses did not provide additional particulars of the “confidential information” described in the statement of claim. <eos/><bos/>Many of the responses repeated the statements in the statement of claim, and added that additional particulars requested were within the knowledge of the defendants or, in some cases, the individual defendants, or some of them.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id2c021908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">33</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Evertz&apos;s counsel wrote to counsel for the Providius Defendants to provide further particulars with respect to Evertz&apos;s claim. <eos/><bos/>In this letter, Evertz&apos;s counsel stated that they were providing <begin.quote ID="QT_0034"/>“the particulars Evertz currently had regarding the improper taking of confidential information”<end.quote refid="QT_0034"/>. <eos/><bos/>Evertz&apos;s counsel&apos;s letter listed 22 emails and general descriptions of the information transmitted by these 22 emails. <eos/><bos/>The letter also provided what was described as <begin.quote ID="QT_0035"/>“the particulars currently within the knowledge of Evertz”<end.quote refid="QT_0035"/> with respect to the products of Lawo and Providius that incorporated confidential information belonging to Evertz. <eos/><bos/>The letter from Evertz&apos;s counsel concluded with the statement <begin.quote ID="QT_0033"/>“[w]e anticipate that more information regarding both the taking of confidential information by the defendant and its incorporation into the defendants&apos; products will be obtained during discoveries”<end.quote refid="QT_0033"/>.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id2c048a08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">34</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motions judge observed that the authorities cited by the defendants establish that a plaintiff who pleads a cause of action for breach of confidence must plead the material facts upon which the claim is based, and the facts cannot consist of bald, conclusory, allegations that a group of defendants took or misused “confidential information”.<eos/><bos/> Each defendant is entitled to know with particularity what confidential information the defendant is alleged to have taken, and the acts allegedly taken by the defendant to misuse the confidential information. <eos/><bos/>It is not an answer for a plaintiff to say that these facts are within the knowledge of the defendants, or that the information will be provided after examinations for discovery have been conducted. <eos/><bos/>In paragraph 91 of the statement of claim, Evertz pleaded that <begin.quote ID="QT_0036"/>“[t]he information the defendants stole from Evertz included confidential information about the Evertz IP solution, including, among other things, software, architecture, product solution, roadmap, materials, workflow, and pricing information”<end.quote refid="QT_0036"/>. <eos/><bos/>These descriptions of categories of confidential information were too vague and general to satisfy the minimum requirement for pleading material facts to support a claim for breach of confidence.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id2c048a18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">35</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In paragraph 92 of the statement of claim, Evertz pleaded that <begin.quote ID="QT_0037"/>“Lawo, Providius, and the Individual Defendants acted as a single, overarching conspiracy to build their own IP-based broadcast network product line using stolen information from Evertz”<end.quote refid="QT_0037"/>. <eos/><bos/>This pleading also did not allege material facts that were sufficient meet the minimum level of material fact disclosure because the pleading did not inform each defendant of the acts that Evertz alleged the defendant took to misuse Evertz&apos;s confidential information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id2c048a28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">36</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motions judge did not agree that the particulars provided sufficient material facts that would allow the defendants to know the confidential information that each defendant was alleged to have misappropriated, or the acts taken by each defendant to misuse the confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The statement of claim, even as supplemented by the responses to the demands for particulars, did not reach the minimum level of material fact disclosure that is required for a statement of claim that pleads causes of action based upon alleged misappropriation and misuse of confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The proper order was to strike out the statement of claim.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id2c048a38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">37</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motions judge noted that leave to amend a pleading can properly be given where it is possible to cure deficiencies in a pleading. <eos/><bos/>Leave to amend should only be refused in the clearest of cases. <eos/><bos/>The facts pleaded in the statement of claim as supplemented by the first responses to the defendants&apos; demands for particulars and the particulars provided in the November 23, 2018 letter were not sufficient to satisfy the minimum level of fact disclosure that is required for causes of action based upon alleged misappropriation and misuse of confidential information. <eos/><bos/>However, the motions judge was not satisfied that the statement of claim was necessarily fatally defective or that it would not be possible for Evertz to cure the defects in its pleading through proper amendments. <eos/><bos/>This was not a case where Evertz should be denied leave to amend its statement of claim.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id2c048a48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">38</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Furfari v. Pedias</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id2c06fb08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">39</footnote.reference>] the Plaintiff claimed that the defendant entered his home while he was on vacation and took some confidential documents and sought damages totaling $300,000, including aggravated and punitive damages. <eos/><bos/>The Defendant&apos;s motion to strike the claim on the basis that the claim did not plead the necessary elements and material facts to support the claim for breach of confidence, and that the claim for aggravated was not properly pleaded was allowed.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id2c06fb18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">40</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Plaintiff and the Defendant had been friends until recently. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiff was also friends with the Defendant&apos;s brother, Mario. <eos/><bos/>The claim was very short and made the following allegations of fact against the Defendant:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0038"/>1. The Plaintiff owns a farm located in King City, Ontario (“Property”).<eos/><bos/> The Plaintiff from time to time would hire the Defendant to carry out a variety of handyman type projects at the Property, including installation and maintenance of internet service and security systems.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0038"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0039"/>2. The Defendant was thus familiar with the Property and enjoyed unsupervised access to it for purposes of the projects given to him by the Plaintiff but for no other purpose.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0039"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0040"/>3. The Defendant understood and agreed that the Plaintiff granted him access to his private property on the basis of the Defendant&apos;s undertaking and promise of confidence and the Defendant&apos;s promise to protect and maintain the Plaintiff&apos;s privacy at all times.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0040"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0041"/>4. On or about May 2018 when the Plaintiff was out of the country and without his knowledge or authorization, the Defendant alone or in concert with others gained access to the Property and removed personal and confidential papers, documents and records of the Plaintiff relating to his personal, financial and banking affairs (“Removed Items”).<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0041"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0042"/>5. Mario was aware that the Plaintiff was out of the country during this time.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0042"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0043"/>6. The actions by the Defendant were unauthorized and were taken without lawful authority or excuse and without colour of right.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0043"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0044"/>7. To the knowledge of the Defendant and Mario, taking of the Removed Items from the Property and any use to which they could be put would be unauthorized by the Plaintiff as well as unlawful.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0044"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0045"/>8. Also to the knowledge of the Defendant, dissemination of the Removed Items to anyone would be detrimental to the Plaintiff and his personal and financial interests.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0045"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id2c06fb28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">41</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Following the service of the statement of claim, the Defendant made a demand for particulars, including a request that the specific documents removed be identified. <eos/><bos/>In response, the Plaintiff did not provide any particulars, in some cases on the grounds that no further particulars were available and in other cases that the request was not the proper subject of a demand for particulars.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id2c096c08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">42</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A claim for breach of confidence requires a plaintiff to prove three elements including that a. the information was confidential; b. the information was conveyed in confidence; and c. the information was misused by the party to whom it was communicated to the detriment of the confider. <eos/><bos/>The Defendant argued that the statement of claim did not properly plead the first and third elements of the claim for breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>With respect to the first element, he argued that the claim did not sufficiently identify the documents to establish that they were confidential. <eos/><bos/>With respect to the third element, he argued that there was no pleading that the information was misused in a way that caused damage to the Plaintiff.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id2c096c18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">43</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>While the motions judge concluded that the first element was sufficiently pleaded, the motions judge agreed that the last element was not properly pleaded. <eos/><bos/>With respect to the first element, the requirement is that the information be confidential. <eos/><bos/>In this case, the claim described the documents as <begin.quote ID="QT_0046"/>“personal and confidential papers, documents and records of the Plaintiff relating to his personal, financial and banking affairs”<end.quote refid="QT_0046"/>. <eos/><bos/>While the claim did not identify the specific documents allegedly taken, they were described as “confidential” and as including financial and banking information, which is information typically considered as confidential. <eos/><bos/>In the motions judge&apos;s view, this was sufficient for the purposes of pleading the first element of the tort of breach of confidence.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id2c096c28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">44</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>With respect to the third element, the claim did not plead that the information was misused by the defendant to the Plaintiff&apos;s detriment. <eos/><bos/>In Lysko v. Braley, the Court of Appeal noted that the concept of “detriment” in the context of a claim for breach of confidence is broad enough <begin.quote ID="QT_0048"/>“to include the emotional or psychological distress that would result from the disclosure of intimate information”<end.quote refid="QT_0048"/>. <eos/><bos/>However, there was no pleading that the Defendant misused the information to the Plaintiff&apos;s detriment. <eos/><bos/>For example, there was no pleading that the information was conveyed to a third party and that the disclosure had a detrimental effect on the Plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>Instead, the pleading on this point was entirely speculative, stating that the Defendant knew that <begin.quote ID="QT_0047"/>“dissemination of the Removed Items to anyone would be detrimental to the Plaintiff and his personal and financial interests”<end.quote refid="QT_0047"/>.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id2c096c38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">45</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motions judge concluded that the Plaintiff should be given an opportunity to remedy the deficiencies in the claims for breach of confidence and for aggravated damages. <eos/><bos/>This was not a case where the claim was so deficient that it could not be remedied or where the Plaintiff had already been given an opportunity to amend his claim.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id2c096c48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">46</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Pastor v. Chen</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id2c096c58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">47</footnote.reference>] the court held that dance steps taught by the plaintiff that were not in the public domain would be considered confidential information worthy of protection by the courts.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Unless information is clearly identifiable and distinct, it will be impossible to determine whether it is confidential. <eos/><bos/>The court in <ital>Faccenda Chicken Ltd. v. Fowler</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id2c0bdd08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">48</footnote.reference>] held that a factor worthy of consideration was whether the relevant information could have easily been isolated from other information that an individual was free to use and disclose:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0049"/>For our part we would not regard the separability of the information in question as being conclusive, but the fact that the alleged “confidential” information is part of a package and that the remainder of the package is not confidential is likely to throw light on whether the information in question is really a trade secret.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0049"/></paratext></para></display.quote><paratext>In denying protection, the court specifically observed that the relevant sales information contained some material that Faccenda Chicken Ltd. conceded was not confidential if looked at in isolation, and that the information about prices was not clearly severable from the rest of the sales information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id2c0bdd18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">49</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00007" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1983031647" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I1f135b618e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Fraser v. Thames Television</cite.query> Ltd.</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id2c0bdd28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">50</footnote.reference>] also confirms the fact that an idea must be distinct and identifiable in order to be protected:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><ital><begin.quote ID="QT_0050"/>This of course does not mean that every stray mention of an idea by one person to another is protected.<eos/><bos/></ital> To succeed in his claim the plaintiff must establish not only that the occasion of communication was confidential, <ital>but also that the content of the idea was clearly identifiable, original, of potential commercial attractiveness and capable of being realised in actuality</ital>.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0050"/></paratext></para></display.quote><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00008" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1972098569" w-pub-number="0005652" ID="I1f141eb18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Gibbons v. Drew Chemical</cite.query> Ltd.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id2c0bdd38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">51</footnote.reference>] the Supreme Court of British Columbia dealt with a situation where a company alleged that its former employee, after the termination of his employment, had breached a covenant not to disclose confidential information. <eos/><bos/>Upon reviewing the evidence, the court concluded that the employee had not delivered any confidential information to a third party or made any other improper use. <eos/><bos/>It stated that, at best, the evidence put forward by the company was inconclusive:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0051"/>The defendant, in my opinion, has failed to prove that the plaintiff delivered confidential documents of “Drew” to a third party. <eos/><bos/>If [the company&apos;s representative] authorized the release of the documents that would be an end of the matter. <eos/><bos/>The evidence called by the defendant to establish the confidential nature of the documents delivered by the plaintiff to [a third party] is inconclusive. <eos/><bos/>I must infer also that the evidence of [the company&apos;s representative], and indeed the documents themselves, would be unlikely to support the defendant&apos;s position, otherwise such evidence would have been given.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0051"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id2c0e4e08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">52</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Id2bdfeb08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>See, for example, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00009" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1996443116" w-pub-number="0005653" ID="I1f1557318e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>CPC International Inc. v. Seaforth Creamery Inc.</ital></cite.query> (1996), 3 C.P.C. (4th) 90, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00010" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1996443116" w-pub-number="0005653" ID="I1f1557328e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">69 C.P.R. (3d) 289</cite.query> (Ont. Ct. (Gen. Div.)).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2bdfeb18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>See <ital>Future Shop v. Northwest-Atlantic (B.C)</ital> (2000), 2 C.P.C. (5th) 358 (B.C.S.C.).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2bdfeb28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00011" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1998457913" w-pub-number="0005506" ID="I1f17a1208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ainsworth Electric Co. v. Alcatel Canada Wire Inc.</ital> (1998), 40 O.R. (3d) 123 (Gen. Div.), at pp. 133-6</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2bdfeb38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>4</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00012" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043398069" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I1f17c8308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Nail Cartel Inc. v. Duclos</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 3516, 2017 BCSC 2313 (B.C. S.C.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2bdfeb48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>5</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00013" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043398069" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I1f17ef408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Nail Cartel Inc. v. Duclos</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 3516, 2017 BCSC 2313 (B.C. S.C.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 6, and 21-22.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2be25c08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>6</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00014" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2011362653" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I1f1816508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Blue Line Hockey Acquisition Co. v. Orca Bay Hockey Ltd. Partnership</ital>, 2007 CarswellBC 208, 2007 BCSC 143</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2be25c18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>7</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00015" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2011362653" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I1f1afc808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Blue Line Hockey Acquisition Co. v. Orca Bay Hockey Ltd. Partnership</ital>, 2007 CarswellBC 208, 2007 BCSC 143</cite.query>, at paras. 1-2, 4-6, and 63.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2be25c28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>8</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00016" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2011362653" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I1f1b4aa08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Blue Line Hockey Acquisition Co. v. Orca Bay Hockey Ltd. Partnership</ital>, 2007 CarswellBC 208, 2007 BCSC 143, at para. 16</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2be25c38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>9</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00017" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2011362653" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I1f1b71b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Blue Line Hockey Acquisition Co. v. Orca Bay Hockey Ltd. Partnership</ital>, 2007 CarswellBC 208, 2007 BCSC 143, at para. 78</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2be25c48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>10</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00018" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2011362653" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I1f1b98c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Blue Line Hockey Acquisition Co. v. Orca Bay Hockey Ltd. Partnership</ital>, 2007 CarswellBC 208, 2007 BCSC 143, at para. 86</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2be4cd08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>11</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00019" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2011362653" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I1f1bbfd08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Blue Line Hockey Acquisition Co. v. Orca Bay Hockey Ltd. Partnership</ital>, 2007 CarswellBC 208, 2007 BCSC 143</cite.query>, at paras. 80-81, and 84.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2be4cd18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>12</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00020" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1983031647" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I1f1be6e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Fraser v. Thames Television Ltd.</ital>, [1983] 2 All E.R. 101 (Q.B.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2be4cd28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>13</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00021" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1985263355" w-pub-number="0003591" w-pinpoint-page="199" ID="I1f1caa308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Promotivate International Inc. v. Toronto Star Newspapers Ltd.</ital> (1985), 23 D.L.R. (4th) 196 at p. 199, 53 O.R. (2d) 9 (H.C.J.)</cite.query>, citing <ital>Saltman Engineering Co. v. Campbell Engineering Co.</ital>, [1963] 3 All E.R. 413<ital>n</ital> (C.A.), and <cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00022" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1968018312" w-pub-number="0004831" ID="I1f1caa338e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Coco v. A.N. Clark (Engineers) Ltd.</ital>, [1969] R.P.C. 41 (Ch.)</cite.query>, in support of that proposition.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2be4cd38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>14</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00023" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1985263355" w-pub-number="0003591" w-pinpoint-page="200" ID="I1f1cf8508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Promotivate International Inc. v. Toronto Star Newspapers Ltd.</ital> (1985), 23 D.L.R. (4th) 196 at p. 200, 53 O.R. (2d) 9 (H.C.J.)</cite.query> (emphasis added).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2be4cd48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>15</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00024" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047688097" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I1f1cf8538e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>CTT Pharmaceutical Holdings v. Rapid Dose Therapeutics</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 3076, 2019 ONSC 1444</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2bf37308e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>16</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00025" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047688097" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I1f1d1f608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>CTT Pharmaceutical Holdings v. Rapid Dose Therapeutics</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 3076, 2019 ONSC 1444, at para. 3</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2bf5e408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>17</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00026" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047688097" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I1f1d46708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>CTT Pharmaceutical Holdings v. Rapid Dose Therapeutics</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 3076, 2019 ONSC 1444</cite.query>, at paras. 13-14.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2bf5e418e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>18</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00027" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047688097" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I1f1d94908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>CTT Pharmaceutical Holdings v. Rapid Dose Therapeutics</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 3076, 2019 ONSC 1444</cite.query>, at paras. 15-16.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2bf5e428e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>19</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00028" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047688097" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I1f1dbba08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>CTT Pharmaceutical Holdings v. Rapid Dose Therapeutics</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 3076, 2019 ONSC 1444</cite.query>, at paras. 17-18.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2bf5e438e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>20</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00029" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048188720" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I1f1de2b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Dowd et al. v. Skip the Dishes Restaurant Services Inc. et al</ital>., 2019 CarswellMan 400, 2019 MBQB 63</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2bf85508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>21</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00030" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048188720" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I1f1e09c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Dowd et al. v. Skip the Dishes Restaurant Services Inc. et al</ital>., 2019 CarswellMan 400, 2019 MBQB 63</cite.query>, at paras. 14-18.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2bf85518e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>22</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00031" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048188720" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I1f1e30d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Dowd et al. v. Skip the Dishes Restaurant Services Inc. et al</ital>., 2019 CarswellMan 400, 2019 MBQB 63</cite.query>, at paras. 146-148.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2bf85528e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>23</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00032" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035096058" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I1f1e7ef08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>JTT Electronics Ltd. v. Farmer</ital>, 2014 CarswellBC 3852, 2014 BCSC 2413</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2bf85538e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>24</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00033" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035096058" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I1f1ea6008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>JTT Electronics Ltd. v. Farmer</ital>, 2014 CarswellBC 3852, 2014 BCSC 2413</cite.query>, at paras. 1-2.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2bf85548e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>25</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00034" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035096058" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I1f1ef4208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>JTT Electronics Ltd. v. Farmer</ital>, 2014 CarswellBC 3852, 2014 BCSC 2413</cite.query>, at paras. 9, and 11-14.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2bfac608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>26</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00035" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035096058" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I1f1f1b308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>JTT Electronics Ltd. v. Farmer</ital>, 2014 CarswellBC 3852, 2014 BCSC 2413</cite.query>, at paras. 30-31, and 37-41.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2bfac618e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>27</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00036" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035096058" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I1f1f42408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>JTT Electronics Ltd. v. Farmer</ital>, 2014 CarswellBC 3852, 2014 BCSC 2413, at para. 52</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2bfac628e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>28</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00037" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047688100" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I1f1f69508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Evertz Technologies Limited v. Lawo AG</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 3078, 2019 ONSC 1355</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00038" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048188725" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I1f1f69538e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2019 CarswellOnt 6686, 2019 ONSC 2756</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2bfac638e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>29</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00039" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047688100" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I1f1f90608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Evertz Technologies Limited v. Lawo AG</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 3078, 2019 ONSC 1355</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00040" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048188725" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I1f1f90638e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2019 CarswellOnt 6686, 2019 ONSC 2756</cite.query>, at paras. 5-6.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2bfac648e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>30</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00041" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047688100" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I1f1fde808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Evertz Technologies Limited v. Lawo AG</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 3078, 2019 ONSC 1355</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00042" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048188725" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I1f1fde838e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2019 CarswellOnt 6686, 2019 ONSC 2756</cite.query>, at paras. 1-3.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2bfd3708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>31</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00043" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047688100" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I1f2005908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Evertz Technologies Limited v. Lawo AG</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 3078, 2019 ONSC 1355</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00044" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048188725" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I1f2005938e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2019 CarswellOnt 6686, 2019 ONSC 2756, at para. 9</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2bffa808e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>32</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00045" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047688100" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I1f202ca08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Evertz Technologies Limited v. Lawo AG</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 3078, 2019 ONSC 1355</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00046" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048188725" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I1f202ca38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2019 CarswellOnt 6686, 2019 ONSC 2756, at para. 10</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2c021908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>33</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00047" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047688100" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I1f207ac08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Evertz Technologies Limited v. Lawo AG</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 3078, 2019 ONSC 1355</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00048" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048188725" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I1f207ac38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2019 CarswellOnt 6686, 2019 ONSC 2756, at para. 13</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2c048a08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>34</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00049" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047688100" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I1f20a1d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Evertz Technologies Limited v. Lawo AG</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 3078, 2019 ONSC 1355</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00050" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048188725" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I1f20a1d38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2019 CarswellOnt 6686, 2019 ONSC 2756, at para. 16</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2c048a18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>35</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00051" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047688100" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I1f20c8e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Evertz Technologies Limited v. Lawo AG</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 3078, 2019 ONSC 1355</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00052" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048188725" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I1f20c8e38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2019 CarswellOnt 6686, 2019 ONSC 2756, at para. 32</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2c048a28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>36</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00053" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047688100" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I1f20eff08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Evertz Technologies Limited v. Lawo AG</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 3078, 2019 ONSC 1355</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00054" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048188725" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I1f20eff38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2019 CarswellOnt 6686, 2019 ONSC 2756, at para. 34</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2c048a38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>37</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00055" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047688100" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I1f2117008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Evertz Technologies Limited v. Lawo AG</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 3078, 2019 ONSC 1355</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00056" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048188725" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I1f2117038e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2019 CarswellOnt 6686, 2019 ONSC 2756, at para. 35</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2c048a48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>38</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00057" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047688100" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I1f213e108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Evertz Technologies Limited v. Lawo AG</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 3078, 2019 ONSC 1355</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00058" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048188725" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I1f213e138e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2019 CarswellOnt 6686, 2019 ONSC 2756, at para. 40</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2c06fb08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>39</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00059" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048716483" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I1f218c308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Furfari v. Pedias</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 11420, 2019 ONSC 4278</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2c06fb18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>40</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00060" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048716483" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I1f21b3408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Furfari v. Pedias</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 11420, 2019 ONSC 4278</cite.query>, at paras. 1-3.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2c06fb28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>41</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00061" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048716483" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I1f21da508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Furfari v. Pedias</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 11420, 2019 ONSC 4278, at para. 5</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2c096c08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>42</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00062" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048716483" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I1f21da538e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Furfari v. Pedias</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 11420, 2019 ONSC 4278, at para. 10</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2c096c18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>43</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00063" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048716483" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I1f2228708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Furfari v. Pedias</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 11420, 2019 ONSC 4278</cite.query>, at paras. 16-17.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2c096c28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>44</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00064" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048716483" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I1f224f808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Furfari v. Pedias</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 11420, 2019 ONSC 4278</cite.query>, at paras. 18-19.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2c096c38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>45</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00065" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048716483" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I1f2276908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Furfari v. Pedias</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 11420, 2019 ONSC 4278</cite.query>, at paras. 21-23.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2c096c48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>46</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00066" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048716483" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I1f229da08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Furfari v. Pedias</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 11420, 2019 ONSC 4278, at para. 37</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2c096c58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>47</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00067" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2002456749" w-pub-number="0006462" ID="I1f22c4b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Pastor v. Chen</ital> (2002), 19 C.P.R. (4th) 206 (B.C. Prov. Ct.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2c0bdd08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>48</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00068" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1985030763" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I1f3e63008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Faccenda Chicken Ltd. v. Fowler</ital>, [1986] 1 All E.R. 617 (C.A.), at p. 627</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>See also <cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00069" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1989314665" w-pub-number="0004655" w-pinpoint-page="69" ID="I1f3e63028e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Reed Stenhouse Ltd. v. Foster</ital> (1989), 98 A.R. 49, 69</cite.query> Alta. L.R. (2d) 80 (Q.B.).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2c0bdd18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>49</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00070" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1985030763" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I1f5b60e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Faccenda Chicken Ltd. v. Fowler</ital>, [1986] 1 All E.R. 617 (C.A.), at pp. 628-9</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2c0bdd28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>50</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00071" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1983031647" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I1f7997408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Fraser v. Thames Television Ltd.</ital>, [1983] 2 All E.R. 101 (Q.B.), at p. 122</cite.query> (emphasis added).<eos/><bos/> See also <cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00072" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1991354399" w-pub-number="0005653" ID="I1f7997438e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>ICAM Technologies Corp. v. Ebco Industries Ltd.</ital></cite.query> (1991), 6 B.L.R. (2d) 98, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00073" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1991354399" w-pub-number="0005653" ID="I1f7997448e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">36 C.P.R. (3d) 504 (B.C.S.C.)</cite.query>, <case.history>affd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00074" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1993381255" w-pub-number="0003986" ID="I1f7997468e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">[1994] 3 W.W.R. 419, 85</cite.query> B.C.L.R. (2d) 318 (C.A.); <cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00075" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1991349616" w-pub-number="0004655" ID="I1f7997488e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Pharand Ski Corp. v. Alberta</ital> (1991), 116 A.R. 326, 80</cite.query> Alta. L.R. (2d) 216 (<cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00076" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1991360976" w-pub-number="0004655" ID="I1f79974a8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Q.B.), supp. reasons 122 A.R. 81, 81</cite.query> Alta. L.R. (2d) 304 (Q.B.), supp. reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00077" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1991349617" w-pub-number="0003986" ID="I1f79974c8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">[1992] 1 W.W.R. 501, 122 A.R. 395 (Q.B.)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>The information need not be completely new: see <cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00078" w-ref-type="RP" w-serial-number="1944119615" w-pub-number="0000602" w-pinpoint-page="657" ID="I1f79974f8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Fairchild Engine &amp; Airplane Corp. v. Cox</ital>, 50 N.Y.S.2d 643, 657 (N.Y. Sup. Ct. 1944)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2c0bdd38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>51</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00079" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1972098569" w-pub-number="0005652" ID="I1f7a0c708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Gibbons v. Drew Chemical Ltd.</ital> (1972), 8 C.P.R. (2d) 105 (B.C.S.C.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2c0e4e08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>52</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175843" w-seq-number="00080" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1972098569" w-pub-number="0005652" ID="I1f7c2f508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Gibbons v. Drew Chemical Ltd.</ital> (1972), 8 C.P.R. (2d) 105 (B.C.S.C.), at p. 109</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 3:12<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
