<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 2:1<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I4e5fc390411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>2.</label.designator><headtext>Legal Bases Used by the Courts for the Protection of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I4e5feaa0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>I.</label.designator><headtext>Generally</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f5c3006ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>2:1.</label.designator><headtext>Generally</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In the British Commonwealth, there is no statute which pertains specifically to confidential business information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id095ee908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>] The law has evolved instead through the common law of precedent. <eos/><bos/>The courts have not, however, been consistent in establishing the basis for the protection of confidential business information. <eos/><bos/>Property, bailment, contract, unjust enrichment, trust, fiduciary duty, good faith and conversion have all, at one time or another, been cited as the legal bases for judicial intervention. <eos/><bos/>Some judges have even intermingled these concepts, and so, it is often difficult to determine which theory is being espoused.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id095ee918e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>This chapter provides an outline of the four most prevalent theories used by the courts as the basis for the protection of confidential information: property theory, the theory that the protection of confidential business information is an equitable right, contract theory, and the theory that the right to confidential business information should be protected as a right in and of itself. <eos/><bos/>The review of each theory includes an analysis of the reasons in support of it as well as the criticisms thereof.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>An action for breach of confidential information has two distinct aspects: the nature of the information protected and the nature of the relationship in which the information was divulged.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id095ee928e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">3</footnote.reference>] The property theory recognizes rights in a novel and concrete idea even in the absence of a contract or of unjust enrichment. <eos/><bos/>It has also been argued that the original legal basis to protect confidential information is equity: the basis of recovery would be one of unjust enrichment or a duty of good faith not to breach a confidential relationship. <eos/><bos/>The third theory is that the proper legal basis is in contract: recovery will be allowed if the plaintiff can prove that there was an explicit or implied promise to pay for or not use an idea. <eos/><bos/>In modern times, the courts have used additional bases such as tort and have also suggested that confidential information should be treated as a <ital>sui generis</ital> concept.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id09615a08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">4</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The prevalent modern view in Anglo-Canadian jurisprudence is that a claim for breach of confidential business information is based in either contract or equity.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id09615a18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">5</footnote.reference>] In contrast, the American courts rely more heavily on the common law doctrines of property and contract. <eos/><bos/>Recently, both the American and the Commonwealth courts have also entertained the suggestion that an action for breach of confidential business information may be based on an independent theory of a <ital>sui generis</ital> wrong relating to broken confidences.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id09615a28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">6</footnote.reference>] In France, since the early 19th century, the courts have traditionally protected confidential information using the contract analogy. <eos/><bos/>In the 20th century, that country has also relied on the equitable basis of unfair competition. <eos/><bos/>The <ital>Civil Code</ital> of France contains specific provisions which deal with unfair competition, and these sections have been invoked where there has been a wrongful appropriation of confidential information. <eos/><bos/>In the early 1930s, the French courts began to accept the notion of proprietary rights in confidential information, although they have yet to clearly accept the property theory.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id09615a38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">7</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Id095ee908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>There are, however, provisions in statutes such as the Federal and Provincial Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Legislation and NAFTA provisions that protect parties from disclosure of trade secrets by government agents under certain conditions. <eos/><bos/>See for example <cite.query w-src-number="0492175816" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1999489383" w-pub-number="0005653" w-pinpoint-page="299" ID="I13720fe08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Bayer Inc. v. Canada (Attorney General)</ital> (1999), 87 C.P.R. (3d) 293 at p. 299, 166 F.T.R. 160n, 243 N.R. 170 (F.C.A.)</cite.query>, leave to appeal to S.C.C. refused 5 C.P.R. (3d) vii.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id095ee918e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>G. Jones, <begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>“Restitution of Benefits Obtained in Breach of Another&apos;s Confidence”<end.quote refid="QT_0001"/> (1970), 86 L.Q.R. 463 at p. 463; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175816" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1769085203" w-pub-number="0003533" ID="I13725e008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Millar v. Taylor</ital> (1769), 4 Burr. 2303, 98 E.R. 201 (K.B.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175816" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1849049683" w-pub-number="0005801" ID="I13725e038e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Prince Albert v. Strange</ital> (1849), 1 H. &amp; Tw. 1, 47 E.R. 1302 (Ch.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id095ee928e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>H.J. Glasbeek, <begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>“Limitations on the Action of Breach of Confidence”<end.quote refid="QT_0002"/> in D. Gibson, ed., <ital>Aspects of Privacy Law: Essays in Honour of John M. Sharpe</ital> (Toronto: Butterworths, 1980), p. 232.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id09615a08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>4</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>D. Vaver, <begin.quote ID="QT_0003"/>“Civil Liability: Trade Secrets in Canada”<end.quote refid="QT_0003"/> (1980-81), 5 C.B.L.J. 253 at p. 262.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id09615a18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>5</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175816" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="ER" w-normalized-cite="L.R. 19EQUK462" w-pub-number="0004915" ID="I1372fa408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Printing and Numerical Registering Co. v. Sampson</ital> (1875), L.R. 19 Eq. 462 (M.R.)</cite.query>, at p. 465.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id09615a28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>6</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>R.G. Hammond, <begin.quote ID="QT_0005"/>“The Origins of the Equitable Duty of Confidence”<end.quote refid="QT_0005"/> (1979), 8 Ang.-Am. L.R. 71 at p. 84.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id09615a38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>7</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>M. Bourgeois, <begin.quote ID="QT_0004"/>“Protecting Business Confidences: A Comparative Study of Quebec and French Law”<end.quote refid="QT_0004"/> (1987-88), 3 I.P.J. 259 at p. 275.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 2:1<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
