<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 6:11<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I55e174b0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>6.</label.designator><headtext>Defences to Claims for Breach of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I56aa42f0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>VI.</label.designator><headtext>Public Policy</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f6fb716ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>6:11.</label.designator><headtext>Contrary to Public Interest—Unclean Hands</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Lord Denning in <ital>Fraser v. Evans</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id7e08a208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>] held that: <begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>“There are some things which may be required to be disclosed in the public interest, in which event no confidence can be prayed in aid to keep them secret.”<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0001"/> The types of information for which disclosure is deemed necessary vary greatly. <eos/><bos/>It has been held that where it would be inequitable to do so, the courts will not order the disclosure of confidential business information.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Hubbard v. Vosper</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id7e08a218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>] the information in question related to the dissemination of particulars of the ideology of the Church of Scientology. <eos/><bos/>The defendant, Vosper, who had been a member, wrote and published a book critical of the church. <eos/><bos/>The book contained substantial extracts from books, bulletins and a letter written by Hubbard, some of which were confidential. <eos/><bos/>The court held that, although the law would, in some cases, restrain a defendant from revealing confidential information, there was good ground for thinking that it was in the public interest that the material in question be made known, because the doctrine of Scientology involved the use of psychological processes which might be dangerous “in untrained hands”.<eos/><bos/> In addition, the court dealt with the church&apos;s “criminal code” which included the following:</paratext><list><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(1)</label.designator></head><paratext>A person has committed a “suppressive act” if, for example, he should give evidence in a court of law hostile to the organization of Scientology, or <begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>“deliver up a Scientologist without defence or protest to the demands of civil or criminal law”<end.quote refid="QT_0002"/>.<eos/><bos/></paratext></para></list.item><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(2)</label.designator></head><paratext>In order for one to be guilty of the suppressive act of first degree murder, the person murdered must not have been guilty of suppressive acts.<eos/><bos/></paratext></para></list.item><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(3)</label.designator></head><paratext>Suppressive persons or groups become “fair game” and, as such, are deprived of any protection from the church.<eos/><bos/></paratext></para></list.item><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(4)</label.designator></head><paratext>No scientologist is to be condemned for <ital>any action</ital> taken against “fair game”.<eos/><bos/></paratext></para></list.item></list><paratext>Although some of these provisions were later altered, the court held that it was in the public interest that such information be made known because the plaintiffs had been protecting their secrets by deplorable means. <eos/><bos/>While this case does not involve business information, it demonstrates the principle that a party may not obtain relief where it does not come with “clean hands” in asking for protection of its secrets.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Id7e08a208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175946" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1968017805" w-pub-number="0003898" ID="I5abd8eb08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Fraser v. Evans,</ital> [1969] 1 Q.B. 349 (C.A.), at p. 362</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7e08a218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175946" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1972022359" w-pub-number="0003898" ID="I5abdb5c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Hubbard v. Vosper</ital>, [1972] 2 Q.B. 84 (C.A.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 6:11<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
