<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 1:5<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I4d7849c0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>1.</label.designator><headtext>Confidential Business Information in Historical Context</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I4d790d10411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>I.</label.designator><headtext>Origins of Intellectual Property</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f59be96ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>1:5.</label.designator><headtext>Industrial Age</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The modern roots of the law of confidential information were established during the Industrial Revolution. <eos/><bos/>From the early 16th to the mid-19th centuries, no significant technologies were introduced that altered the form, volume or speed of information. <eos/><bos/>However, from the 1830s onward, the rate of creation of new technological inventions such as the telegraph, typewriter, transatlantic cable, telephone, motion pictures, commercial radio broadcasting and television broadcasting increased dramatically. <eos/><bos/>These inventions provided almost instant communications and collapsed distance and geographic boundaries.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Icdd791e08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>At the same time, a great number of technological inventions were made to facilitate the production and manufacture of goods, and large corporations were created which in turn required a more complex system to govern the right to ideas. <eos/><bos/>Changes were made to the property rights of manufacturers, and usury laws were modified to stimulate investment. <eos/><bos/>However, although the Industrial Revolution also required a vast labour force to operate the machinery, the labour force could not directly profit from the benefits of manufacturing, and attempts were made by workers to sell their labour more profitably. <eos/><bos/>Initially the courts were unwilling to restrict the freedom of contract between employers and employees, but later, employees began to operate as a group, placing pressure on employers and governments to limit the hours worked and to increase wages.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Icdd7b8f08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The earliest reported English case which dealt with confidential business information was <ital>Morison v. Moat</ital>.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Icdd7e0008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">3</footnote.reference>] This case involved the preparation of a secret medicinal compound which was invented by Morison. <eos/><bos/>Morison disclosed the formula to his partner Moat on condition that the secret not be disclosed to anyone. <eos/><bos/>After the termination of the partnership, Moat&apos;s son used the formula and advertised it as his own. <eos/><bos/>In that case, Sir Gilbert Turner found:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>That the Court has exercised jurisdiction in cases of this nature does not, I think, admit of any question. <eos/><bos/>Different grounds have indeed been assigned for the exercise of that jurisdiction. <eos/><bos/>In some cases it has been referred to property, in others to contract, and in others, again, it has been treated as founded upon trust or confidence, meaning, as I conceive it, that the Court fastens the obligation on the conscience of the party, and enforces it against him in the same manner as it enforces against a party to whom a benefit is given the obligation of performing a promise on the faith of which the benefit has been conferred; but, upon whatever grounds the jurisdiction is founded, the authorities leave no doubt as to the exercise of it.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0002"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Icdd7e0018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">4</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><paratext>Moat&apos;s son was found liable for breach of faith and of the contract entered into by his father, and an injunction was granted to prevent him from using the formula.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Given the inefficiencies of the 19th century intellectual property statutory regimes, judges seemed receptive to granting protection to an individual&apos;s or a firm&apos;s confidential information by invoking common law equitable doctrines.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Icdd7e0028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">5</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The use of contract law to protect confidential information emerged in the early 19th century in both common law and civil law jurisdictions, and by the late 19th century, the contract doctrine had begun to overshadow the equitable and property remedies that had until then been relied on by the courts. <eos/><bos/>Contractual protection began with covenants restricting competition and the dissemination of confidential information in employment situations and evolved to the point where the courts were ready to read into employment contracts implied terms prohibiting the use of confidential information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Icdd807108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">6</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Courts in civil law jurisdictions have also invoked the unfair competition provisions of their civil codes. <eos/><bos/>Since the early 19th century, the French courts have used contract law to protect confidential information, relying on express and implied covenants in the employment context for breach of confidential business information. <eos/><bos/>Manufacturing secrets have been protected by the French Penal Code since 1870, and these provisions are invoked by those seeking to bring an action to restrain the dissemination of information. <eos/><bos/>The French courts have also relied on s. 1382 of the Civil Code to create rules of unfair competition. <eos/><bos/>Acts such as manufacturing products which are confusing with the pre-existing products of another and business or market disruptions are considered wrongful, and possible injury and commercial disturbance alone may engender liability.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Icdd807118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">7</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Icdd791e08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>N. Postman, <ital>Technology</ital> (New York: Knopf, 1992).<eos/><bos/> See also W. Stanbury and I. Vertinsky, <ital>Assessing the Impact of New Information Technologies on Interest Group Behaviour and Policy Making</ital> (Kingston: Queens University, 1994), p. 7.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Icdd7b8f08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175792" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="RP" w-serial-number="1905100369" w-pub-number="0000780" ID="I120846b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Lochner v. New York</ital>, 198 U.S. 45 (1905)</cite.query>; B. Siegan, <ital>Economic Liberties and the Constitution</ital> (Chicago: University of Chicago Press, 1980), p. 58; G. Klueck, <begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>“The Coming Jurisprudence of the Information Age: Examinations of the Three Past Socio-Economic Ages Suggest the Future”<end.quote refid="QT_0001"/> (1984), 21 San Diego L. Rev. 1077 at p. 1096.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Icdd7e0008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175792" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1851042779" w-pub-number="0005000" ID="I12086dc08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Morison v. Moat</ital> (1851), 9 Hare. 241, 68 E.R. 492 (Ch.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Icdd7e0018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>4</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175792" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1851042779" w-pub-number="0005000" w-pinpoint-page="255" ID="I120894d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Morison v. Moat</ital> (1851), 9 Hare. 241, at p. 255, 68 E.R. 492 (Ch.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Icdd7e0028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>5</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175792" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1769085203" w-pub-number="0003533" ID="I1208bbe08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Millar v. Taylor</ital> (1769), 4 Burr. 2303, 98 E.R. 201 (K.B.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175792" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1849049683" w-pub-number="0005801" ID="I1208bbe38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Prince Albert v. Strange</ital> (1849), 1 H. &amp; Tw. 1, 47 E.R. 1302 (Ch.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175792" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1851042779" w-pub-number="0005000" ID="I1208bbe68e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Morison v. Moat</ital> (1851), 9 Hare. 241, 68 E.R. 492 (Ch.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Icdd807108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>6</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>R.G. Hammond, <begin.quote ID="QT_0003"/>“Developments in the Equitable Doctrine of Breach of Confidence”<end.quote refid="QT_0003"/>, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175792" w-seq-number="00007" w-ref-type="N3" w-normalized-cite="1976NZLJNZ278" w-pub-number="0007238" ID="I12090a008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">[1976] N.Z.L.J. 278</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Icdd807118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>7</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>M. Bourgeois, <begin.quote ID="QT_0004"/>“Protecting Business Confidences: A Comparative Study of Quebec and French Law”<end.quote refid="QT_0004"/> (1987-88), 3 I.P.J. 259 at p. 275.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 1:5<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
