<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 2:2<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I4e5fc390411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>2.</label.designator><headtext>Legal Bases Used by the Courts for the Protection of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I4e678bc0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>II.</label.designator><headtext>Property Theory</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f5c3036ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>2:2.</label.designator><headtext>Generally</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Property has been defined as:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>That which is peculiar or proper to any person; that which belongs exclusively to one. <eos/><bos/>In the strict legal sense, an aggregate of rights which are guaranteed and protected by the government … More specifically, ownership; the unrestricted and exclusive right to a thing; the right to dispose of a thing in every legal way, to possess it, to use it, and to exclude every one else from interfering with it.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0001"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id0a075e08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The word “property” refers to tangible property and “choses in action”.<eos/><bos/> The definition of “choses in action” includes all property, tangible and intangible <begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>“whose terms of enjoyment could and would be measured according to the wording of the Letters Patent, or the Act of Legislature or other document that created it”<end.quote refid="QT_0002"/>.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id0a075e18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The property theory focuses on the nature of the information to be protected. <eos/><bos/>It assumes that, even if others are not aware of the content of the information, they know of its existence. <eos/><bos/>Thus, where a property right is recognized, the personal obligation as between two parties may give rise to an equitable interest in the property in relation to which the duty arises. <eos/><bos/>Proponents of the property theory point to the fact that trade secrets and confidential business information are generally considered to be intellectual property and are, like other species of intellectual property, subject to property rights. <eos/><bos/>Furthermore, confidential business information is frequently licensed or assigned, and is created through the same types of processes utilized in patent and copyright law.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id0a075e28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">3</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Many of the early cases used property law as the basis for determining liability for breach of confidential business information. <eos/><bos/>In <ital>Millar v. Taylor</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id0a075e38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">4</footnote.reference>] Mr. Justice Yates held that:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0005"/>Ideas are free. <eos/><bos/>But while the author confines them to his study, they are like birds in a cage, which none but he can have a right to let fly: for, till he thinks proper to emancipate them, they are under his own dominion.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0005"/></paratext></para></display.quote><paratext>An author&apos;s unpublished manuscript therefore <begin.quote ID="QT_0004"/>“is, in every sense, his peculiar property; and no man can take it from him, or make any use of it which he has not authorized, without being guilty of a violation of his property”<end.quote refid="QT_0004"/>.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id0a0c4008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">5</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Abernethy v. Hutchinson</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id0a0c4018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">6</footnote.reference>] the court held that <begin.quote ID="QT_0006"/>“the case could be viewed two ways—either as a question of trust, or a question of property”<end.quote refid="QT_0006"/>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In the later decision of <ital>Boardman v. Phipps</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id0a0c4028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">7</footnote.reference>] Lord Hodson, as part of the majority, held:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0008"/>We are aware that what is called “know-how” in the commercial sense is property which may be very valuable as an asset. <eos/><bos/>I agree with the learned judge and with the Court of Appeal that the confidential information acquired in this case which was capable of being and was turned to account can be properly regarded as the property of the trust.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0008"/></paratext></para></display.quote><paratext>Lord Guest, also part of the majority decision, confirmed that: <begin.quote ID="QT_0007"/>“I see no reason why information and knowledge cannot be trust property”<end.quote refid="QT_0007"/>.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id0a0eb108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">8</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In the Australian case, <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175817" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="U4" w-serial-number="1979099297" w-pub-number="0004888" ID="I13f5e5e18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Deta Nominees Pty. Ltd. v. Viscount Plastic Products</cite.query> Ltd.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id0a0eb118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">9</footnote.reference>] the court took the property theory one step further. <eos/><bos/>In that case, the court held that equity will be invoked in situations where information is the property of a person, into which category most, if not all, trade secret cases will fall. <eos/><bos/>This seems to suggest that the origin of the equitable right is the fact that in most, if not all, cases of confidential information, there is a property right to be protected.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The issue of the legal basis for protection of confidential business information was discussed by the Supreme Court of Canada in the context of criminal law. <eos/><bos/>In <ital>R. v. Stewart</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id0a0eb128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">10</footnote.reference>] Lamer J., for the court, held that confidential information:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0009"/>… possesses many of the characteristics of other forms of property: for example, a trade secret, which is a particular kind of confidential information, can be sold, licensed or bequeathed, it can be the subject of a trust or passed to a trustee in bankruptcy … The cases demonstrate that English and Canadian civil law protect confidential information. <eos/><bos/>However, the legal basis for doing so has not been clearly established by the courts. <eos/><bos/>Some cases have treated confidential information as property, and thus have entitled the owner to exclude others from the use thereof … On the other hand, the courts have recognized certain rights with respect to confidential information in the guise of an equitable obligation of good faith …<end.quote refid="QT_0009"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0010"/>It appears that the protection afforded to confidential information in most civil cases arises more from an obligation of good faith or a fiduciary relationship than from a proprietary interest. <eos/><bos/>No Canadian court has so far conclusively decided that confidential information is property, with all the civil consequences that such a finding would entail.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0010"/></paratext></para></display.quote><paratext>However, the possibility of confidential information being considered a proprietary right in civil cases is left open, as Lamer J. went on to say:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0011"/>It is possible that, with time, confidential information will come to be considered as property in the civil law or even be granted special legal protection by statutory enactment. <eos/><bos/>Even if confidential information were to be considered as property under civil law, it does not, however, automatically follow that it qualifies as property for the purposes of criminal law.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0011"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id0a160408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">11</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><paratext>There has as yet been no definitive word from the Supreme Court of Canada regarding the express acceptance or rejection of the property theory as the doctrinal basis for protection of confidential business information in civil cases. <eos/><bos/>However, see <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175817" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1999428661" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I13f793918e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Cadbury Schweppes Inc. v. FBI Foods</cite.query> Ltd.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id0a187508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">12</footnote.reference>] where the Supreme Court of Canada, while not closing the door on the issue, reaffirmed its reluctance to treat confidential information as a species of property.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In the United States, some American courts have specifically recognized a property right in an idea which is compensable in damages. <eos/><bos/>In <cite.query w-src-number="0492175817" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="RT" w-serial-number="1953116631" w-pub-number="0000345" ID="I13f82fd18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Belt v. Hamilton National Bank</ital></cite.query>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id0a187518e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">13</footnote.reference>] the plaintiff conceived of an idea for a radio program and asked the bank to be a sponsor. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff sought compensation in return for the sponsorship. <eos/><bos/>The bank engaged the plaintiff but later cancelled the agreement and abandoned the program. <eos/><bos/>Some time later, the bank took up the program with another individual. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff sued the bank for the value of his idea. <eos/><bos/>The District Court held:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0012"/>The law has recognized a qualified property right in trade secrets and grants injunctive relief against their use or disclosure by a breach of contract or a violation of confidence. <eos/><bos/>It is but one step further to extend to ideas at least a limited property right … The law now gives effect to a property right in an idea even though the idea may be neither patentable nor subject to copyright.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0012"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id0a1d5708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">14</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><paratext>On appeal, the Circuit Court of Appeal, confirming the District Court judgment, held that:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0013"/>… the dangers [of attributing common property to individual ownership] are sufficiently avoided to warrant the law in placing an idea among protected property rights when it is definite and concrete, new and novel, has usefulness and is disclosed for commercial purposes in circumstances which the parties ought reasonably to construe as contemplating compensation for its use.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0013"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id0a1fc808e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">15</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><paratext>The finding of the Court of Appeal in the <cite.query w-src-number="0492175817" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="RT" w-serial-number="1953116631" w-pub-number="0000345" ID="I13f98f618e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Belt v. Hamilton National Bank</ital></cite.query> case was applied in <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175817" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="RS" w-serial-number="1957110615" w-pub-number="0000350" ID="I13f98f638e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Puente v. President and Fellows of Harvard</cite.query> College</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id0a1fc818e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">16</footnote.reference>] and <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175817" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="RS" w-serial-number="1973120646" w-pub-number="0000867" ID="I13f98f658e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Ed Graham Productions, Inc. v. National Broadcasting</cite.query> Co.</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id0a1fc828e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">17</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The American courts have stressed that, in order to be eligible for protection by the courts, an idea must be <begin.quote ID="QT_0014"/>“original, concrete, useful and disclosed in circumstances which, reasonably construed, clearly indicate that compensation is contemplated if it is accepted and used”<end.quote refid="QT_0014"/>.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id0a223908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">18</footnote.reference>] The purpose of this test is to ensure that the idea merits protection and would not exist but for the efforts of the author:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0015"/>The law shies away from according protection to vagueness, and must do so especially in the realm of ideas with the obvious dangers of a contrary rule. <eos/><bos/>An abstract idea, in any event when not the subject of a contract, is so unattached as to be deemed legally without the quality of individual identity or property.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0015"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id0a223918e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">19</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In addition, the idea must have been used without authorization. <eos/><bos/>If there was independent knowledge of the general idea, and the idea was developed independently, there will be no liability.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id0a223928e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">20</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In the United States, the courts have begun using the misappropriation doctrine to grant remedies where the property rights in an idea have been infringed. <eos/><bos/>The misappropriation doctrine has been defined to consist of the following three elements:</paratext><list><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>1.</label.designator></head><paratext>The plaintiff has made a substantial investment of time, effort and money such that a property right has been created.<eos/><bos/></paratext></para></list.item><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>2.</label.designator></head><paratext>The defendant has appropriated the thing at little or no cost, such that the defendant has <begin.quote ID="QT_0016"/>“reaped where he has not sown”<end.quote refid="QT_0016"/>.<eos/><bos/></paratext></para></list.item><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>3.</label.designator></head><paratext>The plaintiff has been injured as a result of the defendant&apos;s actions.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id0a24aa08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">21</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></list.item></list><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Similarly, in the British case of <ital>Saltman Engineering</ital>, Lord Greene said that <begin.quote ID="QT_0017"/>“what makes [information] confidential is the fact that the maker of the document has used his brain and thus produced a result which can only be produced by somebody who goes through the same process”<end.quote refid="QT_0017"/>.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id0a271b08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">22</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In these cases, the basis of the right is clearly the nature of the information itself. <eos/><bos/>However, a number of criticisms of the property theory have also been expressed.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Id0a075e08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>Black&apos;s Law Dictionary</ital>, 6th ed. (St. Paul, Minn.: West Publishing Co., 1990), p. 1216; F.S. Cohen, “Dialogue on Private Property” (1954), 9 Rutgers L. Rev. 357 at p. 378.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id0a075e18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A. Birrell, <ital>Seven Lectures on the Law and History of Copyright in Books</ital> (New Jersey: Rothman Reprints Inc., 1971), pp. 12-13.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id0a075e28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>D. Vaver, <begin.quote ID="QT_0003"/>“Civil Liability: Trade Secrets in Canada”<end.quote refid="QT_0003"/> (1980-81), 5 C.B.L.J. 253 at p. 261.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id0a075e38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>4</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175817" w-seq-number="00007" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1769085203" w-pub-number="0003533" w-pinpoint-page="2378" ID="I13fb64208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Millar v. Taylor</ital> (1769), 4 Burr. 2303 at pp. 2378-9, 98 E.R. 201 (K.B.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id0a0c4008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>5</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175817" w-seq-number="00008" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1769085203" w-pub-number="0003533" w-pinpoint-page="2379" ID="I13fb8b308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Millar v. Taylor</ital> (1769), 4 Burr. 2303 at p. 2379, 98 E.R. 201 (K.B.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id0a0c4018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>6</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175817" w-seq-number="00009" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1825063549" w-pub-number="0005801" ID="I13fbb2408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Abernethy v. Hutchinson</ital> (1825), 1 H. &amp; Tw. 28, 47 E.R. 1313 (Ch.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id0a0c4028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>7</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175817" w-seq-number="00010" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1966015849" w-pub-number="0004651" ID="I13fe98708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Boardman v. Phipps</ital>, [1967] 2 A.C. 46 (H.L.), at p. 107</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id0a0eb108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>8</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175817" w-seq-number="00011" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1966015849" w-pub-number="0004651" ID="I1401f3d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Boardman v. Phipps</ital>, [1967] 2 A.C. 46 (H.L.), at p. 115</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id0a0eb118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>9</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175817" w-seq-number="00012" w-ref-type="U2" w-serial-number="1979099297" w-pub-number="0004888" ID="I14021ae08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Deta Nominees Pty. Ltd. v. Viscount Plastic Products Ltd.,</ital> [1979] V.R. 167 (S.C.)</cite.query>, at pp. 189-93.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id0a0eb128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>10</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175817" w-seq-number="00013" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1988288193" w-pub-number="0003591" w-pinpoint-page="10" ID="I140241f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>R. v. Stewart</ital> (1988), 50 D.L.R. (4th) 1 at p. 10, [1988] 1 S.C.R. 963</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id0a160408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>11</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175817" w-seq-number="00014" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1988288193" w-pub-number="0003591" w-pinpoint-page="10" ID="I140290108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>R. v. Stewart</ital> (1988), 50 D.L.R. (4th) 1, at pp. 10-11, [1988] 1 S.C.R. 963</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>See also <cite.query w-src-number="0492175817" w-seq-number="00015" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2000543047" w-pub-number="0006462" ID="I140290138e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Techform Products Ltd. v. Wolda</ital> (1999), 5 C.P.R. (4th) 25 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, supp. reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175817" w-seq-number="00016" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2000551519" w-pub-number="0006462" ID="I140290158e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">5 C.P.R. (4th) 289 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, <case.history>revd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175817" w-seq-number="00017" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2001459511" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I140290178e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">206 D.L.R. (4th) 171 (C.A.)</cite.query>, leave to appeal to S.C.C. refused 213 D.L.R. (4th) vi.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id0a187508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>12</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175817" w-seq-number="00018" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1999428661" w-pub-number="0003591" w-pinpoint-page="595" ID="I1402de308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cadbury Schweppes Inc. v. FBI Foods Ltd.</ital> (1999), 167 D.L.R. (4th) 577 at pp. 595-9, [1999] 1 S.C.R. 142</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id0a187518e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>13</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175817" w-seq-number="00019" w-ref-type="RP" w-serial-number="1953116631" w-pub-number="0000345" ID="I140305408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Belt v. Hamilton National Bank</ital>, 108 F. Supp. 689 (D.D.C. 1952)</cite.query>, <case.history><ital>aff&apos;d</ital></case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175817" w-seq-number="00020" w-ref-type="RP" w-serial-number="1953117836" w-pub-number="0000350" ID="I140305428e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">210 F.2d 706 (D.C. Cir. 1953)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id0a1d5708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>14</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175817" w-seq-number="00021" w-ref-type="RP" w-serial-number="1953116631" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="691" ID="I140353608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Belt v. Hamilton National Bank</ital>, 108 F. Supp. 689, at p. 691 (D.D.C. 1952)</cite.query>, <case.history><ital>aff&apos;d</ital></case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175817" w-seq-number="00022" w-ref-type="RP" w-serial-number="1953117836" w-pub-number="0000350" ID="I140353628e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">210 F.2d 706 (D.C. Cir. 1953)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id0a1fc808e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>15</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175817" w-seq-number="00023" w-ref-type="RP" w-serial-number="1953116631" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="709" ID="I14037a708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Belt v. Hamilton National Bank</ital>, 108 F. Supp. 689, at p. 709 (D.D.C. 1952)</cite.query>, <case.history><ital>aff&apos;d</ital></case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175817" w-seq-number="00024" w-ref-type="RP" w-serial-number="1953117836" w-pub-number="0000350" ID="I14037a728e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">210 F.2d 706 (D.C. Cir. 1953)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id0a1fc818e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>16</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175817" w-seq-number="00025" w-ref-type="RP" w-serial-number="1957110615" w-pub-number="0000350" w-pinpoint-page="802" ID="I1403c8908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Puente v. President and Fellows of Harvard College</ital>, 248 F.2d 799, 802 (1st Cir. 1957)</cite.query>, <case.history><ital>cert. denied</ital></case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175817" w-seq-number="00026" w-ref-type="RP" w-serial-number="1958201726" w-pub-number="0000780" ID="I1403c8928e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">356 U.S. 947 (1958)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id0a1fc828e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>17</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175817" w-seq-number="00027" w-ref-type="RP" w-serial-number="1973120646" w-pub-number="0000867" w-pinpoint-page="94" ID="I1403efa08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ed Graham Productions, Inc. v. National Broadcasting Co.</ital>, 180 U.S.P.Q. 93, 94 (N.Y. Sup. Ct. 1973)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id0a223908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>18</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175817" w-seq-number="00028" w-ref-type="RP" w-serial-number="1953116631" w-pub-number="0000345" ID="I140416b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Belt v. Hamilton National Bank</ital>, 108 F. Supp. 689 (D.D.C. 1952)</cite.query>, <case.history><ital>aff&apos;d</ital></case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175817" w-seq-number="00029" w-ref-type="RP" w-serial-number="1953117836" w-pub-number="0000350" ID="I140416b28e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">210 F.2d 706 (D.C. Cir. 1953)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id0a223918e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>19</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175817" w-seq-number="00030" w-ref-type="RP" w-serial-number="1953116631" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="708" ID="I14059d508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Belt v. Hamilton National Bank</ital>, 108 F. Supp. 689, at p. 708 (D.D.C. 1952)</cite.query>, <case.history><ital>aff&apos;d</ital></case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175817" w-seq-number="00031" w-ref-type="RP" w-serial-number="1953117836" w-pub-number="0000350" ID="I14059d528e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">210 F.2d 706 (D.C. Cir. 1953)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>See also <cite.query w-src-number="0492175817" w-seq-number="00032" w-ref-type="RP" w-serial-number="1946114598" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="14" ID="I14059d548e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>O&apos;Brien v. RKO Radio Pictures</ital>, 68 F. Supp. 13, 14 (S.D.N.Y. 1946)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175817" w-seq-number="00033" w-ref-type="ER" w-normalized-cite="68FE2D1207" w-pub-number="0000350" w-pinpoint-page="1210" ID="I14059d568e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sellers v. American Broadcasting Co.</ital>, 68 F.2d 1207, 1210 (11th Cir. 1982)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175817" w-seq-number="00034" w-ref-type="RP" w-serial-number="1975128613" w-pub-number="0000661" ID="I14059d598e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Smith v. Recrion Corp.</ital>, 91 Nev. 666, 669-70, 541 P.2d 663 (1975)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id0a223928e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>20</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175817" w-seq-number="00035" w-ref-type="RP" w-serial-number="1982105257" w-pub-number="0000350" w-pinpoint-page="1210" ID="I1405eb708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sellers v. American Broadcasting Co.</ital>, 668 F.2d 1207, 1210 (11th Cir. 1982)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id0a24aa08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>21</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175817" w-seq-number="00036" w-ref-type="RP" w-serial-number="1982105257" w-pub-number="0000350" ID="I140612808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sellers v. American Broadcasting Co.</ital>, 668 F.2d 1207 (11th Cir. 1982)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175817" w-seq-number="00037" w-ref-type="RP" w-serial-number="1937101466" w-pub-number="0000601" ID="I140612838e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Healey v. R.H. Macy &amp; Co.</ital>, 251 App. Div. 440, 297 N.Y.S. 165 (1937)</cite.query>, <case.history><ital>aff&apos;d without opinion</ital></case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175817" w-seq-number="00038" w-ref-type="RP" w-serial-number="1938102358" w-pub-number="0000578" ID="I140612868e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">277 N.Y. 681, 14 N.E.2d 388 (1938)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id0a271b08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>22</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>Saltman Engineering Co. v. Campbell Engineering Co.</ital>, [1963] 3 All E.R. 413<ital>n</ital> (C.A.), at p. 415.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 2:2<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
