<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 7:23<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I56d26460411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>7.</label.designator><headtext>Remedies for Breach of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I58eb5950411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>III.</label.designator><headtext>Damages</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I5909ddd0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>A.</label.designator><headtext>Legal Basis for a Claim for Damages</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f749916ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>7:23.</label.designator><headtext>Damages for Breach of an Equitable Duty of Confidence or Fiduciary Duty</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Where a duty of confidence or a fiduciary duty has been breached, there may be a cause of action in contract. <eos/><bos/>However, if there is no contractual agreement between the parties, or if the court chooses to ignore the existence of a contract, a plaintiff may rely instead on the equitable doctrine of confidence and/or an action for breach of fiduciary duty.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90ab2408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>] This is particularly true when proceedings are against third parties who have induced one of the plaintiff&apos;s employees to breach his or her contract:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>The law on [the subject of breach of confidence] does not depend on any implied contract. <eos/><bos/>It depends on the broad principle of equity that he who has received information in confidence shall not take unfair advantage of it.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0001"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id90ab2418e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In a case where there is a certain degree of trust reposed in an individual, a claim for breach of fiduciary duty may be invoked to protect the appropriation or dissemination of confidential information. <eos/><bos/>With respect to damages for breach of fiduciary duty, the courts can calculate either in regard to: (i) the profit gained by the wrongdoer, or (ii) the loss of profit suffered by the party to whom the duty was owed.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90ab2428e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">3</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In cases of breach of confidence, the courts have flexibility to fashion a remedy to suit the circumstances.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90ab2438e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">4</footnote.reference>] Where an action is based on the breach of an equitable duty of confidence or good faith, the moving party is entitled to damages in an amount equal to the amount of the wrongdoer&apos;s financial gain.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90ab2448e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">5</footnote.reference>] However, where the wrongdoer has made little or no profit, the court may award damages based on the amount of the moving party&apos;s loss since to hold the wrongdoer merely to an accounting for profits would be to place a premium on inefficiency.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90ab2458e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">6</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The central issue in <ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id90ab2468e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">7</footnote.reference>] was the extent to which the Departing Physicians were entitled to take steps during the 60 Day Period to be able continue their practices in competition with Genesis after the 60 Day Period. <eos/><bos/>The physicians organized and carried on their practice in reproductive medicine through the corporation Genesis. <eos/><bos/>Their relationship was governed by an Amended and Restated Shareholders&apos; Agreement that contained a provision pursuant to which any shareholder could give notice to any other shareholder, thereby requiring the other shareholder to elect either to sell his or her shares or purchase the shares of the person giving the notice. <eos/><bos/>In 2012, the Departing Physicians decided they could no longer practice with Dr. Kashya and they gave notice pursuant to the provision, which required Dr. Kashyap either to sell her shares to them or purchase all of their shares. <eos/><bos/>Dr. Kashyap gave notice that she had elected to purchase the shares of the Departing Physicians.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90ad9508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">8</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Prior to January 31, 2013, the Departing Physicians were shareholders of Genesis through their respective professional corporations. <eos/><bos/>Up to that time they were also directors of Genesis. <eos/><bos/>From January 2013, Drs. Taylor and Hitkari were shareholders of the defendant, Olive either directly or through their professional corporations. <eos/><bos/>Olive was organized in December 2012 and was the company under which the Departing Physicians carried on their medical practices since February 1, 2013. <eos/><bos/>The defendant Dr. Nakhuda was a medical doctor who was employed by Genesis from February 2011 until April 2013 pursuant to an employment contract. <eos/><bos/>In June 2013, he moved his practice to Olive. <eos/><bos/>The defendants Wylie and St. Pierre were formerly senior management employees of Genesis. <eos/><bos/>On December 1, 2012, they gave notices of resignation to Genesis. <eos/><bos/>At the end of their notice period, they took up positions with Olive performing essentially the same functions for that company that they had formerly performed for Genesis.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90ad9518e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">9</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Departing Physicians continued to be employees, directors, and officers of Genesis in the 60 Day Period. <eos/><bos/>The procedures set out in the Shareholders&apos; Agreement required a number of steps to be taken in the 60 Day Period to complete the sale and purchase of the interest of the Departing Physicians. <eos/><bos/>There was no indication that the parties did anything to frustrate the completion of the sale transaction and the sale did complete as agreed. <eos/><bos/>As soon as Dr. Kashyap notified the Departing Physicians that she had elected to buy their shares, they, together with Wylie and St. Pierre, began to make plans to establish a new clinic in which they would continue to provide fertility treatments and consultations in the same manner that they had at Genesis. <eos/><bos/>Wylie and St. Pierre had been long time employees of Genesis and felt a great deal of personal loyalty to the Departing Physicians. <eos/><bos/>On December 1, 2012, they gave notices of termination of their employment with Genesis, effective December 31, 2012. <eos/><bos/>It is agreed that this was the required notice period under their employment contracts. <eos/><bos/>In early December 2012, the defendants took steps to incorporate Olive. <eos/><bos/>On January 1, 2013, Olive opened a temporary office in the same building in which Genesis was located. <eos/><bos/>On January 15, 2013, the Departing Physicians sent out a notice through the British Columbia Medical Association member announcement mailing service to other members of the BCMA, announcing that they were continuing their clinical practices at Olive&apos;s temporary facility and booking patients, effective immediately. <eos/><bos/>However, the Departing Physicians continued to practice at Genesis until the end of January. <eos/><bos/>On February 1, 2013, Genesis began providing some fertility medicine services from the temporary location. <eos/><bos/>The Departing Physicians used the services of Wylie and St. Pierre, during their notice period in December 2012 to assist them in setting up their new temporary and permanent clinics. <eos/><bos/>However, the great majority of time spent by Wylie and St. Pierre on establishing Olive in that month was done on their own time. <eos/><bos/>Wylie and Ms. St. Pierre were not recruited by the Departing Physicians. <eos/><bos/>They actively declared their intention to continue to work with the Departing Physicians as soon as it became possible for them to do so. <eos/><bos/>Ten Genesis employees signed employment contracts with Olive or the Departing Physicians on behalf of Olive prior to January 31, 2013. <eos/><bos/>The ten included all of the senior management team at Genesis. <eos/><bos/>Of the ten, 4 commenced employment with Olive before February 1, 2013.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90ad9528e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">10</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Departing Physicians and Senior Managers admitted that they occupied fiduciary positions with Genesis. <eos/><bos/>In Justice Sewell&apos;s view, the nature of the duties owed during the 60 Day Period must be examined in the context of the relationship between the parties. <eos/><bos/>The critical question was the extent of the duties owed by the defendants in the particular circumstances. <eos/><bos/>The Shareholders&apos; Agreement, the professional responsibilities of the Departing Physicians and the ways in which income was earned and distributed were all circumstances relevant to the determination of the extent of the permissible activities open to the Departing Physicians.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90ad9538e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">11</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Sewell was of the view that the contractual relationship between the parties could inform the scope of the fiduciary obligations owed by one party to the other. <eos/><bos/>It was necessary to determine the nature of the relationship between the parties and, in particular, the nature of the relationship between the physicians who owned Genesis. <eos/><bos/>The starting point for that determination was the Shareholders&apos; Agreement. <eos/><bos/>The parties intended their relationship with respect to the conduct of the affairs of Genesis to be governed by the terms of the Shareholders&apos; Agreement. <eos/><bos/>The unanimity provisions of the Shareholders&apos; Agreement significantly limited the power of its directors to act in a manner that could prejudice other shareholders or Genesis itself. <eos/><bos/>Justice Laskin&apos;s explanation for the rationale of the strict application of fiduciary duties to directors of a company in <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2039181989" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I746f9f118e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Canadian</cite.query> Aero Service</ital> emphasized that the reason for the rule lies in the power that fiduciaries have to affect the rights of other stakeholders in the company. <eos/><bos/>In this case, that power was significantly reduced by the terms of the Shareholders&apos; Agreement. <eos/><bos/>Justice Sewell also consider that the fact that Genesis was a corporation set up to permit the physicians to practice medicine together was relevant because, as practicing physicians, they were subject to a number of express regulations, fiduciary duties and ethical constraints with respect to the provision of medical services to patients. <eos/><bos/>The most important of these was the ethical duty all the physicians to facilitate continuity of care for patients and the right of those patients to receive care from the physician of their choice. <eos/><bos/>The ethical code and standards stress the importance of the patient-physician relationship and generally oppose the termination of the relationship without “legitimate reasons”.<eos/><bos/> The board of the College adopted the Canadian Medical Association&apos;s Code of Ethics as the baseline for all conduct of physicians in B.C. One such fundamental responsibility stated in the Code of Ethics is that a physician must <begin.quote ID="QT_0004"/>“consider first the well-being of the patient.”<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0004"/> Rule 19 of the Code of Ethics states that a physician must <begin.quote ID="QT_0003"/>“having accepted professional responsibility for a patient, continue to provide services until they are no longer required or wanted; until another suitable physician has assumed responsibility for the patient; or until the patient has been given reasonable notice that you intend to terminate the relationship”<end.quote refid="QT_0003"/>. <eos/><bos/>The College has provided a further practice standard titled “Ending the Patient-Physician Relationship” that expands on the duties that physicians owe to their patients. <eos/><bos/>The practice standard states: <begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>“the patient-physician relationship is a fiduciary relationship based on honesty, respect and trust, where the physician prioritizes the patient&apos;s care and well-being, and acknowledges the patient&apos;s autonomy with regard to personal choice, including lifestyle or treatment options. <eos/><bos/>One such personal choice is the ability of patients to choose which physician should treat them. <eos/><bos/>It is also clear that the patient-physician relationship should not be ended by a physician unless there are serious reasons for doing so.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0002"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id90ad9548e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">12</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Sewell explained that if physicians are to uphold their ethical obligations to their patient and respect patient choice, the patient must have the right to be informed of changes to a medical practice and has the right to choose which physician is to treat them, including the right to change clinics at any time. <eos/><bos/>The jurisprudence recognizes that the nature of the fiduciary duties owed in a corporation established to deliver professional services must be modified to accommodate the fiduciary and ethical duties owed to patients and clients and the ethical responsibilities of professionals.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90b00608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">13</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Sewell appreciated that there were a number of factual differences between the authorities and this case. <eos/><bos/>Genesis was a corporation and the Departing Physicians owed fiduciary duties to it. <eos/><bos/>The solicitation to which the plaintiffs objected in this case was not made to patients but to referring physicians. <eos/><bos/>The Departing Physicians left Genesis pursuant to the terms of the Shareholders&apos; Agreement and received a substantial payment for their interest in Genesis. <eos/><bos/>However, the underlying principle that giving priority to the duties owed by doctors to their patients takes precedence over some fiduciary duties to their employer that might apply in other circumstances applied in this case.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90b00618e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">14</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiffs expressly stated that they did not object to the defendants communicating with patients. <eos/><bos/>They did, however, say that the notice to the medical profession sent out in January 2013 was a breach of duty. <eos/><bos/>The difficulty that Justice Sewell had with that submission was that the Departing Physicians were specialists. <eos/><bos/>As a general rule in British Columbia, patients must be referred to a specialist by another physician for consultations. <eos/><bos/>A restriction on the ability of the Departing Physicians to communicate with referring doctors is also an unacceptable restriction on the right of patients to be treated by the doctor of their choice. <eos/><bos/>It is also in the public interest that referring physicians be provided with up to date and accurate information as to the professional staff of a clinic to whom they are making referrals.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90b00628e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">15</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The combined effect of the contractual arrangement between the parties and the fiduciary, regulatory and ethical duties owed to patients led Justice Sewell to conclude that the Departing Physicians were entitled to take significant steps to establish a new clinic as soon as they knew they were being bought out of Genesis and would no longer be practicing there. <eos/><bos/>Within the 60 Day Period the Departing Physicians were entitled to secure new premises for their practices, to make arrangements to permit them to provide uninterrupted medical services to their patients and to inform other physicians of the establishment of their new practice. <eos/><bos/>These steps included making staffing arrangements within reasonable limits. <eos/><bos/>The Departing Physicians did not breach their fiduciary duties as directors of Genesis by taking immediate steps to set up a new clinic once they were made aware that they could not practice at Genesis, provided that they acted fairly in doing so.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90b00638e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">16</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiffs alleged that many steps taken by the defendants damaged Genesis&apos;s interests and constituted breaches of fiduciary duty or unauthorized use of confidential information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90b00648e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">17</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>With respect to the removal of payroll information as well as the information used by Olive in the preparation of its business plan, it was a breach of confidence and breach of fiduciary duty to use that information without Genesis&apos;s consent.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90b00658e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">18</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Sewell considered that it was a breach of fiduciary duty on the part of the Departing Physicians not to inform Dr. Kashyap that they had entered into employment contracts with the Senior Managers and to use the services of the Senior Managers while they were still employed by Genesis. <eos/><bos/>However, once they were no longer employed by Genesis, the Senior Managers were entitled to work to prepare the Olive clinic to be able to begin providing patient care on February 1, 2013. <eos/><bos/>There were times when Wylie and St. Pierre performed services relating to setting up Olive while they were working in Genesis&apos;s office. <eos/><bos/>However, this occurred only rarely and both Wylie and St. Pierre competently carried out their duties for Genesis during December 2012. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence of any material amount of Olive related services being carried out by either of these defendants when they should have been working for Genesis.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90b00668e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">19</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The signing of employment contracts with other Genesis employees within the 60 Day Period without making full disclosure to Genesis was a breach of fiduciary duty on the part of the Departing Physicians.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90b00678e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">20</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Sewell accepted that Wylie used financial information about Genesis&apos;s operations in preparing the Olive Business Plan and for the purpose of preparing contracts of employment with Genesis employees. <eos/><bos/>This was a breach of fiduciary duty and an appropriation of Genesis&apos;s confidential information. <eos/><bos/>However, this information was not of significant importance to Olive or Genesis.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90b00688e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">21</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>While Justice Sewell did not accept that Dr. Kashyap was kept completely in the dark about their activities, Genesis was entitled to be kept informed of the Departing Physicians&apos; activities to allow it to manage its own future. <eos/><bos/>As fiduciaries, the Departing Physicians had a duty of candour as well as loyalty. <eos/><bos/>In Justice Sewell&apos;s view, they did not fulfill their duty of candour during the 60 Day Period. <eos/><bos/>Genesis did go through a period of uncertainty and disruption after Dr. Kashyap elected to purchase the Departing Physicians shares. <eos/><bos/>However, those difficulties were not primarily attributable to any breaches of duty or wrongdoing on the part of the defendants. <eos/><bos/>Dr. Kashyap undoubtedly had the right to buy out the Departing Physicians. <eos/><bos/>However, she did not think through the practical consequences of her decision in several important respects. <eos/><bos/>The first of these was she was purchasing a company whose most valuable assets were the doctors who practiced in the clinic. <eos/><bos/>Dr. Kashyap must be taken to have realized that much of the financial success of Genesis was derived from the personal reputations and abilities of the doctors who practiced in it. <eos/><bos/>Her decision to buyout the Departing Physicians resulted in the immediate loss of three of its five Physicians, and the likely departure of a fourth. <eos/><bos/>The second consideration was that the number of employees, the amount of equipment and the infrastructure associated with Genesis were all designed to support a clinic in which 4 or 5 doctors would be practicing. <eos/><bos/>In this regard, the number of doctors practicing at Genesis was the limiting factor on both its size and the amount of revenue it could generate. <eos/><bos/>The third consideration was that the Shareholders&apos; Agreement made it clear that the Departing Doctors had an unrestricted right to immediately begin competing with Genesis as soon as they ceased to be Shareholders. <eos/><bos/>The fourth consideration was that many of the employees of Genesis would be likely to leave that company and seek work elsewhere as soon as they were in a position to do so. <eos/><bos/>This was so for two reasons. <eos/><bos/>Firstly, Genesis clearly had more staff than it reasonably required to provide support for a one or two physician practice. <eos/><bos/>Secondly, many of the staff had worked closely with the Departing Physicians for many years and would naturally have wished to continue to do so. <eos/><bos/>Dr. Kashyap lacked a plan for dealing with these difficulties. <eos/><bos/>The lack of such a plan greatly contributed to her difficulties. <eos/><bos/>None of these difficulties can be attributed to any wrongful acts on the part of the defendants.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90b27708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">22</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiffs alleged that the defendants breached their fiduciary duties after the 60 Day Period by continuing to use confidential information belonging to Genesis and by continuing to covertly gather information about Genesis and its employees from Collings and using that information to recruit Genesis employees Collings continued to work at Genesis in a managerial role after she had decided to move to Olive. <eos/><bos/>It was clear that she was acting in the interests of Olive in making decisions about staffing matters at Genesis. <eos/><bos/>Collings remained at Genesis until May 16, 2013. <eos/><bos/>During that period, she frequently communicated with Wylie about Genesis employees and made recommendations as to which employees Olive should consider hiring. <eos/><bos/>Utilizing information obtained from Collings was a breach of fiduciary duty on the part of the fiduciary defendants. <eos/><bos/>It also constituted improper use of confidential information about Genesis&apos;s operations and human resources challenges. <eos/><bos/>Unlike many of the other breaches complained of, the actions of Collings were damaging to Genesis.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90b27718e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">23</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Genesis had established some breaches of fiduciary duty and some breaches of confidence. <eos/><bos/>A plaintiff that establishes breaches of fiduciary duty and breach of confidence is entitled to compensation either as damages for losses incurred or by an order requiring the defendant to account for any gains wrongfully obtained. <eos/><bos/>The defendants submitted that Genesis was required to elect what remedy it sought for the wrongs it alleged were committed against it by the time it closed its case. <eos/><bos/>The defendants relied on the judgement of Justice Myers in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2030436470" w-pub-number="0006459" ID="I747d5ab08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>First Majestic Silver Corp. v. Davila</ital>, 2013 BCSC 717 at para. 200</cite.query>, <case.history>aff&apos;d</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2033538552" w-pub-number="0006458" ID="I747d5ab28e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2014 BCCA 214</cite.query>, leave to appeal to the S.C.C refused, 35962 (27 November 2014), quoting from <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1995257032" w-pub-number="0004891" ID="I747d5ab48e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Island Records Ltd v. Tring International Plc.</ital>, [1996] 1 W.L.R. 1256</cite.query> (H.C.J. ChD. (Eng.)):</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0005"/>200. <eos/><bos/>He [the Judge in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1995257032" w-pub-number="0004891" ID="I747df6f18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Island Records]</cite.query> then went on to consider the issue before him (where the trial <ital>was</ital> split):</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext>7. Four principles are clear. <eos/><bos/>First whilst a plaintiff can apply in proceedings in the alternative for damages and an account of profits, he cannot obtain judgment for both: he can only obtain judgment for one or the other: see Neilson v Betts LR5 HL1 and De Vitre v Belts (1873) LR6 HL 319 at 321. <eos/><bos/>Second once judgment has been entered either for damages or an account of profits, any right-of election is lost: any claim to the remedy other than that for which judgment is entered is forever lost: see <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1940033761" w-pub-number="0004651" w-pinpoint-page="30" ID="I747ee1508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">United Australia v Barclays Bank [1941] AC 1 at 30</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>Third a party should in general not be required to elect or be found to have elected between remedies unless and until he is able to make an informed choice. <eos/><bos/>A right of election, if it is to be meaningful and not a mere gamble, must embrace the right to readily available information as to his likely entitlement in case of both the two alternative remedies. <eos/><bos/>It is quite unreasonable to require the plaintiff to speculate totally in the dark as to whether or not the sum recoverable by way of damages will exceed that recoverable under an account of profits. <eos/><bos/>In an analogous situation, it has been held unreasonable to require a plaintiff to speculate whether a payment into Court is sufficient to satisfy his claim for damages for infringement of copyright before he has been afforded inspection of the records of sales in the defendants books: see Mate &amp; Son v Samuel Stephen Ltd (1928–1935) Mac CC 257 at 261. <eos/><bos/>Fourth the exercise of the right of election should not be unreasonably delayed to the prejudice of the defendant.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0005"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id90b27728e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">24</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Sewell concluded that <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00007" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2030436470" w-pub-number="0006459" ID="I747f7d918e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>First Majestic</ital></cite.query> was distinguishable because in that case the plaintiffs were seeking to defer making an election as to remedy until after the court quantified the relief they would be entitled to under the alternative claims. <eos/><bos/>Justice Myers did not accede to that request and required the plaintiffs to elect the remedy they sought at the end of the trial. <eos/><bos/>Justice Sewell did not take any of the cases cited by the defendants to stand for the proposition that a plaintiff who has established a wrong and seeks a particular remedy that the court does not consider appropriate should be left with no remedy. <eos/><bos/>The law gives the court a considerable degree of discretion in fashioning an appropriate remedy once it determines that the defendants are liable. <eos/><bos/>In this case, the plaintiffs set out the relief they sought in their closing submissions. <eos/><bos/>There was nothing that precluded them from seeking alternative remedies if the court determined that their preferred remedy was unavailable.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90b27738e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">25</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In Justice Sewell&apos;s view, the correct approach to determining the remedy in a case in which either an accounting of profits attributable to a breach of fiduciary duty or damages for loss suffered by the principal as a result of the breach is set out in <ital>Moore International (Canada) Ltd. v. Carter</ital> (1984), 56 B.C.L.R. 207 (C.A.):</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0007"/>19. <eos/><bos/>The availability of these remedies was discussed by Mr. Justice Laskin in the Can. <eos/><bos/>Aero case at pp. 621–2.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0007"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0008"/>20. <eos/><bos/>In my opinion the plaintiff is not required to elect one remedy or the other. <eos/><bos/>He may lead evidence of both his own loss and his fiduciary&apos;s profit. <eos/><bos/>And the trial judge may then make an award of compensation that is supported by the evidence.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0008"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0009"/>21. <eos/><bos/>In this case, Mr. Justice Legg made an award of damages. <eos/><bos/>But he did not think that the direct evidence in support of the loss sustained by Moore was as helpful in determining that loss as the indirect evidence of the loss constituted by the evidence of Salton&apos;s profit. <eos/><bos/>The decision to adopt that train of reasoning depended on an assessment of the weight to be attached to the testimony of particular witnesses and belongs in the province of the trial judge. <eos/><bos/>It is not wrong in principle.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0009"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0010"/>22. <eos/><bos/>I have two further general comments.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0010"/></paratext></para><para><paratext>23. <eos/><bos/>The first is this. <eos/><bos/>The fiduciary or his accomplice should not be permitted to gain from the breach of the fiduciary&apos;s obligation of trust and good faith. <eos/><bos/>So, if their profit is greater than the loss by the former employer, an accounting is a better standard of compensation than damages. <eos/><bos/>But, conversely, the employer should not be penalized for any business ineptitude of the fiduciary or his accomplice. <eos/><bos/>So, if the loss by the employer is greater than the profit of the fiduciary, damages would be the better standard of compensation. <eos/><bos/>It follows that, where the evidence will support a sound assessment based on an accounting of profits and also a sound assessment based on a calculation of loss, and where, in the particular circumstances, both remedies are available and both are supported by the pleadings and the evidence, the compensation awarded should be the higher of the two. <eos/><bos/>I think that this is the principle adopted, even before the fusion of law and equity, in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00008" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1867078213" w-pub-number="0005775" ID="I748263c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Wightman v. Helliwell (1867), 13 Gr. 330 (Upper Canada, Chancery)</cite.query> where, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00009" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1867078213" w-pub-number="0005775" w-pinpoint-page="344" ID="I748263c28e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">at p. 344</cite.query>, Chancellor VanKoughnet said that: “The principle and the object in every case is to make good the loss caused by the acts of omission or commission of the trustee, or to wrest from him any benefit he has, or is taken to have, derived from the use of the trust moneys.”<eos/><bos/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0012"/>24. <eos/><bos/>My second comment is that I consider it the better practice not to make an award of damages to the nearest cent, unless it is intended as compensation for a specific debt or expenditure. <eos/><bos/>Damages are a matter of assessment, not a matter of calculation. <eos/><bos/>The purpose of calculation is not to provide a substitute for an assessment but to anchor the assessment in the evidence. <eos/><bos/>In this case, Mr. Justice Legg was assessing Moore&apos;s loss and was using Salton&apos;s profit as an aid in the assessment of Moore&apos;s loss. <eos/><bos/>I do not think that it is an error of law to reach an assessment of damages to the nearest cent in those circumstances, but I think that it gives a misleading appearance of precision to an assessment that ought to transcend mathematics. <eos/><bos/>And it invites attacks based on flaws in the starting figures and imperfections in the arithmetic.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0012"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id90b4e808e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">26</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Genesis left it up to the court to determine an award of compensation that was supported by the evidence. <eos/><bos/>Justice Sewell concluded that it was entitled to do so and was not required to elect one remedy or the other.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90b4e818e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">27</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Determining an appropriate remedy in this case presented challenges that were not present in many of the cases relied upon by the plaintiffs. <eos/><bos/>Most of those cases involved a central act that was a breach of fiduciary duty. <eos/><bos/>In such cases, less serious breaches of duty can be viewed as being done pursuant to an object that was itself a breach. <eos/><bos/>In this case, however, the Departing Physicians had the right to set up a competing clinic within which to practice and the benefit they obtained came from that lawful activity. <eos/><bos/>Justice Sewell explained that the Court must be careful not to deprive them of that benefit in any remedy granted.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90b4e828e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">28</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In addition, the authorities make it clear that any remedy must be restitutionary and the object should be to put the plaintiff in as good a position it would have been in had there been no breach. <eos/><bos/>The court must therefore fashion a remedy that is appropriate to the wrong established. <eos/><bos/>The Departing Physicians breached their fiduciary duty to Genesis to act fairly in the following ways: a) By entering into employment agreements with Wylie and St. Pierre and other Genesis employees while the Departing Physicians continued to be directors of Genesis without making proper disclosure of that fact to Genesis b) By utilizing confidential information of Genesis in the preparation of Olive&apos;s business plan c) By utilizing confidential information of Genesis in connection with hiring Genesis employees. <eos/><bos/>The Departing Physicians breached the Shareholders&apos; Agreement by utilizing Genesis&apos;s financial information. <eos/><bos/>Wylie wrongfully used confidential information belonging to Genesis and failed to disclose to Dr. Kashyap that she had signed an employment contract with the Departing Physicians. <eos/><bos/>As a fiduciary, Wylie owed a duty to disclose that fact to Dr. Kashyap. <eos/><bos/>She also breached her fiduciary duty by conferring with Collings about what Genesis employees Olive should offer employment to while Collings was employed as head of the nursing department at Genesis. <eos/><bos/>The only breach of fiduciary duty St. Pierre committed was her failure to disclose to Dr. Kashyap that she had signed an employment agreement with the Departing Physicians. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence that St. Pierre removed or misused any confidential information belonging to Genesis.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90b4e838e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">29</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The preferred remedy sought by the plaintiffs was a judgment equal to the price the Plaintiffs paid to purchase the business of Genesis. <eos/><bos/>The fundamental factual premise of this was that the Defendants, immediately upon Dr. Kashyap becoming obliged to pay the $4.275 million for their shares, set out to destroy that very business that they had just sold to Dr. Kashyap.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90b4e848e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">30</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Sewell concluded that the plaintiffs failed to establish entitlement to this remedy. <eos/><bos/>The fundamental obstacle to granting this remedy was that Genesis was not a party to the share purchase agreement. <eos/><bos/>This remedy would therefore be appropriate only if Dr. Kashyap established a basis for it. <eos/><bos/>She had not established a breach of the contract pursuant to which the shares were purchased from the Departing Physicians. <eos/><bos/>On this ground alone, the claim for return of the purchase price must fail. <eos/><bos/>In addition, the plaintiffs failed to demonstrate that the Departing Physicians set out to destroy the business they had just sold to Dr. Kashyap. <eos/><bos/>The object pursued by the Departing Physicians was to continue to practice medicine together in their area of specialty. <eos/><bos/>In pursuing that objective, they breached certain duties to Genesis. <eos/><bos/>They did not destroy Dr. Kashyap&apos;s practice or deprive her of the right to utilize the assets of Genesis for that purpose. <eos/><bos/>The wrongful acts of the Departing Physicians were not the reason for most of the difficulties Genesis faced.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90b75908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">31</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>As an alternative remedy, the plaintiffs sought an order that the Departing Physicians disgorge all benefits earned by the Defendants for a period of two years. <eos/><bos/>Justice Sewell concluded that such a remedy would be disproportionate to any wrongs done by the defendants. <eos/><bos/>The first difficulty with it was that it ignored the contractual right of the Departing Physicians to compete with Genesis. <eos/><bos/>Genesis&apos;s claim for a disgorgement of profits also failed to recognize that the defendants were only required to disgorge any benefits they received from their breach of duty. <eos/><bos/>They are not required to disgorge any benefits they obtained from lawful activity on their part. <eos/><bos/>Substantially all of the benefits the Departing Shareholders earned from Olive were acquired from their skill, effort and professional standing in the medical profession. <eos/><bos/>There was no indication that the Departing Physicians received a significant benefit from their breaches of fiduciary duty. <eos/><bos/>The breaches they committed did not make any material contribution to their success. <eos/><bos/>The stringent rule requiring a fiduciary to account for profits should not be carried to extremes and should not be transformed into a vehicle for the unjust enrichment of the plaintiff.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90b75918e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">32</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The defendant&apos;s conduct with respect to recruiting Genesis&apos;s employees and their failure to be candid with Genesis about their organizational activities in the 60 Day Period, did cause some harm to Genesis. <eos/><bos/>In addition, the conduct of Collings constituted unfair competition after the 60 Day Period. <eos/><bos/>As these were breaches of equitable duties, compensation for them must be assessed on equitable principles. <eos/><bos/>In assessing claims for damages or equitable compensation for breach of fiduciary duty and breach of confidence, the courts do not require the same degree of certainty as in cases of breach of contract or tort. <eos/><bos/>Nevertheless, there must still be a connection between the breach and the damages claimed. <eos/><bos/>Justice Sewell observed:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0013"/>The principles were discussed <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00010" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1991346037" w-pub-number="0005156" ID="I748b3d608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Canson Enterprises Ltd. v. Boughton &amp; Co., [1991] 3 S.C.R. 534 at para. 72</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>Justice La Forest drew a distinction between cases in which a trustee or fiduciary has obtained property that properly belongs to its principal and those in which the fiduciary has acted in breach of its duty and thereby injured its principal:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext>The appellants urged us to accept the manner of calculating compensation adopted by the courts in trust cases or situations akin to a trust, and they relied in particular on the Guerin case, supra. <eos/><bos/>I think the courts below were perfectly right to reject that proposition. <eos/><bos/>There is a sharp divide between a situation where a person has control of property which in the view of the court belongs to another, and one where a person is under a fiduciary duty to perform an obligation where equity&apos;s concern is simply that the duty be performed honestly and in accordance with the undertaking the fiduciary has taken on; see Sealy, “Some Principles of Fiduciary Obligation”, [1963] Cambridge L.J. 119; Sealy, “Fiduciary Relationships”, [1962] Cambridge L.J. 69. <eos/><bos/>In the case of a trust relationship, the trustee&apos;s obligation is to hold the res or object of the trust for his cestui que trust, and on breach the concern of equity is that it be restored to the cestui que trust or if that cannot be done to afford compensation for what the object would be worth. <eos/><bos/><ital>In the case of a mere breach of duty, the concern of equity is to ascertain the loss resulting from the breach of the particular duty. <eos/><bos/>Where the wrongdoer has received some benefit, that benefit can be disgorged, but the measure of compensation where no such benefit has been obtained by the wrongdoer raises different issues. <eos/><bos/>I turn then specifically to that situation.<eos/><bos/></ital> (Emphasis added.)<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0013"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id90bc3b08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">33</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In Justice Sewell&apos;s view, compensation must be assessed by determining the loss suffered by Genesis from the breaches found to have occurred. <eos/><bos/>Genesis advanced a claim for damages ranging from $1,071,949 to $1,278,050 for losses attributable to the defendants&apos; wrongful conduct.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90beac08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">34</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Sewell was satisfied that there was a causal link between additional training time for new nurses and conduct of Collings on Olive&apos;s behalf. <eos/><bos/>However, the evidence as to the actual amount of training time incurred was deficient. <eos/><bos/>However, many nurses left Genesis for reasons unrelated to any actions on the part of the defendants. <eos/><bos/>Genesis was entitled to an award of $10,000 for this claim. <eos/><bos/>This award took into account the fact that it would have been expected that there would have been significant staffing changes that resulted from the departure of the Departing Physicians and the attendant reduction of the size of its operations. <eos/><bos/>Many of the nurses who left Genesis did so because of their long association with the Departing Physicians and unhappiness with the working environment at Genesis and not because of any wrongful recruiting activities. <eos/><bos/>These factors justified a lower assessment of damages for this claim.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90beac18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">35</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Genesis claimed for lost revenue from PGD cycles that Lafreniere referred on to Olive while he was employed at Genesis. <eos/><bos/>Olive accepted these referrals without seeking or obtaining Genesis&apos;s consent. <eos/><bos/>The opportunity to do these cycles was a corporate opportunity belonging to Genesis that Olive had no right to appropriate without Genesis&apos;s informed consent or if the patient made an independent decision to choose to use Olive. <eos/><bos/>Malice or bad faith are not essential elements of a claim for the wrongful appropriation of a corporate opportunity. <eos/><bos/>To succeed in a claim to require an accounting all that Genesis needs to establish is that it did not give its informed consent. <eos/><bos/>Genesis established a claim for the diversion of referrals. <eos/><bos/>Justice Sewell accepted Genesis&apos;s evidence that it earned a profit of $7,458 per cycle and therefore award rounded damages of $40,000 for this claim.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90beac28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">36</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Genesis advanced a claim of $61,643 for wages paid to staff members for December 2012 and January 2013. <eos/><bos/>All of the employees in question continued to fulfill their employment obligations to Genesis in the relevant periods and Genesis accordingly has had the benefit of the services they performed. <eos/><bos/>However, Genesis was entitled to some measure of compensation for the time the named staff employees were paid while they were performing services for Olive. <eos/><bos/>It is impossible to determine the value of that time with any degree of certainty. <eos/><bos/>An award of $15,000, being approximately 25% of the wages paid was reasonable. <eos/><bos/>This award was primarily based on the conduct of Collings and Wylie&apos;s cooperation in and knowledge of that conduct.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90beac38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">37</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Genesis claimed reimbursement of a number of expenses it paid which it alleged should be charged to the Departing Physicians. <eos/><bos/>The Departing Physicians retained Weir and Company to provide advice with respect to the tax implications of purchasing Dr. Kashyap&apos;s shares in Genesis. <eos/><bos/>Genesis paid these fees. <eos/><bos/>These expenses should properly have been born by the shareholders who incurred them. <eos/><bos/>Genesis paid dues for the Departing Physicians in January 2013 for the College of Physicians and Surgeons of British Columbia, the British Columbia Medical Association and another professional organization to which Dr. Yuzpe belonged. <eos/><bos/>These dues presumably related to the 2013 calendar year, during which the Departing Physicians worked at Olive for 11 months. <eos/><bos/>Genesis should not have paid for dues which permitted the Departing Physicians to continue their practice at Olive. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, the defendants were liable for 11/12 of these items. <eos/><bos/>The total of these items was $10,274.49. 11/12ths of that amount was rounded to $9,420.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90beac48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">38</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The defendants conceded that fees related to billings for private practice billings to MSP were properly chargeable to the Departing Physicians. <eos/><bos/>Genesis was entitled to judgment in the amount of $3,477 for this claim.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90beac58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">39</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Genesis claimed $3,679.20 for membership fees paid on behalf of staff that resigned to work for Olive. <eos/><bos/>While many Genesis staff members left it of their own volition after January 31, 2013, Collings was acting improperly in assisting Olive in evaluating Genesis staff as future Olive employees. <eos/><bos/>Olive obtained a benefit from the prepayment of these fees. <eos/><bos/>When the fees were paid, the Departing Physicians had an expectation that many of the employees on whose behalf they were paid would eventually move to their new clinic. <eos/><bos/>The defendants failed to make adequate disclosure of their intention to hire these staff members. <eos/><bos/>Even if the defendants did not wrongfully recruit these employees they should not have caused Genesis to pay their fees in full without fully informing Dr. Kashyap that they considered it appropriate to offer employment to them. <eos/><bos/>In these particular circumstances, Justice Sewell allowed this claim, which was rounded up to $3680.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90beac68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">40</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Although it was not specifically sought by Genesis, Justice Sewell considered that some award was appropriate for the disruption caused to it by the lack of candour of the Departing Physicians in informing Genesis about their activities during the 60 Day Period. <eos/><bos/>The unfair competition engaged in by Olive through Collings&apos; activities also warranted an award of compensation. <eos/><bos/>The amount of such an award could not be tied to any specific claim, nor could it be measured with any degree of certainty. <eos/><bos/>Given the size of Genesis&apos;s operation, the amounts paid to the Departing Shareholders, the revenue generated by Olive and the fact that Olive did make use of confidential information belonging to Genesis, particularly in preparing its application for Bank financing and from information obtained from Collings, Justice Sewell considered an award of $100,000 to be appropriate.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90c11d08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">41</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Genesis sought an award of punitive damages. <eos/><bos/>Justice Sewell concluded that the conduct of the defendants did not rise to the level of a marked departure from the ordinary standards of human decency.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The defendants no doubt exhibited a high level of animosity to Dr. Kashyap. <eos/><bos/>However, the case against them rested principally upon an allegation of breaches of fiduciary duty. <eos/><bos/>The underpinning of Genesis&apos;s case was that the defendants who were found to be fiduciaries preferred their own interests over that of the company to which they owed fiduciary duties. <eos/><bos/>However, Justice Sewell rejected Genesis&apos;s submission that the defendants set out to destroy it or acted maliciously and with a view to injure it. <eos/><bos/>In the particular context of this case, in which the defendants genuinely felt aggrieved at losing the business they had built up over many years, their conduct, although wrongful in some respects, was not so egregious as to warrant an award of punitive damages.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90c11d18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">42</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Genesis was awarded damages as equitable compensation against the Departing Physicians as follows:</paratext><tbl ID="I593cada0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><table frame="all"><eos/><bos/><tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="left"><colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="4*"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="25*"/><colspec colnum="3" colname="3" colwidth="7*"/><tbody><row><entry colname="1">1.</entry><entry colname="2">New nurse training costs</entry><entry colname="3">$10,000</entry></row><row><entry colname="1">2.</entry><entry colname="2">PGD cycles referred to Olive</entry><entry colname="3">$40,000</entry></row><row><entry colname="1">3.</entry><entry colname="2">Staff Wages</entry><entry colname="3">$15,000</entry></row><row><entry colname="1">4.</entry><entry colname="2">Weir and Company billings</entry><entry colname="3">$5,600</entry></row><row><entry colname="1">5.</entry><entry colname="2">Professional Dues</entry><entry colname="3">$9,420</entry></row><row><entry colname="1">6.</entry><entry colname="2">MSP registration fees</entry><entry colname="3">$3,477</entry></row><row><entry colname="1">7.</entry><entry colname="2">Memberships for employees</entry><entry colname="3">$3,680</entry></row><row><entry colname="1">8.</entry><entry colname="2">Damages for disruption and—breach of confidence</entry><entry colname="3">$100,000</entry></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2">Total</entry><entry colname="3">$187,000[<footnote.reference refid="Id90c11d28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">43</footnote.reference>]</entry></row></tbody></tgroup><eos/></table></tbl><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00011" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2039181989" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I749a31818e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">XY, LLC v. Canadian Topsires Selection</cite.query> Inc.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id90c11d38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">44</footnote.reference>] the major issue was the determination of damages with respect to: firstly, Tang, Zhang and Ai De, if liability was established; and, secondly, the other defendants against whom liability had already been established. <eos/><bos/>XY sought compensatory damages arising in the period after that considered by the Court in the Original Action after the end of 2008, on the basis of conspiracy and breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>In the original action, the Court had granted judgment in favour of XY against JingJing, Zhu, and two of his employees, Tang and Zhou in the amount of $8.5 million on the basis of breach of contract, breach of confidence, conspiracy and deceit. <eos/><bos/>The Court had also granted a permanent and mandatory injunction designed to protect XY&apos;s intellectual property and technology rights.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90c11d48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">45</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge observed that the overall objective in assessing damages (or profits) in intellectual property cases is to find a broadly equitable result. <eos/><bos/>It <begin.quote ID="QT_0014"/>“must always be more or less a matter of estimate, because it is impossible to ascertain, with arithmetical precision, what, in the ordinary course of business, would have been the amount of the plaintiffs&apos; sales and profits. <eos/><bos/>If a plaintiff establishes that a loss has been suffered, the difficulty of determining the amount does not excuse the wrongdoer from paying damages or disgorging its profits. <eos/><bos/>Damages are to be assessed by the court, not calculated, based on facts that were within the plaintiff&apos;s power to prove, and upon which the court may make a fair and reasonable estimate of damages.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0014"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id90c38e08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">46</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In considering the calculation of damages, the Court in the original action stated that factual inferences may be drawn against the party who has failed to produce records that would be relevant to the calculation of damages and applied this principle against the defendants. <eos/><bos/>Concerted actions were taken by the defendants to avoid document disclosure in the current litigation. <eos/><bos/>IEI&apos;s embryo production records were intentionally not disclosed to their lawyers. <eos/><bos/>In addition to misleading the IND Group&apos;s external lawyers, the IND Group employees intentionally suppressed disclosure of the 2009 CTS semen-production record, as well as all their records from China. <eos/><bos/>Semen-production records, embryo-production records and embryos sales/use records, both in Canada and China, were not produced. <eos/><bos/>XY made reasonably persistent efforts to obtain records from the defendants that would reveal the actual scope of the Canadian and Chinese operations, both before and after the commencement of this litigation.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90c38e18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">47</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The IND Group companies kept detailed and well-organized records of its semen and embryo production. <eos/><bos/>There was no reason to think that there had been any change in the manner and extent of the defendants&apos; recordkeeping relating to semen and embryo production. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge concluded that Zhu, either personally or within the IND Group companies that he controlled, had detailed records relating to the production and use of sexed semen and embryos in China, including the birth of live calves, within his control and/or possession. <eos/><bos/>He also had production records of the IND Group&apos;s operations in Canada up to the time of the APO in April 2012. <eos/><bos/>XY sought a remedy based on an assessment of the highest reasonable number, and value, of sexed semen and embryos likely created and used by the defendants in Canada and China. <eos/><bos/>In these circumstances, the principle of <ital>omnia praesumuntur contra spoliatorem</ital> applied. <eos/><bos/>Since the defendants made it impossible to determine the extent of their operations in Canada and China, an inference should be drawn that the defendants used all the sexed semen and embryos they reasonably had the capacity to produce.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90c38e28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">48</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>XY submitted that its claim for unjust enrichment could stand alongside the claims for breach of confidence and conspiracy. <eos/><bos/>It argued that the Court could fashion an appropriate remedy of damages for the breach of confidence and conspiracy, and disgorgement of profits for the unjust enrichment, while still being careful to ensure there was no overlap in remedy. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge agreed with XY that: a) its claims against Zhu and the IND Group companies for damages (breach of confidence and conspiracy) and for disgorgement of profits (unjust enrichment) were alternative remedies. <eos/><bos/>As such, XY was required to elect as to which remedy it would seek judgment. <eos/><bos/>XY sought judgment based on a disgorgement of profits as against Zhu, IND, IDI, IEI, CTS, FBI and Ai De, jointly and severally; b) its claims against Zhu and the IND Group companies on the one hand, and Tang and Zhang on the other, were cumulative remedies. <eos/><bos/>XY could pursue Tang and Zhang on another basis (i.e. damages for breach of confidence and conspiracy), which was the basis upon which XY sought judgment against them jointly and severally; and c) any amounts collected from Tang and Zhang would constitute partial satisfaction of the amount of the judgment as against Zhu and the IND Group companies. <eos/><bos/>The relief as sought by XY was granted as against the various defendants.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90c38e38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">49</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The following relief was granted, in addition to the mandatory and prohibitory injunction provisions and declaration of constructive trust: 1. Zhu, CTS, FBI, IND, IEI IDI and Ai De Diagnostic (collectively, the “IND Judgment Debtors”), jointly and severally, shall pay the plaintiff $269,856,121.68, which includes pre-judgment interest to January 15, 2016, plus a per diem pre-judgment interest rate of $19,969.35 from January 16, 2016 to the date of this judgment 2. Tang and Zhang jointly and severally, shall pay the plaintiff $60,059,536.86, which includes pre-judgment interest to January 15, 2016, plus a per diem pre-judgment interest rate of $4,444.41 from January 16, 2016 to the date of judgment. 3. The IND Judgment Debtors, jointly and severally, shall pay the plaintiff punitive damages of $300,000. 4. Tang shall pay the plaintiff punitive damages in the amount of $100,000. 5. Zhang shall pay the plaintiff punitive damages in the amount of $100,000. 6. The IND Award, the Tang and Zhang Award, and the awards of punitive damages against the IND Judgment Debtors, Tang and Zhang shall bear post-judgment interest pursuant to the <ital>Court Order Interest Act</ital>, R.S.B.C. 1996, c. 79, from the date of judgment.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90c38e48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">50</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00012" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2039565063" w-pub-number="0005475" ID="I749fd6d18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>TDC Broadband Inc. v. Nova Scotia (Attorney General)</ital></cite.query>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id90c38e58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">51</footnote.reference>] the plaintiff submitted that the defendant&apos;s breach of confidence caused it to suffer a compensable loss. <eos/><bos/>TDC sought damages for economic loss in the amount of $2,495,000; special damages associated with its bankruptcy in the amount of $56,147; general damages of $300,000; punitive damages of $275,000; together with prejudgment interest, costs and disbursements. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff&apos;s focus was on demonstrating the complete loss of value for the delivery system. <eos/><bos/>The calculation of damages flowed from that premise. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge concluded that the loss of value was something less than that claimed.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90c38e68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">52</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>There were two significant aspects of the plaintiff&apos;s confidential information used by the defendant to construct the RFP. The first was the Business Proposal. <eos/><bos/>The second was 5 different aspects of the TDC information in the pilot RFP. The defendant did not include TDC information in the pilot RFP that detailed the most valuable part of the delivery system, which was the overall assembly of the many off the shelf constituent hardware parts together with Dennis Cockerill&apos;s configurations that made them work together. <eos/><bos/>Also, the evidence did not support a conclusion that Seaside had the ability to or did deploy the TDC delivery system in the Cumberland pilot. <eos/><bos/>Nor did the evidence demonstrate that other bidders subsequently deployed a system based upon the pilot RFP information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90c5ff08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">53</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge did not agree with the submission that what the Province did was create a <begin.quote ID="QT_0015"/>“monopoly for the provision of rural broadband service”<end.quote refid="QT_0015"/>. <eos/><bos/>Other technologies existed to provide this service, and there was no evidence that competing suppliers were barred from establishing a competing business using any delivery system it chose. <eos/><bos/>TDC was the only company that had attempted to provide fixed wireless broadband to this very difficult and underserved segment of the Nova Scotia marketplace, but it had not shown that its system was financially viable. <eos/><bos/>If it had the necessary funding from non-governmental sources then it could have continued to operate, notwithstanding the Province&apos;s decision to “enter the fray”.<eos/><bos/> Refusing to award TDC the pilot on the basis of its lack of financial stability, business acumen, lack of customer support and service capability is not the same as setting up a process whereby competition is eliminated from the market through the designation of a single company or group of companies to be the sole provider of that service. <eos/><bos/>The Cumberland RFP demonstrated that there was competition in the marketplace.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90c5ff18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">54</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge was satisfied that without a substantial contribution of government funding and a significant rapid development of its business expertise TDC would not have been able to continue to develop its operations beyond 2006, with or without the Province&apos;s decision to support other providers. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence that TDC could meet either of its needs, in particular because the requisite business experience was dependent upon non-existent funds to hire qualified people to take the company forward.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90c5ff28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">55</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge agreed, in part, that but for the intervention of the government into the marketplace TDC would have had options to its further progress, including that it could have licenced, sold or partnered and used the Delivery System for their profit. <eos/><bos/>TDC was too confident in its belief that the strength of its technology could overcome the company&apos;s financial problems. <eos/><bos/>There was an erroneous assumption that the Province would have to do business with TDC. It was easy to see in hindsight that once it became apparent that there was insufficient capital available to carry on the business the company needed to: 1. Partner with someone who had the resources to take the development and distribution of its technology to the next level; or 2. Hire themselves out to the Province or another ISP on a consulting basis to share their expertise; or 3. Sell the rights to the delivery system. <eos/><bos/>These were TDC&apos;s only viable options. <eos/><bos/>Seaside was interested in a collaboration with TDC as of July 2006 and it was TDC who walked away from the discussions. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence that TDC attempted to partner with any other person or company. <eos/><bos/>The Province provided TDC with opportunities to engage with Flam. <eos/><bos/>TDC representatives did not act on this advice. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence that TDC made efforts to explore licencing or sale of its product. <eos/><bos/>The option to licence, sell or partner was certainly open to TDC at least until the award of the Cumberland Pilot, which was before the successful bidder would have to begin developing their delivery system. <eos/><bos/>The extent to which it was still an option until TDC&apos;s May 2007 bankruptcy depends upon the extent to which the Cumberland RFP damaged the commercial value of the TDC confidential information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90c5ff38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">56</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The claim of “economic loss” is intended to provide compensatory damages for harm to economic interests. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge was satisfied that the TDC delivery system and Business Proposal had value and that some of that value was lost by the inclusion of TDC&apos;s confidential information in the Cumberland RFP. Further, a sum that recognizes the value to the Province for its use of the plaintiff&apos;s confidential information was also an appropriate basis upon which to assess damages. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge did not agree that most or all of the value of the delivery system was lost by the disclosure to bidders of TDC&apos;s information in the Cumberland RFP. As such, the defendant should not be liable for the entire value of the cost of developing the Delivery System.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90c5ff48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">57</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The extent of the damage to the commercial value of the plaintiff&apos;s confidential information was integral to the assessment of the loss suffered. <eos/><bos/>Specifically, the trial judge found that: (a) The pilot RFP contained TDC information that conveyed to Seaside (and other bidders) the general structure of the TDC system, but did not reveal all of the technical detail necessary to duplicate the TDC system; (b) Seaside did not use the most technologically advanced aspects of the TDC delivery system in the pilot area, likely because it did not have the intellectual property that Dennis Cockerill held to himself; (c) The choice of the coverage area of Cumberland County set out in the pilot RFP provided a much less challenging topography than Caledonia and almost certainly guaranteed the technological success of Seaside&apos;s pilot without using the TDC technology. <eos/><bos/>As such, the advantages of TDC&apos;s delivery system were not as necessary to the success of the pilot project; (d) The choice of Cumberland County for the pilot also offered a greater potential for subscriber uptake, by reason of the demographics for that area as compared to Caledonia; (e) The provincial RTF issued in 2007 contained further technical information that was consistent with the TDC system but still did not provide detailed specifications or configurations that were held only by Dennis Cockerill; (f) The use of the Motorola Canopy system was known to the industry and in particular to Seaside which was already using it as part of a fixed wireless delivery system in certain parts of Cape Breton in the summer of 2006; (g) The Province could not grant TDC an exclusive right to use the 900 MHz spectrum- that was a factor controlled by Industry Canada; (h) The Province did not and would not have entered into a contract providing TDC with the exclusive use of its towers to provide Broadband delivery. <eos/><bos/>TDC would have received a licence to use the towers but because of TDC&apos;s constantly changing plans an agreement was never finalized; (i) During the period of its lease of the provincially owned towers TDC could expect to be the beneficiary of a similar clause to that in their draft agreement, that is, that no subsequent user could install in a way that interfered with the signals of existing tower users. <eos/><bos/>The result could have aided TDC in maintaining any competitive edge it had by getting to the market with its product before other ISPs, but it was not a guarantee against competition that also used the towers; (j) TDC overreached by trying to widely expand when it should have been consolidating in more profitable areas while it had the capital to do so; (k) TDC had exhausted its funding by the summer of 2006, and did not have a viable business plan in the absence of government funding; (l) The Province had no legal obligation to TDC to support its business nor to ensure its ongoing viability; (m) It was unrealistic for TDC to assume that the Province would sole source contracts of this magnitude and complexity, or that the Province would skew the tender process so as to overlook the financial instability and customer service inadequacies of TDC; (n) There was no basis upon which TDC could have been justified to rely upon the defendant to provide funding for its operations; (o) By the time of the trial, Premier MacDonald&apos;s promise of 100% broadband coverage in Nova Scotia was still not achieved despite the expenditure of millions of dollars by the defendant.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90c87008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">58</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge concluded that “something special” was misused by the defendant. <eos/><bos/>This information provided great value to the Rural Broadband team in drafting its pilot RFP and in being able to do so quickly, which was crucial to Flam&apos;s superiors. <eos/><bos/>In effect, TDC&apos;s information educated the Project members in a highly complicated technology where otherwise its only apparent source of technical information was Dan MacDonald, who was not an expert in the field. <eos/><bos/>Learning what the issues were and determining the ways to address those problems made that information a valuable asset. <eos/><bos/>However, what ultimately ended up in the RFP was an identification of the issues and not a lot of the answers arrived at by TDC. However, the RFP designers were not experts in the industry and so the TDC information that the Project members sought and obtained provided a shortcut, which the defendant did not have the permission to take and did not pay for. <eos/><bos/>The Province gained from the knowledge acquired by TDC&apos;s principals over an extended period of time. <eos/><bos/>There is an important difference though between what the Rural Broadband Project team members knew of the TDC delivery system and Business Proposal, and what it misused. <eos/><bos/>The defendant was only liable for that which it provably misused. <eos/><bos/>There was no basis upon which to conclude that members of the Rural Broadband project passed on any TDC confidential information to Seaside or the other bidders in ways other than that set out in the pilot RFP. Once the pilot RFP was released the extent of the damage to TDC had crystallized. <eos/><bos/>There was no basis upon which the defendant would have required TDC&apos;s further assistance, unless it was prepared to seek the undisclosed and more valuable TDC information held by Dennis Cockerill. <eos/><bos/>It did not and so TDC could not be compensated for that which it did not provide. <eos/><bos/>The value of the plaintiff&apos;s economic loss was to be measured by considering the value to the Province of retaining TDC to assist the Rural Broadband Project between the Project&apos;s inception in March 2006 and the release of the RFP in September 2006; and also as a product of the intrinsic value of the information that was lost by TDC and gained by the defendant. <eos/><bos/>A way of looking at the value of the misused information is the cost that would be agreed to by a willing buyer and a willing seller where the product purchased was the provision of TDC&apos;s information and in person expertise, together with the right for the Project to use the information for the development of the Rural Broadband project and the construction of the pilot RFP. In giving up this information to the Province there would be a corresponding diminishment in the overall commercial value of the information provided by TDC, once published in the RFP. The value of the plaintiff&apos;s economic loss was $125,000.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90c87018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">59</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The bankruptcy of TDC was not causally connected to the defendant&apos;s tortious conduct. <eos/><bos/>The bankruptcy was an inevitable result of the Plaintiff&apos;s inability to find new capital or to develop an adequate revenue stream to maintain its operations. <eos/><bos/>The market place was still open to TDC after the Province initiated the Rural Broadband project. <eos/><bos/>Any ISP that was not selected in the tender process was free to compete to the limit of its financial and technological capabilities. <eos/><bos/>TDC did not have the funding to continue.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90c87028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">60</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff claimed general damages in the amount of $300,000 for loss of goodwill and business reputation. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence to support the conclusion that the plaintiff suffered a loss of goodwill and business reputation that was caused by the defendant. <eos/><bos/>No valuation of these assets had been tendered and having regard to the evidence it was unlikely that there was significant value in these accounts by the time the pilot RFP was made public in September 2006. <eos/><bos/>By August 2006 TDC was unable to raise funding. <eos/><bos/>The uptake of service was significantly less than what was anticipated and there was an interruption of service that month due to non-payment of bills. <eos/><bos/>The evidence supported the conclusion that TDC&apos;s business reputation and technical reputation were already seriously damaged before the publication of the pilot RFP. The claim for general damages based upon the loss of goodwill and business reputation was dismissed.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90c87038e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">61</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>On appeal in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00013" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2039565063" w-pub-number="0005475" ID="I74bc86918e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>TDC Broadband Inc. v. Nova Scotia (Attorney General)</ital></cite.query>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id90c87048e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">62</footnote.reference>] Justice Bourgeois dismissed the appellant&apos;s appeal of the trial judge&apos;s damage assessment. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge&apos;s findings leading to the conclusion that the respondent did breach its duty of confidence were not challenged on appeal. <eos/><bos/>The appellant submitted that the trial judge made several errors that led to an inordinately low award of compensatory damages. <eos/><bos/>At the hearing, the appellant presented three inter-related arguments: based on his own factual finding that the confidential information disclosed was “something special”, the trial judge failed to apply the correct valuation analysis; related to the above, the trial judge misunderstood the purpose of the expert evidence presented by the appellant which formed the basis of its claim for compensatory damages and, as such, he improperly discounted it; the trial judge further failed to consider the damages arising from the respondent&apos;s second improper disclosure in the provincial RFP. The appellant asserted that these errors led the trial judge to an inordinately low award, and that he ought to have awarded compensatory damages as calculated by its expert as set out in her report. <eos/><bos/>In the alternative, the appellant submitted that the trial judge failed to award damages based upon the “springboard” doctrine.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90c87058e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">63</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>With respect to the appellant&apos;s first argument that the trial judge failed to apply a proper valuation analysis, the appellant grounded its argument in the judgment of <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00014" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1999428661" w-pub-number="0005156" ID="I74bd70f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cadbury Schweppes Inc. v. FBI Foods Ltd.</ital>, [1999] 1 S.C.R. 142</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>The appellant argued that <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00015" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1999428661" w-pub-number="0005156" ID="I74bd70f38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cadbury</ital></cite.query> adopted the earlier approach of the English Court of Appeal in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00016" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1969019738" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I74bd70f48e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seager v. Copydex Ltd. (No.2)</ital>, [1969] 2 All E.R. 718</cite.query>, in which Lord Denning set out a method of damage assessment based upon the quality of the confidential information at the heart of the breach. <eos/><bos/>The appellant submitted that the trial judge properly found the information used by the respondent was “something special”.<eos/><bos/> However, having made that finding, it argued that the trial judge was then bound to assess damages on the basis of <begin.quote ID="QT_0016"/>“the value as between a willing seller and a willing buyer”<end.quote refid="QT_0016"/>. <eos/><bos/>The appellant submitted that the trial judge failed to undertake such an assessment, instead assessing damages as if the information were “nothing very special”, resulting in an improper award based upon a consultant fee.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90c87068e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">64</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In dismissing these submissions, Justice Bourgeois observed that the trial judge made several factual determinations that were particularly relevant to his assessment of economic loss, none of which were challenged on appeal, stating:</paratext><list><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>•</label.designator></head><paratext>The respondent did not use or disclose <begin.quote ID="QT_0018"/>“the most valuable part of the appellant&apos;s delivery system”<end.quote refid="QT_0018"/>;</paratext></para></list.item><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>•</label.designator></head><paratext>Neither Seaside, the successful bidder on the Cumberland RFP, nor the other successful bidders on the Provincial RFP, utilized systems based upon the confidential information disclosed;</paratext></para></list.item><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>•</label.designator></head><paratext>The appellant&apos;s factual assertion that <begin.quote ID="QT_0017"/>“Absent the Province improperly using the confidential information regarding the Delivery System, TDC would have been the only provider with a technology that was proven to work in the topography of rural Nova Scotia”<end.quote refid="QT_0017"/> was rejected as an overstatement;</paratext></para></list.item><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>•</label.designator></head><paratext>The appellant was the only company that had attempted to provide a fixed wireless delivery system in rural areas, but it had not shown that its system was financially viable;</paratext></para></list.item><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>•</label.designator></head><paratext>The Cumberland RFP required, amongst other criteria, that a successful bidder have a viable business plan, which the appellant did not have.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90cae108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">65</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></list.item></list><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Bourgeois observed that a review of Justice Binnie&apos;s reasons in Cadbury makes clear that in citing <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00017" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1969019738" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I74bfbae18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seager</ital></cite.query>, he was in no way endorsing a rigid or defined approach to assessing damages for breach of confidence, but in fact, stated the opposite:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0019"/>24 The result of Lac Minerals is to confirm jurisdiction in the courts in a breach of confidence action to grant a remedy dictated by the facts of the case rather than strict jurisdictional or doctrinal considerations. <eos/><bos/>See J. D. Davies, “Duties of Confidence and Loyalty”, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00018" w-ref-type="ER" w-normalized-cite="1990LLOYDSMARCOMLQ4" w-pub-number="0005217" w-pinpoint-page="5" ID="I74c009008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">[1990] Lloyd&apos;s Mar. &amp; Com. L.Q. 4, at p. 5</cite.query>:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext>There is much to be said for the majority view [in Lac Minerals Ltd.] that, if a ground of liability is established, then the remedy that follows should be the one that is most appropriate on the facts of the case rather than one derived from history or over-categorization.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0019"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id90cae118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">66</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Bourgeois observed that the facts of a particular case can give rise to numerous approaches to valuing the damages flowing from a breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>In Justice Bourgeois&apos; view, in assessing compensatory damages, the trial judge utilized a flexible approach to the facts as he found them. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge combined a willing seller/willing buyer approach with one that also recognized a depreciation in the value of the information disclosed. <eos/><bos/>Justice Bourgeois saw no error in this approach.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90cae128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">67</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The appellant submitted that the trial judge had the necessary evidence to establish the fair market value of the delivery system, but failed to use it as a means of determining damages on the basis of a “willing seller/willing buyer” assessment. <eos/><bos/>The expert opinion was presented for the purpose of establishing the fair market value of the delivery system, which, the appellant asserted, was equivalent to what a willing buyer and willing seller would establish as a fair sale price. <eos/><bos/>The expert opined that value as being between $2,035,000 and $2,495,000. <eos/><bos/>The appellant contended that the trial judge was confused with respect to the purpose of the expert report: it was not to make a claim for lost profits, but rather to reflect the fair market value of the delivery system for the purpose of establishing a sale price between a willing buyer and seller. <eos/><bos/>Based on this misapprehension, the trial judge erroneously discounted the expert opinion based on certain assumptions relied upon by the expert. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge noted a number of assumptions contained in the expert opinion. <eos/><bos/>However, the appellant submitted that none of the assumptions were relevant to the purpose of the expert&apos;s valuation: to establish what a willing buyer would pay for the delivery system. <eos/><bos/>All of the assumptions criticized by the trial judge applied to a scenario in which the appellant retained the delivery system and continued to operate it. <eos/><bos/>None applied to a scenario where the system was purchased by any number of potential buyers. <eos/><bos/>As such, the assumptions the trial judge viewed as undermining the valuation would have no impact on the value of the system to a willing buyer. <eos/><bos/>The appellant argued that the trial judge ought not to have rejected the expert opinion and should have awarded the higher end of her valuation.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90cd5208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">68</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Bourgeois concluded that the trial judge in no way misapprehended the purpose of the expert opinion or its content. <eos/><bos/>The appellant&apos;s claim that the trial judge misunderstood the report as being a loss of profits quantification, as opposed to establishing a market value for the purposes of a willing buyer and willing seller, was refuted by the report itself. <eos/><bos/>Two alternative approaches to quantifying the appellant&apos;s economic loss were considered: the lost profit approach and the business valuation approach. <eos/><bos/>The expert concluded that the former was the appropriate means of establishing the appellant&apos;s loss. <eos/><bos/>Given the framing of the expert opinion and its statement of claim seeking <begin.quote ID="QT_0020"/>“loss of past and future profits”<end.quote refid="QT_0020"/>, the appellant&apos;s assertion that the trial judge suffered from a misapprehension was unwarranted.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90cd5218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">69</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Bourgeois did not accept the appellant&apos;s suggestion that the factual assumptions identified by the trial judge as undermining the expert opinion were irrelevant to its claim. <eos/><bos/>The expert specifically indicated that should the evidence at trial not support the assumptions she had been asked to apply by the appellant and its legal counsel, her opinion might change. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge found that the evidence at trial did not support several of those key assumptions. <eos/><bos/>As such, the trial judge was entitled to view the expert&apos;s valuation with wariness.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90cd5228e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">70</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The appellant&apos;s third source of alleged error was that the trial judge, in undertaking his consideration of compensatory damages, only considered the breach of confidence arising from the misuse of information in the Cumberland RFP. Despite having found that further technical information “consistent with the TDC system” had been released in the provincial RFP, the trial judge improperly confined his valuation to the damages arising from the initial disclosure.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90cd5238e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">71</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Bourgeois observed that the appellant based the quantification of its economic loss on the KPMG report. <eos/><bos/>The author identified the “valuation date” as being the issuance of the Cumberland RFP. No additional quantification was presented for additional damages arising from the second release. <eos/><bos/>Given the appellant&apos;s expert treated the initial release as the moment when its damages crystallized, the trial judge could hardly be faulted for doing the same. <eos/><bos/>In light of how the appellant chose to structure its claim at trial and the evidentiary record, Justice Bourgeois was satisfied the trial judge was not obligated to consider additional damages arising from the provincial RFP.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90cd5248e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">72</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The appellant&apos;s alternative argument was presented in the event that the Court of Appeal found that it was open to the trial judge to reject the “willing seller/willing buyer” valuation. <eos/><bos/>The appellant submitted that having rejected that opinion, the trial judge ought to have employed the “springboard” doctrine. <eos/><bos/>This was explained as <begin.quote ID="QT_0021"/>“the value of the cost of developing the Delivery System and a consulting fee as the Province saved itself those costs by taking and improperly using the Delivery System”<end.quote refid="QT_0021"/>. <eos/><bos/>On appeal, the appellant asserted that the value, utilizing a 2.5-year time frame representing the time to develop the system, would equate to damages of $750,000. <eos/><bos/>It calculated this as being a consultation fee, being the salary over the development period for the three Cockerill brothers, plus the compensatory damages awarded by the trial judge.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90cd5258e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">73</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge agreed with the appellant&apos;s assertion that the respondent obtained a head start in the drafting and development of the RFPs by using its confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge also found, however, that the successful bidders did not ultimately deploy systems that used the appellant&apos;s confidential information. <eos/><bos/>He further found the breach did not involve the most valuable aspects of the delivery system.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90cd5268e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">74</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Bourgeois observed that the approach to assessing damages for a breach of confidence is necessarily a flexible one. <eos/><bos/>The appellant presented no authority for its proposition that the trial judge was obligated to use any particular assessment approach. <eos/><bos/>Further, the appellant had not demonstrated that the trial judge erred by failing to award its claim for its entire research and development costs. <eos/><bos/>Justice Bourgeois observed that the trial judge was faced with a complex and unique set of factual circumstances where the appellant established a breach of confidence, but the evidence supporting its claim for damages was lacking Justice Bourgeois concluded that the trial judge was entitled to consider the evidence and apply a flexible approach to assessing damages.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90cfc308e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">75</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00019" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2037249540" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I74c8bb918e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">No Limits Sportswear Inc. v. 0912139 B.C.</cite.query> Ltd.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id90cfc318e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">76</footnote.reference>] the plaintiffs claimed that the defendants misused confidential information provided to them by the plaintiff No Limits. <eos/><bos/>The confidential information related to the plaintiffs&apos; business plans in relation to a brand of men&apos;s underwear known as SAXX underwear. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs alleged that the defendants misused the confidential information to develop and eventually launch in the following year a competing brand of men&apos;s underwear, the brand “MyPakage”.<eos/><bos/> The plaintiffs pleaded that as a result of the defendants&apos; alleged misconduct, the plaintiffs suffered a loss of opportunity and a reduction of their market share and market position, and they sought compensatory damages in this regard. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs submitted that their damages should be calculated based on the theory that all sales and gifts by the defendants of MyPakage underwear, to date and for some years into the future, should be treated as a loss of sales of SAXX product by the plaintiffs. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs projected damages of approximately $23 million into 2018.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90cfc328e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">77</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The defendants submit that the third element of a breach of confidence claim, namely misuse of confidential information, also requires that the unauthorized use of the information be to the detriment of the information-provider in order to complete the cause of action. <eos/><bos/>Thus they argue, if the information-provider has suffered no damages, there is no valid claim for breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge observed that the defendants overstate the clarity of the law on this issue, stating as follows:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0023"/>The facts in Lac Minerals were that the defendant did make unauthorized use of the information to the detriment of the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>The judgment of La Forest J. in Lac Minerals commented on this as part of the analysis of the third element above, but it is unclear whether he was referring to the remedy rather than the cause of action because he also held that any use other than a permitted use was a breach of duty: see 635–642.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0023"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0024"/>In Cadbury, the issue before the Court concerned the proper remedies for breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>The fact of breach of confidence was not questioned.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0024"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0025"/>The Court in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00020" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1999428661" w-pub-number="0005156" w-pinpoint-page="para" ID="I74c9f4118e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Cadbury at para</cite.query>. 54 declined to rule definitively on the question of whether detriment to the information-provider is a necessary element of the cause of action for breach of confidence.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0025"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0026"/>In Minera, the BC Court of Appeal noted that the law is unsettled on whether detriment is a necessary element of an action in breach of confidence: see para. 85. <eos/><bos/>However, in that case a detriment was proven.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0026"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0027"/>In <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00021" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034750957" w-pub-number="0006459" ID="I74cade708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seaway Marine Services Ltd. v. Weiwaikum General Partner Ltd</ital>., 2014 BCSC 2102 (B.C. S.C.)</cite.query>, Thompson J. dealt with a claim for breach of confidence and held that <begin.quote ID="QT_0022"/>“the proposition that detriment is an essential element of the cause of action is not entirely free of doubt”<end.quote refid="QT_0022"/> at para. 94.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0027"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0028"/>Nevertheless, the judgment in Cadbury does suggest that general damages for breach of confidence cannot be awarded where the party suing has elected to claim that the breach of confidence caused financial loss but has failed to prove a financial loss. <eos/><bos/>This appears to be the reasoning of Binnie J. at paras. 52–54:<end.quote refid="QT_0028"/></paratext></para><head style="l" parent="display.quote"><headtext><bold>F. Relevance of Detriment</bold></headtext></head><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0029"/>[52] La Forest J. said in Lac Minerals that if the plaintiff is able to establish that the defendant made an unauthorized use of the information <ital>to the detriment</ital> of the party communicating it, the cause of action is complete (at pp. 635–36 and 657; see also <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00022" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1991354399" w-pub-number="0005653" ID="I74cd01508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>ICAM Technologies Corp. v. EBCO Industries Ltd</ital>. (1991), 36 C.P.R. (3d) 504 (B.C.S.C.)</cite.query>, <case.history>affirmed</case.history> (1993), <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00023" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1993381255" w-pub-number="0005653" ID="I74cd01528e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">52 C.P.R. (3d) 61 (B.C.C.A.)</cite.query>, per Toy J.A., <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00024" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1993381255" w-pub-number="0005653" w-pinpoint-page="63" ID="I74cd01548e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">at pp. 63–64</cite.query>; <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00025" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1993385927" w-pub-number="0005506" ID="I74cd01568e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Ontex Resources Ltd. v. Metalore</cite.query><end.quote refid="QT_0029"/></ital></paratext></para><para><paratext><ital><begin.quote ID="QT_0030"/></ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00026" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1993385927" w-pub-number="0005506" ID="I74cd4f708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Resources Ltd.</ital> (1993), 13 O.R. (3d) 229 (C.A.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00027" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1992370679" w-pub-number="0005653" ID="I74cd4f728e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>655 Developments Ltd. v. Chester Dawe Ltd</ital>. (1992), 42 C.P.R. (3d) 500 (Nfld. S.C.)</cite.query>.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0030"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0031"/>[53] <ital>The issue of detriment arises in this case because the trial judge made a specific finding that the respondents had not suffered financial loss, yet she proceeded to find liability and award damages “in the interest of fairness”.<eos/><bos/></ital> While La Forest J. in Lac Minerals considered detriment to be an essential element of the breach of confidence action (Sopinka J. did not express a view on this point in his discussion of the applicable principles), it is clear that La Forest J. regarded detriment as a broad concept, large enough for example to include the emotional or psychological distress that would result from the disclosure of intimate information (see, <ital>e.g., </ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00028" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1964015422" w-pub-number="0004697" ID="I74cdc4a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Argyll (Duchess) v. Argyll (Duke)</ital>, [1967] Ch. 302</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>In the <ital>Spycatcher</ital> case, <ital>supra</ital>, Lord Keith of Kinkel observed, at p. 256, that in some circumstances the disclosure itself might be sufficient without more to constitute detriment:<end.quote refid="QT_0031"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0032"/>So I would think it a sufficient detriment to the confider that information given in confidence is to be disclosed to persons whom he would prefer not to know of it, even though the disclosure would not be harmful to him in any positive way.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0032"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0033"/>54 <ital>The concept of detriment need not be explored on this occasion</ital> because, as the Court of Appeal correctly emphasized, the parties had agreed prior to trial that any evidence regarding losses allegedly suffered by the plaintiff would be deferred to a post-trial reference. <eos/><bos/>This arrangement obviated the need for the respondents to lead evidence of detriment at the liability trial. <eos/><bos/><ital>In the end, however, having elected the remedy of financial compensation, the respondents will obviously have to demonstrate at the reference the nature and extent of any detriment suffered to establish the basis for a monetary award</ital>. [<eos/><bos/>Emphasis added.]<end.quote refid="QT_0033"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id90d23408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">78</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge concluded that since the goal of the remedy for breach of confidence is to restore the plaintiff to the position it would have been but for the breach, that in a case where the only remedy claimed is compensation for the plaintiff&apos;s losses, failure to prove any losses would mean failure to prove entitlement to a remedy.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90d23418e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">79</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The claimed loss of business opportunity was based on the theory that the SAXX product lost market share to the MyPakage product, which got a head start in the market due to the defendants&apos; misuse of confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs have failed to call any credible evidence that they suffered a loss of business opportunity, loss of market share, or loss of market position as a result of the launch of the MyPakage business and MyPakage product.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90d23428e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">80</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The evidence from Hawrish highlighted the fact that there were a number of potential outcomes that could arise from MyPakage underwear being sold in the market. <eos/><bos/>One outcome could be that MyPakage educated consumers about this new category of specialty men&apos;s underwear, expanding the overall customer base for SAXX products as well. <eos/><bos/>Indeed, some consumers introduced to this specialty market by the MyPakage product and advertising could have since become loyal Saxx Apparel consumers if they found the Saxx Apparel product to be superior. <eos/><bos/>This was speculative, but so too was any theory to the contrary.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90d23438e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">81</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>To prove damages, the plaintiffs relied solely on the evidence of two members of the No Limits corporate team, McCurry and Jewell. <eos/><bos/>Neither witness was independent or objective in the way an independent expert witness would be. <eos/><bos/>McCurry had no evidence to give that would allow the Court to conclude that every sale or gift of the MyPakage product (or any portion thereof) resulted in lost Saxx Apparel sales. <eos/><bos/>He simply did some calculations on the instructions of the plaintiffs&apos; counsel that he should assume 100% of sales or gifts of MyPakage product, beginning in 2011, equated to lost sales of SAXX product, and then apply Saxx Apparel profit margins to those figures. <eos/><bos/>He also assumed without any evidentiary basis that any loss of sales of SAXX product due to sales of the MyPakage product would increase by 20% each year from 2011 through 2018, and projected a total loss of sales of just over $23 million. <eos/><bos/>No independent evidence, such as that by a business valuator, was tendered to justify McCurry&apos;s calculations, including: the 20% increase, the time span of the claim, and the fact there were no allowances for contingencies and no present valuing of this enormous claim. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidentiary basis on which one could conclude that McCurry&apos;s calculation was a fair assessment of the plaintiffs&apos; damages. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs called no evidence as to their market share or market position in relation to other brands of men&apos;s underwear in 2009 or subsequently. <eos/><bos/>There was therefore no evidence capable of supporting factual conclusions as to what the plaintiffs could have achieved in sales of the SAXX product, but for alleged sales of MyPakage product, compared to what the plaintiffs did actually achieve in sales of the SAXX product after the alleged misconduct and launch of the MyPakage product.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90d23448e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">82</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>While the equitable principles upon which a claim for breach of confidence is based are flexible, there still needs to be some evidence to support the remedy claimed.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90d23458e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">83</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>There was not the proper evidentiary support on which to base a finding that the MyPakage product and MyPakage marketing efforts had a negative impact on the plaintiffs&apos; sales of SAXX or Saxx Apparel&apos;s market share. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs failed to prove their claim for relief which was based on the allegation that they would have been in a better position, with greater market share, and greater sales, but for the defendants&apos; breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs had therefore not proved their only claim to a remedy.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90d23468e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">84</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00029" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2038152801" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I74d42d418e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Jane Doe 464533 v. D.</cite.query> (N.)</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id90d23478e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">85</footnote.reference>] the plaintiff&apos;s ex-boyfriend posted an intimate video of her on a pornography website without her knowledge or consent. <eos/><bos/>In early December 2011, the plaintiff learned that the defendant had posted the video she sent him on an Internet pornography website under the “user submissions” section of the website. <eos/><bos/>As posted by the defendant, the video was titled <begin.quote ID="QT_0034"/>“college girl pleasures herself for ex boyfriends (<ital>sic</ital>) delight.”<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0034"/> She further learned that the defendant had been showing it to some of the young men with whom they had attended high school. <eos/><bos/>She later learned that the video had been posted online on the same day she had sent it to him, and that its existence had become known among some of her friends. <eos/><bos/>The video was available online for approximately three weeks, before it was “removed”.<eos/><bos/> There was no way to know how many times it was viewed or downloaded or if and how many times it may have been copied onto other media storage devices or recirculated. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff&apos;s lawyer sent a demand letter to the defendant in February 2012. <eos/><bos/>The defendant admitted having posted the video, but advised that it had been removed and that he did not consider that the plaintiff&apos;s claims for compensation had any merit. <eos/><bos/>The defendant failed to serve a statement of defence and had been noted in default.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90d4a508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">86</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The consequences for the plaintiff arising from the defendant&apos;s conduct had been significant and long-lasting. <eos/><bos/>She saw a counsellor at her school for over a year and a half to deal with the emotional fallout from the posting of the video. <eos/><bos/>She experienced serious depression and emotional upset. <eos/><bos/>On the occasions since the incident when she has encountered the defendant she has become emotionally distraught and unable to cope, sometimes collapsing. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff remains conscious of the fact that the video was viewed by acquaintances of the defendant, that its existence is known to other members of her former social circle and has caused harm to her reputation. <eos/><bos/>Even today, more than four years after the incident, she is emotionally fragile and worried about the possibility that the video may someday resurface and have an adverse impact on her employment, her career, or her future relationships. <eos/><bos/>She continues to be distraught about the incident and afraid that these feelings will haunt her for a long time to come. <eos/><bos/>Despite these challenges, she finished her undergraduate studies and was attending a graduate program that would enable her to become a health care professional when she graduated. <eos/><bos/>She remained worried, however, that the defendant&apos;s actions had put her future career in jeopardy should news of these events surface again.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90d4a518e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">87</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The judge concluded that there are both established and developing legal grounds that support the proposition that the courts can and should provide civil recourse for individuals who suffer harm arising from this misconduct and should intervene to prevent its repetition. <eos/><bos/>There can be little doubt that the decision by the plaintiff to provide the defendant with an intimate video of herself engages issues of confidentiality and privacy. <eos/><bos/>They had a close personal and romantic relationship of some duration. <eos/><bos/>It was on the basis of that relationship that she agreed to provide him with private images of her. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff&apos;s decision to send the video was premised upon the defendant&apos;s assurance that he alone would view it. <eos/><bos/>His decision to share it publicly was a clear breach of the terms upon which it was communicated to him.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90d4a528e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">88</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff has made out a cause of action for breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>The elements required to make out the tort of breach of confidence are: a) that the information must have the necessary quality of confidence about it; b) that the information must have been imparted in circumstances importing an obligation of confidence; and c) that there must be unauthorized use of that information to the detriment of the party communicating it. <eos/><bos/>The video created by the plaintiff met the first test, being confidential information. <eos/><bos/>It had <begin.quote ID="QT_0035"/>“the necessary quality of confidence about it”<end.quote refid="QT_0035"/>. <eos/><bos/>It was private and personal to the plaintiff and was not (until it was shared on the Internet and otherwise by the defendant) publicly available. <eos/><bos/>The circumstances that led to the creation and communication of the video clearly demonstrated that it was communicated to the defendant on the express basis that he would treat it as confidential. <eos/><bos/>Thus the second element was met. <eos/><bos/>The third element of the tort, use of the information to the detriment of the party communicating it, is ordinarily considered in commercial circumstances, where the recipient has misused the confidential information for commercial advantage, at the expense or to the detriment of the other party. <eos/><bos/>An essential element in any tort is harm to the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>There is no rational basis to distinguish between economic harm and psychological, emotional and physical harm, such as was experienced by the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>In any event, the possible future adverse impact on the plaintiff&apos;s career and employment prospects arising from the possibility that the video may someday resurface, also demonstrated actionable harm.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90d4a538e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">89</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff&apos;s action was commended under the Simplified Procedure and thus her damage claim was limited to $100,000. <eos/><bos/>Plaintiff&apos;s counsel submitted that a much higher award was suitable, but conceded that she was restricted to the $100,000 limit.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90d4a548e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">90</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In support of the damage award sought, plaintiff&apos;s counsel analogized this case to ones involving claims arising from physical sexual battery, with its attendant psychological impact and consequences: although the physical injuries may be modest and ones from which the victim may recover relatively promptly, the emotional and psychological effects of the offensive conduct are frequently severe and long-lasting. <eos/><bos/>Given the novelty of the plaintiff&apos;s claim, there is no Canadian case law to guide in determining a suitable monetary award in this case. <eos/><bos/>That said, in light of the nature of the wrong, the significant and ongoing impact of the defendant&apos;s conduct on the plaintiff&apos;s emotional and psychological health, and its similarity to the impact of a sexual assault, some assistance may be found in that category of cases. <eos/><bos/>The judge recognized that, unlike cases which involved actual battery of the plaintiff, there was no physical touching. <eos/><bos/>That said, the plaintiff&apos;s resulting injuries bear striking similarities to those for which the courts have awarded compensation in other cases. <eos/><bos/>The actions of the defendant offended and compromised the plaintiff&apos;s dignity and personal autonomy. <eos/><bos/>A non-pecuniary damage award in a case such as this should similarly <begin.quote ID="QT_0036"/>“demonstrate, both to the victim and to the wider community, the vindication of these fundamental, although intangible, rights which have been violated by the wrongdoer.”<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0036"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id90d4a558e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">91</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The judge considered the factors approved by the Supreme Court in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00030" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2007509454" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I74d650208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Blackwater v. Plint</ital>, 2005 CarswellBC 2358 (S.C.C.)</cite.query>: With respect to the circumstances of the victim at the time of the events, including factors such as age and vulnerability, the plaintiff was 18 years old at the time of the incident, a young adult who was a university student. <eos/><bos/>Judging by the impact of the defendant&apos;s actions, she was a vulnerable individual. <eos/><bos/>With respect to the circumstances of the assaults including their number, frequency and how violent, invasive and degrading they were, the wrongful act consisted of uploading to a pornographic website a video recording that displayed intimate images of the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>The defendant&apos;s actions were thus very invasive and degrading. <eos/><bos/>The recording was available for viewing on the Internet for some three weeks. <eos/><bos/>It is impossible to know how many times it was viewed, copied or downloaded, or how many copies still exist elsewhere, out of the defendant&apos;s (and the plaintiff&apos;s—and the Court&apos;s) control. <eos/><bos/>As well, the defendant showed the video to his friends, who were also acquaintances of the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>Although there was no physical violence, in these circumstances, especially in light of the multiple times the video was viewed by others and, more importantly, the potential for the video still to be in circulation, it was appropriate to regard this as tantamount to multiple assaults on the plaintiff&apos;s dignity. <eos/><bos/>With respect to the circumstances of the defendant, including age and whether he or she was in a position of trust, the defendant was also 18 years of age. <eos/><bos/>He and the plaintiff had been in an intimate—and thus trusting—relationship over a lengthy period. <eos/><bos/>It was on this basis, and on the basis of his assurances that he alone would view it, that he persuaded her to provide the video. <eos/><bos/>His conduct was tantamount to a breach of trust. <eos/><bos/>With respect to the consequences for the victim of the wrongful behaviour including ongoing psychological injuries, the consequences were emotionally and psychologically devastating for the plaintiff and are ongoing. <eos/><bos/>Having regard to these factors and the past and ongoing impact of the defendant&apos;s actions on the plaintiff, the judge assessed her general damages at $50,000. <eos/><bos/>This case involved much more than an invasion of a right to informational privacy and was in many ways it is analogous to a sexual assault.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90d71608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">92</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>This was a case where an award of aggravated damages was warranted. <eos/><bos/>Such damages may be awarded where the damage to the plaintiff was aggravated by the manner in which the culpable act was committed. <eos/><bos/>Here, the posting of the video amounted to a breach of the trust reposed by the plaintiff in the defendant that he would not reveal it to anyone else. <eos/><bos/>This feature of the defendant&apos;s behaviour was an affront to their relationship that made the impact of his actions even more hurtful and painful for the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>The judge awarded $25,000 on this account.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90d71618e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">93</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff was also awarded punitive damages of $25,000. <eos/><bos/>An award of punitive damages may be appropriate where the defendant has acted in a high-handed or arrogant fashion or has recklessly disregarded the plaintiff&apos;s rights or the potential impact of the defendant&apos;s intentional conduct. <eos/><bos/>Those are apt descriptions of the defendant&apos;s conduct here. <eos/><bos/>He gave no consideration to the inevitable impact of his actions on the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>He had not apologized; indeed, according to the plaintiff, despite being aware of the harm he has caused, when they have encountered one another since the event, he has had an insolent look on his face, and has shown no remorse. <eos/><bos/>In relation to quantum, proportionality is an important consideration in making an award of punitive damages. <eos/><bos/>Other factors include the blameworthiness of the defendant&apos;s conduct (high); the degree of vulnerability of the plaintiff (significant); the harm directed specifically at the plaintiff (again, significant).<eos/><bos/> Importantly, the defendant acted with malice. <eos/><bos/>Another consideration is the need for deterrence. <eos/><bos/>While this case may be novel, it should serve as a precedent to dissuade others from engaging in similar harmful conduct. <eos/><bos/>A final consideration was the other penalties imposed on the defendant for the same misconduct. <eos/><bos/>Here, the defendant faced no criminal sanctions: his acts took place before Parliament criminalized such conduct. <eos/><bos/>The absence of a specific criminal sanction is no bar to an award of punitive damages in a civil case.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90d71628e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">94</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff sought orders that would prevent a repetition of the defendant&apos;s conduct and further violations of her rights. <eos/><bos/>Such relief was appropriate to ensure that no further incidents of this nature occur. <eos/><bos/>It was unclear whether the defendant still possessed any copies of the video or other intimate images of the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>To address that possibility, an order shall issue directing the defendant to immediately destroy any and all intimate images or recordings of the plaintiff, in whatever form they may exist, that he has in his possession, power or control. <eos/><bos/>A further order shall issue permanently prohibiting the defendant from publishing, posting, sharing or otherwise disclosing in any fashion any intimate images or recordings of the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>The judge also granted an order permanently prohibiting the defendant from communicating with the plaintiff or members of her immediate family, either directly or indirectly.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90d71638e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">95</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Zoic Studios BC Inc. v. Gannon</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id90d71648e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">96</footnote.reference>] the plaintiff was a computer visual effects studio which specialized in feature films, television shows, commercials, video games, advertising and online content. <eos/><bos/>Zoic BC was a wholly owned subsidiary of Zoic LA, a mid-sized Los Angeles based studio. <eos/><bos/>Zoic BC became the main provider of visual effects for seasons 1 through 3 of Eureka. <eos/><bos/>The first season of Eureka did not run smoothly. <eos/><bos/>The visual effects side of Eureka was understaffed. <eos/><bos/>In the fall of 2009, Mr. Adams and the defendant began to discuss starting their own visual effects studio and doing freelance work. <eos/><bos/>Around that time they purchased an RED camera which would allow them to shoot some of their “own projects.” <eos/><bos/>They also set up G-mail accounts with their business name, Leviathan. <eos/><bos/>Mr. Adams left Zoic BC in late January of 2010. <eos/><bos/>When he left Zoic BC, he did not know whether Leviathan was going to get a contract for season 4 of Eureka. <eos/><bos/>Mr. Adams signed a work-for-hire contract on February 17, 2010, for Leviathan Studios to provide some of the visual effects for season 4 of Eureka. <eos/><bos/>At that time, the defendant was still employed by Zoic BC. Leviathan Studios had not yet been incorporated. <eos/><bos/>Leviathan Studios was officially incorporated on February 22, 2010. <eos/><bos/>Both the defendant and Mr. Adams were listed as shareholders and directors. <eos/><bos/>On March 1, 2010, the defendant advised Zoic LA she was resigning. <eos/><bos/>On March 11, 2010, Zoic BC learned of the existence of Leviathan Studios.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The court concluded that the defendant breached her duty of fidelity, good faith and loyalty to Zoic BC. Her conduct while she was still employed by Zoic BC went beyond mere planning to establish a competing business. <eos/><bos/>The allegations of misuse of confidential information, centred on bid templates that were used on behalf of Leviathan to bid on season 4 of Eureka. <eos/><bos/>The issue was whether that use was a misuse and, therefore, a breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>The actuals template was the document used by Zoic BC to track their costs and profits and was used by the defendants to apply for a loan. <eos/><bos/>This document information regarding the hours bid for episodes 1 through 18 of season 3, how many of those hours were actually used, the total revenue and profit. <eos/><bos/>This was information that was not accessible outside the plaintiff&apos;s business. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff suffered a detriment through the misuse of the information. <eos/><bos/>The defendant was in breach of her duty of confidentiality and her duty of good faith. <eos/><bos/>Leviathan was also responsible for the breach. <eos/><bos/>The actuals template was used to apply for a loan on its behalf.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The misuse of confidential information allowed Leviathan and the defendants to springboard ahead. <eos/><bos/>They put Leviathan in a place to transition somewhat more easily into providing visual effects for Eureka than they could otherwise have done. <eos/><bos/>However, it was not “far easier.” <eos/><bos/>The defendants would have been in a position based on their knowledge and skill to determine pricing structures and rates fairly easily. <eos/><bos/>Zoic BC had a chance, albeit a very small chance, to renew the contract. <eos/><bos/>It was entitled to receive damages for loss of opportunity for the defendant&apos;s breach of fidelity for her failure to disclose Mr. Gore&apos;s departure. <eos/><bos/>As for the amount that the damages should be reduced by for the possibility the plaintiff would not have been awarded the contract, the loss of opportunity damages was reduced by 95%. <eos/><bos/>There was only about a 5% chance that Mr. Gore could have been persuaded to return. <eos/><bos/>Eureka would likely have gone where Mr. Gore recommended. <eos/><bos/>The defendants&apos; actions were not an effective or dominant cause of the plaintiff&apos;s loss.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90d98708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">97</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>On appeal, the main thrust of the appellant&apos;s position was that the Trial Judge focused almost entirely on whether the employee had the legal authority to bind Zoic BC, and/or whether her authority at Zoic BC was unfettered and that the Trial Judge failed to consider whether the employee exercised discretionary power to affect Zoic BC&apos;s practical interests.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90d98718e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">98</footnote.reference>] In dismissing the ground of appeal relating to breach of fiduciary duty, Justice Chiasson observed that the trial judge examined very thoroughly the authority of the employee, was alive to the law of fiduciary duty and that she considered the effect of the employee&apos;s authority on the interests of Zoic BC. The trial judge made no error of law. <eos/><bos/>Her findings of fact were supported by the evidence.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90d98728e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">99</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Court of Appeal allowed the appeal to the extent only of remitting the matter to the trial judge with the direction that she consider whether an equitable accounting should be ordered arising out of the personal respondents&apos; breach of their duty of fidelity and loyalty by competing with the appellant.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90d98738e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">100</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Difficulty or uncertainty in the proof of damages will not excuse a wrongdoer or preclude recovery by an injured party.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90d98748e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">101</footnote.reference>] See also <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00031" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1969019738" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I74e98a018e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Seager v. Copydex Ltd.</cite.query> (No. 2)</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id90d98758e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">102</footnote.reference>] where, for the purposes of assessment, the court divided confidential information into three categories: “nothing very special”, “something special” and “very special indeed”.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The basic thrust of the confidential information claim in <ital>Zesta Engineering Ltd. v. Cloutier</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id90d98768e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">103</footnote.reference>] was that “know-how”, information and documents regarding the design and manufacture of thermocouples that it had developed through trial and error over many years, were valuable information that Kelvin unlawfully used to springboard its new business into competition with Zesta. <eos/><bos/>Zesta pointed to the fact that, within two to three months of setting up business, Kelvin was manufacturing thermocouples that were identical to those produced by Zesta. <eos/><bos/>In doing so, Kelvin utilized a production system that was modeled on the one created at Zesta over the course of many years, utilizing equipment, supplies, suppliers and techniques developed and refined by Zesta through years of effort, experimentation, trial and error.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90d98778e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">104</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff Zesta carried on business as a distributor of electrical heaters, temperature controls, temperature sensors called thermocouples, power controls and similar equipment for industrial applications. <eos/><bos/>The shares of Zesta were owned by Vincent Eastman and his wife Ruth. <eos/><bos/>Vincent Eastman was the founder, President and controlling mind of Zesta. <eos/><bos/>The defendant David Cloutier was the son-in-law of Vincent and Ruth Eastman, being the husband of their daughter Mary. <eos/><bos/>Cloutier and Mary had lived separately since 1998. <eos/><bos/>Mary was estranged from her parents and siblings, many of whom were Zesta employees. <eos/><bos/>Cloutier was the Vice-President and Assistant General Manager of Zesta at the time of the events in issue.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90d98788e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">105</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The defendant Kelvin was incorporated in early 2000. <eos/><bos/>It carried on a business similar to and in many ways competitive with that of Zesta. <eos/><bos/>Kelvin was incorporated by Durante, who originally owned 70% of its shares, while the remaining 30% were owned by the defendant Peatling. <eos/><bos/>All of Cloutier, Durante, Sanger and White were associated in some capacity with the business of Kelvin.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90dbf808e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">106</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A large measure of Zesta&apos;s success was attributable to Cloutier. <eos/><bos/>In addition to being Vincent Eastman&apos;s son-in-law, he was his right-hand man and they worked very closely together. <eos/><bos/>The deterioration in the marital relationship between Cloutier and his wife was accompanied by deterioration in the business relationship between Cloutier and Vincent Eastman. <eos/><bos/>Cloutier&apos;s attendances at the Zesta premises became less and less frequent. <eos/><bos/>Matters approached the level of animosity in the fall of 1999 as a result of an incident involving a Zesta salesman named Marcel Jones. <eos/><bos/>The Jones incident caused Zesta to believe that the solicitation of Jones was part of an elaborate plan by Cloutier and the others to take away the core of Zesta&apos;s business and to compete unlawfully. <eos/><bos/>Zesta&apos;s perspective triggered a series of employee terminations and departures. <eos/><bos/>Cloutier was fired. <eos/><bos/>According to Durante, once he found himself unexpectedly unemployed after having spent his entire working life with Zesta, he decided to try his hand at setting up his own small distribution business in the same sphere as Zesta, the only field of business he knew. <eos/><bos/>At Sanger&apos;s suggestion, Durante met with Peatling who agreed to invest in the new enterprise. <eos/><bos/>Kelvin evolved into a much more substantial operation with the financial backing of Peatling. <eos/><bos/>The new Kelvin premises were outfitted with virtually the same equipment found in the Zesta manufacturing plant, in order to enable Kelvin to go into the business of manufacturing thermocouples.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90dbf818e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">107</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The concept of confidential information is not limited to trade secrets and that information may be confidential if the whole result is not known, though its separate features or ingredients are capable of being ascertained by actual inspection by any member of the public. <eos/><bos/>Further, <begin.quote ID="QT_0037"/>“it is enough that the information represents in some considerable degree the independent efforts of the claimant”<end.quote refid="QT_0037"/>. <eos/><bos/>Insofar as Zesta&apos;s production processes, equipment, supplies and suppliers are concerned, however, subject to one exception, the court was unable to find that this information was confidential or communicated in confidential circumstances. <eos/><bos/>The theory behind thermocouples has been known for approximately 150 years. <eos/><bos/>They are broadly available from a number of sources and the principal considerations driving customer purchase decisions are price, product reliability and reliability of supply. <eos/><bos/>There is not very much magic or ingenuity in the design and manufacture of a thermocouple. <eos/><bos/>With respect to specific design improvements or advancements, there was no evidence that any of these attained by Zesta were protected by patents or other industrial design rights. <eos/><bos/>A thermocouple is an inherently “low tech” device.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90dbf828e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">108</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In relation to suppliers of equipment and materials, it may well be that, over the years, Zesta spent time and undertook research to determine which sources of supply of which equipment were best suited to its operations. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence that Zesta had contractual rights of exclusivity with any of these suppliers or that it alone came up with the idea of dealing with specific equipment manufacturers. <eos/><bos/>The court did have concerns in one particular area, however, relating to product costing. <eos/><bos/>When Zesta began to manufacture thermocouples, it initiated a database program and compiled data to keep track of its manufacturing costs. <eos/><bos/>In turn, this allowed Zesta to not only keep track of its manufacturing expenses, but also to forecast the cost of meeting specific customer orders, in order to factor in markup and to bid competitively. <eos/><bos/>By the end of 1999, the defendant White had assumed responsibility for most of the costing exercise, utilizing costing spreadsheets that included such information as the costs and number of individual components used for a particular model, the reject cost, the labour cost, the total cost, and markup factors. <eos/><bos/>The significance of this information was that it went to the heart of the pricing of Zesta&apos;s products in a competitive market where price was one of the most important factors in a purchaser&apos;s decision when choosing a thermocouple supplier. <eos/><bos/>Zesta&apos;s costing information was treated as confidential information. <eos/><bos/>Even if White merely retained the information in his memory and not on paper or in electronic form, it was Zesta&apos;s confidential information regarding the time and expense required to manufacture the specified thermocouples. <eos/><bos/>By incorporating it into Kelvin&apos;s costing spreadsheet, White was misusing Zesta&apos;s confidential information for the benefit of Kelvin. <eos/><bos/>In turn, Kelvin used the information supplied by White using the Zesta confidential information for purposes of submitting a thermocouple pricing quote to Husky. <eos/><bos/>In so doing, they breached Zesta&apos;s rights.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90dbf838e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">109</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Zesta did not quantify its damage claim by reference to this specific wrong. <eos/><bos/>The court estimated, however, that it would have taken Kelvin approximately six months to develop this body of knowledge on its own. <eos/><bos/>In other words, instead of being able to cost its thermocouple products accurately at the commencement of its operations in March 2000, on its own Kelvin would have taken until September 2000 to be able to do so. <eos/><bos/>In assessing damages for this wrong, it was difficult to correlate any specific loss or damage to Zesta. <eos/><bos/>The proper award was the value of the benefit gained by Kelvin in wrongfully exploiting this confidential information. <eos/><bos/>Zesta would have been able to make the thermocouple sales that Kelvin did during this period. <eos/><bos/>In its first year of operation Kelvin had $496,135 in sales, and a contribution margin of $271,513. <eos/><bos/>As with Zesta, not all of Kelvin&apos;s business was comprised of thermocouple manufacturing and sales, however, so not all of that revenue was connected to the misuse of the production costing information. <eos/><bos/>At Zesta, manufacturing represented approximately 25 to 35% of annual revenues. <eos/><bos/>If one assumed the same ratio at Kelvin, the manufacturing portion of the contribution margin of $271,513 was reduced to between $68,000 and $95,000 approximately. <eos/><bos/>Allowing for six months of improper use of the information would reduce that sum to between $34,000 and $47,500. <eos/><bos/>Erring on the side of the innocent party, Zesta was awarded damages of $45,000 against Kelvin.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id90dbf848e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">110</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Id90ab2408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>Saltman Engineering Co. v. Campbell Engineering Co.</ital>, [1963] 3 All E.R. 413<ital>n</ital> (C.A.).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90ab2418e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00032" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1967018556" w-pub-number="0004891" ID="I75032c808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seager v. Copydex Ltd.</ital>, [1967] 1 W.L.R. 923 (C.A.), at p. 931</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>See also <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00033" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1949034206" w-pub-number="0004707" ID="I75032c828e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>R.L. Crain Ltd. v. Ashton</ital>, [1950] 1 D.L.R. 601, [1950] O.R. 62 (C.A.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90ab2428e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>See the discussion on damages in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00034" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1998466685" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I7503efd08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>MacDonald v. Klein</ital> (1998), 84 A.C.W.S. (3d) 503, [1998] O.J. No. 4922 (Gen. Div.)</cite.query>), supp. reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00035" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1999484514" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I7503efd38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">87 A.C.W.S. (3d) 32</cite.query> (Ont. Ct. (Gen. Div.)) and <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00036" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2001348305" w-pub-number="0005460" ID="I7503efd58e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>McCormick Delisle &amp; Thompson Inc. v. Ballantyne</ital> (2001), 145 O.A.C. 379</cite.query>, 12 B.L.R. (3d) 257 (<cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00037" w-ref-type="ER" w-normalized-cite="158OACCA196n" w-pub-number="0005460" ID="I7503efd78e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">C.A.), leave to appeal to S.C.C. refused 158 O.A.C. 196<ital>n</ital>, 285 N.R. 397<ital>n</ital></cite.query><ital>.<eos/></ital></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90ab2438e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>4</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00038" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1991354399" w-pub-number="0005653" ID="I7504b3218e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>ICAM Technologies Corp. v. Ebco Industries Ltd.</ital></cite.query> (1991), 6 B.L.R. (2d) 98, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00039" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1991354399" w-pub-number="0005653" ID="I7504b3228e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">36 C.P.R. (3d) 504 (B.C.S.C.)</cite.query>, <case.history>affd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00040" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1993381255" w-pub-number="0003986" ID="I7504b3248e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">[1994] 3 W.W.R. 419, 85</cite.query> B.C.L.R. (2d) 318 (C.A.); <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00041" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1998460288" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I7504b3268e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Apotex Fermentation Inc. v. Novopharm Ltd.</ital> (1998), 162 D.L.R. (4th) 111, [1998] 10 W.W.R. 455 (Man. C.A.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00042" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027253060" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I7504b3298e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>GasTOPS Ltd. v. Forsyth</ital>, 2012 CarswellOnt 2539, 2012 ONCA 134</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90ab2448e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>5</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00043" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1986268645" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I7505eba08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>LAC Minerals Ltd. v. International Corona Resources Ltd.</ital> (1986), 25 D.L.R. (4th) 504, 53 O.R. (2d) 737 (H.C.J.)</cite.query>, <case.history>affd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00044" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1987290799" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I7505eba38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">44 D.L.R. (4th) 592, 62 O.R. (2d) 1 (C.A.)</cite.query>, <case.history>affd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00045" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1989312320" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I7505eba68e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">61 D.L.R. (4th) 14, [1989] 2 S.C.R. 574</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90ab2458e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>6</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00046" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1983171055" w-pub-number="0005150" ID="I750639c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>White Oaks Welding Supplies v. Tapp</ital> (1983), 149 D.L.R. (3d) 159, 42 O.R. (2d) 445 (H.C.J.)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>However, see <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00047" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1999489430" w-pub-number="0005460" ID="I750639c38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ben-Israel v. Vitacare Medical Products Inc.</ital> (1999), 122 O.A.C. 57, 87 C.P.R. (3d) 518 at p. 523 (C.A.)</cite.query> where the Ontario Court of Appeal refused to give damages to cover expenses incurred in developing the product as the expenses would have been incurred whether or not there had been a breach.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90ab2468e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>7</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00048" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I750660d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90ad9508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>8</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00049" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I750687e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 2–6.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90ad9518e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>9</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00050" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I7506aef08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 9–12.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90ad9528e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>10</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00051" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I7506fd108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 42, 45–46, and 48–56.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90ad9538e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>11</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00052" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I750724208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 87, and 95–96.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90ad9548e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>12</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00053" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I75074b308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 98 and 101–111.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90b00608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>13</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00054" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I750772408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 112–113.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90b00618e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>14</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00055" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I750799508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233, at para. 116</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90b00628e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>15</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00056" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I7507c0608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 118–119.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90b00638e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>16</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00057" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I7507e7708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 123, 125, and 134.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90b00648e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>17</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00058" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I75080e808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 135 and 138.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90b00658e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>18</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00059" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I750835908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233, at para. 145</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90b00668e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>19</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00060" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I75085ca08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 154–156.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90b00678e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>20</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00061" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I750883b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233, at para. 164</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90b00688e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>21</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00062" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I7508aac08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233, at para. 172</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90b27708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>22</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00063" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I7508d1d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 186–195.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90b27718e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>23</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00064" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I7508f8e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 201–206.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90b27728e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>24</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00065" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I75091ff08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 276–278.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90b27738e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>25</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00066" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I750947008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 279–281.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90b4e808e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>26</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00067" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I75096e108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233, at para. 282</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90b4e818e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>27</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00068" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I750995208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233, at para. 284</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90b4e828e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>28</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00069" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I7509bc308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 285–287.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90b4e838e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>29</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00070" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I7509e3408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 288–294.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90b4e848e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>30</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00071" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I750a0a518e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233, at para. 296</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90b75908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>31</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00072" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I750a58708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 297–300.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90b75918e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>32</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00073" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I750a7f808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 310, 312–313, 331, and 334–335.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90bc3b08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>33</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00074" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I750aa6908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 336–339.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90beac08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>34</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00075" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I750acda08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 341 and 343.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90beac18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>35</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00076" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I750af4b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 349–350.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90beac28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>36</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00077" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I750b1bc08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 360, 364–366, and 370.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90beac38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>37</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00078" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I750b42d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233, at para. 371</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90beac48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>38</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00079" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I750b69e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 399, 402, and 409.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90beac58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>39</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00080" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I750bb8008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 417–418.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90beac68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>40</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00081" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I750bb8038e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233, at para. 419</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90c11d08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>41</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00082" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I750c06208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 436–437.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90c11d18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>42</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00083" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I750c2d308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 438, and 440–441.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90c11d28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>43</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00084" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I750c54408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233, at para. 444</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90c11d38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>44</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00085" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039181989" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I750c54438e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>XY, LLC v. Canadian Topsires Selection Inc.</ital>, 2016 CarswellBC 1648, 2016 BCSC 1095</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90c11d48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>45</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00086" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039181989" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I750ca2608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>XY, LLC v. Canadian Topsires Selection Inc.</ital>, 2016 CarswellBC 1648, 2016 BCSC 1095</cite.query>, at paras. 3–5.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90c38e08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>46</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00087" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039181989" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I750cc9708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>XY, LLC v. Canadian Topsires Selection Inc.</ital>, 2016 CarswellBC 1648, 2016 BCSC 1095</cite.query>, at paras. 285–286.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90c38e18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>47</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00088" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039181989" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I750cf0808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>XY, LLC v. Canadian Topsires Selection Inc.</ital>, 2016 CarswellBC 1648, 2016 BCSC 1095</cite.query>, at paras. 287–291.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90c38e28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>48</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00089" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039181989" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I750d17908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>XY, LLC v. Canadian Topsires Selection Inc.</ital>, 2016 CarswellBC 1648, 2016 BCSC 1095</cite.query>, at paras. 295–298.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90c38e38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>49</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00090" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039181989" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I750d3ea08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>XY, LLC v. Canadian Topsires Selection Inc.</ital>, 2016 CarswellBC 1648, 2016 BCSC 1095</cite.query>, at paras. 363–367.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90c38e48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>50</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00091" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039181989" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I750d65b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>XY, LLC v. Canadian Topsires Selection Inc.</ital>, 2016 CarswellBC 1648, 2016 BCSC 1095, at para. 416</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90c38e58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>51</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00092" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039565063" w-pub-number="0005475" ID="I750d8cc08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>TDC Broadband Inc. v. Nova Scotia (Attorney General)</ital>, 2016 CarswellNS 669, 2016 NSSC 206</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90c38e68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>52</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00093" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039565063" w-pub-number="0005475" ID="I750db3d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>TDC Broadband Inc. v. Nova Scotia (Attorney General)</ital>, 2016 CarswellNS 669, 2016 NSSC 206, at para. 178</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90c5ff08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>53</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00094" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039565063" w-pub-number="0005475" ID="I750ddae08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>TDC Broadband Inc. v. Nova Scotia (Attorney General)</ital>, 2016 CarswellNS 669, 2016 NSSC 206</cite.query>, at paras. 180–182.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90c5ff18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>54</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00095" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039565063" w-pub-number="0005475" ID="I750e01f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>TDC Broadband Inc. v. Nova Scotia (Attorney General)</ital>, 2016 CarswellNS 669, 2016 NSSC 206</cite.query>, at paras. 189–192.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90c5ff28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>55</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00096" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039565063" w-pub-number="0005475" ID="I750e29008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>TDC Broadband Inc. v. Nova Scotia (Attorney General)</ital>, 2016 CarswellNS 669, 2016 NSSC 206, at para. 196</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90c5ff38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>56</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00097" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039565063" w-pub-number="0005475" ID="I750e50108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>TDC Broadband Inc. v. Nova Scotia (Attorney General)</ital>, 2016 CarswellNS 669, 2016 NSSC 206</cite.query>, at paras. 197–202.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90c5ff48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>57</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00098" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039565063" w-pub-number="0005475" ID="I750e77208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>TDC Broadband Inc. v. Nova Scotia (Attorney General)</ital>, 2016 CarswellNS 669, 2016 NSSC 206</cite.query>, at paras. 204–205.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90c87008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>58</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00099" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039565063" w-pub-number="0005475" ID="I750e9e308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>TDC Broadband Inc. v. Nova Scotia (Attorney General)</ital>, 2016 CarswellNS 669, 2016 NSSC 206, at para. 227</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90c87018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>59</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00100" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039565063" w-pub-number="0005475" ID="I750eec508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>TDC Broadband Inc. v. Nova Scotia (Attorney General)</ital>, 2016 CarswellNS 669, 2016 NSSC 206</cite.query>, at paras. 229, 232, and 239–241.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90c87028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>60</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00101" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039565063" w-pub-number="0005475" ID="I750f13608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>TDC Broadband Inc. v. Nova Scotia (Attorney General)</ital>, 2016 CarswellNS 669, 2016 NSSC 206, at para. 247</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90c87038e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>61</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00102" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039565063" w-pub-number="0005475" ID="I750f3a708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>TDC Broadband Inc. v. Nova Scotia (Attorney General)</ital>, 2016 CarswellNS 669, 2016 NSSC 206</cite.query>, at paras. 248–251.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90c87048e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>62</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00103" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043960549" w-pub-number="0005475" ID="I750f61808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>TDC Broadband Inc. v. Nova Scotia (Attorney General)</ital>, 2018 CarswellNS 145, 2018 NSCA 22 (N.S. C.A.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90c87058e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>63</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00104" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043960549" w-pub-number="0005475" ID="I750f88908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>TDC Broadband Inc. v. Nova Scotia (Attorney General)</ital>, 2018 CarswellNS 145, 2018 NSCA 22 (N.S. C.A.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 9, 12, and 17.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90c87068e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>64</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00105" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043960549" w-pub-number="0005475" ID="I750fd6b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>TDC Broadband Inc. v. Nova Scotia (Attorney General)</ital>, 2018 CarswellNS 145, 2018 NSCA 22 (N.S. C.A.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 18–20.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90cae108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>65</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00106" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043960549" w-pub-number="0005475" ID="I750ffdc08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>TDC Broadband Inc. v. Nova Scotia (Attorney General)</ital>, 2018 CarswellNS 145, 2018 NSCA 22 (N.S. C.A.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 32–33.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90cae118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>66</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00107" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043960549" w-pub-number="0005475" ID="I751024d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>TDC Broadband Inc. v. Nova Scotia (Attorney General)</ital>, 2018 CarswellNS 145, 2018 NSCA 22 (N.S. C.A.)</cite.query>, at paragraph 37.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90cae128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>67</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00108" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043960549" w-pub-number="0005475" ID="I751072f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>TDC Broadband Inc. v. Nova Scotia (Attorney General)</ital>, 2018 CarswellNS 145, 2018 NSCA 22 (N.S. C.A.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 39–40.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90cd5208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>68</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00109" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043960549" w-pub-number="0005475" ID="I75109a008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>TDC Broadband Inc. v. Nova Scotia (Attorney General)</ital>, 2018 CarswellNS 145, 2018 NSCA 22 (N.S. C.A.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 21–26.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90cd5218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>69</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00110" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043960549" w-pub-number="0005475" ID="I7510c1108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>TDC Broadband Inc. v. Nova Scotia (Attorney General)</ital>, 2018 CarswellNS 145, 2018 NSCA 22 (N.S. C.A.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 42–45.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90cd5228e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>70</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00111" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043960549" w-pub-number="0005475" ID="I7510e8208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>TDC Broadband Inc. v. Nova Scotia (Attorney General)</ital>, 2018 CarswellNS 145, 2018 NSCA 22 (N.S. C.A.)</cite.query>, at paragraph 46.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90cd5238e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>71</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00112" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043960549" w-pub-number="0005475" ID="I75110f308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>TDC Broadband Inc. v. Nova Scotia (Attorney General)</ital>, 2018 CarswellNS 145, 2018 NSCA 22 (N.S. C.A.)</cite.query>, at paragraph 27.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90cd5248e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>72</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00113" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043960549" w-pub-number="0005475" ID="I75115d508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>TDC Broadband Inc. v. Nova Scotia (Attorney General)</ital>, 2018 CarswellNS 145, 2018 NSCA 22 (N.S. C.A.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 47–48.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90cd5258e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>73</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00114" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043960549" w-pub-number="0005475" ID="I751184608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>TDC Broadband Inc. v. Nova Scotia (Attorney General)</ital>, 2018 CarswellNS 145, 2018 NSCA 22 (N.S. C.A.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 29–30.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90cd5268e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>74</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00115" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043960549" w-pub-number="0005475" ID="I7511ab708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>TDC Broadband Inc. v. Nova Scotia (Attorney General)</ital>, 2018 CarswellNS 145, 2018 NSCA 22 (N.S. C.A.)</cite.query>, at paragraph 51.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90cfc308e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>75</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00116" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043960549" w-pub-number="0005475" ID="I7511f9908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>TDC Broadband Inc. v. Nova Scotia (Attorney General)</ital>, 2018 CarswellNS 145, 2018 NSCA 22 (N.S. C.A.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 52–53.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90cfc318e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>76</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00117" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037249540" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I751220a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>No Limits Sportswear Inc. v. 0912139 B.C. Ltd.</ital>, 2015 CarswellBC 2712, 2015 BCSC 1698</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90cfc328e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>77</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00118" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037249540" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I751247b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>No Limits Sportswear Inc. v. 0912139 B.C. Ltd.</ital>, 2015 CarswellBC 2712, 2015 BCSC 1698</cite.query>, at paras. 1–6.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90d23408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>78</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00119" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037249540" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I75126ec08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>No Limits Sportswear Inc. v. 0912139 B.C. Ltd.</ital>, 2015 CarswellBC 2712, 2015 BCSC 1698</cite.query>, at paras. 23–30.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90d23418e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>79</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00120" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037249540" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I751295d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>No Limits Sportswear Inc. v. 0912139 B.C. Ltd.</ital>, 2015 CarswellBC 2712, 2015 BCSC 1698, at para. 31</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90d23428e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>80</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00121" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037249540" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I7512bce08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>No Limits Sportswear Inc. v. 0912139 B.C. Ltd.</ital>, 2015 CarswellBC 2712, 2015 BCSC 1698</cite.query>, at paras. 114–115.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90d23438e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>81</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00122" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037249540" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I7512e3f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>No Limits Sportswear Inc. v. 0912139 B.C. Ltd.</ital>, 2015 CarswellBC 2712, 2015 BCSC 1698, at para. 120</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90d23448e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>82</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00123" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037249540" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I75130b008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>No Limits Sportswear Inc. v. 0912139 B.C. Ltd.</ital>, 2015 CarswellBC 2712, 2015 BCSC 1698</cite.query>, at paras. 121–126.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90d23458e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>83</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00124" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037249540" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I751332108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>No Limits Sportswear Inc. v. 0912139 B.C. Ltd.</ital>, 2015 CarswellBC 2712, 2015 BCSC 1698, at para. 137</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90d23468e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>84</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00125" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037249540" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I751359208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>No Limits Sportswear Inc. v. 0912139 B.C. Ltd.</ital>, 2015 CarswellBC 2712, 2015 BCSC 1698, at para. 138</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90d23478e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>85</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00126" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038152801" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I751380308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jane Doe 464533 v. D. (N.)</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 911, 2016 ONSC 541</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90d4a508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>86</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00127" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038152801" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I7513a7408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jane Doe 464533 v. D. (N.)</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 911, 2016 ONSC 541</cite.query>, at paras. 1–2, 8, and 10.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90d4a518e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>87</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00128" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038152801" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I7513f5608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jane Doe 464533 v. D. (N.)</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 911, 2016 ONSC 541</cite.query>, at paras. 11–14.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90d4a528e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>88</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00129" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038152801" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I75141c708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jane Doe 464533 v. D. (N.)</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 911, 2016 ONSC 541</cite.query>, at paras. 19–20.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90d4a538e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>89</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00130" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038152801" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I751443808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jane Doe 464533 v. D. (N.)</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 911, 2016 ONSC 541</cite.query>, at paras. 21–25.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90d4a548e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>90</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00131" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038152801" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I75146a908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jane Doe 464533 v. D. (N.)</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 911, 2016 ONSC 541, at para. 50</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90d4a558e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>91</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00132" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038152801" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I751491a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jane Doe 464533 v. D. (N.)</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 911, 2016 ONSC 541</cite.query>, at paras. 51–52, and 56.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90d71608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>92</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00133" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038152801" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I7514dfc08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jane Doe 464533 v. D. (N.)</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 911, 2016 ONSC 541</cite.query>, at paras. 57–58.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90d71618e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>93</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00134" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038152801" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I751506d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jane Doe 464533 v. D. (N.)</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 911, 2016 ONSC 541, at para. 59</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90d71628e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>94</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00135" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038152801" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I75152de08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jane Doe 464533 v. D. (N.)</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 911, 2016 ONSC 541</cite.query>, at paras. 60–63.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90d71638e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>95</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00136" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038152801" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I751554f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jane Doe 464533 v. D. (N.)</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 911, 2016 ONSC 541, at para. 64</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90d71648e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>96</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00137" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028621307" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I75157c008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Zoic Studios BC Inc. v. Gannon</ital>, 2012 CarswellBC 2792, 2012 BCSC 1322</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90d98708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>97</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00138" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028621307" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I7515a3108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Zoic Studios BC Inc. v. Gannon</ital>, 2012 CarswellBC 2792, 2012 BCSC 1322</cite.query>, at paras. 314–441.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90d98718e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>98</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00139" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036767826" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I7515ca208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Zoic Studios B.C. Inc. v. Gannon</ital>, 2015 CarswellBC 2077, 2015 BCCA 334, at para. 61</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90d98728e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>99</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00140" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036767826" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I7515f1308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Zoic Studios B.C. Inc. v. Gannon</ital>, 2015 CarswellBC 2077, 2015 BCCA 334, at para. 62</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90d98738e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>100</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00141" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036767826" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I751618408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Zoic Studios B.C. Inc. v. Gannon</ital>, 2015 CarswellBC 2077, 2015 BCCA 334, at para. 91</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90d98748e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>101</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00142" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2000539618" w-pub-number="0005485" ID="I751618438e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Apotex Fermentation Inc. v. Novopharm Ltd.</ital> (2000), 144 Man. R. (2d) 96, 4 C.P.R. (4th) 148 (Q.B.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90d98758e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>102</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00143" w-ref-type="ER" w-normalized-cite="1967 1WLRUK809" w-pub-number="0004891" ID="I751702a28e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seager v. Copydex Ltd. (No. 2)</ital>, [1967] 1 W.L.R. 809 (C.A.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90d98768e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>103</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00144" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2023458724" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I751729b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Zesta Engineering Ltd. v. Cloutier</ital>, 2010 CarswellOnt 7953, 2010 ONSC 5810</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00145" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2029685095" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I751729b38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2013 CarswellOnt 410, 2013 ONSC 385</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90d98778e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>104</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00146" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2023458724" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I751750c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Zesta Engineering Ltd. v. Cloutier</ital>, 2010 CarswellOnt 7953, 2010 ONSC 5810</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00147" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2029685095" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I751750c38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2013 CarswellOnt 410, 2013 ONSC 385, at para. 198</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90d98788e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>105</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00148" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2023458724" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I75179ee08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Zesta Engineering Ltd. v. Cloutier</ital>, 2010 CarswellOnt 7953, 2010 ONSC 5810</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00149" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2029685095" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I75179ee38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2013 CarswellOnt 410, 2013 ONSC 385</cite.query>, at paras. 2–4.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90dbf808e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>106</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00150" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2023458724" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I7517c5f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Zesta Engineering Ltd. v. Cloutier</ital>, 2010 CarswellOnt 7953, 2010 ONSC 5810</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00151" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2029685095" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I7517c5f38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2013 CarswellOnt 410, 2013 ONSC 385, at para. 5</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90dbf818e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>107</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00152" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2023458724" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I751814108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Zesta Engineering Ltd. v. Cloutier</ital>, 2010 CarswellOnt 7953, 2010 ONSC 5810</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00153" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2029685095" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I751814138e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2013 CarswellOnt 410, 2013 ONSC 385</cite.query>, at paras. 14–16, 20–29, and 32–33.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90dbf828e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>108</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00154" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2023458724" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I75183b208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Zesta Engineering Ltd. v. Cloutier</ital>, 2010 CarswellOnt 7953, 2010 ONSC 5810</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00155" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2029685095" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I75183b238e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2013 CarswellOnt 410, 2013 ONSC 385</cite.query>, at paras. 200–206.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90dbf838e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>109</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00156" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2023458724" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I751889408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Zesta Engineering Ltd. v. Cloutier</ital>, 2010 CarswellOnt 7953, 2010 ONSC 5810</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00157" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2029685095" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I751889438e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2013 CarswellOnt 410, 2013 ONSC 385</cite.query>, at paras. 207–214.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id90dbf848e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>110</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00158" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2023458724" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I7518b0508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Zesta Engineering Ltd. v. Cloutier</ital>, 2010 CarswellOnt 7953, 2010 ONSC 5810</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175976" w-seq-number="00159" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2029685095" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I7518b0538e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2013 CarswellOnt 410, 2013 ONSC 385</cite.query>, at paras. 237 and 289–291.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 7:23<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
