<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 2:12<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I4e5fc390411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>2.</label.designator><headtext>Legal Bases Used by the Courts for the Protection of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I4ea9ebf0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>IV.</label.designator><headtext>Contract Theory</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f5ea016ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>2:12.</label.designator><headtext>Criticism—Not All Breaches of Confidential Business Information Are Covered by Contracts</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The problems encountered as a result of the appropriation of confidential information may not always be solved by invoking the law of contract. <eos/><bos/>This is particularly so if the plaintiff&apos;s action is brought, not against the other contracting party, but against a third party who acquired the secret from the other contracting party. <eos/><bos/>This may also be true where two parties enter into abortive negotiations, during the course of which confidential information is communicated.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id170e5408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Because there are many situations in which confidential business information is appropriated where there is no express or implied contract in place, contract law cannot be the basis of a right to confidential business information per se. <eos/><bos/>It is submitted that the failure to take into account the cases where liability has been imposed in the absence of any contractual relationship between the parties is the most serious flaw in the contract theory.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Id170e5408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>G. Jones, <begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>“Restitution of Benefits Obtained in Breach of Another&apos;s Confidence”<end.quote refid="QT_0001"/> (1970), 86 L.Q.R. 463.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 2:12<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
