<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 8:8<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I59ba4210411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>8.</label.designator><headtext>Practical Advice for Protecting Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I59bf7230411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>II.</label.designator><headtext>Specific Steps to Protect Confidentiality</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I59dc7010411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>B.</label.designator><headtext>Treatment of Confidential Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f749b86ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>8:8.</label.designator><headtext>Company Manuals and Documents Containing Confidential Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A review of relevant company policies related to confidential information should be conducted with an employee at the time he or she begins employment. <eos/><bos/>Certainly the fact that the employee will obtain confidential information should be addressed at the outset of the relationship.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Where a company manual or other sensitive information is distributed to employees in connection with their employment duties, signed acknowledgments of receipt should be obtained by the company. <eos/><bos/>In addition, company manuals can be numbered to allow the employer to easily account for all copies. <eos/><bos/>The employer should ensure that all confidential manuals or documents are returned prior to an employee&apos;s departure from employment. <eos/><bos/>At that time, the employee should also sign an acknowledgment stating that he or she has returned all confidential documents and information, including copies, prior to departure.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>During employment, when sensitive documents are removed from secure areas, a log book should be maintained to ensure proper monitoring and return. <eos/><bos/>In addition, any document or binder containing confidential material should be marked as such and stamped with appropriate phrases such as “Strictly Confidential” and “Do Not Copy”.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Support staff who come into contact with confidential information should be made aware of their duties and of any relevant business policies.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Finally, it should be clear to all individuals in receipt of sensitive information that such information must not be discussed in public areas such as elevators or reception areas.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></section.body></section><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 8:8<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
