<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 4:45<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I5089a870411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>4.</label.designator><headtext>Confidential Business Information and the Employment Relationship</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I52517020411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>V.</label.designator><headtext>Fiduciary Duty</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I53a16fc0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>B.</label.designator><headtext>Remedies Table—Employment Relationship—Breach of Fiduciary Duty</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f65f5e6ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>4:45.</label.designator><headtext>Computer Enhancement Corp. v. J.C. Options</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><ital>Computer Enhancement Corp. v. J.C. Options</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 952, 2016 ONSC 452</headtext><eos/><eop/></head><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Award</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The defendants shall pay the plaintiffs damages in the amount of $132,581.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Summary of Facts:</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The claim was brought by the plaintiff corporation against two of its former employees for damages for breach of contract and breach of fiduciary duty in connection with the sale of computer memory products. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff CEC was in the business of selling memory products for computers to its customers. <eos/><bos/>CEC was a “reseller”.<eos/><bos/> It did not manufacture computer parts, but acted as a middleman, finding the parts that its customers needed and bidding on contracts. <eos/><bos/>It maintained some inventory, although it often acted as a “broker”.<eos/><bos/> Its customers may be resellers or end users. <eos/><bos/>The defendant Jason began working at CEC in the summer of 1995, and was one of its top sales representatives. <eos/><bos/>By 2008 he was earning $896,000 per year as a commissioned sales representative at CEC. <eos/><bos/>Throughout his employment Jason remained a commissioned salesperson. <eos/><bos/>He did not attend management meetings, and did not hire, fire, or supervise other employees. <eos/><bos/>Jason had autonomy in putting together his own deals, although some terms, such as credit limits, were approved by Russell Roberts. <eos/><bos/>The other defendant was Jason&apos;s younger brother, Jeffrey who began working as an “inside salesman” to assist Jason and two other CEC sales representatives in April 2000. <eos/><bos/>When Jason was hired by CEC in June of 1995 he was not asked to sign any contract of employment. <eos/><bos/>On January 3, 1996, Jason was asked by Russell Roberts, to sign a non-competition/non-solicitation agreement with CEC. <eos/><bos/>The agreement was signed on January 3, 1996. <eos/><bos/>Jeffrey signed an identical agreement when he was hired on April 28, 2000. <eos/><bos/>In 2005 Jeffrey and his spouse Crystal registered an unincorporated business named “JC Options”.<eos/><bos/> The business was registered in Crystal&apos;s name for tax purposes, but was operated exclusively by Jeffrey. <eos/><bos/>While still employed as a salesperson at CEC, Jeffrey, through JC Options, began to bid against CEC for contracts with CEC&apos;s existing customers on whose accounts he worked with Jason or the other sales representatives. <eos/><bos/>Jeffrey used his inside knowledge of CEC&apos;s bids to underbid CEC and was awarded half a dozen contracts between 2005 and 2009. <eos/><bos/>JC Options flew under the radar until 2009, when CEC lost a sale to one of its major customers, and, upon making enquiries, discovered that the winning bid was made by a company called JC Options. <eos/><bos/>Further investigation revealed that JC Options was registered under Jeffrey and Crystal. <eos/><bos/>Jeffrey was fired by CEC on February 15, 2009. <eos/><bos/>From that date forward he continued to compete with CEC through JC Options. <eos/><bos/>Jason returned from a vacation on or around February 16, 2009 and was informed that Jeffrey had been dismissed. <eos/><bos/>Jason continued at CEC after his brother was fired, but decided soon after to leave CEC and go into business with his brother. <eos/><bos/>On March 19, 2009 Jason and Jeffrey met with a lawyer and, on March 20, 2009 JC Options was incorporated with Jason and Jeffrey as directors. <eos/><bos/>Jason&apos;s intention at this point was to leave CEC and go into business with his brother, competing directly against CEC.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Jeffrey acknowledged that his competition with CEC while he was a CEC employee was inappropriate, and the dispute with regard to those sales was one of how to calculate damages. <eos/><bos/>Jason denied that he competed with CEC or solicited any of its customers on behalf of JC Options while he was still employed at CEC.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>While the brothers learned the computer parts sales business during their time at CEC, CEC did not manufacture any of these parts, and did not have any confidential patents, designs, trade secrets or processes. <eos/><bos/>The brothers knew who the CEC customers were, and Jason built business relationships with those customers on behalf of CEC. <eos/><bos/>Jason was the top sales representative at CEC and was responsible for a large portion of CEC profits. <eos/><bos/>Jason could fairly be described as the “face of CEC” to its customers; he was the only individual at CEC that most of his customers dealt with. <eos/><bos/>The customers were not, however, exclusive to CEC or an industry secret. <eos/><bos/>Everyone in the industry knew who were the players and potential customers. <eos/><bos/>The names of potential customers are available in the public domain on various websites which list the “top 100” dealers of the major computer and IT manufacturers such as IBM, Hewlett Packard and CISCO. <eos/><bos/>Many sales leads were the result of “cold calls” to these dealers to find out their current requirements. <eos/><bos/>There were many competitors in the marketplace, and CEC bid on each contract in competition with other computer parts resellers. <eos/><bos/>The needs and requirements of each customer would change with each contract, and each successive bid had to succeed on its own merits. <eos/><bos/>Customers generally went with the lowest bid and competition increased from year to year. <eos/><bos/>While Jeffrey used his inside knowledge of CEC&apos;s bids to underbid CEC while he worked at CEC, this inside knowledge was of little use after both brothers left CEC, since they would have no knowledge of CEC bids prepared after March 27, 2009. <eos/><bos/>The product, cost and mark-up would change with every bid.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Reasons Given by Court for Award:</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The most problematic period was the time between February 15, 2009 when Jeffrey was fired and March 27, 2009 when Jason quit. <eos/><bos/>Jason was still employed at CEC during this period, and had access to CEC bidding information. <eos/><bos/>Jeffrey was successfully competing against CEC during this period. <eos/><bos/>JC Options produced invoices from some of Jason&apos;s largest CEC customers dated as early as February 20, 2009. <eos/><bos/>Given the brothers&apos; admitted intention to go into business together, the trial judge did not believe that they had no discussions regarding their proposed enterprise prior to the March 19, 2009 meeting with their lawyer. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge inferred that they formed an intention to work together on or soon after February 16, and that they did work in concert during that entire period. <eos/><bos/>This resulted in JC Options&apos; successful bids between February 16, 2009 and April 9, 2009. <eos/><bos/>As a result, both brothers were responsible for the activities of JC Options from February 16, 2009 on.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In considering the issues, it was necessary to distinguish among four separate time periods, since the answer to each question depended upon the time in question. <eos/><bos/>The first period was up to February 15, 2009, when Jeffrey was terminated. <eos/><bos/>There was no dispute that Jeffrey owed a fiduciary duty not to compete with CEC until that date. <eos/><bos/>The second period was from February 15, 2009 to March 27, 2009, when Jason resigned. <eos/><bos/>There was no dispute that Jason owed a fiduciary duty not to compete with CEC during this period of time. <eos/><bos/>The third period was from March 27, 2009 to the issuance of the Court Order on April 9, 2009. <eos/><bos/>Neither brother was a CEC employee during this period. <eos/><bos/>The fourth period was the period after the issuance of the Court Order on April 9, 2009. <eos/><bos/>Both brothers were bound by this Order.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A departing employee may plan and prepare for his next employment before departure from his existing employment. <eos/><bos/>The boundary lies in when that preparation becomes actual competition, which trespasses on the basic duties. <eos/><bos/>If Jason had done nothing more than meet with a lawyer and incorporate JC Options prior to leaving CEC, there might be no violation of his fiduciary duties to his employer. <eos/><bos/>But JC Options was already a going concern operating in competition with CEC when Jason became a director of the company on March 20, 2009, and Jason was working with Jeffrey to lure CEC customers to JC Options from at least the date of the first Metafore invoice of February 20, 2009, more than a month before Jason resigned from CEC. <eos/><bos/>This amounted to actual competition. <eos/><bos/>As of April 9, 2009, the brothers were subject to the court order, which replaced any prior legal responsibilities. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, the issue of Jason&apos;s post-employment fiduciary duties to his former employer related only to the two week period between March 27, 2009 and April 9, 2009.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Since Jason was not a manager or officer of CEC, the issue was whether Jason could properly be described as a “key employee”.<eos/><bos/> Jason did have a fiduciary duty to his former employer to not solicit former customers for at least that two-week period of time prior to the court order on the basis of the following considerations: Jason was a key employee of CEC. <eos/><bos/>He was the top sales representative of the company, which had only seven sales representatives at the time that he left. <eos/><bos/>He was the face of CEC to most of those customers, and the only person that many of the customers dealt with. <eos/><bos/>Several customers testified that they never dealt with anyone else at CEC. <eos/><bos/>He built relationships with those customers on behalf of CEC. <eos/><bos/>He was a trusted employee who was given considerable autonomy to put together his own sales deals. <eos/><bos/>Jason dealt with a substantial proportion of CEC&apos;s customers for fourteen years, virtually to the exclusion of his employer. <eos/><bos/>He was responsible for a substantial portion of CEC&apos;s revenue. <eos/><bos/>He resigned without any notice.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The final issue related to the quantification of damages for the period up to February 15, 2009 (where liability is admitted) and from February 15, 2009 to April 9, 2009. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge observed that compensation for breach of fiduciary duty has a restitutionary objective. <eos/><bos/>In a case such as this there are two different approaches to compensation: (i) disgorging the benefits wrongfully acquired by the defendant, or (ii) restoring the plaintiff to the position it would have been in if the breach had not occurred. <eos/><bos/>The first approach focuses on the defendant&apos;s gain; the second on the plaintiff&apos;s loss. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff may elect which approach to compensation they are seeking. <eos/><bos/>In the trial judge&apos;s view, the quantification of damages was the same regardless of which approach is taken. <eos/><bos/>The witnesses who were involved in the computer parts sales business at this time as both sellers and customers consistently confirmed that the computer parts sales business became more competitive during that period, with shrinking profit margins, increased international competition and the elimination of “grey market” sales, where resellers sold items not authorized for sale by the manufacturer in a particular market at a reduced rate and higher profit margin. <eos/><bos/>The needs and requirements of each customer would change with each contract, and each successive bid had to succeed on its own merits. <eos/><bos/>This was not a case where customers were exclusive to CEC. <eos/><bos/>Customers generally went with the lowest bid. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, JC Options could not be held responsible for all of CEC&apos;s lost profits during this period. <eos/><bos/>They were, however, responsible for lost profits on sales taken from CEC customers by JC Options. <eos/><bos/>Since the two firms had basically the same profit margins, the profits of JC Options equaled the losses of CEC.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>With respect to the period to February 15, 2009, the defendants were ordered to pay $58,331 to the plaintiff for the sales made by Jeffrey and JC Options to CEC customers while Jeffrey was still an employee of CEC.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>With respect to the period from February 15, 2009 to April 9, 2009, CEC was entitled to a return of the gross profits of JC Options for this period. <eos/><bos/>Based on the invoices provided, JC Options made approximately $297,000 in sales to CEC customers during this period. <eos/><bos/>Based on a profit margin of 25% damages for this period were $74,250.00.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></section.body></section><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 4:45<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
