<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 4:18<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I5089a870411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>4.</label.designator><headtext>Confidential Business Information and the Employment Relationship</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I51acf2c0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>IV.</label.designator><headtext>Restrictive Covenants</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f6382d6ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>4:18.</label.designator><headtext>Reasonableness of Restrictive Covenants—Duration</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The case law has consistently supported the principle that a restrictive covenant must be of a limited and reasonable duration.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id41a5a608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>] As to the actual competitive activities of a former employee, <ital>i.e.</ital>, the ability to make competitive use of confidential information, the length of time considered reasonable will depend upon the facts of the individual case. <eos/><bos/>The employee&apos;s position is particularly important. <eos/><bos/>A reasonable duration will usually be the length of time necessary for the employer to train an employee to fill the position that was vacated. <eos/><bos/>In addition, the employer must be allowed to solidify its interest in corporate opportunities and customers.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175872" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2042193556" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2ed3cc118e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Kerzner v. American Iron &amp; Metal Company</cite.query> Inc.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id41a81708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>] Kerzner was first hired in 1980 by a privately owned family business providing recyclable products to foundries and smelters and steel mills in Canada and elsewhere. <eos/><bos/>Kerzner eventually became a one third owner of the company. <eos/><bos/>He also became the company&apos;s president. <eos/><bos/>In August 2008, the company was purchased by ArcelorMittal. <eos/><bos/>Part of the arrangement with ArcelorMittal was that Kerzner would continue to be employed as the general manager (Non-Ferrous Products) of ArcelorMittal Ottawa. <eos/><bos/>Kerzner worked for ArcelorMittal under a series of employment agreements. <eos/><bos/>The 2014 Employment Agreement was a two-year fixed term contract. <eos/><bos/>It contained provisions governing payments due to Kerzner in the event of early termination of his employment by the employer.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id41a81718e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">3</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In March 2015, ArcelorMittal Ottawa was acquired by the defendant. <eos/><bos/>Kerzner&apos;s employment was transferred to AIM. <eos/><bos/>On 11 September 2015, AIM provided Kerzner with one week of working notice of the termination of his employment. <eos/><bos/>He was advised that he would be provided with six months&apos; salary continuation and benefits coverage, purportedly in accordance with the provisions of his May 2014 employment agreement. <eos/><bos/>When, Kerzner accepted a position with an Ottawa-based direct competitor of ArcelorMittal Ottawa, AIM purported to invoke its right under the 2014 Employment Agreement to suspend or terminate all remaining termination payments and benefits that would otherwise have been owed to Kerzner.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id41a81728e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">4</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The agreement in place at the time of the plaintiff&apos;s termination was the 2014 Employment Agreement. <eos/><bos/>Kerzner, through his family trust, which was one of the sellers of Bakermet shares, entered into a “Non-Competition and Non-Solicitation Agreement” with Bakermet and ArcelorMittal Montréal Inc., effective for five years. <eos/><bos/>The non-competition clause precluded Kerzner from being employed by any business related to the acquisition, processing and marketing of superior recyclable products from all types of ferrous and non-ferrous metal as conducted by ArcelorMittal Ottawa, ArcelorMittal Montréal and ArcelorMittal SA in Ontario, Québec and the Atlantic Provinces for eighteen months following the termination of his employment. <eos/><bos/>The non-solicitation provision related to the same territory and was effective for two years.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id41a81738e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">5</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>To be enforceable, restrictive covenants must be reasonable in all of the circumstances. <eos/><bos/>The parties agreed that a determination of whether a restrictive covenant is reasonable will be influenced by whether it was negotiated as part of the sale of the business by Bakermet to ArcelorMittal, or as part of an employment agreement. <eos/><bos/>There could be no doubt that it was important to ArcelorMittal, at the time of its acquisition of Bakermet, that Kerzner should be both retained as a senior employee but also restricted in his ability to compete with ArcelorMittal or solicit its business in the event that he left the company. <eos/><bos/>This was reflected not only in the employment contracts but, also, in a separate Non-Competition and Non-Solicitation Agreement, which was signed concurrently with the share purchase transaction in August 2008 and which was effective for five years. <eos/><bos/>However, by the time the 2014 Employment Agreement was entered into, the separate Non-Competition and Non-Solicitation Agreement had run its course.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id41a81748e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">6</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The judge concluded that although the 2014 Employment Agreement contained non-solicitation and non-competition terms that replicated those found in the 2011 agreement and that were similar, but not identical, to those contained in the 2008 Employment Agreement, AIM could not, on the one hand, argue that the plaintiff was subject to a series of short-term contracts with his rights as an employee limited accordingly, but simultaneously argue that the non-competition and non-solicitation clauses contained in those employment agreements should be assessed in the context of the plaintiff&apos;s sale of his Bakermet shares. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, the reasonableness of the non-competition and non-solicitation provisions in the 2014 Employment Agreement were be assessed having regard to the other provisions of that agreement rather than the longer-term relationship between the plaintiff and the defendant&apos;s predecessors, and in particular the plaintiff&apos;s sale of his shares in Bakermet.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id41a81758e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">7</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The 2014 Employment Agreement was for a term of two years. <eos/><bos/>The non-competition obligation survived for eighteen months following the termination of employment. <eos/><bos/>The non-solicitation provisions survived for two years following the termination of employment.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id41aa8808e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">8</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>It is well settled that a factor determining the reasonableness of a covenant in restraint of trade in an employment contract is the duration of the restraint. <eos/><bos/>In circumstances where there is a fixed term contract of employment, one of the factors to be taken into account when considering the reasonableness of the restrictive covenant is whether it is temporally proportionate to the term of the employment. <eos/><bos/>The judge observed that while there are plenty of examples of cases in which eighteen month or two year restrictive covenants for senior employees in positions comparable to Kerzner&apos;s had been deemed by courts to be reasonable, none of those decisions involved fixed term employment contracts for a relatively short term of employment. <eos/><bos/>The judge concluded that AIM could not have it both ways. <eos/><bos/>It was unreasonable for an employer in the position of AIM to insist on a fixed term arrangement, yet simultaneously restrain Kerzner from working elsewhere in the only business he had been involved in for the past 35 years, for a period of time that, in the case of the non-solicitation restriction, was for the same length of time as the employment contract itself.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id41aa8818e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">9</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Kerzner&apos;s acknowledgement that the defendant required protection of its legitimate business interest was a factor to be taken into consideration. <eos/><bos/>However, the judge concluded that read and considered in the context of a short, fixed-term contract with unreasonably broad geographic restrictions, and even allowing for the fact that the 2014 Employment Agreement provided Kerzner with an entitlement to compensation upon termination that was more generous than his statutory entitlement, the non-competition and non-solicitation clauses were unreasonable and, hence, unenforceable.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id41aa8828e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">10</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>AIM&apos;s statement of defence and counterclaim requested a declaration that Kerzner breached his fiduciary obligations to AIM by commencing employment with a competitor in November 2015. <eos/><bos/>No particulars of Kerzner&apos;s alleged breach of his fiduciary obligations were pleaded, but a clue could be found in a paragraph addressing damages which referred to confidential and proprietary information having been taken and/or used by Kerzner.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id41aa8838e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">11</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The judge accepted the basic premise that Kerzner&apos;s fiduciary responsibilities did not automatically end with his employment. <eos/><bos/>The assertion that the taking up of employment with Palmer was in breach of his fiduciary responsibilities was harder to sustain given the finding that the restrictive covenants were unenforceable. <eos/><bos/>Kerzner scrupulously refrained from soliciting any and all customers of AIM. <eos/><bos/>Beyond the bald assertion in the counterclaim that AIM had been damaged by its confidential and proprietary information having been taken or used by Kerzner, AIM presented no evidence to the contrary. <eos/><bos/>The record was insufficient to support any finding that Kerzner breached any continuing fiduciary obligations he may have had to AIM.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id41aa8848e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">12</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In the context of a restrictive covenant entered into many years prior to the litigation, courts will usually determine the reasonableness of a restrictive covenant with reference to the time when the covenant was entered into.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Id41a5a608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>See, for example, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175872" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1966075753" w-pub-number="0005149" ID="I2ed9e6908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Northern Messenger (Calgary) Ltd. v. Frost</ital> (1966), 57 D.L.R. (2d) 456, 56 W.W.R. 412 (Alta. S.C.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175872" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1981180250" w-pub-number="0004655" ID="I2ed9e6938e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Reed Shaw Osler Ltd. v. Wilson</ital> (1981), 35 A.R. 451</cite.query>, 17 Alta. L.R. (2d) 81 (C.A.); <cite.query w-src-number="0492175872" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1983171047" w-pub-number="0005150" ID="I2ed9e6958e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Western Inventory Service Ltd. v. Sager</ital> (1983), 148 D.L.R. (3d) 434, 42 O.R. (2d) 166 (H.C.J.)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>Even a one-year restriction may be too long in dynamic markets, see the U.S. decision of <cite.query w-src-number="0492175872" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="RT" w-serial-number="1999242654" w-pub-number="0004637" ID="I2ed9e6998e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EarthWeb v. Schlack</ital></cite.query>, 99 Civ. 10035, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175872" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="RP" w-serial-number="1999242654" w-pub-number="0004637" ID="I2ed9e69a8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">71 F. Supp. 2d 299 (New York)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>However, see <cite.query w-src-number="0492175872" w-seq-number="00007" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1997414191" w-pub-number="0003986" ID="I2eda0da08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Avva Light Corp. v. Komonoski</ital>, [1997] 8 W.W.R. 155, 204 A.R. 344 (Q.B.)</cite.query>, where a covenant of three years was considered to be inside the acceptable parameters of enforceability.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id41a81708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175872" w-seq-number="00008" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042193556" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2eda5bc08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Kerzner v. American Iron &amp; Metal Company Inc.</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 11049, 2017 ONSC 4352</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id41a81718e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175872" w-seq-number="00009" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042193556" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2eda82d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Kerzner v. American Iron &amp; Metal Company Inc.</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 11049, 2017 ONSC 4352</cite.query>, at paras. 1-8.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id41a81728e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>4</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175872" w-seq-number="00010" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042193556" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2edaa9e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Kerzner v. American Iron &amp; Metal Company Inc.</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 11049, 2017 ONSC 4352</cite.query>, at paras. 10, 12, and 38.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id41a81738e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>5</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175872" w-seq-number="00011" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042193556" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2edad0f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Kerzner v. American Iron &amp; Metal Company Inc.</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 11049, 2017 ONSC 4352</cite.query>, at paras. 26-27, and 29.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id41a81748e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>6</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175872" w-seq-number="00012" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042193556" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2edb1f108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Kerzner v. American Iron &amp; Metal Company Inc.</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 11049, 2017 ONSC 4352</cite.query>, at paras. 81, and 84-85.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id41a81758e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>7</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175872" w-seq-number="00013" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042193556" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2edb46208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Kerzner v. American Iron &amp; Metal Company Inc.</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 11049, 2017 ONSC 4352</cite.query>, at paras. 86-87.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id41aa8808e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>8</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175872" w-seq-number="00014" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042193556" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2edb6d308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Kerzner v. American Iron &amp; Metal Company Inc.</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 11049, 2017 ONSC 4352, at para. 88</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id41aa8818e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>9</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175872" w-seq-number="00015" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042193556" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2edb94408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Kerzner v. American Iron &amp; Metal Company Inc.</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 11049, 2017 ONSC 4352</cite.query>, at paras. 89-90, and 92-93.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id41aa8828e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>10</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175872" w-seq-number="00016" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042193556" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2edbbb508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Kerzner v. American Iron &amp; Metal Company Inc.</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 11049, 2017 ONSC 4352, at para. 101</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id41aa8838e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>11</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175872" w-seq-number="00017" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042193556" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2edc09708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Kerzner v. American Iron &amp; Metal Company Inc.</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 11049, 2017 ONSC 4352</cite.query>, at paras. 137-138.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id41aa8848e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>12</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175872" w-seq-number="00018" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042193556" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2edc30808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Kerzner v. American Iron &amp; Metal Company Inc.</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 11049, 2017 ONSC 4352</cite.query>, at paras. 139-141.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 4:18<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
