<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 4:26<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I5089a870411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>4.</label.designator><headtext>Confidential Business Information and the Employment Relationship</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I52517020411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>V.</label.designator><headtext>Fiduciary Duty</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I5251be40411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>A.</label.designator><headtext>Analysis</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f638456ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>4:26.</label.designator><headtext>The Employment Context</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Certain employment duties continue following the termination of an employment relationship. <eos/><bos/>Departing “fiduciaries” will continue to owe a heightened duty to their former employers even after the relationship ends. <eos/><bos/>In <ital>Canadian Aero Service Ltd v. O&apos;Malley</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id488d3a08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>] the Supreme Court held that the former employees:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>… were “top management” and not mere employees whose duty to their employer, unless enlarged by contract, consisted only of respect for trade secrets and for confidentiality of customer lists. <eos/><bos/>Theirs was a larger, more exacting duty which, unless modified by statute or by contract … was similar to that owed to a corporate employer by its directors.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0002"/></paratext></para></display.quote><paratext>The court, <ital>per</ital> Laskin J., stated that holding the officers accountable to the corporation <begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>“was simply recognition of the degree of control which their initiatives and responsibilities had given them in corporate operations”<end.quote refid="QT_0001"/>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Directors and other truly senior management will, in all but the rarest of situations, owe their employer a fiduciary level of responsibility.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id488d3a18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>] The problem comes in defining “senior management”.<eos/><bos/> In this section there will be an analysis of the distinction between most employees or what <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1973144068" w-pub-number="0005150" ID="I38f4b9218e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Canadian Aero Services</ital></cite.query> referred to as “mere employees”, and “top management” or “fiduciary” employees.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A title, while providing an indication, will not by itself give rise to fiduciary responsibilities. <eos/><bos/>The actual duties of the employee will determine whether a fiduciary level obligation is owing. <eos/><bos/>Titles that simply attach prestige to a position but bestow insignificant management authority will not result in fiduciary status.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id488fab08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">3</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>An employee may owe a fiduciary duty to his or her employer where the employee has discretionary power to affect adversely the employer&apos;s interests and the employer is vulnerable to the exercise of that power.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id488fab18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">4</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id488fab28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">5</footnote.reference>] the plaintiff, Capital Direct, which was in the business of providing home equity and residential mortgage financing to individuals, applied for an interim injunction restraining the defendant Blanchette, a former employee of Capital Direct and a licensed mortgage broker, from <begin.quote ID="QT_0003"/>“soliciting, serving, referring, directing, receiving business from, contacting or continuing any form of communication with any clients or active prospect of Capital Direct with whom she had contact or knowledge of during her employment with Capital Direct.”<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0003"/> Blanchette was hired and employed as a “Mortgage Salesperson” pursuant to a written employment agreement in 2005. <eos/><bos/>During her employment with Capital Direct she was also described and held out to the public as a “Mortgage Planner” or “Mortgage Advisor”.<eos/><bos/> The Original Employment Agreement contained a one-year non-competition clause, limited geographically to the <begin.quote ID="QT_0004"/>“City of Vancouver and the Lower Mainland”<end.quote refid="QT_0004"/>, and with respect to any business involving the business of private mortgage lending or private mortgage brokering. <eos/><bos/>The Original Employment Agreement contained a confidentiality clause that required Blanchette to keep all information provided to her by Capital Direct confidential, including information relating to any customer, and not to release, use, or disclose the information unless she obtained the prior written permission of Capital Direct. <eos/><bos/>The Original Employment Agreement expired on February 24, 2006. <eos/><bos/>Clause 3.2 of the Original Employment Agreement stated that the initial term could be extended for a further one-year period, on a recurring basis, upon the written agreement of both parties. <eos/><bos/>However, the Original Employment Agreement was never extended or renewed. <eos/><bos/>The parties agreed that from February 25, 2006 until her departure from Capital Direct, Blanchette&apos;s employment was not governed by a written employment agreement, nor was it subject to any express restrictive covenants or confidentiality provisions.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id488fab38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">6</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Capital Direct&apos;s business development efforts involved significant advertising across a wide range of media. <eos/><bos/>Blanchette was never the face of Capital Direct. <eos/><bos/>Capital Direct never used or displayed her name, contact information, picture, or bio in any of its advertising or on its website. <eos/><bos/>Blanchette did not engage in any networking activities for Capital Direct, nor was she required to do so. <eos/><bos/>Rather, potential clients who contacted Capital Direct were distributed on a rotating basis to all of the mortgage brokers.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id488fab48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">7</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In late 2017, Blanchette took a three-month medical leave of absence. <eos/><bos/>When she commenced her leave, she was one of three mortgage brokers. <eos/><bos/>Following her return, Blanchette&apos;s authority and discretion were significantly decreased by Capital Direct, including that she was only referred new phone leads/clients from outside the Metro Vancouver area; her authority to approve mortgages up to $500,000 was decreased to only lower value mortgages; she could no longer contact an investor directly to deal with changes to the Loan to Value ratio or the funding amount after a mortgage was approved and prior to funding; whereas she could previously initial the change without question; she no longer had authority to negotiate a repayment program; she could no longer waive or reduce NSF fees unless she had approval; she could no longer approve holds on a client&apos;s payments without approval; she needed approval before allowing clients to send and sign mortgage package documents outside the Capital Direct office; and her time/schedule was managed by the Capital Direct administrative staff and manager whereas she previously had autonomy to set her own schedule. <eos/><bos/>By the time of her return, Capital Direct had employed three new brokers, bringing the total number of active brokers to six. <eos/><bos/>The three new junior brokers were assigned to work with and train under the other two senior brokers. <eos/><bos/>Blanchette was not provided with any assistance from these new employees.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48921c08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">8</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>On July 13, 2018, Capital Direct provided one year&apos;s working notice of termination to Blanchette. <eos/><bos/>Settlement negotiations continued until February 12, 2019, when they broke down for the final time. <eos/><bos/>Capital Direct directed Blanchette to report to work on February 13, 2019. <eos/><bos/>Blanchette did not report to work. <eos/><bos/>Capital Direct treated Blanchette&apos;s employment as having been ended by her.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48921c18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">9</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Capital Direct discovered that Blanchette had referred a client of Capital Direct to her son. <eos/><bos/>Blanchette sent an email to this client stating that she was transferring her mortgage broker license to work independently of Capital Direct, and would be working with her son going forward. <eos/><bos/>The client later received an approval through her son but did not go ahead with that financing as the client received a better offer from Capital Direct.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id489e5108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">10</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Blanchette said that from this point until the end of February 2019, she did not initiate contact with any clients, former clients, or active prospects of Capital Direct, as she needed to wait until her Mortgage Sub Broker license had been officially transferred. <eos/><bos/>The clients she had any contact with during this period were either ones who contacted her directly or who were close friends or associates. <eos/><bos/>Once her Mortgage Sub Broker license was officially transferred to a new brokerage, Blanchette did begin contacting certain former clients she had personally serviced at Capital Direct. <eos/><bos/>She provided her new contact information, advised them that she had made a switch from working for Capital Direct, and reassured them that she was available to answer any questions or concerns they had going forward.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48a81508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">11</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Blanchette acknowledged that she had the names, phone numbers and email addresses of some of her former clients at Capital Direct, information she personally collected over many years. <eos/><bos/>She collected this information to help her do her job better, to stay in touch and maintain relationships with her clients, and to reconcile commissions. <eos/><bos/>She collected this information on her own initiative and was not directed to do so by Capital Direct as part of her job duties. <eos/><bos/>Blanchette did not download or take any customer lists compiled by Capital Direct, nor did she possess a list of Capital Direct clients with whom she did not personally deal. <eos/><bos/>Blanchette did not take or possess any documents of Capital Direct containing detailed customer information relating to their needs or preferences, the rates they paid, their credit rating, or their income, assets or debt.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48a81518e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">12</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Blanchette said that to date she had not benefitted financially from any of her initiated contacts with former clients. <eos/><bos/>The only amount she has been paid arising from a former client was from one person who called her to arrange financing to pay out an existing Capital Direct mortgage.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48a81528e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">13</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Branch concluded that the heightened standard of strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case should be applied for the following reasons: the request for injunctive relief at trial would likely become moot by the time the matter reached that stage, as any duties Blanchette might owe to Capital Direct not to solicit former clients, even at a fiduciary level, would likely have expired; an injunction would clearly affect Blanchette&apos;s ability to earn a living. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff was almost 64 years old. <eos/><bos/>An injunction against any communication with individuals with whom she has worked over many years would clearly be detrimental to her ability to earn a living.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48aa8608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">14</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Branch observed that Capital Direct initially had non-competition and confidentiality clauses in place, but those fell away as its relationship with Blanchette continued. <eos/><bos/>Absent contractual duties governing the conduct of a former employee, Capital Direct must rely on common law principles. <eos/><bos/>It first placed reliance on the concept of fiduciary duty. <eos/><bos/>Capital Direct alleged that by virtue of the trust, confidence and broad discretion possessed by Blanchette, Capital Direct was subject to a peculiar vulnerability to the exercise of her powers. <eos/><bos/>Justice Branch concluded that there was not a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that Blanchette would be found to be a fiduciary given that: she was not the general manager or broker on record, even in name only; she was no longer subjected to any restrictive covenants; she was not in management at all, having no employees under her; she was not identified on marketing materials; she did not have access to all of Capital Direct&apos;s confidential information; she was not the primary point of contact for Capital Direct&apos;s major client or group of clients; she was only one of eight brokers; she did not supervise any other employees; the defendant&apos;s reputation did not rest in Blanchette&apos;s hands; she was not the first point of contact with any clients, who were simply referred to her randomly; her client list had diminished such that she was not an integral part of the financial success of the office. <eos/><bos/>Her commissions had reduced to approximately one-half of what the other senior mortgage brokers were achieving; even according to the defendant, she had no power to make referrals to other companies without management approval; and, particularly after she was given her one-year notice, her rights and responsibilities were greatly reduced. <eos/><bos/>This showed a lack of trust, rather than to her being a repository of trust.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48acf708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">15</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Based on her limited discretion and authority, Justice Branch concluded that Capital Direct was not particularly vulnerable to loss, harm, and damage if Blanchette failed to perform her duties.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48acf718e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">16</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Even if there was no fiduciary duty, there may still be other common law duties applicable to departing employees. <eos/><bos/>There was support for Capital Direct&apos;s position that there was at least a more limited duty on the part of the former employee not to misuse confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The improper use of confidential client information by an employee constitutes a breach of the employee&apos;s duty of confidence. <eos/><bos/>However, Justice Branch concluded that there was not a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that Blanchette misused confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The information that Blanchette retained was not a client list as that term is properly understood. <eos/><bos/>She did not download, take, print off or extract a client list from the plaintiff&apos;s systems. <eos/><bos/>Rather, she simply had a list of persons with whom she had had previous contact on her phone. <eos/><bos/>Further, it was only basic name, phone number or email information, and not more material information such as mortgage renewal dates, interest rates charged, current banking profiles, or other personal characteristics. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence that the defendant extracted information “in fraud of” Capital Direct or that it was intentionally <begin.quote ID="QT_0006"/>“acquired to advance his own business”<end.quote refid="QT_0006"/>. <eos/><bos/>Rather, the information was simply gathered in her phone over the many years of her employment. <eos/><bos/>Capital Direct did not assert that Blanchette took a copy of any client list, nor that she emailed a list of customer names to her personal email account. <eos/><bos/>Nor was there evidence that she made a special effort to duplicate or imprint any formal client lists or sheets into her memory or her phone. <eos/><bos/>Nor did the information include <begin.quote ID="QT_0005"/>“the clients&apos; needs, the clients&apos; preferences, and the rates that the clients were willing to pay”<end.quote refid="QT_0005"/>. <eos/><bos/>Rather, it was simply contact information already on her phone. <eos/><bos/>Hence, the relatively passive retention of name of contact information on her phone gathered over the course of her employment did not amount to the misuse of confidential information on the facts.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48acf728e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">17</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>M-I Drilling Fluids Canada, Inc v. Cottle</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id48acf738e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">18</footnote.reference>] the Plaintiff alleged that between 2009 and 2013, Cottle took kickbacks from two of its suppliers. <eos/><bos/>In May 2009, Cottle became a business development manager for MID&apos;s Sulfatreat Unit. <eos/><bos/>Between May 1, 2009 and September 23, 2013, IAL was a supplier of Odour Control Systems to MID. <eos/><bos/>During this period, Cottle, on behalf of MID, signed purchase orders for Odour Control containers from IAL. <eos/><bos/>These purchase orders were countersigned by another MID employee. <eos/><bos/>IAL agreed to provide Cottle with a payment equal to 3-10% of the value of these purchase orders. <eos/><bos/>Cottle issued 117 invoices from CACI, the company owned by Cottle, to IAL for these payments. <eos/><bos/>CACI received payment for all but one of these invoices, the total amount paid being $77,751.98. <eos/><bos/>Indy was also a supplier of Odour Control containers to MID. <eos/><bos/>Cottle, on behalf of MID, signed purchase orders for Odour Control containers from Indy. <eos/><bos/>These purchase orders were countersigned by another MID employee. <eos/><bos/>Indy agreed that it would provide Cottle with a payment equal to 3-10% of the value of these purchase orders. <eos/><bos/>Cottle issued 7 invoices from CACI to Indy in respect of the purchase of Odour Control containers. <eos/><bos/>CACI received payment for all of these invoices, the total amount paid being $11,113.86. <eos/><bos/>On February 3, 2012, Cottle received and signed a written reprimand from MID regarding his receipt of a single payment from IAL. <eos/><bos/>Cottle understood that MID considered his taking this single payment to be a breach of the Code of Ethics. <eos/><bos/>Following this reprimand, Cottle continued to invoice IAL and Indy and to receive payments from them. <eos/><bos/>In April 2013, Cottle suffered a heart attack and went on a disability leave of absence. <eos/><bos/>During Cottle&apos;s absence, Karpovich discovered unmarked white binders in a credenza in Cottle&apos;s office which contained some of the invoices from CACI to IAL and Indy. <eos/><bos/>Based on this discovery of the payments received by Cottle through CACI, MID terminated Cottle&apos;s employment.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48acf748e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">19</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Jones observed that the courts must take a cautious approach in imposing fiduciary duties on employees. <eos/><bos/>Nevertheless, the case law is clear that fiduciary obligations may be imposed on “key” employees who, on the facts of the particular case, are in a position to affect the interests of their employers.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48acf758e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">20</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Jones concluded that Cottle was a key employee of MID. <eos/><bos/>He had substantial responsibility for the operation of the Sulfatreat unit and functioned quite autonomously. <eos/><bos/>While it was true that his purchase orders had to be countersigned, this did not appear to have imported a significant supervisory aspect. <eos/><bos/>Similarly, while there was no evidence that Cottle had access to the kind of confidential information so often discussed in the key employee cases, it was clear that he had the primary relationship with Sulfatreat&apos;s suppliers and possibly with its customers as well. <eos/><bos/>Justice Jones concluded that he was in a position to have a marked impact on MID&apos;s economic interests. <eos/><bos/>As a key employee, Cottle had a fiduciary obligation to act in MID&apos;s interests and to avoid placing his personal interests in conflict therewith. <eos/><bos/>He breached this obligation by taking the Payments.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48af6808e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">21</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Rather than the usual remedy of damages, MID sought disgorgement of the profits Cottle made from the Payments. <eos/><bos/>Justice Jones concluded that this was an appropriate case for the disgorgement of profits remedy. <eos/><bos/>Cottle had, and breached, a fiduciary duty and it would be inequitable to permit him to retain the benefits he obtained through that breach. <eos/><bos/>The full amount of the Payments both before and after the 2012 warning must be disgorged. <eos/><bos/>Cottle did not dispute that he obtained Payments in the amounts of $77,751.98 from IAL and $11,113.86 from Indy.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48af6818e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">22</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Cottle argued that MID should be precluded from obtaining disgorgement of the Payments by the doctrine of estoppel by representation and/or estoppel by conduct. <eos/><bos/>Estoppel requires a positive representation by one party with the intention that it be relied upon by the other and action by the second party in reliance on that representation such that it would be inequitable to allow the first party to resile from it. <eos/><bos/>Cottle asserted that he relied on the representations made by MID in both the 2012 warning letter and the 2013 termination letter. <eos/><bos/>The 2012 warning letter stated that <begin.quote ID="QT_0007"/>“failure to conform to company policies and procedures in the future will lead to further disciplinary actions up to and including termination of employment.”<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0007"/> The 2013 letter stated that his position with MID was terminated immediately. <eos/><bos/>Neither letter made any reference to recovery of the Payments. <eos/><bos/>Cottle&apos;s position was that, because there was no such reference, he believed that termination of his employment was the full extent of the potential repercussions of his conduct. <eos/><bos/>Justice Jones rejected these submissions. <eos/><bos/>The 2012 warning letter was issued to Cottle when he was still an employee of MID and was intended to alter his behaviour, rather than to waive any remedies available to MID. <eos/><bos/>Further, Cottle did not have clean hands. <eos/><bos/>Justice Jones rejected his argument that he had permission to accept the Payments and found he was well aware that his conduct was dishonest. <eos/><bos/>It would not be appropriate to relieve him of the consequences, notwithstanding that they may be greater than he anticipated. <eos/><bos/>Cottle made the decision to engage in dishonest conduct because he calculated that it was “worth the risk”.<eos/><bos/> Though he may have miscalculated, he must bear the consequences of the risk he chose to run.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48af6828e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">23</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>An award of punitive damages was appropriate. <eos/><bos/>Cottle engaged in a course of conduct that he knew was wrongful, even after having been expressly warned against it. <eos/><bos/>To limit the consequences to the relinquishment of his ill-gotten gains would be insufficient to achieve the goal of punishment and deterrence. <eos/><bos/>In Justice Jones&apos; view, the $50,000 sought by MID was excessive. <eos/><bos/>While Cottle&apos;s conduct was certainly perfidious, his intent was to profit himself rather than to injure MID. <eos/><bos/>Thus, the malice that drove the award in <ital>Hill</ital> was absent. <eos/><bos/>Justice Jones awarded punitive damages in the amount of $12,000. <eos/><bos/>This amount represented a reasonable proportion of the overall damages award and was sufficient to express the Court&apos;s disapprobation of Cottle&apos;s conduct, but was not irrationally high.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48af6838e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">24</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2044743804" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I392da3718e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Alberta Finance &amp; Mortgage Corporation v. Bruce Steel Erectors</cite.query> Ltd.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id48af6848e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">25</footnote.reference>] a Master granted partial summary judgment in favour of the Plaintiff AFMC against the Defendants relating to two invoices found in the records of Fabricators following its bankruptcy. <eos/><bos/>The Master found that the two personal Defendants had breached their fiduciary duties to Fabricators by misappropriating the contracts and their proceeds with respect to both the Hotel Project and the USBC Project for the benefit of themselves and Industrial. <eos/><bos/>Prasad appealed the Master&apos;s Order as it pertained to himself only.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48af6858e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">26</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Bruce was an officer and director of Fabricators. <eos/><bos/>Prasad was employed as the general manager of Fabricators and was not and never was a director of Fabricators.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48af6868e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">27</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Fabricators had secured contracts for the two projects in March and April of 2014. <eos/><bos/>Due to Fabricators&apos; precarious financial situation, it was not able to purchase steel on credit to complete the two projects. <eos/><bos/>Prasad deposed that he was instructed by Bruce to arrange with the two clients to retroactively switch the contracts from Fabricators to Industrial, with Bruce personally putting up the funds to cover the required steel purchases. <eos/><bos/>That was how Industrial ended up with payment for these two invoices.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48b1d908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">28</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Master essentially treated Prasad and Bruce as if they were the same. <eos/><bos/>However, while Bruce was a director and shareholder of Fabricators, Prasad was neither. <eos/><bos/>While. <eos/><bos/>Bruce was certainly a director and officer of Fabricators and could fairly be said to be a fiduciary, the same was not true of Prasad. <eos/><bos/>Prasad was not a director nor a senior officer of Fabricators, although he was a senior employee. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, under law, since Prasad was not categorically a fiduciary, a determination had to be made as to whether he was an <ital>ad hoc</ital> fiduciary based on being a key employee.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48b1d918e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">29</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Mah observed that there are many cases stating that fiduciary relationships may arise in the employment context and constitute an employee as the fiduciary of the employer. <eos/><bos/>However, an employee can be a senior employee or a critical employee without being a fiduciary. <eos/><bos/>Justice Mah did not decide the point as to whether Prasad was indeed an <ital>ad hoc</ital> fiduciary at Fabricators based on his position as a senior employee. <eos/><bos/>Justice Mah only observed that Prasad was entitled to that analysis. <eos/><bos/>Given the current state of the record, Justice Mah could not say that AFMC had proven all elements of the cause of action of breach of fiduciary duty in respect of Prasad, or that Prasad had no defence or was missing critical elements of proof necessary to maintain the defence that he was not a fiduciary.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48b1d928e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">30</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Mah concluded with respect to Mr. Prasad that an examination of the existing record could not lead to an adjudication and disposition that was fair and just to both AFMC and Prasad; and there were three issues of merit (breach of fiduciary duty, conspiracy and damages) that genuinely required amplification given the conflict in evidence, and this was not a case where AFMC&apos;s claim against Prasad for the value of the two invoices was so compelling that it should be determined summarily.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48b1d938e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">31</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Horizon Entertainment Cargo Ltd. v. Marshall</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id48b1d948e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">32</footnote.reference>] the statement of claim pled that Marshall was a former director of the plaintiff and that Williams was a former officer of the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>Both paragraphs were admitted by the defendants in their statement of defence and counterclaim. <eos/><bos/>Marshall and Williams sought leave to amend their pleading to withdraw those admissions and to specifically plead that neither was a director or officer of the plaintiff nor held himself out to be. <eos/><bos/>Further they sought leave to plead the circumstances by which their names were registered as officers and directors and the steps they took upon discovery of the registration.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48b1d958e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">33</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff conceded that the withdrawal of the admissions raised a triable issue. <eos/><bos/>Horizon alleged that Marshall was its most senior employee in addition to being a director and was responsible for securing and dealing with customers for Horizon, collecting accounts and negotiating fees with subcontractors. <eos/><bos/>He had access to Horizon&apos;s confidential information. <eos/><bos/>Horizon entered into a network arrangement with a company. <eos/><bos/>Horizon pled that Williams was appointed an officer of Horizon during that association, which lasted until November 2011. <eos/><bos/>In this capacity, it was alleged that Williams had confidential information of Horizon. <eos/><bos/>Horizon alleged that the defendants embarked on a scheme to divert the plaintiff&apos;s business opportunities to the corporate defendants. <eos/><bos/>Horizon alleged that Marshall and Williams owed it fiduciary duties as a director and officer, respectively. <eos/><bos/>The withdrawal of the admission that Marshall was a director and Williams an officer raised a triable issue concerning the nature of their duties to the plaintiff.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48b1d968e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">34</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Marshall&apos;s lawyer ordered a corporate search of the plaintiff and it was discovered that Marshall had been listed as a director since January 2011. <eos/><bos/>Starting in late August 2012 Marshall&apos;s lawyer sent demands that Marshall be removed from the corporate filings. <eos/><bos/>It was not until that time that the plaintiff took the position that Marshall was a director. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff ultimately responded that Marshall was a director as he had <begin.quote ID="QT_0008"/>“implicitly consented to be a director by conducting himself as one”<end.quote refid="QT_0008"/>, occupied the position of director regardless of the name attached to the position and was therefore a director for the purposes of the <ital>Ontario Business Corporations Act</ital> until his resignation in January 2012.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48b44a08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">35</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Horizon&apos;s financial consultant filed the Notice of Change adding Marshall and Williams as a director and an officer. <eos/><bos/>He did not seek confirmation from either Marshall or Williams or request a signed resolution confirming the appointment or a signed consent to act. <eos/><bos/>He did not ask to see the minute book.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48b44a18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">36</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>When the plaintiffs&apos; solicitor was suspended from practice in 2016, the defendants retained new counsel who proposed amending the defence so that it corresponded with their instructions to their former solicitor and the position that they had taken since August 2012 that they had never been directors or officers. <eos/><bos/>Plaintiff&apos;s counsel refused to consent to the proposed amendments on that basis that it would suffer prejudice due to the passage of time and the money expended to date.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48b44a28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">37</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Master was satisfied that the defendants did not intend to admit that they were directors and officers of the plaintiff and that there was a reasonable explanation for the admission and its withdrawal. <eos/><bos/>Before the litigation started, in August 2012 Marshall&apos;s lawyer wrote to request that the corporate filings be changed. <eos/><bos/>Within a short time of having filed the defence, Marshall and Williams requested that their lawyer amend the defence to remove those admissions but he did not act on their instructions.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48b44a38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">38</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Master observed that the plaintiff could still argue that Marshall and Williams held themselves out as directors and officers of the plaintiff and had fiduciary duties as key employees and that their conduct left the plaintiff in the position it presently found itself. <eos/><bos/>Indeed, it may still argue that Williams and Marshall were in fact directors and officers. <eos/><bos/>It would just have to prove that allegation in the normal course rather than rely on an admission.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48b44a48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">39</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Horizon argued that it had lost the concession on which its allegation of fiduciary duty was based. <eos/><bos/>There was now a triable issue that Horizon must prove which was conceded before and it was prejudiced as a result. <eos/><bos/>In the Master&apos;s view, this conflated two branches of the test. <eos/><bos/>In order for a party to withdraw an admission, it must demonstrate in each instance that the proposed amendment raises a triable issue. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff in effect argued that the motion should be defeated because the amendment raised a triable issue. <eos/><bos/>If this were a proper interpretation, no motion to withdraw an admission would succeed for to prove the first element (creation of a triable issue) would be to fail on the third (non-compensable prejudice).<eos/><bos/> The raising of a triable issue allows a motion to withdraw an admission to succeed; its existence is not the basis on which the motion should fail.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48b44a58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">40</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Master did not accept the plaintiff&apos;s argument that it may not have continued the litigation absent the admissions. <eos/><bos/>It must have had a basis to allege in the statement of claim that Marshall and Williams were directors and officers and must have been prepared to prove that point on some evidence other than the surprising admission. <eos/><bos/>Prior to the litigation, the plaintiff knew that both Marshall and Williams strongly objected to having been listed as directors and officers of the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>In any event, the withdrawal of these admissions did not preclude the plaintiff from proving that the defendants owed it a fiduciary duty. <eos/><bos/>First, it may still prove that Marshall and Williams were directors and officers by leading whatever evidence it had in hand when it drafted statement of claim making those allegations. <eos/><bos/>Even if the plaintiff could not establish that Marshall and Williams were directors and officers <ital>per se</ital>, it was still open to it to prove that they were fiduciaries.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48b44a68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">41</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id48b6bb08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">42</footnote.reference>] the trial judge concluded that the director-employee did not owe fiduciary obligations to any of the plaintiffs. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs also alleged that Vinall&apos;s misuse of their confidential and proprietary information constituted a breach of his fiduciary duty. <eos/><bos/>However, because the judge concluded that Vinall did not owe fiduciary obligations to the plaintiffs, the judge did not consider the breach of confidentiality claims within that frame of reference.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48b6bb18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">43</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Sateri organization was an international conglomerate consisting of several corporations. <eos/><bos/>One of its chief undertakings was the production of dissolving wood pulp, including a specialty acetate grade. <eos/><bos/>The defendant Vinall was a mechanical and electrical engineer. <eos/><bos/>He accumulated many years of experience in and extensive knowledge about the global pulp and paper industry, including the manufacture of dissolving pulp and the conversion of a conventional mill to a dissolving pulp facility.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48b6bb28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">44</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge observed that the nub of the plaintiffs&apos; complaint was that Vinall&apos;s knowledge about the Thurso Mill as a possible conversion candidate came to him as a fiduciary and was recommended by him to Sateri in that capacity and in breach of the duties of his office, he assisted a third party, Fortress, to acquire that opportunity. <eos/><bos/>In so doing, the plaintiffs alleged that Vinall placed himself in an impermissible conflict between his personal interest and the fiduciary obligations he owed to them.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48b6bb38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">45</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge observed that the corporate opportunity doctrine is a simple label for a complex construct. <eos/><bos/>The gravamen of the wrong and the fundamental basis of liability under the corporate opportunity rubric is that the fiduciary has permitted self-interest for profit to collide with the heightened duties owed by virtue of his or her fiduciary stature. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge also commented upon the parameters of the doctrine, stating:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0009"/>In <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2010223186" w-pub-number="0006459" ID="I3941eec08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Pan Pacific Recycling Inc. v. So</ital>, 2006 BCSC 1337</cite.query>, Sigurdson J. commented that the terminology used in Canaero of a “maturing business opportunity” that the corporation is “actively pursuing”, and the phrase, “ripening business opportunity” used in subsequent cases, are probably misleading insofar as they suggest that fiduciaries are only forbidden from taking opportunities that the corporation is willing and able to pursue. <eos/><bos/>The doctrine has a much wider grasp. <eos/><bos/>Sigurdson J. concluded that for liability to attach, the corporation does not have to establish that but for the fiduciary breach it would have pursued the opportunity and would have made the profit in question. <eos/><bos/>The rigour of the principle referred to by Sigurdson J. was affirmed by the Court of Appeal in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2012444287" w-pub-number="0006458" ID="I3941eec28e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Canadian Metals Exploration Ltd. v. Wiese</ital>, 2007 BCCA 318[Canadian Metals]</cite.query>, which held, at para. 19, that a fiduciary may not make personal use of an opportunity even where the corporation is unable to take it up or has declined to pursue it: see also, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2012388816" w-pub-number="0006489" ID="I3941eec48e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>3464920 Canada Inc. v. Strother</ital>, 2007 SCC 24.<end.quote refid="QT_0009"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id48b6bb48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">46</footnote.reference>]</cite.query></paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge noted that the extent to which the business opportunity must have “matured” is unsettled.<eos/><bos/></paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0010"/>In a case that Mr. Vinall relies on, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2011473123" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3942d9208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Donor Gateway Inc. v. Passero</ital>, 2007 CarswellOnt 724 at para. 14 (Ont S.C.J.)</cite.query>, the court held that the business opportunity had to be a “prize ready for immediate grasping”.<eos/><bos/> However, in Blue Line Hockey Acquisition Co. v. Orca Bay Hockey Ltd. Partnership, 2009 BCCA 34at para. 61, the Court of Appeal, without deciding the issue, postulated:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext>If and when the point is ever argued, then, a Canadian court might well take the view that the appropriation of an opportunity “belonging to” a corporation by a director or former director merit equitable intervention even where the opportunity is not a “mature” one.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0010"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id48b6bb58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">47</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Vinall had been aware of the suitability of the Thurso Mill as a potential conversion mill long before he joined Sateri. <eos/><bos/>In performing his work assignment at Sateri, he learned that Fraser Papers was under creditor protection, a fact that was within the public domain. <eos/><bos/>Vinall regarded Fraser Papers&apos; financial descent as a significant plus in terms of the attractiveness of acquiring the Thurso Mill and was one the reasons he recommended the Thurso Mill to Sateri. the chief strategic decision-maker, were those he expressed at the October 8 Meeting. <eos/><bos/>Vinall was instructed to attend that meeting at the last minute, and not as a decision-maker, but as someone with stock technical knowledge of mills in Canada. <eos/><bos/>During the October 8 Meeting, little more than introductory remarks had been made about the Thurso Mill before Tanoto, the chief strategic decision-maker, halted the discussion by expressing his unqualified and unchallenged rejection of it. <eos/><bos/>It was also significant to the judge that there was an absence of evidence to indicate that Tanoto underwent a change of mind on the matter after the October 8 Meeting or that the plaintiffs subsequently adopted a different stance. <eos/><bos/>The very notion of the Thurso Mill as a candidate for conversion by Sateri was preliminary and superficial. <eos/><bos/>It was essentially over before it began and did not even rise to the threshold of being the subject matter of a considered discussion.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48b92c08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">48</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The evidence about whether the plaintiffs had reached a decision concerning the Thurso Mill was not inconclusive. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge found that with Tanoto&apos;s unequivocal decree of rejection of the Thurso Mill at the outset, it was not even raised as a possible prospect before the board at the Second October Meeting, the subsequent board meeting in December 2009, or ever.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48b92c18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">49</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiffs&apos; primary contention was that there was a <ital>per se</ital> fiduciary relationship between Vinall and Sateri Singapore and Sateri International Co. flowing from his appointment as a director of each. <eos/><bos/>The second ground asserted was that, quite apart from his status as a director, Vinall derived his fiduciary obligations from his role as a senior officer and a member of high-level management in the Sateri enterprise. <eos/><bos/>They submitted that Vinall qualified as a fiduciary under the top management and key employee tests.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48b92c28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">50</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiffs argued that Vinall breached all such fiduciary duties through his secret relationship with Fortress by: a) entering that relationship with the aim of setting up a business that would compete with them; b) assisting Fortress in establishing a competing business while he was still employed by them; c) profiting from the Thurso Mill opportunity that came to his attention by virtue of his position with them; d) using their resources, confidential information and work product in pursuing the Thurso Mill opportunity and providing the same to Fortress; and e) withholding material facts from them regarding both his involvement with Fortress and the nature of the opportunity that he and Fortress were pursuing.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48b92c38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">51</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Vinall was not appointed a director of Sateri Singapore and Sateri International Co. until he signed consents to act as such effective December 26, 2009. <eos/><bos/>At that time, he had been working at Sateri for close to one year. <eos/><bos/>He was never appointed a director of his employer, Sateri Shanghai.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48b92c48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">52</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Several of the specific allegations of breach of fiduciary duty against Vinall pertained to his alleged misconduct that occurred before his first directorship, for example, planting the seeds to appropriate the Thurso Mill opportunity and to secretly compete with his employer. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs conceded that Vinall&apos;s appointments as director did not have any retrospective effect and did not impose fiduciary obligations in the pre-directorship period. <eos/><bos/>With respect to that period (and afterward), the plaintiffs relied on the key employee test and the <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00007" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1987290530" w-pub-number="0005156" ID="I394aef728e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Frame</ital></cite.query> analysis to establish Vinall&apos;s elevated stature of a fiduciary.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48b92c58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">53</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge considered it logical to begin by determining whether Vinall owed fiduciary duties to any of the plaintiffs before he entered into a <ital>per se</ital> fiduciary relationship with Sateri International Co. and Sateri Singapore as a result of being appointed a director.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48b92c68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">54</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Vinall had acquired extensive experience in and knowledge of the operation of conventional and dissolving pulp mills and of the conversion of the former to the latter long before he was hired by Sateri Shanghai. <eos/><bos/>He was recruited by Sateri because of the breadth of his credentials in those areas.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48b92c78e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">55</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Vinall&apos;s position in the organization did not unfold in the manner that he and Sateri executive management had envisaged. <eos/><bos/>The effort required to stabilize and improve the running of the Bahia Mill was considerably more challenging and time-consuming than had been forecast. <eos/><bos/>Vinall had little choice but to continue to concentrate on the day-to-day mill operations long after the initial six month period had elapsed, and even throughout the tenure of his employment. <eos/><bos/>Once the Vinall family relocated to Singapore, Vinall maintained his routine of working roughly three weeks of the month at the Bahia Mill and returning to his family base approximately every fourth week. <eos/><bos/>Substantially all of the business he engaged in while at the Singapore head office pertained to operational issues of the Bahia Mill. There were less than a small handful of exceptions to this. <eos/><bos/>One of them was the short-lived assignment he received in early October 2009 to provide input and collaborate with Li to identify potential mill candidates for conversion.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48bb9d08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">56</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>There was little cogent evidence about the nature of Vinall&apos;s authority over his managers. <eos/><bos/>Despite the fact that they reported directly to him, he was not allowed to make any staff changes in respect of them unless he first obtained approval from head office. <eos/><bos/>He was likewise not entitled to independently hire or terminate other senior employees at the Bahia Mill, or an employee who worked across jurisdictions. <eos/><bos/>The ambit of his authority with respect to the hiring and firing of lower-level staff was also constrained. <eos/><bos/>He was only permitted to fill vacancies at the Bahia Mill in respect of jobs that ranged from entry-level to mid-management, although not for all departments. <eos/><bos/>Even then, he was without authority to increase the overall employee headcount; that decision was reserved for head office management. <eos/><bos/>All decisions pertaining to the salaries and wages of the employees at the Bahia Mill and the plantation were set and controlled by human resources in Shanghai or Singapore, and not by Vinall. <eos/><bos/>He had no involvement in hiring senior staff or management level employees to fill positions at head office or outside the Bahia Mill and plantation.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48bb9d18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">57</footnote.reference>] Vinall&apos;s authority relative to financial matters pertaining to the Bahia Mill and the plantation was also circumscribed. <eos/><bos/>The financial side of the Brazilian operations were managed centrally in Singapore and, the designated financial employee on the ground at the Bahia Mill did not answer or report to Vinall. <eos/><bos/>The monetary ceiling imposed upon Vinall&apos;s entitlement to incur capital expenditures was relatively modest.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48bb9d28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">58</footnote.reference>] Vinall did not collaborate in the making of any higher level financial and economic decisions, for example, how to hedge against marketplace risk relative to any of the plaintiffs or Sateri&apos;s businesses. <eos/><bos/>He did not play a role of any importance in the budgetary process in respect of any of the plaintiffs.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48bb9d38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">59</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge concluded that it had not been shown that Vinall had broad access to financial and strategic confidential information of the nature and import that, if disclosed, left any of the plaintiffs susceptible to material harm or had the potential of significantly impairing their competitive advantage.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48bb9d48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">60</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Vinall&apos;s participation in the identification of mill candidates for conversion to dissolving pulp did not stand as an exception. <eos/><bos/>He was not part of management&apos;s pre-discussions as to whether and why a mill conversion might be a prudent growth mode for the organization. <eos/><bos/>The strategic decision to explore that option as a possibility had already been made by those ranking above Vinall at the executive management level before he became aware of the matter and received instructions to carry out his small part. <eos/><bos/>Vinall&apos;s assignment was simply to compile a list of recommended mill targets in collaboration with others and, on short notice, make a presentation at an early stage of the budgeting process. <eos/><bos/>The assignment was not unique to Vinall. <eos/><bos/>Li, Shaohua and Van Lee had each received similar instructions.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48bb9d58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">61</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Overall, the evidence revealed very little about how any of the plaintiffs might be vulnerable, even in theory, to the exercise of power or discretion granted to Vinall. <eos/><bos/>The Sateri organization followed a classically top-down management model, with a multi-layer hierarchy of management and authority over its various business interests. <eos/><bos/>Although Vinall ran the Bahia Mill, he was not a member of the plaintiffs&apos; upper management empowered to make decisions of consequence with regard to that business operation or any other. <eos/><bos/>Although he was given the impressive title of “President of Upstream” and later “President Specialty Cellulose”, Vinall was not an actual corporate officer of any plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>The restrictions imposed upon his discretion, power, and authority were very much by design and his actions were significantly overseen by the superior ranks of executive management for the purpose and in a manner that effectively safeguarded the plaintiffs&apos; interests and the valuable Bahia Mill. Though Vinall was expected to assume a significantly more enhanced management role once the Bahia Mill was running satisfactorily, that eventuality did not come about. <eos/><bos/>Instead, and despite his impressive title, Vinall&apos;s power and authority remained narrow and highly controlled and his discretion significantly fettered and constrained. <eos/><bos/>Had he been conferred with the extensive and high-level profit and loss power and authority for the upstream operation he had been recruited to do, he may well have owed fiduciary obligations to the plaintiffs, but he had not been.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48be0e08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">62</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>An examination of the nature and scope of the power, authority and discretion delegated to Vinall and his responsibilities with respect to the Bahia Mill, the planation and, more crucially, relative to the plaintiffs showed that Vinall was not imbued with the distinguishing hallmarks of the fiduciary dynamic before he was appointed as a director. <eos/><bos/>He was not vested with the autonomy to exercise his limited delegated power, authority or discretion in a manner that could genuinely direct, affect or alter the legal, economic or vital practical interests of any of the plaintiffs or steer the management of their affairs. <eos/><bos/>He did not undertake to act in an utterly selfless manner so as to elevate him to the stature of a fiduciary. <eos/><bos/>Vinall&apos;s controlled and constrained authority did not leave the plaintiffs in a position of vulnerability.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48be0e18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">63</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Vinall&apos;s conduct was not above reproach. <eos/><bos/>He violated provisions of the Sateri Employment Contract and Declaration and breached his implied contractual duties of fidelity, good faith and loyalty. <eos/><bos/>It was incumbent on the Court to avoid the trap of reading equity backwards by reasoning that, on account of that misconduct, Vinall owed fiduciary duties to the plaintiffs.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48be0e28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">64</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>It was alleged that Vinall&apos;s responsibilities and those of other senior management cut “across multiple companies” in the Sateri “Group”.<eos/><bos/> The trial judge did not accept this evidence as remotely accurate. <eos/><bos/>Nevertheless, the plaintiffs asserted that based on this assertion, the language of the Sateri Employment Contract that linked most of Vinall&apos;s contractual obligations to the wider “Group”, and pursuant to the common employer doctrine, Vinall&apos;s fiduciary obligations were owed to all members of the “Sateri International Group”.<eos/><bos/> In support of their assertion, the plaintiffs relied on the following statement by Stacey Ball in the 1999 edition of <ital>Canadian Employment Law</ital>, adopted by the Ontario Court of Appeal in <ital>Downtown Eatery (1993) Ltd. v. </ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00008" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2001348816" w-pub-number="0005506" ID="I395acdf08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ontario</ital> (2001), 54 O.R. (3d) 161, 2001 CarswellOnt 1680 (Ont. C.A.)</cite.query>, leave to appeal refused [2002] 3 S.C.R. vi (note), <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00009" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2002057095" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I395acdf38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2002 CarswellOnt 246 (S.C.C.)</cite.query>:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0011"/>The courts now recognize that, for purposes of determining the contractual and fiduciary obligations which are owed by employers and employees, an individual can have more than one employer. <eos/><bos/>The courts now regard the employment relationship as more than a matter of form and technical corporate structure. <eos/><bos/>Consequently, the present law states that an individual may be employed by a number of different companies at the same time.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0011"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0012"/>In the 2013 update of Mr. Ball&apos;s text, Canadian Employment Law, loose-leaf (Toronto: Canada Law Book, 2013-) at § 13.30.3(5), he writes:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext>Fiduciary obligations referred to in Canaero have been found to be owed not merely to the employee&apos;s immediate employer, but also to related companies of a corporate employer. <eos/><bos/>Consequently, just as the courts will go behind the corporate veil and find an employee to be employed by a “group enterprise”, fiduciary obligations can be owed to a “corporate group”.<eos/><bos/> This approach is sound in that, since corporate groups can owe employees common law obligations, there is nothing in policy or principle against a fiduciary employee owing obligations which extend beyond the technical employer in appropriate cases.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0012"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id48be0e38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">65</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge was skeptical of the <ital>quid pro quo</ital> reasoning that says simply because related corporate entities can owe duties to an employee of one of their affiliated companies, the employee may, in return, owe fiduciary duties to the corporate group as a whole. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge observed that it would be a most exceptional, even rare, case that would justify finding that an employee owed a fiduciary duty to an affiliated company of the actual employer, solely on the basis of the interrelation between those companies, and where there is an absence of factors that support a fiduciary relationship with the affiliate in the first place. <eos/><bos/>If the employee does not exercise a robust level of unilateral power, authority and discretion over the affiliate&apos;s vital interests and affairs and the affiliate is not vulnerable to the employee, it does not seem equitable to impose a fiduciary duty on that employee as regards the affiliate. <eos/><bos/>In doing so, the so-called fiduciary employee, who is unable to meaningfully participate in the management of the affiliate or influence its affairs, is held to a stringent standard of conduct without being granted any of the powers normally associated with such a burden. <eos/><bos/>The affiliated company thus reaps the benefit of being owed a fiduciary duty without ever assuming the risk of making itself vulnerable to the exercise of the discretion, power and authority of the employee in question. <eos/><bos/>This kind of logic would also allow for a backdoor to create a fiduciary duty where one would not otherwise exist.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48be0e48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">66</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Moreover, and in any event, in order for the doctrine to apply, the employee must first owe fiduciary duties to his or her immediate employer. <eos/><bos/>Only where that threshold exists, would the principle apply in appropriate cases to lift the corporate veil of the other corporations of the corporate group so as to extend the fiduciary employee&apos;s fiduciary obligations beyond the “technical employer” to the wider corporate group. <eos/><bos/>That threshold connection had not been proven in this case.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48c07f08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">67</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Vinall was aware that the Sateri Employment Contract stated he could be appointed a director of any company that fell within the broadly defined Sateri “Group” of companies, and that he was required to accept the appointment. <eos/><bos/>He therefore gave it little thought and assumed that he was being appointed as a mere matter of corporate convenience and expediency. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence to indicate that Mr. Vinall was advised about the appointments in advance or after they were made, or was told what they entailed. <eos/><bos/>He was not provided with any of the documents referred to in the consents. <eos/><bos/>Vinall did not attend an official board meeting of any of the plaintiffs or any Sateri company of which he was made a director. <eos/><bos/>He was not kept informed as to whether any such meetings had been convened, and was not supplied with an agenda or meeting minutes.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48c07f18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">68</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiffs asserted that the law of fiduciary duty does not recognize a nominal, passive or dummy director. <eos/><bos/>Their contention was that, as a matter of law, all directors owe fiduciary duties to their respective corporations.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48c07f28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">69</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge concluded that Vinall was not a fiduciary in relation to the plaintiffs and did not owe them fiduciary duties, under the key employee test. <eos/><bos/>It was to be emphasized that his responsibilities and the nature and ambit of his power, autonomy and discretion did not change after he was appointed a director of Sateri International Co. and Sateri Singapore or the non-plaintiff companies.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48c07f38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">70</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Vinall&apos;s <ital>per se</ital> fiduciary relationship with Sateri International Co. and Sateri Singapore borne out of his directorships of those corporations did not carry the essential characteristics inherent in a fiduciary relationship. <eos/><bos/>The fact that Vinall had little choice under the provisions of the Sateri Employment Contract but to accept those appointments lent support to the finding that he did not enjoy the rank of a true fiduciary. <eos/><bos/>So too did the fact that his job description and work assignments could be determined by his superiors at any time, and that he could be seconded to any of the companies within the “Group” at the pleasure of management. <eos/><bos/>This was an exceptional case of the kind envisaged by Sopinka J. in <ital>Lac Minerals</ital> where the presumption that Vinall&apos;s status as a director imposed fiduciary obligations upon him, had been rebutted by cogent evidence. <eos/><bos/>Vinall&apos;s stature as a director of Sateri International Co. and Sateri Singapore simply did not suffice. <eos/><bos/>In the material timeline Vinall was not in a fiduciary relationship with, and owed no fiduciary obligations to, any of the plaintiffs.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48c07f48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">71</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00010" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2035348352" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I3968b0a18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Dillon v. Dillon Hillstead Melanson C.G.A. Prof.</cite.query> Corp.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id48c07f58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">72</footnote.reference>] DHM commenced an action against Gord Dillon and Mike Dillon for conspiracy to breach fiduciary obligations. <eos/><bos/>Mike Dillon was terminated from his employment with DHM. In addition to being an employee, Mike Dillon was one of the shareholders and directors of DHM. Immediately upon his termination, Mike Dillon took no further role in the operation or management of DHM. In July 2010, Gordon Dillon, a former partner in the predecessor to DHM, came out of retirement and set up a new accounting firm. <eos/><bos/>Shortly after Gord Dillon opened his new firm, a substantial number of clients from DHM switched their business to Gord Dillon&apos;s firm and three former employees of DHM commenced employment at Gord Dillon&apos;s firm. <eos/><bos/>DHM formed the belief that Gord Dillon and Mike Dillon were working together in the new firm.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48c07f68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">73</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>There is an existing cause of action in Saskatchewan for conspiracy to breach fiduciary obligations. <eos/><bos/>The court observed that it was important at the outset to recognize that Gord Dillon owed no fiduciary obligations to DHM. Gord Dillon had not practised accounting for four and one half years at the point when he again began practicing, well beyond the three year term of the restrictive covenant contained in the Withdrawal Agreement and also beyond the reach of any fiduciary obligations owed by Gord Dillon. <eos/><bos/>There were no restrictions of any kind on Gord Dillon re-entering the practice of accounting in Regina, taking clients from DHM or hiring staff away from DHM. Gord Dillon&apos;s only potential liability came from a claim that he conspired with Mike Dillon to breach Mike Dillon&apos;s fiduciary obligation.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48c2f008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">74</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The court first had to determine what fiduciary obligations, if any, were owed by Mike Dillon to DHM. As of June 30, 2010, Mike Dillon was a senior management employee who had been terminated for cause. <eos/><bos/>At the time of his termination, he was also a director of DHM. The court observed that it is well settled that a senior management employee or a director of a corporation owes a fiduciary obligation to his former employer or the corporation he is or was a director of. <eos/><bos/>Mike Dillon was not subject to a non-competition or non-solicitation agreement, but his fiduciary obligations existed even in the absence of such a contract. <eos/><bos/>This fiduciary obligation does not exist only if the employee, officer or director resigns or retires. <eos/><bos/>It may also continue if such a person involuntarily leaves. <eos/><bos/>A fiduciary obligation does not continue, or at least is significantly reduced, if an employee is wrongfully dismissed. <eos/><bos/>The fiduciary duty, however, will continue if the employee is terminated for cause. <eos/><bos/>The continuation of a fiduciary duty upon termination for cause will continue because the former employer is not in breach of the contract of employment or its duties owed to the employee. <eos/><bos/>Such a rule avoids the mischief of an employee who wishes to depart from engaging in behaviour which leaves the employer with no choice but to terminate the employee for cause which would then free the employee to breach his obligations in a manner harmful to the employer. <eos/><bos/>If an employer has acted in good faith and upheld its end of the employment contract, the fiduciary obligation will continue.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48c2f018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">75</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge concluded that Mike Dillon clearly owed a fiduciary obligation to DHM which continued after his termination for cause on June 30, 2010. <eos/><bos/>He was a key management employee and a director of DHM. He had significant responsibilities and access to confidential and important information in these roles. <eos/><bos/>However, not every action taken by Mike Dillon that had a connection to DHM&apos;s former clients, employees of DHM or the operation of Gord Dillon&apos;s new business would result in a breach of Mike Dillon&apos;s fiduciary obligations. <eos/><bos/>While DHM was highly suspicious that Mike Dillon and Gord Dillon were working in concert in an effort to take DHM&apos;s employees and clients, DHM failed to prove any of the following: a. Any contact between Mike Dillon and DHM&apos;s current or former employees after June 30, 2010 and before the former employees commenced working for Gord Dillon; b. Any contact between Mike Dillon and any clients or former clients of DHM between June 30, 2010 and July 1, 2011; c. Any accounting work done for any of DHM&apos;s former clients, or for any other client, by Mike Dillon between June 30, 2010 and July 1, 2011; d. Any solicitation of DHM&apos;s clients by Mike Dillon at any point in time after June 30, 2010, despite over four years having passed since his termination; e. Any communication of any kind between Mike Dillon and Gord Dillon regarding the solicitation of DHM&apos;s clients or enticement of DHM&apos;s employees; f. The provision of any of DHM&apos;s confidential information or client lists from Mike Dillon to Gord Dillon; g. The use of any of DHM&apos;s confidential information or client lists by Mike Dillon or Gord Dillon; and h. Any communications between Mike Dillon and Gord Dillon whereby Gord Dillon induced or encouraged Mike Dillon to breach any agreements or duties with DHM. Accordingly, DHM failed to prove Mike Dillon solicited clients, enticed employees away from DHM, used confidential information or provided confidential information to Gord Dillon. <eos/><bos/>The actions taken by Mike Dillon subsequent to his termination did not constitute a breach of fiduciary obligations. <eos/><bos/>The assistance provided to Gord Dillon in setting up his office in the summer of 2010 did not involve the use of any confidential information or involve activities directly related to any of DHM&apos;s clients. <eos/><bos/>The fact of Mike Dillon subsequently working as a staff accountant for Gord Dillon one year after his termination, using his skills and knowledge to provide accounting services to some of the same clients he serviced at DHM did not constitute a breach of his fiduciary obligation. <eos/><bos/>With regard to the alleged conspiracy, there was no evidence of any communications or plans between Mike Dillon and Gord Dillon for Gord Dillon to use information obtained from Mike Dillon in breach of his fiduciary obligations. <eos/><bos/>There was no breach simply as a result of Gord Dillon taking staff and clients directly from DHM. While the circumstances and timing of Gord Dillon&apos;s new accounting practice coming into existence were suspicious, the setting up of a new office by Gord Dillon, and the exodus of clients and staff, was not, on its own, capable of proving a breach of fiduciary obligations by Mike Dillon.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48c2f028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">76</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge observed that the onus was on DHM to prove the breach, but noted that DHM did not call any of the independent witnesses who had direct knowledge of the activities allegedly engaged in by Mike Dillon and Gord Dillon. <eos/><bos/>None of the three former DHM employees were called as witnesses by DHM to testify about what they observed in the office from July 2010 to July 2011. <eos/><bos/>These witnesses were all well known to DHM, worked on a daily basis in Gord Dillon&apos;s new office and would have been able to provide independent testimony regarding the presence and activities of Mike Dillon in Gord Dillon&apos;s new office, but none of them were called to testify. <eos/><bos/>Likewise, DHM was well aware of the names and addresses of all 70 clients that transferred their business to Gord Dillon&apos;s new firm, but none of them were called to testify. <eos/><bos/>Again, the former clients had no vested interest in the outcome of the matter and could have provided evidence regarding whether or not they were solicited by Mike Dillon. <eos/><bos/>None of DHM&apos;s witnesses had any knowledge of any contact by Mike Dillon with his former clients, any accounting work done by Mike Dillon for those clients or any contact with the staff. <eos/><bos/>The court was left with the uncontradicted evidence of Mike Dillon and Gord Dillon which established the absence of a breach of a fiduciary obligation by Mike Dillon.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48c2f038e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">77</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The defendants in <ital>2261897 <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00011" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2036255273" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I397f1ed18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Ontario Inc. v. Quest Audio Visual</cite.query> Inc.</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id48c2f048e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">78</footnote.reference>] moved for summary judgment on the claim and counterclaim arising from the departure of the defendant Terry from his former employment at the plaintiff Center Stage. <eos/><bos/>Terry had worked in the Audio Visual industry for a number of years and in association with a number of different employers. <eos/><bos/>His expertise was in the field of sales and, over the years, he had developed a “stable” of clients with whom he had a close relationship and who followed him through the various changes in his employment status over several years. <eos/><bos/>Terry&apos;s various employers were in the business of assisting their clients to stage multi-media events such as conferences, presentations and the like, at venues both public and private across the country. <eos/><bos/>While clients in this industry might return repeatedly to a single supplier or relationship, contracts were almost invariably restricted to a single event or project. <eos/><bos/>In August, 2011, Terry left his prior employer and accepted a position as <begin.quote ID="QT_0013"/>“Senior Account Executive/Director of Business Development”<end.quote refid="QT_0013"/> at the plaintiff Center Stage and signed a contract of employment. <eos/><bos/>A significant element in his hire was his ability to bring with him a “book of business” represented by his existing client contacts and his ability to lever his relationship with them and familiarity with their business needs to obtain new business over time. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff was keen to ensure that Terry entered all data from his contacts and events that he worked on with them into their proprietary data base so future use could be made of it. <eos/><bos/>Terry was not paid anything for the relationships he brought with him and the plaintiff sought no assurances regarding Terry&apos;s possible status as a fiduciary from his former employer beyond verifying that there was no non-solicitation agreement in place. <eos/><bos/>Terry&apos;s contract of employment contained a non-solicitation clause. <eos/><bos/>For just over two years, from August, 2011 until November 7, 2013, Terry worked with the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>In October, 2013, a major contract obtained by Terry for the plaintiff with the Bank of Nova Scotia experienced technical difficulties. <eos/><bos/>The client was unhappy and sought certain discounts or credits from the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>In the course of an exchange of emails regarding the matter of the requested discount, a principal of the plaintiff, sent a number of intemperate emails to Terry which virtually dared him to resign. <eos/><bos/>On November 5, 2013, that principal of the plaintiff and Terry had another unpleasant confrontation. <eos/><bos/>On November 7, 2013, Terry wrote to the plaintiff indicating that he was resigning with immediate effect. <eos/><bos/>The next day, Terry commenced work with the defendant Quest under a contract of employment that on its terms was economically superior to the one Terry had with the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>Quest obtained a number of contracts after Terry joined them from six former clients of the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>In no case was there evidence of solicitation of any of these clients by Terry. <eos/><bos/>They were, for the most part, long time contacts of Terry brought with him from when he joined the plaintiff in 2011 or, in one case, a client that a long-time client had recommended him to and who took the initiative of searching out Terry&apos;s new employer.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48c56108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">79</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The court concluded that the plaintiff had no claim for breach of non-solicitation provisions of the Non-Solicitation provisions of the Employment Agreement against either defendant. <eos/><bos/>As drafted, the non-solicitation agreement would potentially prohibit Terry from earning any kind of living in the industry for a year and was manifestly unreasonable. <eos/><bos/>Neither Terry nor a prospective employer would have any basis to know which potential client was included or excluded. <eos/><bos/>A blanket prohibition on dealing with a broad, unknown data base of actual and former customers and clients or prospects of the plaintiff unrelated to actual confidential information pertaining to such customers possessed by the party being restrained is overbroad.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48c56118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">80</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff alleged that Terry was bound by the full range of fiduciary duties which, they claimed, included non-solicitation obligations. <eos/><bos/>The judge was of the view that there was no issue requiring a trial on the matter of whether Terry was a fiduciary. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge noted as follows:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0015"/>D. Brown J., as he then was, conducted a detailed review of the jurisprudence regarding fiduciary duties of departing employees and which types of employees have and have not been found to be subject to fiduciary duties in the case of <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00012" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2012159854" w-pub-number="0006729" ID="I398057508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Boehmer Box L.P. v Ellis Packaging Limited et al</ital>., [2007] O.J. No. 1694</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>Factors which he found to be important in that case included exclusive relationships with customers, the ability to act unilaterally and bind the employer as well as the responsibility of supervising employees. <eos/><bos/>The employee in question in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00013" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2012159854" w-pub-number="0006729" ID="I398057538e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Boehmer</cite.query> was the highest paid employee of the plaintiff, a factor which failed to weigh heavily since the compensation came largely from commissions. <eos/><bos/>The employee was found not to be a fiduciary but rather someone who <begin.quote ID="QT_0014"/>“seemed to perform the classic roles of a good salesperson --- know where the market is, and keep the customer satisfied”<end.quote refid="QT_0014"/>. <eos/><bos/>I find the phrase a particularly apt description of Mr. Terry&apos;s role in the present case.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0015"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id48c56128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">81</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The judge concluded that Terry was not a fiduciary. <eos/><bos/>Terry had no exclusive territory or customers <ital>per se</ital>. <eos/><bos/>Far from being management, he was treated and described by a principal of the plaintiff rather derisively as an employee who had failed to make transition to earn promotion into management. <eos/><bos/>While he certainly bid for contracts from clients and, to that extent, might be said to have “set prices”, he only “set prices” in the way that an estimator on a construction project sets prices. <eos/><bos/>His budgets, invoices and write-downs were subject to review, supervision and approval procedures from above. <eos/><bos/>Expenses on sales calls needed to be pre-approved by his supervisors. <eos/><bos/>He was closely supervised, admonished and disciplined on numerous occasions by a principal of the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>The judge concluded that all of the foregoing was inconsistent with a fiduciary and the very limited evidence of a nominal supervisory role over two other sales people did not alter the picture.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48c56138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">82</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff characterized Terry as the “face” of Center Stage with its clients. <eos/><bos/>The judge concluded that the employment agreement and the evidence told a different tale. <eos/><bos/>The employment agreement obliged him to enter details regarding events <begin.quote ID="QT_0016"/>“to allow Operations to implement the job”<end.quote refid="QT_0016"/>. <eos/><bos/>The evidence was that Terry was not required to be on site for events that he sold as the technical team of the plaintiff were used for that purpose. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff had a number of faces working with clients on events --- Terry was merely the “sales” face for clients he brought to the plaintiff.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48c56148e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">83</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The judge observed that the claim that the defendant was a fiduciary precluded from maintaining any relationship with clients that he brought at no charge to the plaintiff was all the more untenable when coupled with the conclusion that the plaintiff repudiated its agreement with Terry and constructively dismissed him. <eos/><bos/>This fact took Terry&apos;s fact situation out of the fact pattern of all of the cases cited by the plaintiff which involved employees who secretly competed for several years with their employer or who exploited exclusive relationships granted to them by their employer and developed during their employment. <eos/><bos/>As a non-fiduciary, Terry&apos;s obligations as a departing employee were not extensive and there was no evidence that any of these were breached. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence that he took any actual confidential information of any kind with him.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48c7d208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">84</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The judge noted that the duties of a departing fiduciary are not fixed and uniform. <eos/><bos/>Misuse of confidential information to the detriment of its rightful owner, for example, is a frequently cited basis for intervention by the courts. <eos/><bos/>The problem with the plaintiff&apos;s claim was that substantially all of the client relationships that it sought to impose an exclusive protective cloak around via its equitable claims were relationships that the plaintiff had prior to allegedly becoming a fiduciary. <eos/><bos/>This was not a case of sale of a business --- the plaintiff did not buy the goodwill from Terry. <eos/><bos/>He did not possess any confidential information from them since he already possessed it before becoming associated with them. <eos/><bos/>A fiduciary, particularly one whose employment has been terminated, would not have more than the slightest of duties to the employer. <eos/><bos/>Such duties might, for example, extend to a brief period of non-solicitation that might not preclude responding to contacts initiated by the client, and certainly not in cases where there is any suggestion the employer is using the window to defame the former employee. <eos/><bos/>The parties entered into an agreement regarding non-solicitation which by its terms was inapplicable. <eos/><bos/>The court should not impose through fiduciary duties stricter limitations than the parties themselves have bargained for in their contract.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48c7d218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">85</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>If mistaken in characterizing Terry as a non-fiduciary, the court would have nevertheless dismissed the plaintiff&apos;s claims on the basis that the right to call a fiduciary to account is of course a prerogative of the courts of equity and equity has ever required clean hands of its applicants. <eos/><bos/>An employer who constructively dismisses an employee, viciously defamed him both to his new employer and to at least one client while making thinly veiled threats to the new employer is in no position to claim clean hands when it approaches a court of equity for relief in respect of a client list it acquired from that same employee free of charge.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48c7d228e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">86</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Guzzo v. Randazzo</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id48c7d238e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">87</footnote.reference>] the formation of a new local of the Carpenters came into existence by virtue of the efforts of the former employees and members of Local 1110, in particular Randazzo, the former business manager of Local 1110, with the assistance of Carpenters members. <eos/><bos/>Randazzo was alleged to have been in the role of a fiduciary vis-à-vis LiUNA and consequently, given the circumstances of her departure and establishment of a new local, it was alleged she breached her fiduciary duty of loyalty and confidentiality.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48c7d248e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">88</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Section 63(2) of the <ital>Labour Relations Act, 1995</ital>, S.O. 1995, c. 1, provides a mechanism by which employees in a bargaining unit can apply for a declaration that their union to date no longer represents them. <eos/><bos/>This application is to be within the last three months of the prevailing collective agreement. <eos/><bos/>This time of potential union replacement is referred to as the “open period”.<eos/><bos/> If the Ontario Labour Relations Board decides that more than 40 percent of the employees no longer wish to be represented by the existing union, the union is required to direct a representation vote be taken. <eos/><bos/>Coincidentally, another union can apply to be the certified representative, or “bargaining agent”, of the employees in question. <eos/><bos/>This displacement exercise is referred to as “raiding”.<eos/><bos/> The new local proceeded to “raid” the membership of LiUNA based at certain nursing homes/long-term care facilities, during the open period of their collective agreements, which commenced around the time of the formation of the new local. <eos/><bos/>HOPE was initially successful at the four nursing homes and two subsequent units in achieving representation of the workers at those locations with a consequential loss of union memberships payable to LiUNA.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48c7d258e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">89</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>As a result of Randazzo&apos;s efforts, PNFO had come within the LiUNA umbrella as a provisional Local 1110. <eos/><bos/>Randazzo was appointed business manager of the local, which meant that she was a member of the executive board. <eos/><bos/>As a result of the provisional nature of Charter 1110, Randazzo had no cheque signing authority, nor could she employ or dismiss employees or set employment policies or rates of pay. <eos/><bos/>All of these activities required the approval of the executive board. <eos/><bos/>The provisional nature of the Charter meant that in accordance with the LiUNA constitution, that Charter could be revoked, amended, and consolidated without notice of hearing by the International Vice President, Central and Eastern Canada Regional Manager and President of Local 837, Mancinelli. <eos/><bos/>The executive board was not elected as a consequence of the local being provisional. <eos/><bos/>Its members were appointed essentially by Mancinelli.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48c7d268e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">90</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Randazzo received a letter from Mancinelli October 11, 2011 that addressed her as “Acting Business Manager”.<eos/><bos/> Mancinelli was implementing some changes to improve the financial position of the local. <eos/><bos/>This was the first time her own position had been referred to as “acting” and the executive board had been referred to as “advisory”.<eos/><bos/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id48ca4308e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">91</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>As of November 2011, Local 1110 had nine employees, one of whom was Randazzo and another being Guzzo who ultimately replaced Randazzo as “Acting Business Manager”.<eos/><bos/> The largest bargaining units at Local 1110 represented at that time were the four nursing homes known as the four W&apos;s. <eos/><bos/>The “open periods” of the four W&apos;s would be over at the end of 2011. <eos/><bos/>Fearful with respect to her employment, Randazzo started to look for a new union home. <eos/><bos/>The business plan that Randazzo produced and sent to Moszynski set out the various open periods prevailing with respect to certain collective agreements at the time with Local 1110 as the bargaining agent. <eos/><bos/>The principal thrust was to demonstrate how the new local to be formed could “raid” these sites to ensure a financially feasible base. <eos/><bos/>The proposed staffing was set out along with a budget which factored for the various salaries of staff. <eos/><bos/>The plan did not contain any information confidential to LiUNA.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48ca4318e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">92</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>All of the former Local 1110 employees had either cellular phones or laptops utilized by them for fulfilling their employment and for their personal needs. <eos/><bos/>They had received $500 towards the purchase of the laptops. <eos/><bos/>Randazzo believed that the laptop would be hers when she left the employ of Local 1110. <eos/><bos/>The cellphones would have contact numbers with various employees of the bargaining units. <eos/><bos/>It was not until November 14th, 2011 after LiUNA had commenced a motion seeking an injunction that the property was returned to Local 1110 through counsel. <eos/><bos/>It would appear that the defendants had on their computers materials relevant to both unions. <eos/><bos/>Randazzo was emphatic in her testimony that none of the information contained on any device was used during the subsequent campaign. <eos/><bos/>The reason for delay in surrendering the devices was that they were working nonstop on the campaign.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48ca4328e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">93</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge concluded that Randazzo was not a fiduciary and consequently was not liable for damages for breach of fiduciary duties. <eos/><bos/>She was liable for damages arising out of breach of basic employee duties.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48ca4338e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">94</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>As an appointed business manager, Randazzo was required, according to the Uniform District Council Constitution, to perform all of the duties of business manager as if she had been elected. <eos/><bos/>The constitution defined the role of Business Manager. <eos/><bos/>The Business Manager was the representative of the District Counsel and was responsible for the conduct at the local in a manner consistent with the policies of the District Counsel. <eos/><bos/>Randazzo did not conduct negotiations with employers. <eos/><bos/>Section 4 referred to the role of the Business Manager organizing the work within the jurisdiction of the local, and directing and supervising subordinates, with the power to discharge them if necessary. <eos/><bos/>In reality this was not the case. <eos/><bos/>Randazzo could neither hire, fire nor set rates of remuneration; she could only make recommendations to the Executive Board. <eos/><bos/>The constitution of LiUNA revealed a hierarchical structure. <eos/><bos/>The day-to-day activities that Randazzo was involved in included fielding complaints from shop stewards working within the various bargaining units and possibly individual members. <eos/><bos/>She brought forth grievances and liaised with management at times when she felt conflicted when the union had directly or indirectly invested in the management company. <eos/><bos/>She would know the expiration dates of the collective agreements, all of which were in the public domain. <eos/><bos/>Theoretically, it was her responsibility as business manager to be responsible for the day-to-day management of the Union, but Mancinelli oversaw the local. <eos/><bos/>He could profoundly effect the status of the local. <eos/><bos/>He appointed the executive board and the Business Manager. <eos/><bos/>The former he could demote to an advisory board, the latter to an acting business manager. <eos/><bos/>Randazzo&apos;s opinions did not always prevail as illustrated in her seeking an end to the provisional status of the local and being consistently rebuffed, to the extent that she feared for her employment.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48ca4348e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">95</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The indicia to be considered on the issue of whether a former employee was a “key employee”, such that he or she owed a fiduciary duty to their former employer and not to solicit former employer&apos;s customers appear to be geared to the employee as a salesperson. <eos/><bos/>There were some criteria that applied to Randazzo, equating employees in a collective bargaining unit as the “customers”.<eos/><bos/> She certainly would be a primary contact, but given the presence of stewards, presumably she would not necessarily be the only contact. <eos/><bos/>Randazzo would be responsible in a way for servicing these customers in terms of grievances but she would be assisted in that regard by others. <eos/><bos/>There were five servicing representatives and two organizers assigned to the local.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48ca4358e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">96</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge observed that Justice Price in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00014" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034252048" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I398a90808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>John A. Ford &amp; Associates Inc. v. Keegan</ital>, 2014 CarswellOnt 11892, 2014 ONSC 4989</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00015" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035738949" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I398a90838e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2015 CarswellOnt 4418, 2015 ONSC 1747</cite.query>, addressed the vulnerability aspect to be considered when determining whether or not an employee can be considered in a fiduciary relationship with the employer and put forth additional criteria, stating:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0017"/>[191] Additionally, courts have considered the following:<end.quote refid="QT_0017"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0018"/>(a) Whether the employee has scope for the exercise of some discretion or power, can unilaterally exercise that power or discretion so as to effect [sic] the beneficiary&apos;s legal or practical interest;<end.quote refid="QT_0018"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0019"/>(b) Whether the employer is vulnerable to or at the mercy of the employee holding a discretion or power; the employee&apos;s knowledge of customer contact information, needs and preferences, and therefore, an ability to influence customers;<end.quote refid="QT_0019"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0020"/>(c) Whether the employee has “encyclopedic knowledge” of his/her employer&apos;s customers, unrestricted access to all customer lists and information concerning customers, and knowledge of policy issues and personal contact with, and responsibility for, a large portion of customers;<end.quote refid="QT_0020"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0021"/>(d) The employee&apos;s knowledge of the business and market opportunity of the employer or playing a role in the employer&apos;s strategic market development;<end.quote refid="QT_0021"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0022"/>(e) Whether or not the employee&apos;s functions are essential to the employer&apos;s business, therefore rendering the employer vulnerable to the employee&apos;s departure.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0022"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id48ccb408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">97</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Price considered the influence of the employee over the employer. <eos/><bos/>Key personnel or fiduciaries <begin.quote ID="QT_0023"/>“could unilaterally use their authority in a way that would affect their employer&apos;s economic and legal interest. <eos/><bos/>Justice Price noted that the influence must contain the power to direct and guide the affairs of the company. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge concluded that this was not the level of influence Randazzo had. <eos/><bos/>The performance of her job would no doubt have an influence in that the employees of the bargaining units would be happy or not with the representations provided by the local, but that would be the case with any employee providing front line service. <eos/><bos/>Randazzo was not the only face of the Union that the employees in the bargaining unit would see. <eos/><bos/>Mancinelli held considerable and over-riding power through key employees to negate Randazzo&apos;s influence and in fact did so. <eos/><bos/>Randazzo through her contacts and experience over the years had numerous contacts within the workplaces. <eos/><bos/>She was personal and obviously quite dedicated to the members in the units. <eos/><bos/>Because of the quality of her work there would be a loss if she departed but to equate that loss generally with vulnerability on the part of the local would in a way penalize a good worker.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0023"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id48ccb418e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">98</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge further observed that if the employer unfairly changes the nature of the relationship by dismissing or constructively dismissing an employee, the trust relationship is absent and the expectation of mutual self-interest is askew. <eos/><bos/>If the employee was a fiduciary, that individual is relieved of their fiduciary obligations. <eos/><bos/>The individual becomes a regular employee unless of course they accept the terms of the changed employment which in itself has fiduciary overtones. <eos/><bos/>Randazzo could be found to have been “constructively dismissed”.<eos/><bos/> Anyone who is a business manager of a local for over fourteen years would believe their job description had been significantly changed if it was reduced to “an acting” role. <eos/><bos/>This new designation would remove Randazzo even further from an influential role in the union. <eos/><bos/>She had become a “stand in”.<eos/><bos/> It is hard to conceive how Randazzo would be considered a “fiduciary” given her demotion by Mancinelli. <eos/><bos/>In the context of all her circumstances Randazzo was the one who was “vulnerable”.<eos/><bos/> There was an obvious power imbalance in favour of Mancinelli which belied any vulnerability to or dependence upon Randazzo. <eos/><bos/>The categorization of Randazzo as a fiduciary would torture the concept.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48ccb428e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">99</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>However, once the potential for a raid was accepted by the Carpenters and employment was offered, Randazzo was precluded from any steps such as solicitation in furtherance thereof, for the duration of her employment with LiUNA. <eos/><bos/>By not providing LiUNA with any notice, the defendant employees got the jump on Local 1110 in the open period of the 4 W&apos;s. <eos/><bos/>Local 1110 had to scramble to compete. <eos/><bos/>The complete absence of a notice period by the defendant employees was particularly egregious in that it was accompanied by competition “during employment” with LiUNA, their employer. <eos/><bos/>Randazzo&apos;s breach of her duties to exercise good faith and loyalty/fidelity to LiUNA was not of such a magnitude that it elevated her role to that of fiduciary employee, but it should be compensated for by an award of damages. <eos/><bos/>Randazzo was to pay the plaintiffs Local 1110 $15,000.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48ccb438e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">100</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>On appeal in <ital>Guzzo v. Randazzo</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id48cf2508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">101</footnote.reference>] the Appellants submitted that the trial judge erred in not finding that Randazzo was a fiduciary and that she breached that fiduciary duty to Local 1110. <eos/><bos/>They also argued that the damages awarded to be paid by certain Respondents to the Appellants did not reflect the damages caused by their conduct.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48cf2518e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">102</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Appellants argued that the trial judge made a palpable and overriding error in failing to find Randazzo to be a fiduciary. <eos/><bos/>It is undisputed that there exists jurisprudence to support the general conclusion that officers of a union may hold a fiduciary position with respect to the union and its members. <eos/><bos/>To find a fiduciary relationship, what is generally required is evidence of a mutual understanding that one party has relinquished her own self-interest and agreed to act solely on behalf of the other party. <eos/><bos/>Fiduciary obligations tend to be imposed only where one party is, in reality, at the mercy of the other and places total reliance and dependent on the fiduciary. <eos/><bos/>As a result, whether a fiduciary obligation exists must be decided based on the particular circumstances of each case. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge considered that even the fact that an employee may be a key employee or the fact that the employer may be vulnerable are not absolutely determinative of the imposition of a fiduciary relationship and the obligations that flow from that designation. <eos/><bos/>Those are simply two factors among many to be considered. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge made several findings of fact, supported by the evidence, which served to characterize Randazzo&apos;s power and influence over the Appellants as being quite limited. <eos/><bos/>Given the provisional nature of Local 1110&apos;s charter, it could be amended, revoked and consolidated abruptly and without notice. <eos/><bos/>Although the Executive Board tended to agree with any recommendations made by Randazzo it was not obliged to do so. <eos/><bos/>Randazzo had no cheque-signing authority. <eos/><bos/>Although she had employees reporting to her, she could not employ or dismiss employees, set employment policies or rates of pay, or establish budgets without approval of the Executive Board. <eos/><bos/>Randazzo was not directly responsible to the local union membership. <eos/><bos/>In addition, although Randazzo could appoint stewards and was in charge of field representatives, she was not the only contact for Local 1110 bargaining unit members, given the presence of many stewards, service representatives, and organizers. <eos/><bos/>Although Randazzo was knowledgeable as to the provisions of the relevant collective agreements, it was observed that these were public documents. <eos/><bos/>Although she may have been knowledgeable with respect to labour law practices, including the conduct of grievances, such knowledge was neither unique nor proprietary to Local 1110. <eos/><bos/>In contrast, Mancinelli had broad powers concerning Local 1110, and he exercised those powers without much restraint. <eos/><bos/>Mancinelli was the person in control of Local 1110. <eos/><bos/>When the events occurred, Randazzo was its newly-demoted “Acting” Business Manager.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48cf2528e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">103</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Divisional Court did not accept that the fact that the trial judge&apos;s references to the Uniform Constitution of the LIUNA District Council rendered his conclusion that Randazzo was not a fiduciary one that could not be sustained on appeal. <eos/><bos/>In coming to the conclusion that he did the trial judge relied on the powers and roles that the key players actually played in the running of Local 1110, not on how those powers or roles were set out in any particular document. <eos/><bos/>Furthermore, the Divisional Court did not agree that the trial judge reached his conclusion that Randazzo was not a fiduciary purely on the basis that there was someone senior to her or she had a reporting obligation. <eos/><bos/>Rather, the trial judge made findings of fact as to Randazzo&apos;s powers in context and within the particular organization in which such powers could be exercised. <eos/><bos/>The facts as found by the trial judge, amply supported his conclusion that Local 1110 was not at the mercy of, reliant on, or dependent on Randazzo.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48cf2538e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">104</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>As the trial judge noted, what is confidential information is a determination to be made in the context of the circumstances. <eos/><bos/>It must be considered in light of what items a departing employee rightfully may be able to take away from employment which include general skills and knowledge acquired on the job. <eos/><bos/>Although the trial judge found that it would have been preferable for the Defendants to leave all equipment and documents behind when they left, mere possession of these items is not a breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge found that the Appellants were unable to specifically prove what information had been either used or misused, or how. The trial judge also found that Randazzo&apos;s creation of a business plan for the Carpenters, using a report that she had prepared previously for Local 1110 as a guide and using information that was publicly available and not confidential, was only an incident of “precedent usage” and not a breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>In general, the trial judge found that the material said to have been retained by the Defendants lacked any “aura of confidentiality” and was generally available to the public. <eos/><bos/>He made this finding after examining the material in detail and absent a palpable and overriding error, his findings were entitled to deference. <eos/><bos/>The Divisional Court concluded that the findings made were available to the trial judge on the evidence before him.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48cf2548e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">105</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Consbec Inc. v. Walker</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id48cf2558e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">106</footnote.reference>] the trial judge dismissed the majority of Consbec&apos;s claims holding that Peter was not Consbec&apos;s fiduciary and had not breached his common-law duties as an employee. <eos/><bos/>However, the judge held that Peter had failed to give Consbec reasonable notice before terminating his employment and awarded Consbec damages in that regard. <eos/><bos/>In its appeal, Consbec contended that the trial judge committed a number of errors in dismissing Consbec&apos;s claim against Peter for breach of fiduciary duty. <eos/><bos/>In the alternative, Consbec argued that the judge erred in finding that Peter had not breached his common-law duties of confidentiality, good faith, and fidelity he owed as an employee.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48cf2568e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">107</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In 1997, Rick hired Peter to work for Consbec. <eos/><bos/>Initially, Peter worked at Consbec&apos;s head office. <eos/><bos/>In June 1998, Peter went to Moncton, New Brunswick, as manager of the Eastern Division. <eos/><bos/>In May 1999, Consbec opened a Western Division and Peter went to Kamloops, British Columbia to manage that office. <eos/><bos/>The Western Division office was a 5-foot square space in front of a welding shop. <eos/><bos/>The Western Division closed in 2009. <eos/><bos/>Peter did not have a contract of employment with Consbec and his duties and responsibilities were never reduced to writing. <eos/><bos/>Although Consbec sought to portray Peter as a “manager”, the trial judge found that he <begin.quote ID="QT_0025"/>“can best be described as an estimator”<end.quote refid="QT_0025"/>, whose duties were <begin.quote ID="QT_0024"/>“limited to managing his own daily activities of work and sometimes project site management and making arrangements for labour”<end.quote refid="QT_0024"/>. <eos/><bos/>Peter&apos;s role was to solicit blasting and drilling contracts. <eos/><bos/>Peter determined which projects were available to bid on from BC Bid, a website that lists public sector projects that provincial government departments, municipalities, etc. are undertaking. <eos/><bos/>Peter then determined which contractors would likely bid on a particular project and contacted them to determine whether they would like a bid from Consbec. <eos/><bos/>To prepare a bid, Peter found out as much information as he could about a particular job. <eos/><bos/>Peter prepared bids using a Microsoft Excel spreadsheet that Richard had developed for Consbec. <eos/><bos/>Peter provided Richard with the information he obtained about a particular project and Richard used the spreadsheet to independently prepare a bid. <eos/><bos/>Peter and Richard discussed their respective bids and, if necessary, made adjustments. <eos/><bos/>Richard had the final say. <eos/><bos/>Richard was aware of all the bids Peter made. <eos/><bos/>In the event that a formal contract was required after a bid was accepted, that contract was signed at Consbec&apos;s head office. <eos/><bos/>From time to time, Peter signed-off with respect to the hours persons hired for a specific project worked. <eos/><bos/>He sent all payroll and accounting documents to head office. <eos/><bos/>Peter made no corporate decisions, nor was he asked to participate in corporate meetings. <eos/><bos/>He did not have authority to sign Consbec cheques or make electronic transfers or payments from the company&apos;s accounts.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48d19608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">108</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Court of Appeal rejected Consbec&apos;s argument that the trial judge erred in finding that Peter was not a fiduciary. <eos/><bos/>Consbec alleged that contrary to the judge&apos;s finding that Peter was an estimator, Peter was in fact a key employee in whom Consbec placed considerable trust and confidence. <eos/><bos/>Consbec&apos;s arguments amounted to an attempt to have the appellate Court retry the case and make findings of fact that differed from the trial judge&apos;s findings. <eos/><bos/>That is something this Court can do only in limited circumstances. <eos/><bos/>In coming to a conclusion with respect to Peter&apos;s role with Consbec the trial judge made detailed and comprehensive findings. <eos/><bos/>As Consbec&apos;s claim that Peter was a fiduciary was based on a factual matrix it failed to prove at trial, there was no need to discuss the law relating to fiduciaries in detail. <eos/><bos/>On the facts the trial judge found, Peter was not a person whom Consbec entrusted with discretionary powers that could affect Consbec&apos;s interests. <eos/><bos/>Much like Gannon in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00016" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036767826" w-pub-number="0006458" ID="I399eb4c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Zoic Studios B.C. Inc. v. Gannon</ital>, 2015 BCCA 334</cite.query>, at paras. 60-64, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00017" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036767826" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I399eb4c28e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">386 D.L.R. (4th) 662</cite.query>, who was found not to be a fiduciary even though she held the position of <begin.quote ID="QT_0026"/>“executive creative director and visual effects supervisor”<end.quote refid="QT_0026"/>, Peter&apos;s authority was circumscribed and head office made all key decisions regarding the Western Division&apos;s operations.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48d19618e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">109</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge rejected Consbec&apos;s claim that Peter took Consbec&apos;s Excel spreadsheet, took or destroyed Consbec&apos;s client (contact) list, and wiped an office computer clean. <eos/><bos/>The Court of Appeal concluded that Consbec sought to have the appellate Court retry the case and make findings of fact that differed from the trial judge&apos;s findings. <eos/><bos/>For example, Consbec challenged the judge&apos;s finding that Consbec failed to prove Peter took the Excel spreadsheet and used it to compete. <eos/><bos/>In making that finding the judge referred not only to Peter&apos;s denial but also to Consbec&apos;s failure to present any direct evidence that Peter took the spreadsheet or expert evidence to support its allegation that someone took the spreadsheet and wiped a computer clean. <eos/><bos/>In addition, the judge found that Consbec failed to prove even the existence of the contact list it alleged Peter took. <eos/><bos/>In effect, the trial judge found that all that Peter took with him when he left Consbec were the general skills and knowledge he had acquired while working for that company. <eos/><bos/>That is something he was entitled to do.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48d19628e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">110</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Enbridge Gas Distribution Inc. v. Marinaccio</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id48d19638e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">111</footnote.reference>] the motion judge found that Marinaccio owed a fiduciary duty to Enbridge and that he breached his fiduciary duty by secretly profiting at the expense of his employer. <eos/><bos/>A business arrangement was made by Piro and Montaldi with Marinaccio who at the time was an operations supervisor with Enbridge with authority to retain third party contractors and to approve payment of invoices. <eos/><bos/>Piro was a labourer who worked for various companies that did business with Enbridge. <eos/><bos/>Montaldi was an accountant and financial planner. <eos/><bos/>Enbridge often required repair work to be done on properties where Enbridge technicians had done the maintenance work. <eos/><bos/>Piro would register business entities to do the work. <eos/><bos/>Marinaccio would hire contractors to do the work. <eos/><bos/>Montaldi would prepare the invoices to be given to Enbridge. <eos/><bos/>Marinaccio would approve the invoices. <eos/><bos/>Marinaccio, Piro and Montaldi would share the payments from Enbridge in predetermined percentages. <eos/><bos/>Marinaccio had by the time of trial admitted that the entire scheme was a fraud. <eos/><bos/>No work was ever done. <eos/><bos/>All the invoices were phoney.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48d19648e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">112</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Marinaccio had discretionary power both to hire outside contractors for Enbridge and to approve the payment of invoices they submitted. <eos/><bos/>Enbridge was undoubtedly vulnerable to the exercise of that power because Marinaccio used his power to defraud his employer of over $6.5 million over the course of six and a half years. <eos/><bos/>The fact that Marinaccio had the authority, opportunity and ability to perpetrate such a large-scale fraud on his employer over such a prolonged period of time was some evidence that he possessed the hallmarks of a fiduciary duty: discretionary power over a correspondently vulnerable employer.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48d40708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">113</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In upholding this finding, the Court of Appeal cautioned that it should not be taken to signify that many mid-level employees of large corporations will owe a fiduciary duty to their employer. <eos/><bos/>The finding in this case not only rested on its particulars facts but was largely uncontested. <eos/><bos/>If the question whether Marinaccio owed a fiduciary duty to Enbridge had been more vigorously challenged, the motion judge may have taken a different view.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48d40718e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">114</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00018" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2029178457" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I39ab10d18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Movassaghi v. Steels Industrial Products</cite.query> Ltd</ital>.,[<footnote.reference refid="Id48d40728e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">115</footnote.reference>] the court concluded that Dr. Movassaghi owed a fiduciary duty to Gasmaster before and after his departure. <eos/><bos/>Dr. Movassaghi was the general manager of Gasmaster and its key employee regarding all matters relating to the development and application of the RPC technology. <eos/><bos/>There was no question that Dr. Movassaghi was part of the “top management” of Gasmaster even though he was not an officer or director of that company.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A finding of an employee as “key” does not necessarily mean the employee was in a fiduciary capacity to the company.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48d40738e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">116</footnote.reference>] In <ital>Zoic Studios BC Inc. v. Gannon</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id48d40748e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">117</footnote.reference>] the employer was a computer visual effects studio which specialized in feature films, television shows, commercials, video games, advertising and online content. <eos/><bos/>Zoic LA chose willing employees to relocate to Vancouver to set up the office. <eos/><bos/>Two senior employees were chosen including the defendant. <eos/><bos/>In 2008, the employee was elevated to executive creative director. <eos/><bos/>She also held the role of visual effects supervisor. <eos/><bos/>The employee reported directly to Zoic LA.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge concluded that substantively there is little difference between the categorical and principled approach to determining whether an employee is a fiduciary, stating:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0027"/>… It appears the ability of the employee to control the legal or economic interests of the employer is an important function of the fiduciary in both approaches.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0027"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0028"/>In any case, under either approach I cannot find that Ms. Gannon stood in a fiduciary position to Zoic BC. Admittedly, this is a case that comes very close to the line. <eos/><bos/>Had Ms. Gannon had any additional authority I would have concluded that she was in a fiduciary position. <eos/><bos/>As it stands, however, in my view, Ms. Gannon did not rise to that level.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0028"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0029"/>It is not disputed that Ms. Gannon had never occupied the position of an officer or director of Zoic BC. Equally, it is also not disputed that Ms. Gannon was the “top employee” in Zoic BC. This fact alone, however, is not enough to engender a fiduciary relationship between Ms. Gannon and Zoic BC.<end.quote refid="QT_0029"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id48d40758e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">118</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Under either approach, the trial judge could not find that the employee stood in a fiduciary position to the employer. <eos/><bos/>The fact that she was the “top employee” in Zoic BC was not enough to establish a fiduciary relationship between the employee and the employer. <eos/><bos/>The evidence did not support a finding that the employee had the ability to affect her employer&apos;s legal or economic interests, an element that is necessary for both the principled and the categorical approaches to determination of fiduciary status:[<footnote.reference refid="Id48d40768e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">119</footnote.reference>]</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0030"/>In summary, I find that while Ms. Gannon was the top employee in Vancouver, her control and authority of the company was significantly limited by Zoic LA. She had the authority to hire and dismiss, but this was limited to transitional hires. <eos/><bos/>She did not have any sort of authority that could affect the financial or legal interests of Zoic BC. She could not spend more than $1,000 without approval, she could not unilaterally change daily rates charged to clients. <eos/><bos/>She could not contractually bind Zoic BC. Her position did not put Zoic BC in a vulnerable position.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0030"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id48d67808e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">120</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge also observed that the structure of the employer must be viewed in relation to Zoic LA. The employer was a wholly owned subsidiary. <eos/><bos/>It would be artificial to view the structure of the employer on its own, without regard to the guiding influence and oversight of Zoic LA. While the employee may have been the “top employee”, she still answered to the management of Zoic LA. The management of Zoic LA was the top management of both Zoic studios. <eos/><bos/>The control and authority of Zoic BC lay with them. <eos/><bos/>The employee did not have the authority to sign contracts for Zoic BC to provide visual effects to clients. <eos/><bos/>If she did not have the authority to bind Zoic BC to provide the one and only service it was designed to provide, it is difficult to see how she could have guided the interests of Zoic BC in any significant way. <eos/><bos/>While the defendant was the top employee in Vancouver, her control and authority of the company was significantly limited by Zoic LA. She had the authority to hire and dismiss, but this was limited to transitional hires. <eos/><bos/>She did not have any sort of authority that could affect the financial or legal interests of Zoic BC. She could not spend more than $1,000 without approval, she could not unilaterally change daily rates charged to clients. <eos/><bos/>She could not contractually bind Zoic BC. Her position did not put Zoic BC in a vulnerable position.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48d67818e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">121</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>On appeal, the main thrust of the appellant&apos;s position was that the Trial Judge focused almost entirely on whether the employee had the legal authority to bind Zoic BC, and/or whether her authority at Zoic BC was unfettered and that the Trial Judge failed to consider whether the employee exercised discretionary power to affect Zoic BC&apos;s practical interests.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48d67828e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">122</footnote.reference>] In dismissing the ground of appeal relating to breach of fiduciary duty, Justice Chiasson observed that the trial judge examined very thoroughly the authority of the employee, was alive to the law of fiduciary duty and that she considered the effect of the employee&apos;s authority on the interests of Zoic BC. The trial judge made no error of law. <eos/><bos/>Her findings of fact were supported by the evidence.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48d67838e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">123</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Court of Appeal allowed the appeal to the extent only of remitting the matter to the trial judge with the direction that she consider whether an equitable accounting should be ordered arising out of the personal respondents&apos; breach of their duty of fidelity and loyalty by competing with the appellant.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48d67848e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">124</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A key employee is one who generally is responsible for guiding the business affairs of the employer, is involved in the decision-making process or is someone having access to confidential information that if disclosed could impair competitive advantage that the employer enjoys. <eos/><bos/>In <ital>Laplante v. Hennessy-Craibe</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id48d67858e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">125</footnote.reference>] the plaintiff had operated the business of Pascalina&apos;s since 1992. <eos/><bos/>The defendant, a student at Pascalina&apos;s between 1993 and 1995, became a teacher&apos;s aide at Pascalina&apos;s in 1996 and an instructor in 1998. <eos/><bos/>Her duties as an instructor included choreography, choosing and purchasing costumes, as well as choosing hair styles and make-up for recitals and competitions. <eos/><bos/>In 2008 the defendant entered into an employment agreement with Pascalina&apos;s for employment to teach dancing. <eos/><bos/>There was no restrictive covenant in the employment agreement. <eos/><bos/>In 2011 the defendant set up her own dance school business, competing with the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>The court concluded that the defendant&apos;s responsibility for the plaintiff&apos;s business did not come close to the necessary elements required for a key employee as outlined by Richardson J.A. in <ital>Imperial Sheet Metal Ltd. v. Landry</ital>:[<footnote.reference refid="Id48d67868e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">126</footnote.reference>]</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0031"/>74. <eos/><bos/>Richardson J.A. In Imperial Sheet Metal suggested the following non-exhaustive code of necessary elements as to what are the constituent elements for a key employee to attract the fiduciary obligation suggested here by the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>A “key” employee is: (1) an integral and indispensable component of the management team that is responsible for guiding the business affairs of the employer; (2) necessarily involved in the decision-making process; and (3), therefore, has broad access to confidential information that if disclosed would significantly impair the competitive advantages that the former employer enjoyed. <eos/><bos/>These employees fall within the categories: “top management”, “senior management” or “key management”.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0031"/></paratext></para></display.quote><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The fact that several students and instructors followed her to her new business did not in and of itself constitute proof of the plaintiff&apos;s claim that the defendant was a key employee. <eos/><bos/>The defendant returned or destroyed all registration forms and any and all other property of Pascalina&apos;s that she had in her possession.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48d8e908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">127</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Planit Search Inc. v. Mann</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id48d8e918e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">128</footnote.reference>] the fact that Soucy, a “Senior Account Manager” for the plaintiff who did not have persons reporting to him, may have been privy the plaintiff&apos;s databases which might have contained some confidential information regarding candidates or clients to perform his work, did not by itself, mean that Soucy was a fiduciary of the plaintiff.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff was a placement agency which specialized in IT personnel with expertise in enterprise resource planning software. <eos/><bos/>Soucy was a commissioned recruiting contractor. <eos/><bos/>His duties were to post available positions, identify and contact potential employee, set up interviews with possible candidates and place selected candidates in the available positions. <eos/><bos/>In between periods of employment with the plaintiff, Soucy worked as a recruitment contractor for competitors of the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>Soucy now worked for a competitor.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48d8e928e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">129</footnote.reference>] During the 14 years during which the plaintiff had operated, it created a database of about 80,000 IT candidates, being persons with IT expertise mostly in the ERP area. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff also created a database which included approximately 12,000 clients who used IT personnel with the required IT skills. <eos/><bos/>Some of the candidates and clients in the databases had never been involved in any business arrangement with the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>The candidates in the database were better described as candidates and potential future candidates. <eos/><bos/>Likewise, the clients in the database were better described as clients and potential clients. <eos/><bos/>The databases were available to the plaintiff&apos;s employees to help them generate business for the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>After his departure from the plaintiff, Soucy contacted some potential candidates including some which the plaintiff alleged were “its candidates” from the databases and IBM, which the plaintiff alleged was “its client” from the databases, for the purpose of placing employees in the IT area. <eos/><bos/>However, the court concluded that it was not known whether those persons or company were in the plaintiff&apos;s databases or what information there was about them. <eos/><bos/>It was not known if they were actual candidates and clients of the plaintiff or potential candidates or clients. <eos/><bos/>It was not known whether the information regarding them was publicly available or known to competitors in the industry. <eos/><bos/>It was not known whether they had a contract with the plaintiff and, if so, on what terms.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48d8e938e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">130</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The court concluded that there was no evidence that Soucy was in a position to make any managerial or corporate decisions on behalf of the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>He had no discretion to make such decisions on behalf of the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>Given his previous comings and goings at the plaintiff, it was hard to imagine that the plaintiff would consider him a key or high level employee or provide Soucy with any discretionary authority for serious matters. <eos/><bos/>There were no other hallmarks of a fiduciary relationship. <eos/><bos/>There was not an “above-average level of trust” in or responsibility given to Soucy.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48d8e948e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">131</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Future Shop v. Northwest-Atlantic (B.C.)</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id48d8e958e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">132</footnote.reference>] the court, in holding that one of the individual defendants was not a fiduciary, emphasized that the “reality” of the situation did not match the “characterizations” presented in the plaintiff&apos;s materials:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0032"/>Ms. Moseley had, despite her title, no authority to bind Future Shop in relation to real estate transactions. <eos/><bos/>She had no authority to make important decisions, and her spending authority was limited to $5,000.00 without the approval of Gary Patterson. <eos/><bos/>All offers to lease had to be discussed and approved by Patterson before they were issued and all such offers were, in any event, conditional on the President&apos;s approval.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0032"/></paratext></para></display.quote><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Similarly, the absence of a title will not in itself prevent fiduciary level accountability.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48db5a08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">133</footnote.reference>] In <ital>Harris Scientific Products Ltd. v. Araujo</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id48db5a18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">134</footnote.reference>] the court reviewed the defendant&apos;s situation and held that he was not one of the plaintiff&apos;s key employees:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><ital><begin.quote ID="QT_0033"/>Although David Araujo was, historically and overall, a valued employee of Harris, at the time of his dismissal, he did not have the power to put Harris at legal or practical risk.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0033"/></ital></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0034"/>The law establishes that the label of “officer” or “director” is not a mandatory pre-requisite to fiduciary obligations: <ital>Lac Minerals</ital>. <eos/><bos/>The fact that David Araujo was neither an officer nor a director of Harris is clearly not determinative of whether he should be characterized as a key employee. <eos/><bos/>It is also clear that, when assessing the role of a specific employee, the court must take into account the size and nature of the business in addition to the responsibilities of the individual employee. <eos/><bos/>Reminding myself that the law requires the court to examine the content or substance of a relationship and not its form, the court nevertheless concludes that the evidence in this case establishes that Mr. Araujo did not have the scope to unilaterally affect the legal or practical interests of Harris: Mr. Araujo&apos;s work was essentially done at Mr. Spenceley&apos;s direction.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0034"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0035"/>The Harris environment was small; Mr. Araujo was given both a title to better deal with Harris customers and the opportunity of dealing with some of Harris&apos; key contacts. <eos/><bos/>I accept Mr. Araujo&apos;s evidence that the business of Harris was relatively straightforward and easy. <eos/><bos/>The fact that an employee has occasion to meet with an employer&apos;s key contacts does not necessarily mean that the introduced employee becomes a key employee.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0035"/></paratext></para></display.quote><paratext>(Emphasis in original.)<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A fiduciary duty may be imposed on lower level employees, including those with little control or authority, if their functions are essential to the employer&apos;s business, thus rendering them “key personnel”.<eos/><bos/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id48db5a28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">135</footnote.reference>] However, an employee&apos;s sales volumes and the size of sales alone do not reflect a fiduciary duty, but rather the employer&apos;s decision not to protect itself by a restrictive covenant or otherwise.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48db5a38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">136</footnote.reference>] As a general principle, however, an employee unable to “act” independently, <ital>i.e.</ital>, without the approval of another, will not normally be considered a fiduciary.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48db5a48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">137</footnote.reference>] In the right circumstances, even administrative employees may be found to have fiduciary obligations.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48ddcb08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">138</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>It is also necessary to examine the employee&apos;s overall responsibilities with the employer, particularly the degree of control and authority the employee had with respect to the employer&apos;s operations or some part thereof.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48ddcb18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">139</footnote.reference>] <ital>Canadian Aero Service Ltd. v. O&apos;Malley</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id48ddcb28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">140</footnote.reference>] made it clear that the courts will classify those employees who exercise <begin.quote ID="QT_0036"/>“the real influence in directing the corporation”<end.quote refid="QT_0036"/> as fiduciaries.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A number of other factors have also influenced the courts in their determination of whether former employees will be held accountable as fiduciaries, including their remuneration, the influence they had over customers, their knowledge of the business, whether or not they had signing authority, their relation to corporate opportunities and customers, and the length of time they were in their positions.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48ddcb38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">141</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00019" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2029696331" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I39c920218e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Evans v. Sports</cite.query> Corp</ital>.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48ddcb48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">142</footnote.reference>] a sports agent was neither a director nor shareholder of the employer and could not hire or promote any employee. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge upheld his employer&apos;s counterclaim by finding that the sports agent had solicited the employer&apos;s employees and clients and had breached both the restrictive covenant in his employment contract and his fiduciary duty to his former employer.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge rejected the employee&apos;s submission that he was but a minor cog in the employer&apos;s operation noting that the employer entrusted the “Czech-Slovak Pipeline” to the employee for six years, with little or no supervision. <eos/><bos/>With respect to many clients, the employee was the only senior employee they knew and had worked with. <eos/><bos/>The Court of Appeal was satisfied that the evidence disclosed that the employee was the face and voice of the employer in North America for those Czech and Slovak professional hockey clients recruited by Henys and Kadlecek, both of whom were paid by the employer to recruit players on its behalf. <eos/><bos/>The employee was entrusted with primary responsibility for the development of these players, and was expected to and did develop close personal relationships with them. <eos/><bos/>The element of vulnerability is apparent. <eos/><bos/>The Court of Appeal stated:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0037"/>As this court pointed out, however, in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00020" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1996443994" w-pub-number="0006455" ID="I39cb1bf08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Anderson, Smyth &amp; Kelly Custom Brokers Ltd. v. World Wide custom Brokers Ltd, 1996 ABCA 169 at para 15, 39</cite.query> Alta LR (3d) 411, the status of a fiduciary does not emanate from holding corporate office. <eos/><bos/>Rather, it relates to the responsibilities entrusted to an employee, including any attendant power to affect the economic interests of the company. <eos/><bos/>In this case, while the Eastern European market was merely a segment of the overall business operations of TSC, Evans was entrusted with primary responsibility for its successful operation. <eos/><bos/>TSC paid Henys and Kadlecek to find and recruit players who were then turned over to Evans. <eos/><bos/>Evans could then use the power and influence arising from the personal relationship developed with these players, either for the benefit of TSC, or for himself. <eos/><bos/>The great majority of the revenues flowing to Evans and his company, after he left TSC, were from the players originally entrusted to his care by TSC.<end.quote refid="QT_0037"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id48e03c08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">143</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Court of Appeal observed that the situation was akin to the appropriation of a corporate opportunity; namely, players entrusted to the employee to develop on behalf of the employer were diverted to his own benefit.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48e03c18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">144</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Court of Appeal did not subscribe to the view that a termination of employment will automatically relieve a former employee of ongoing fiduciary obligations. <eos/><bos/>It was only after the employee gave notice that he would be departing that the employer required that he immediately leave his office and asserted that it had no further need for his services. <eos/><bos/>While the court did not condone the failure of the employer to make payment for the five-day balance of the term, it was doubtful that the breach to make payment constituted a wrongful dismissal and, in any event, involved no repudiation of the employment contract. <eos/><bos/>In these circumstances, the employer&apos;s relatively minor breach of contract was irrelevant to the employee&apos;s ongoing fiduciary obligations and did not serve to relieve him of them.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id48e03c28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">145</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In analyzing whether an employee is a fiduciary, it is necessary to look to the cumulative effect of all factors that relate to the ability to act and to control the corporation. <eos/><bos/>Making use of the test in <ital>Frame v. Smith</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id48e03c38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">146</footnote.reference>] it must then be asked whether the employee, in exercising the discretion or power he or she had, could unilaterally exercise that power or discretion so as to affect the employer&apos;s interests. <eos/><bos/>Then, most importantly, the employer must demonstrate that it was peculiarly vulnerable to or at the mercy of the former employee.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Jones v. Klassen</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id48e03c48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">147</footnote.reference>] the court held that the plaintiff was in a position of power with the defendant such that he was the “face” of Edward Jones:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0038"/>Within the framework of what Edward Jones offered all its clients, Mr. Klassen had the discretion to make recommendations for purchases, sales, and in essence, all the day-to-day decisions relating to Edward Jones&apos; clients in Mr. Klassen&apos;s territory. <eos/><bos/>Edward Jones&apos; success in that St. Albert office was entirely dependent upon Mr. Klassen&apos;s activities and interaction with the clients of that office. <eos/><bos/>Mr. Klassen argues that because he was just one of 10,000 investment associates of Edward Jones, he was a small fish in the sea. <eos/><bos/>However, he was the very biggest fish — indeed, the <ital>only</ital> fish — in that office.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0038"/></paratext></para><head parent="display.quote"><headtext>…..</headtext></head><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0039"/>Accordingly, in my view it is reasonable to find Mr. Klassen to be in a fiduciary relationship with Edward Jones. <eos/><bos/>He certainly was able to exercise some discretion or power, and exercising that discretion or power affected Edward Jones&apos; legal and practical interests. <eos/><bos/>It is clear Edward Jones was particularly vulnerable to Mr. Klassen&apos;s discretion and power when one considers the contract Edward Jones had him sign before the company educated him and hired him on as one of its investment advisors, and when one considers the steps Edward Jones promptly took to effect damage control when he abruptly abandoned ship.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0039"/></paratext></para></display.quote><paratext>(Emphasis in original.)<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Courts will not reach the conclusion that an employee owes fiduciary obligations lightly. <eos/><bos/><ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00021" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2000668478" w-pub-number="0003986" ID="I39cd3ed18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Firemaster Oilfield Services Ltd. v. Safety Boss (Canada)</cite.query> (1993) Ltd.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id48e03c58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">148</footnote.reference>] provides a good summary of the relevant case law:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0041"/>In my view, it is ludicrous to conclude that Campbell was a beneficiary <begin.quote ID="QT_0040"/>“peculiarly vulnerable to or at the mercy of the fiduciary (Cusson) holding the discretion or power”<end.quote refid="QT_0040"/>. <eos/><bos/>A finding of vulnerability, in my view, would perpetrate manifest unfairness on Cusson. <eos/><bos/>It would put him in the position of having been a mere flunky, just another salesman, totally answerable to Campbell, but tied to Campbell more dramatically than he would have been had a restrictive covenant been negotiated. <eos/><bos/>Put another way, the Court would be taking an ordinary employee, with no power or authority, and making him more because of the nature of his sales job and the location of his assignment. <eos/><bos/>In my view, this is not warranted, when clearly Cusson was not treated as a key employee in any way by Campbell or others prior to his resignation. <eos/><bos/>Further, had a restrictive covenant been negotiated, it would have been subject to the scrutiny of the Court.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0041"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0042"/>In <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00022" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1996449587" w-pub-number="0004655" ID="I39d025008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Physique Health Club Ltd. v. Carlsen</ital> (1996) 193 A.R. 196 (C.A.)</cite.query>; leave refused <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00023" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1997420043" w-pub-number="0006741" ID="I39d025028e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">[1997] S.C.C.A. No. 40</cite.query>, the Court of Appeal of Alberta held that a Court should not use the requirement of notice to impose, through the back door, a quasi-restrictive covenant. <eos/><bos/>In that case, the Court accepted the finding of the trial judge that the employee, Carlsen, was a fiduciary employee but, held that as such he need only have provided six weeks&apos; notice of departure. <eos/><bos/>In my view, the Court&apos;s comments should similarly apply to a characterization of an employee as “key” or otherwise. <eos/><bos/>That is, a Court should be cautious in utilizing this characterization to impose, through the back door, a quasi-restrictive covenant.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0042"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0043"/>In that regard, counsel for the Defendants argues that in an employment context, the Courts have been particularly reluctant to impose fiduciary duties, and the Supreme Court of Canada has made it clear that fiduciary obligations should not be frequently imposed. <eos/><bos/>The fiduciary obligation has been described by the Supreme Court as “the law&apos;s blunt tool” which must be reserved for situations in which there is a real need for the special protection that equity affords: LAC Minerals <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00024" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2001342253" w-pub-number="0006715" w-pinpoint-page="60" ID="I39d94cc18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Ltd. v. International Corona Resources Ltd. (supra) at 60-64</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>That may be overstating the caution referred to by the Supreme Court. <eos/><bos/>However, the need for caution in a situation such as this, of an employee who appears to be similar in terms of function and responsibility to his colleagues and who is not subject to a restrictive covenant is borne out by the following statement of Mr. Justice Paul in Barton Insurance Brokers Ltd. v. Irwin (<cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00025" w-ref-type="ER" w-serial-number="1997420043" w-pub-number="0006741" w-pinpoint-page="88" ID="I39d94cc28e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">supra) at 88</cite.query>:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext>In the case at bar, I am of the respectful view that the conclusions of the learned trial judge were soundly based in law and fact. <eos/><bos/>Absent an enforceable agreement to refrain from soliciting former customers, I am not of the view that any duty, fiduciary or otherwise, should have been found to prevent Ms. Irwin from canvassing former clients. <eos/><bos/>In cases involving activity by key or senior former employees, or by directors in situations disclosing manifest unfairness, such as found in Smith Paper Ltd. [57134 Manitoba Ltd.] or Tree Savers International Ltd., a court may be persuaded to grant injunctive relief or to award damages against former employees. <eos/><bos/>However, the general interest of the public in free competition and the consideration that in general citizens should be free to pursue new opportunities, in my opinion, requires courts to exercise caution in imposing restrictive duties on former employees in less than clear circumstances. <eos/><bos/>Generally speaking, as I noted from the earlier authorities referred to, the law favours the granting of freedom to individuals to pursue economic advantage through mobility in employment. <eos/><bos/>To find liability against the defendants on the facts of this case would, in my view, not be appropriate.<eos/><bos/></paratext></para><para><paratext>In certain circumstances, which I think would be relatively rare, a former employee of less than senior management or directorial status might be found subject to a fiduciary duty for instance—a “key employee” finding might serve to found such a duty. <eos/><bos/>But I do not believe that courts should be easily persuaded to find that ordinary employees would be subject to such continuing duties.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0043"/></paratext></para></display.quote></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0044"/>Clearly, this caution has been exercised by other courts. <eos/><bos/>In <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00026" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1988288252" w-pub-number="0005653" w-pinpoint-page="143" ID="I39dccf308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">RW Hamilton Ltd. v. Aeroquip Corp. (1988), 22 C.P.R. (3d) 135, at 143 (Ont. H.C.J.)</cite.query> Mr. Justice Smith stated:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext>In my view, the approach of the courts has struck a balance between the need for compelling persons who occupy such high positions in the business or corporate world that the law should prevent the few who could easily succumb to the temptation of serving two masters from so doing, and freedom of trade. <eos/><bos/>They should be made to conform to a high standard of ethical behaviour even if by doing so the courts may appear to be encroaching upon the requirements of freedom of trade. <eos/><bos/>Not all managerial positions should lead to the imposition of the very high duty of a trustee lest the law commit a high proportion of employees in this province to slavery.<eos/><bos/></paratext></para><para><paratext>Employers are protected from the faithless actions of top management by the law of trusts and, failing that, in respect of lower level employees by certain elementary rules of decency that will prevent theft of confidential information and of customer lists. <eos/><bos/>Beyond this the law dare not go, preferring that the business community rely on contractual arrangements. <eos/><bos/>This is precisely what the plaintiff did when he later hired Peter Coulen on a contract that included a three-month, non-competition clause.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0044"/></paratext></para></display.quote></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0045"/>I have found Cusson was clearly no more than an ordinary employee. <eos/><bos/>He had no management status or responsibilities, and I have not found any other circumstances to justify the relatively rare finding that he was key. <eos/><bos/>He should be granted the advantage of the law, which, as stated above, favours the granting of freedom to individuals to pursue economic advantage through mobility of employment, in this case, not just for alternative employment, but also to pursue a business opportunity.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0045"/></paratext></para></display.quote><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Id488d3a08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00027" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1973144068" w-pub-number="0005150" w-pinpoint-page="381" ID="I39dd44608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Canadian Aero Service Ltd v. O&apos;Malley</ital> (1973), 40 D.L.R. (3d) 371 at p. 381, [1974] 1 S.C.R. 592</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id488d3a18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>However, where directorships are largely symbolic or for the convenience of the employer, the court may not place as much significance on them: see <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00028" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1999491154" w-pub-number="0006698" ID="I39dd6b718e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cherry Lane Fashion Group (North America) Ltd. v. Stranahan</ital> (1999), 90 A.C.W.S. (3d) 401, [1999] B.C.J. No. 1802 (S.C.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id488fab08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>See, for example, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00029" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1983171968" w-pub-number="0005150" ID="I39de7ce08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Nelson Burns &amp; Co. v. Gratham Industries Ltd.</ital> (1983), 150 D.L.R. (3d) 692, 42 O.R. (2d) 705 (H.C.J.)</cite.query>, <case.history>affd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00030" w-ref-type="ER" w-normalized-cite="30DLR4CA158n" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I39de7ce38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">30 D.L.R. (4th) 158<ital>n</ital>, 55 O.R. (2d) 426<ital>n</ital> (C.A.)</cite.query>, leave to appeal to S.C.C. refused <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00031" w-ref-type="ER" w-normalized-cite="56OR2CA604n" w-pub-number="0005505" ID="I39dea3f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">56 O.R. (2d) 604<ital>n</ital>, 18 O.A.C. 238<ital>n</ital></cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00032" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1978153197" w-pub-number="0005652" ID="I39dea3f38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Empire Stevedores (1973) Ltd. v. Sparringa</ital> (1978), 39 C.P.R. (2d) 177</cite.query>, 19 O.R. (2d) 610<ital>fn</ital> (<case.history>S.C.</case.history>), <case.history>affd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00033" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1978155150" w-pub-number="0005505" ID="I39dea3f58e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">19 O.R. (2d) 610, 4</cite.query> B.L.R. 103 (H.C.J.); <ital>Tomenson Saunders Whitehead Ltd. v. Baird</ital> (1980), 7 C.C.E.L. 176 (Ont. H.C.J.).<eos/><bos/> See also <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00034" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1997421936" w-pub-number="0003986" ID="I39dea3f78e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Suncan Industries Ltd. v. Hefner</ital>, [1998] 7 W.W.R. 40, 162 Sask. R. 29 (Q.B.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00035" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027503053" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I39dea3fa8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Consolidated Compressor Co. v. Northwest Equipment Ltd.</ital>, 2012 CarswellAlta 660, 2012 ABQB 222</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id488fab18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>4</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>See generally, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00036" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1987290530" w-pub-number="0005156" ID="I39df19218e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Frame v Smith, 1987 CanLII 74 (SCC), [1987] 2 SCR 99 at paras 39-42, 42 DLR (4th) 81 (WL)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00037" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036649829" w-pub-number="0006457" ID="I39df19248e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">HRC Tool &amp; Die Mfg Ltd v Naderi, 2015 ABQB 437</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id488fab28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>5</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00038" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048642413" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I39df40308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 1906, 2019 BCSC 1068</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id488fab38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>6</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00039" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048642413" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I39df67408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 1906, 2019 BCSC 1068</cite.query>, at paras. 1-4.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id488fab48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>7</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00040" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048642413" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I39df8e508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 1906, 2019 BCSC 1068</cite.query>, at paras. 6-7.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48921c08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>8</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00041" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048642413" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I39dfb5608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 1906, 2019 BCSC 1068</cite.query>, at paras. 8-10.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48921c18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>9</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00042" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048642413" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I39dfdc708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 1906, 2019 BCSC 1068, at para. 21</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id489e5108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>10</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00043" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048642413" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I39e003808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 1906, 2019 BCSC 1068, at para. 22</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48a81508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>11</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00044" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048642413" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I39e02a908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 1906, 2019 BCSC 1068</cite.query>, at paras. 23-24.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48a81518e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>12</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00045" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048642413" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I39e051a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 1906, 2019 BCSC 1068, at para. 25</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48a81528e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>13</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00046" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048642413" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I39e078b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 1906, 2019 BCSC 1068, at para. 26</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48aa8608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>14</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00047" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048642413" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I39e09fc08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 1906, 2019 BCSC 1068, at para. 27</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48acf708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>15</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00048" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048642413" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I39e0c6d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 1906, 2019 BCSC 1068</cite.query>, at paras. 38-43.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48acf718e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>16</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00049" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048642413" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I39e0ede08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 1906, 2019 BCSC 1068, at para. 44</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48acf728e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>17</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00050" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048642413" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I39e114f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 1906, 2019 BCSC 1068</cite.query>, at paras. 45-49, 52, and 54.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48acf738e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>18</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00051" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043995957" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I39e13c008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>M-I Drilling Fluids Canada, Inc v. Cottle</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 452, 2018 ABQB 143</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48acf748e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>19</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00052" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043995957" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I39e163108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>M-I Drilling Fluids Canada, Inc v. Cottle</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 452, 2018 ABQB 143</cite.query>, at paras. 1 and 3.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48acf758e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>20</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00053" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043995957" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I39e18a208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>M-I Drilling Fluids Canada, Inc v. Cottle</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 452, 2018 ABQB 143</cite.query>, at paras. 25 and 27.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48af6808e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>21</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00054" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043995957" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I39e1b1308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>M-I Drilling Fluids Canada, Inc v. Cottle</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 452, 2018 ABQB 143</cite.query>, at paras. 35-36.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48af6818e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>22</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00055" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043995957" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I39e1d8408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>M-I Drilling Fluids Canada, Inc v. Cottle</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 452, 2018 ABQB 143</cite.query>, at paras. 56, 59, and 61.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48af6828e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>23</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00056" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043995957" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I39e1ff508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>M-I Drilling Fluids Canada, Inc v. Cottle</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 452, 2018 ABQB 143</cite.query>, at paras. 62, 64, and 67-68.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48af6838e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>24</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00057" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043995957" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I39e226608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>M-I Drilling Fluids Canada, Inc v. Cottle</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 452, 2018 ABQB 143</cite.query>, at paras. 71 and 74.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48af6848e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>25</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00058" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044743804" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I39e24d708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Alberta Finance &amp; Mortgage Corporation v. Bruce Steel Erectors Ltd.</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 1134, 2018 ABQB 453</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48af6858e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>26</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00059" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044743804" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I39e274808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Alberta Finance &amp; Mortgage Corporation v. Bruce Steel Erectors Ltd.</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 1134, 2018 ABQB 453</cite.query>, at paras. 1-4.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48af6868e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>27</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00060" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044743804" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I39e29b908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Alberta Finance &amp; Mortgage Corporation v. Bruce Steel Erectors Ltd.</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 1134, 2018 ABQB 453</cite.query>, at paras. 8-9.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48b1d908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>28</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00061" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044743804" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I39e2c2a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Alberta Finance &amp; Mortgage Corporation v. Bruce Steel Erectors Ltd.</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 1134, 2018 ABQB 453, at para.10</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48b1d918e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>29</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00062" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044743804" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I39e2e9b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Alberta Finance &amp; Mortgage Corporation v. Bruce Steel Erectors Ltd.</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 1134, 2018 ABQB 453, at para.19</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48b1d928e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>30</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00063" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044743804" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I39e310c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Alberta Finance &amp; Mortgage Corporation v. Bruce Steel Erectors Ltd.</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 1134, 2018 ABQB 453, at para.22</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48b1d938e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>31</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00064" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044743804" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I39e337d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Alberta Finance &amp; Mortgage Corporation v. Bruce Steel Erectors Ltd.</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 1134, 2018 ABQB 453, at para.28</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48b1d948e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>32</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00065" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225392" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39e35ee08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Horizon Entertainment Cargo Ltd. v. Marshall</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 5009, 2018 ONSC 2097</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48b1d958e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>33</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00066" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225392" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39e35ee38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Horizon Entertainment Cargo Ltd. v. Marshall</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 5009, 2018 ONSC 2097, at para.1</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48b1d968e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>34</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00067" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225392" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39e385f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Horizon Entertainment Cargo Ltd. v. Marshall</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 5009, 2018 ONSC 2097</cite.query>, at paras. 5-6.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48b44a08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>35</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00068" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225392" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39e3ad008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Horizon Entertainment Cargo Ltd. v. Marshall</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 5009, 2018 ONSC 2097, at para.12</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48b44a18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>36</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00069" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225392" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39e3d4108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Horizon Entertainment Cargo Ltd. v. Marshall</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 5009, 2018 ONSC 2097, at para. 14</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48b44a28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>37</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00070" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225392" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39e3fb208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Horizon Entertainment Cargo Ltd. v. Marshall</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 5009, 2018 ONSC 2097, at para. 21</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48b44a38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>38</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00071" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225392" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39e422308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Horizon Entertainment Cargo Ltd. v. Marshall</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 5009, 2018 ONSC 2097, at para. 22</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48b44a48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>39</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00072" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225392" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39e449408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Horizon Entertainment Cargo Ltd. v. Marshall</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 5009, 2018 ONSC 2097, at para. 31</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48b44a58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>40</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00073" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225392" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39e449438e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Horizon Entertainment Cargo Ltd. v. Marshall</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 5009, 2018 ONSC 2097, at para. 32</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48b44a68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>41</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00074" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225392" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39e470508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Horizon Entertainment Cargo Ltd. v. Marshall</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 5009, 2018 ONSC 2097</cite.query>, at paras. 33-34.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48b6bb08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>42</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00075" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I39e497608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48b6bb18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>43</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00076" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225392" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39e4be708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Horizon Entertainment Cargo Ltd. v. Marshall</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 5009, 2018 ONSC 2097, at para. 461</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48b6bb28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>44</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00077" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225392" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39e4e5808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Horizon Entertainment Cargo Ltd. v. Marshall</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 5009, 2018 ONSC 2097</cite.query>, at paras. 3 and 6.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48b6bb38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>45</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00078" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225392" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39e50c908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Horizon Entertainment Cargo Ltd. v. Marshall</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 5009, 2018 ONSC 2097, at para. 317</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48b6bb48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>46</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00079" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225392" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39e533a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Horizon Entertainment Cargo Ltd. v. Marshall</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 5009, 2018 ONSC 2097</cite.query>, at paras. 326-327.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48b6bb58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>47</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00080" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225392" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39e55ab08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Horizon Entertainment Cargo Ltd. v. Marshall</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 5009, 2018 ONSC 2097, at para. 328</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48b92c08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>48</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00081" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225392" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39e581c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Horizon Entertainment Cargo Ltd. v. Marshall</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 5009, 2018 ONSC 2097</cite.query>, at paras. 329, and 333-334.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48b92c18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>49</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00082" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225392" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39e5a8d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Horizon Entertainment Cargo Ltd. v. Marshall</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 5009, 2018 ONSC 2097, at para. 336</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48b92c28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>50</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00083" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225392" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39e5cfe08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Horizon Entertainment Cargo Ltd. v. Marshall</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 5009, 2018 ONSC 2097</cite.query>, at paras. 365-369.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48b92c38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>51</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00084" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225392" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39e5f6f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Horizon Entertainment Cargo Ltd. v. Marshall</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 5009, 2018 ONSC 2097, at para. 373</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48b92c48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>52</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00085" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225392" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39e61e008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Horizon Entertainment Cargo Ltd. v. Marshall</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 5009, 2018 ONSC 2097, at para. 379</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48b92c58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>53</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00086" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225392" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39e645108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Horizon Entertainment Cargo Ltd. v. Marshall</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 5009, 2018 ONSC 2097, at para. 380</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48b92c68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>54</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00087" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225392" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39e66c208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Horizon Entertainment Cargo Ltd. v. Marshall</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 5009, 2018 ONSC 2097, at para. 381</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48b92c78e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>55</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00088" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225392" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39e693308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Horizon Entertainment Cargo Ltd. v. Marshall</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 5009, 2018 ONSC 2097</cite.query>, at paras. 382-383.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48bb9d08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>56</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00089" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225392" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39e6ba408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Horizon Entertainment Cargo Ltd. v. Marshall</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 5009, 2018 ONSC 2097</cite.query>, at paras. 385-386.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48bb9d18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>57</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00090" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225392" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39e6e1508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Horizon Entertainment Cargo Ltd. v. Marshall</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 5009, 2018 ONSC 2097</cite.query>, at paras. 393-394.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48bb9d28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>58</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00091" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225392" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39e708608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Horizon Entertainment Cargo Ltd. v. Marshall</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 5009, 2018 ONSC 2097</cite.query>, at paras. 396-399.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48bb9d38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>59</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00092" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225392" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39e756808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Horizon Entertainment Cargo Ltd. v. Marshall</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 5009, 2018 ONSC 2097</cite.query>, at paras. 400-402.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48bb9d48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>60</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00093" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225392" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39e77d908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Horizon Entertainment Cargo Ltd. v. Marshall</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 5009, 2018 ONSC 2097</cite.query>, at paras. 405-406.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48bb9d58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>61</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00094" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225392" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39e7a4a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Horizon Entertainment Cargo Ltd. v. Marshall</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 5009, 2018 ONSC 2097, at para. 407</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48be0e08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>62</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00095" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225392" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39e7cbb08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Horizon Entertainment Cargo Ltd. v. Marshall</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 5009, 2018 ONSC 2097</cite.query>, at paras. 413-414.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48be0e18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>63</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00096" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225392" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39e7f2c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Horizon Entertainment Cargo Ltd. v. Marshall</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 5009, 2018 ONSC 2097, at para. 415</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48be0e28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>64</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00097" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225392" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39e819d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Horizon Entertainment Cargo Ltd. v. Marshall</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 5009, 2018 ONSC 2097, at para. 416</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48be0e38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>65</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00098" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225392" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39e840e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Horizon Entertainment Cargo Ltd. v. Marshall</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 5009, 2018 ONSC 2097</cite.query>, at paras. 417-419.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48be0e48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>66</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00099" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225392" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39e867f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Horizon Entertainment Cargo Ltd. v. Marshall</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 5009, 2018 ONSC 2097</cite.query>, at paras. 427-428.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48c07f08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>67</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00100" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225392" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39e88f008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Horizon Entertainment Cargo Ltd. v. Marshall</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 5009, 2018 ONSC 2097, at para. 430</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48c07f18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>68</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00101" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225392" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39e8dd208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Horizon Entertainment Cargo Ltd. v. Marshall</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 5009, 2018 ONSC 2097</cite.query>, at paras. 434-436.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48c07f28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>69</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00102" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225392" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39e904308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Horizon Entertainment Cargo Ltd. v. Marshall</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 5009, 2018 ONSC 2097, at para. 437</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48c07f38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>70</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00103" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225392" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39e92b408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Horizon Entertainment Cargo Ltd. v. Marshall</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 5009, 2018 ONSC 2097, at para. 452</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48c07f48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>71</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00104" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044225392" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39e952508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Horizon Entertainment Cargo Ltd. v. Marshall</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 5009, 2018 ONSC 2097</cite.query>, at paras. 453-454.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48c07f58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>72</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00105" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035348352" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I39e979608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Dillon v. Dillon Hillstead Melanson C.G.A. Prof. Corp.</ital>, 2015 CarswellSask 34, 2015 SKQB 18</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48c07f68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>73</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00106" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035348352" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I39e9a0708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Dillon v. Dillon Hillstead Melanson C.G.A. Prof. Corp.</ital>, 2015 CarswellSask 34, 2015 SKQB 18</cite.query>, at paras. 1-3.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48c2f008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>74</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00107" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035348352" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I39e9c7808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Dillon v. Dillon Hillstead Melanson C.G.A. Prof. Corp.</ital>, 2015 CarswellSask 34, 2015 SKQB 18</cite.query>, at paras. 209-210.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48c2f018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>75</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00108" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035348352" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I39e9ee908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Dillon v. Dillon Hillstead Melanson C.G.A. Prof. Corp.</ital>, 2015 CarswellSask 34, 2015 SKQB 18</cite.query>, at paras. 211-216.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48c2f028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>76</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00109" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035348352" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I39ea3cb08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Dillon v. Dillon Hillstead Melanson C.G.A. Prof. Corp.</ital>, 2015 CarswellSask 34, 2015 SKQB 18</cite.query>, at paras. 217, 226-230 and 232.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48c2f038e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>77</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00110" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035348352" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I39ea63c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Dillon v. Dillon Hillstead Melanson C.G.A. Prof. Corp.</ital>, 2015 CarswellSask 34, 2015 SKQB 18</cite.query>, at paras. 233-235.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48c2f048e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>78</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00111" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036255273" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39ea8ad08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2261897 Ontario Inc. v. Quest Audio Visual Inc.</ital> 2015 CarswellOnt 6832, 2015 ONSC 2428 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00112" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037554476" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39ea8ad38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2015 CarswellOnt 16969, 2015 ONSC 6866</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48c56108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>79</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00113" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036255273" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39eab1e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2261897 Ontario Inc. v. Quest Audio Visual Inc.</ital> 2015 CarswellOnt 6832, 2015 ONSC 2428 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00114" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037554476" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39eab1e38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2015 CarswellOnt 16969, 2015 ONSC 6866</cite.query>, at paras. 1, 6-10, 13-14, and 18.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48c56118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>80</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00115" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036255273" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39eb00008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2261897 Ontario Inc. v. Quest Audio Visual Inc.</ital> 2015 CarswellOnt 6832, 2015 ONSC 2428 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00116" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037554476" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39eb00038e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2015 CarswellOnt 16969, 2015 ONSC 6866</cite.query>, at paras. 31-33.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48c56128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>81</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00117" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036255273" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39eb27108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2261897 Ontario Inc. v. Quest Audio Visual Inc.</ital> 2015 CarswellOnt 6832, 2015 ONSC 2428 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00118" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037554476" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39eb27138e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2015 CarswellOnt 16969, 2015 ONSC 6866, at para. 38</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48c56138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>82</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00119" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036255273" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39eb4e208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2261897 Ontario Inc. v. Quest Audio Visual Inc.</ital> 2015 CarswellOnt 6832, 2015 ONSC 2428 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00120" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037554476" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39eb4e238e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2015 CarswellOnt 16969, 2015 ONSC 6866, at para. 39</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48c56148e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>83</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00121" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036255273" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39eb75308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2261897 Ontario Inc. v. Quest Audio Visual Inc.</ital> 2015 CarswellOnt 6832, 2015 ONSC 2428 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00122" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037554476" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39eb75338e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2015 CarswellOnt 16969, 2015 ONSC 6866, at para. 42</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48c7d208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>84</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00123" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036255273" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39ebc3508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2261897 Ontario Inc. v. Quest Audio Visual Inc.</ital> 2015 CarswellOnt 6832, 2015 ONSC 2428 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00124" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037554476" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39ebc3538e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2015 CarswellOnt 16969, 2015 ONSC 6866</cite.query>, at paras. 44-45.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48c7d218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>85</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00125" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036255273" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39ebea608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2261897 Ontario Inc. v. Quest Audio Visual Inc.</ital> 2015 CarswellOnt 6832, 2015 ONSC 2428 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00126" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037554476" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39ebea638e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2015 CarswellOnt 16969, 2015 ONSC 6866, at para. 50</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48c7d228e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>86</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00127" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036255273" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39ec11708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2261897 Ontario Inc. v. Quest Audio Visual Inc.</ital> 2015 CarswellOnt 6832, 2015 ONSC 2428 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00128" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037554476" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39ec11738e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2015 CarswellOnt 16969, 2015 ONSC 6866, at para. 46</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48c7d238e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>87</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00129" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037776888" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39ec38808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Guzzo v. Randazzo</ital>, 2015 CarswellOnt 18762, 2015 ONSC 6936</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00130" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038708043" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39ec38838e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 5965, 2016 ONSC 2588</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48c7d248e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>88</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00131" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037776888" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39ec86a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Guzzo v. Randazzo</ital>, 2015 CarswellOnt 18762, 2015 ONSC 6936</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00132" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038708043" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39ec86a38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 5965, 2016 ONSC 2588</cite.query>, at paras. 1, 3, and 6.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48c7d258e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>89</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00133" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037776888" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39ecadb08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Guzzo v. Randazzo</ital>, 2015 CarswellOnt 18762, 2015 ONSC 6936</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00134" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038708043" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39ecadb38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 5965, 2016 ONSC 2588</cite.query>, at paras. 11-13.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48c7d268e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>90</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00135" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037776888" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39ecfbd08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Guzzo v. Randazzo</ital>, 2015 CarswellOnt 18762, 2015 ONSC 6936</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00136" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038708043" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39ecfbd38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 5965, 2016 ONSC 2588</cite.query>, at paras. 19-21.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48ca4308e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>91</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00137" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037776888" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39ed22e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Guzzo v. Randazzo</ital>, 2015 CarswellOnt 18762, 2015 ONSC 6936</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00138" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038708043" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39ed22e38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 5965, 2016 ONSC 2588</cite.query>, at paras. 29 and 32.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48ca4318e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>92</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00139" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037776888" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39ed71008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Guzzo v. Randazzo</ital>, 2015 CarswellOnt 18762, 2015 ONSC 6936</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00140" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038708043" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39ed71038e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 5965, 2016 ONSC 2588</cite.query>, at paras. 34-36, 39, and 44.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48ca4328e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>93</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00141" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037776888" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39ed98108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Guzzo v. Randazzo</ital>, 2015 CarswellOnt 18762, 2015 ONSC 6936</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00142" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038708043" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39ed98138e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 5965, 2016 ONSC 2588</cite.query>, at paras. 74, 82, and 84.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48ca4338e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>94</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00143" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037776888" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39ede6308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Guzzo v. Randazzo</ital>, 2015 CarswellOnt 18762, 2015 ONSC 6936</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00144" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038708043" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39ede6338e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 5965, 2016 ONSC 2588, at para. 236</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48ca4348e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>95</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00145" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037776888" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39ee0d408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Guzzo v. Randazzo</ital>, 2015 CarswellOnt 18762, 2015 ONSC 6936</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00146" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038708043" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39ee0d438e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 5965, 2016 ONSC 2588</cite.query>, at paras. 120-122, and 124-126.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48ca4358e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>96</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00147" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037776888" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39ee5b608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Guzzo v. Randazzo</ital>, 2015 CarswellOnt 18762, 2015 ONSC 6936</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00148" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038708043" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39ee5b638e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 5965, 2016 ONSC 2588</cite.query>, at paras. 127-128.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48ccb408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>97</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00149" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037776888" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39ee82708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Guzzo v. Randazzo</ital>, 2015 CarswellOnt 18762, 2015 ONSC 6936</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00150" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038708043" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39ee82738e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 5965, 2016 ONSC 2588</cite.query>, at paras. 130-131.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48ccb418e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>98</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00151" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037776888" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39eed0908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Guzzo v. Randazzo</ital>, 2015 CarswellOnt 18762, 2015 ONSC 6936</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00152" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038708043" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39eed0938e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 5965, 2016 ONSC 2588</cite.query>, at paras. 132-133, and 136.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48ccb428e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>99</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00153" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037776888" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39eef7a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Guzzo v. Randazzo</ital>, 2015 CarswellOnt 18762, 2015 ONSC 6936</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00154" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038708043" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39eef7a38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 5965, 2016 ONSC 2588</cite.query>, at paras. 141, 146-147, and 159-160.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48ccb438e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>100</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00155" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037776888" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39ef45c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Guzzo v. Randazzo</ital>, 2015 CarswellOnt 18762, 2015 ONSC 6936</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00156" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038708043" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39ef45c38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 5965, 2016 ONSC 2588</cite.query>, at paras. 184, 210, and 213-214.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48cf2508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>101</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00157" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041971433" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39ef6cd08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Guzzo v. Randazzo</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 9950, 2017 ONSC 1845 (Ont. Div. Ct.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48cf2518e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>102</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00158" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041971433" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39ef93e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Guzzo v. Randazzo</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 9950, 2017 ONSC 1845 (Ont. Div. Ct.)</cite.query>, at paras. 1 and 5.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48cf2528e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>103</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00159" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041971433" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39efbaf08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Guzzo v. Randazzo</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 9950, 2017 ONSC 1845 (Ont. Div. Ct.)</cite.query>, at paras. 61-62, and 65-73.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48cf2538e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>104</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00160" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041971433" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39f009108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Guzzo v. Randazzo</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 9950, 2017 ONSC 1845 (Ont. Div. Ct.)</cite.query>, at paras. 77-78.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48cf2548e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>105</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00161" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041971433" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39f030208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Guzzo v. Randazzo</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 9950, 2017 ONSC 1845 (Ont. Div. Ct.)</cite.query>, at paras. 81-83.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48cf2558e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>106</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00162" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038457254" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I39f057308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Consbec Inc. v. Walker</ital>, 2016 CarswellBC 642, 2016 BCCA 114</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48cf2568e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>107</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00163" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038457254" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I39f07e408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Consbec Inc. v. Walker</ital>, 2016 CarswellBC 642, 2016 BCCA 114</cite.query>, at paras. 4-5.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48d19608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>108</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00164" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038457254" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I39f0a5508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Consbec Inc. v. Walker</ital>, 2016 CarswellBC 642, 2016 BCCA 114</cite.query>, at paras. 10-16.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48d19618e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>109</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00165" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038457254" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I39f0f3708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Consbec Inc. v. Walker</ital>, 2016 CarswellBC 642, 2016 BCCA 114</cite.query>, at paras. 38-42.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48d19628e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>110</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00166" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038457254" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I39f11a808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Consbec Inc. v. Walker</ital>, 2016 CarswellBC 642, 2016 BCCA 114</cite.query>, at paras. 18, 43, 45, and 47.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48d19638e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>111</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00167" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028761358" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39f141908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Enbridge Gas Distribution Inc. v. Marinaccio</ital>, 2012 CarswellOnt 12100, 2012 ONCA 650 (Ont. C.A.)</cite.query>, leave to appeal refused <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00168" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2030440343" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39f141938e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2013 CarswellOnt 4864, 2013 CarswellOnt 4865 (S.C.C.)</cite.query>, leave to appeal refused <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00169" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2030440344" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39f141968e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2013 CarswellOnt 4866, 2013 CarswellOnt 4867 (S.C.C.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48d19648e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>112</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00170" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028761358" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39f18fb08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Enbridge Gas Distribution Inc. v. Marinaccio</ital>, 2012 CarswellOnt 12100, 2012 ONCA 650 (Ont. C.A.)</cite.query>, leave to appeal refused <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00171" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2030440343" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39f18fb38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2013 CarswellOnt 4864, 2013 CarswellOnt 4865 (S.C.C.)</cite.query>, leave to appeal refused <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00172" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2030440344" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39f18fb68e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2013 CarswellOnt 4866, 2013 CarswellOnt 4867 (S.C.C.)</cite.query>, at paras. 2-5.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48d40708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>113</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00173" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028761358" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39f1ddd08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Enbridge Gas Distribution Inc. v. Marinaccio</ital>, 2012 CarswellOnt 12100, 2012 ONCA 650 (Ont. C.A.)</cite.query>, leave to appeal refused <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00174" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2030440343" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39f1ddd38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2013 CarswellOnt 4864, 2013 CarswellOnt 4865 (S.C.C.)</cite.query>, leave to appeal refused <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00175" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2030440344" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39f1ddd68e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2013 CarswellOnt 4866, 2013 CarswellOnt 4867 (S.C.C.)</cite.query>, at paras. 17-19.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48d40718e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>114</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00176" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028761358" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39f2ef408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Enbridge Gas Distribution Inc. v. Marinaccio</ital>, 2012 CarswellOnt 12100, 2012 ONCA 650 (Ont. C.A.)</cite.query>, leave to appeal refused <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00177" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2030440343" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39f2ef438e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2013 CarswellOnt 4864, 2013 CarswellOnt 4865 (S.C.C.)</cite.query>, leave to appeal refused <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00178" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2030440344" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39f2ef468e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2013 CarswellOnt 4866, 2013 CarswellOnt 4867 (S.C.C.)</cite.query>, at para. 20. <eos/><bos/>A trial judge&apos;s or a motion judge&apos;s finding of a fiduciary duty is entitled to significant deference from an appellate court. <eos/><bos/>The motion judge could not be faulted for his brief treatment of the question whether Marinaccio owed a fiduciary duty to Enbridge because that question did not appear to have been a live issue. <eos/><bos/>Although an appellate court has the authority to revisit an issue that was conceded before a motion judge, it should be reluctant to do so. <eos/><bos/>Moreover, even if the court does revisit this issue, the question whether a person owes a fiduciary duty is largely a factual inquiry.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48d40728e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>115</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00179" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2029178457" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I39f33d608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Movassaghi v. Steels Industrial Products Ltd</ital>., 2012 CarswellBC 3513, 2012 BCSC 1663 (B.C. S.C.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00180" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2031955084" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I39f33d638e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2013 CarswellBC 3406, 2013 BCSC 2040</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48d40738e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>116</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00181" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028621307" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I39f38b808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Zoic Studios BC Inc. v. Gannon</ital>, 2012 CarswellBC 2792, 2012 BCSC 1322 (B.C. S.C.)</cite.query>, at para. 98.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48d40748e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>117</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00182" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028621307" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I39f3b2908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Zoic Studios BC Inc. v. Gannon</ital>, 2012 CarswellBC 2792, 2012 BCSC 1322 (B.C. S.C.)</cite.query>, at paras. 3-9.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48d40758e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>118</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00183" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028621307" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I39f3d9a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Zoic Studios BC Inc. v. Gannon</ital>, 2012 CarswellBC 2792, 2012 BCSC 1322 (B.C. S.C.)</cite.query>, at paras. 112-114.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48d40768e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>119</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00184" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028621307" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I39f400b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Zoic Studios BC Inc. v. Gannon</ital>, 2012 CarswellBC 2792, 2012 BCSC 1322 (B.C. S.C.)</cite.query>, at paras. 133-135 and 149-150.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48d67808e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>120</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00185" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028621307" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I39f427c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Zoic Studios BC Inc. v. Gannon</ital>, 2012 CarswellBC 2792, 2012 BCSC 1322 (B.C. S.C.)</cite.query>, at para. 181.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48d67818e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>121</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00186" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028621307" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I39f475e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Zoic Studios BC Inc. v. Gannon</ital>, 2012 CarswellBC 2792, 2012 BCSC 1322 (B.C. S.C.)</cite.query>, at para. 115.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48d67828e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>122</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00187" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036767826" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I39f49cf08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Zoic Studios B.C. Inc. v. Gannon</ital>, 2015 CarswellBC 2077, 2015 BCCA 334, at para. 61</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48d67838e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>123</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00188" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036767826" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I39f49cf38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Zoic Studios B.C. Inc. v. Gannon</ital>, 2015 CarswellBC 2077, 2015 BCCA 334, at para. 62</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48d67848e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>124</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00189" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036767826" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I39f4c4008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Zoic Studios B.C. Inc. v. Gannon</ital>, 2015 CarswellBC 2077, 2015 BCCA 334, at para. 91</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48d67858e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>125</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00190" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026261395" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39f4eb108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Laplante v. Hennessy-Craibe</ital>, 2011 CarswellOnt 10270, 2011 ONSC 5601</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48d67868e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>126</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00191" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2012535541" w-pub-number="0005474" ID="I39f512208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Imperial Sheet Metal Ltd. v. Landry</ital>, 2007 CarswellNB 298, 2007 NBCA 51</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48d8e908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>127</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00192" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026261395" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39f539308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Laplante v. Hennessy-Craibe</ital>, 2011 CarswellOnt 10270, 2011 ONSC 5601</cite.query>, at paras. 2-3, 5, 18, 21, 23, 28.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48d8e918e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>128</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00193" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2031914048" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39f560408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Planit Search Inc. v. Mann</ital>, 2013 CarswellOnt 15233, 2013 ONSC 6847</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48d8e928e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>129</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00194" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2031914048" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39f5ae608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Planit Search Inc. v. Mann</ital>, 2013 CarswellOnt 15233, 2013 ONSC 6847</cite.query>, at paras. 2-3, 7 and 35.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48d8e938e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>130</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00195" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2031914048" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39f5d5708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Planit Search Inc. v. Mann</ital>, 2013 CarswellOnt 15233, 2013 ONSC 6847</cite.query>, at paras. 10-11, 14-15 and 22-23.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48d8e948e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>131</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00196" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2031914048" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39f5fc808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Planit Search Inc. v. Mann</ital>, 2013 CarswellOnt 15233, 2013 ONSC 6847</cite.query>, at paras. 32-34.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48d8e958e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>132</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>Future Shop v. Northwest-Atlantic (B.C.)</ital> (2000), 2 C.P.C. (5th) 358 (B.C.S.C.) at para. 50.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48db5a08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>133</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00197" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1983169894" w-pub-number="0005161" ID="I39f75c108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Hawboldt Industries Ltd. v. Chester Basin Hydraulics &amp; Machine Ltd.</ital> (1983), 57 N.S.R. (2d) 413, 22</cite.query> B.L.R. 215 (<case.history>S.C.</case.history>).<eos/><bos/> See also, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00198" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2001342253" w-pub-number="0006715" ID="I39f75c128e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Crossdock International Inc. v. Turner-Lander</ital>, [2001] M.J. No. 21 (Q.B.)</cite.query>, vard <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00199" w-ref-type="ER" w-normalized-cite="2001MJNOCA529" w-pub-number="0006715" ID="I39f75c148e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">[2001] M.J. No. 529 (C.A.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00200" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1998460163" w-pub-number="0003986" ID="I39f75c168e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Polar Bear Rubber Ltd. v. Brothers Industrial Supply Ltd.,</ital> [1999] 1 W.W.R. 522, 128 Man. R. (2d) 105 (Q.B.)</cite.query>, <case.history>affd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00201" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1998468800" w-pub-number="0003986" ID="I39f75c198e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">[1999] 7 W.W.R. 633, 131 Man. R. (2d) 292, 187 W.A.C. 292 (C.A.)</cite.query> and <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00202" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1997414597" w-pub-number="0003986" ID="I39f783208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EII Ltd. v. Dutko,</ital> [1998] 2 W.W.R. 597, 119 Man. R. (2d) 178</cite.query> <ital>sub nom. Gerrard-Ovalstrapping v. Dutko</ital> (Q.B.).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48db5a18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>134</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>Harris Scientific Products Ltd. v. Araujo</ital> (2005), 54 Alta. L.R. (4th) 195 (Q.B.), at paras. 59-61.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48db5a28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>135</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00203" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1997419731" w-pub-number="0003986" ID="I39f9cd108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Provincial Plating Ltd. v. Steinkey</ital>, [1998] 3 W.W.R. 1, 162 Sask. R. 241 (Q.B.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00204" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1984194367" w-pub-number="0005160" ID="I39f9cd138e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Merlo v. Demarco Agencies Ltd</ital>. (1984), 48 Nfld. &amp; P.E.I.R. 227, 2 C.P.R. (3d) 205 (Nfld. Dist. Ct.)</cite.query>, vard <case.history>on other grounds</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00205" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1987295135" w-pub-number="0005160" ID="I39f9cd168e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">62 Nfld. &amp; P.E.I.R. 248, 22 C.P.R. (3d) 74 (Nfld. C.A.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00206" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1997414597" w-pub-number="0003986" ID="I39f9cd198e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EII Ltd. v. Dutko</ital>, [1998] 2 W.W.R. 597, 119 Man. R. (2d) 178</cite.query> <ital>sub nom. Gerrard-Ovalstrapping v. Dutko</ital> (Q.B.).<eos/><bos/> For a summary of five cases that have held non-management employees to owe fiduciary obligations and five cases reaching the opposite conclusion, see <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00207" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2012159854" w-pub-number="0005628" ID="I39f9cd1c8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Boehmer Box L.P. v. Ellis Packaging Ltd.</ital>, 2007 C.L.L.C. ¶ 210-025 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 46-47. <eos/><bos/>See also <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00208" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2014759958" w-pub-number="0005158" ID="I39f9cd1e8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Brunswick News Inc. v. Langdon</ital> (2007), 334 N.B.R. (2d) 273 (Q.B.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00209" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2015305503" w-pub-number="0007214" ID="I39f9cd208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Road Trailer Rentals Inc. v. Robinson</ital> (2008), 43 B.L.R. (4th) 305 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00210" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027308870" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I39f9cd228e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>ADM Measurements Ltd. v. Bullet Electric Ltd.</ital>, 2012 CarswellAlta 302, 2012 ABQB 150</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48db5a38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>136</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00211" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1997419731" w-pub-number="0003986" ID="I39fa69508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Provincial Plating Ltd. v. Steinkey</ital>, [1998] 3 W.W.R. 1, 162 Sask. R. 241 (Q.B.)</cite.query> (<ital>obiter</ital>).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48db5a48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>137</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>See for example, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00212" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1991346479" w-pub-number="0005653" ID="I39fb05918e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Crain-Drummond Inc. v. Hamel</ital></cite.query> (1991), 35 C.C.E.L. 55, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00213" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1991346479" w-pub-number="0005653" ID="I39fb05928e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">36 C.P.R. (3d) 151</cite.query> (Ont. Ct. (Gen. Div.)), <case.history>affd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00214" w-ref-type="ER" w-normalized-cite="36CPR3CA163n" w-pub-number="0005653" ID="I39fb05948e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">36 C.P.R. (3d) 163<ital>n</ital></cite.query> (Ont. (Div. Ct.)).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48ddcb08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>138</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>See <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00215" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2012849741" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I39fc17018e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>South Nahanni Trading Co. v. Gravel</ital></cite.query> (2007), 63 C.B.R. (5th) 115, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00216" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2012849741" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I39fc17028e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">159 A.C.W.S. (3d) 325</cite.query> (Ont. S.C.J. (Comm. List)); <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00217" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2021772243" w-pub-number="0006459" ID="I39fc17058e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Procon Mining &amp; Tunnelling Ltd. v. McNeil</ital> (2010), 187 A.C.W.S. (3d) 1023, 2010 BCSC 487</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00218" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2022802265" w-pub-number="0006459" ID="I39fc17078e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2010 BCSC 1151</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00219" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2023370445" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I39fc17098e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2010 CarswellBC 2727, 2010 BCSC 1435</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48ddcb18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>139</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>57134 Manitoba Ltd. v. Palmer</ital> (1985), 65 B.C.L.R. 355, 30 B.L.R. 121 (S.C.), supp. reasons 67 B.C.L.R. 100, 5 C.P.C. (2d) 155 (S.C.), affd 37 B.C.L.R. (2d) 50, 44 B.L.R. 94 (C.A.); <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00220" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1977148370" w-pub-number="0005150" ID="I39fe88008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgar T. Alberts Ltd. v. Mountjoy</ital> (1977), 79 D.L.R. (3d) 108, 16 O.R. (2d) 682 (H.C.J.)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>See also, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00221" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1994406465" w-pub-number="0005506" ID="I39fe88038e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Canadian Industrial Distributors Inc. v. Drague</ital> (1994), 20 O.R. (3d) 574, 7</cite.query> C.C.E.L. (2d) 60, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00222" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1994406465" w-pub-number="0005653" ID="I39fe88058e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">58 C.P.R. (3d) 22 (Gen. Div.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00223" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2000543131" w-pub-number="0005628" ID="I39fe88088e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sanford Evans List Brokerage v. Trauzzi</ital></cite.query> (2000), 50 C.C.E.L. (2d) 105, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00224" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2000543131" w-pub-number="0005628" ID="I39fe88098e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2000 C.L.L.C. ¶ 210-020 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>; and <ital>Edac Inc. v. Tullo</ital> (1999), 47 C.C.E.L. (2d) 264 (Ont. S.C.J.).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48ddcb28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>140</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00225" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1973144068" w-pub-number="0005150" ID="I39ff72608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Canadian Aero Service Ltd. v. O&apos;Malley</ital> (1973), 40 D.L.R. (3d) 371, [1974] 1 S.C.R. 592</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>See <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00226" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2000543131" w-pub-number="0005628" ID="I39ff72648e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sanford Evans List Brokerage v. Trauzzi</ital></cite.query> (2000), 50 C.C.E.L. (2d) 105, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00227" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2000543131" w-pub-number="0005628" ID="I39ff72658e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2000 C.L.L.C. ¶ 210-020 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48ddcb38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>141</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>See for example the review of these issues in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00228" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1997408537" w-pub-number="0004655" w-pinpoint-page="26" ID="I39ffc0808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>CRC-Evans Canada Ltd. v. Pettifer</ital> (1997), 197 A.R. 24, 26</cite.query> C.C.E.L. (2d) 294 (Q.B.), <case.history>affd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00229" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1998458913" w-pub-number="0004655" ID="I39ffc0828e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">216 A.R. 192, 175 W.A.C. 192 (C.A.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00230" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027253060" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39ffc0858e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>GasTOPS Ltd. v. Forsyth</ital>, 2012 CarswellOnt 2539, 2012 ONCA 134</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00231" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2023458724" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39ffc0888e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Zesta Engineering Ltd. v. Cloutier</ital>, 2010 CarswellOnt 7953, 2010 ONSC 5810</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00232" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2029685095" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I39ffc08b8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2013 CarswellOnt 410, 2013 ONSC 385</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00233" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027503053" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I39ffc08e8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Consolidated Compressor Co. v. Northwest Equipment Ltd.</ital>, 2012 CarswellAlta 660, 2012 ABQB 222</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00234" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1996449587" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I39ffc0918e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Physique Health Club Ltd. v. Carlsen</ital>, 1996 CarswellAlta 958, (Alta. C.A.)</cite.query>, reconsideration / <case.history>rehearing refused</case.history>, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00235" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1997420004" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I39ffc0938e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">1997 CarswellAlta 1014 (Alta. C.A.)</cite.query>, leave to appeal refused <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00236" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1997420043" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I39ffc0958e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">1997 CarswellAlta 1287 (S.C.C.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48ddcb48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>142</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00237" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2029696331" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3a0035b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Evans v. Sports Corp.</ital>, 2013 CarswellAlta 19, 2013 ABCA 14 (Alta. C.A.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48e03c08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>143</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00238" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2029696331" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3a005cc08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Evans v. Sports Corp.</ital>, 2013 CarswellAlta 19, 2013 ABCA 14 (Alta. C.A.)</cite.query>, at paras. 32-34.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48e03c18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>144</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00239" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2029696331" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3a00aae08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Evans v. Sports Corp.</ital>, 2013 CarswellAlta 19, 2013 ABCA 14 (Alta. C.A.)</cite.query>, at para. 35.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48e03c28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>145</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00240" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2029696331" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3a00d1f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Evans v. Sports Corp.</ital>, 2013 CarswellAlta 19, 2013 ABCA 14 (Alta. C.A.)</cite.query>, at paras. 36-37; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00241" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027308870" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3a00d1f38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>ADM Measurements Ltd. v. Bullet Electric Ltd.</ital>, 2012 CarswellAlta 302, 2012 ABQB 150</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48e03c38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>146</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00242" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1987290530" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I3a00f9008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Frame v. Smith</ital> (1987), 42 D.L.R. (4th) 81, [1987] 2 S.C.R. 99</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48e03c48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>147</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>Jones v. Klassen</ital> (2006), 55 Alta. L.R. (4th) 354 (Q.B.), at paras. 42 and 44.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id48e03c58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>148</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00243" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2000668478" w-pub-number="0003986" ID="I3a0258908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Firemaster Oilfield Services Ltd. v. Safety Boss (Canada) (1993) Ltd.</ital>, [2001] 4 W.W.R. 256 (Alta. Q.B.)</cite.query> at paras. 45-49. <eos/><bos/>See also <ital>Unified Freight Services Ltd. v. Therriault</ital> (2006), 57 Alta. L.R. (4th) 358 (Q.B.), at paras. 52-65; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00244" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027503053" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3a0258928e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Consolidated Compressor Co. v. Northwest Equipment Ltd.</ital>, 2012 CarswellAlta 660, 2012 ABQB 222</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175880" w-seq-number="00245" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2012367641" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3a0258958e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Torcana Valve Services Inc. v. Anderson</ital>, 2007 CarswellAlta 693, 2007 ABQB 356</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 4:26<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
