<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 4:46<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I5089a870411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>4.</label.designator><headtext>Confidential Business Information and the Employment Relationship</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I52517020411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>V.</label.designator><headtext>Fiduciary Duty</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I53a16fc0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>B.</label.designator><headtext>Remedies Table—Employment Relationship—Breach of Fiduciary Duty</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f65f616ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>4:46.</label.designator><headtext>M.A. Concrete Ltd. v. Truter</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><ital>M.A. Concrete Ltd. v. Truter</ital>, 2015 CarswellBC 377, 2015 BCSC 229, additional reasons 2015 CarswellBC 1345, 2015 BCSC 829, reversed 2016 CarswellBC 803, 2016 BCCA 138, leave to appeal refused 2016 CarswellBC 3091 (S.C.C.), affirmed 2016 CarswellBC 803, 2016 BCCA 138</headtext><eos/><eop/></head><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Award</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff was entitled to an order against the defendants for the following damages arising from the defendant&apos;s breach of fiduciary duty: (1) for loss of opportunity on jobs for which it would have used CGC product, but was not in a position to undertake or perform due to CGC credit restrictions, and postponement of repairs to the large pump due to financial constraints, the amount of $20,000 ($5,000 per month for four months); (2) $12,049.71 for expenses charged to the plaintiff by the defendant and her corporation in connection with the Rosa Project; (3) $32,245, being the profit earned by the defendant&apos;s corporation on the non-Rosa projects involving Quik-Top and decorative concrete; and (4) $7,925 being the amount invoiced by the plaintiff to Smart Surface for the sale to it of Quik-Top, which was purchased from and invoiced by CGC to the plaintiff and paid for by the plaintiff.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Summary of Facts:</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff was a company in the business of installing concrete and gypsum underlayment of floors. <eos/><bos/>The defendant by counterclaim Schwartz purchased the plaintiff as a going concern in 1989. <eos/><bos/>The defendant and Schwartz entered into a Joint Venture Agreement, with Option to Purchase, the terms of which provided that the defendant and her corporation would pay a non-refundable deposit amount of $100,000 for the option to purchase the plaintiff within two years at a price of $1,400,000. <eos/><bos/>The defendant and the plaintiff agreed to collaboratively develop the plaintiff&apos;s business during the JVA period. <eos/><bos/>The discussions between the parties surrounding the purchase continued into early 2011. <eos/><bos/>The defendant and Schwartz reached an agreement on “Proposal Elements” and an “Agreement Summary” which set out the basis for an agreement for the sale of the plaintiff to the defendant, which sale the parties intended to finalize and implement by May 1, 2011. <eos/><bos/>In April 2011, the defendant made an initial deposit of $50,000 into a new bank account for the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>Both parties had signing authority but it was understood between them that the defendant would operate the account and Schwartz would have online access to view the bank statements. <eos/><bos/>The defendant was to deposit all customer payments into the new operating account and to pay all of MAC&apos;s expenses related to the business operation after May 1, 2011. <eos/><bos/>On May 1, 2011, the defendant took over the day-to-day business operations of the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>Between this date and December 2011, the defendant operated the plaintiff&apos;s operations as if she had already had completed her purchase of the business. <eos/><bos/>On December 28, 2011, the defendant without informing Schwartz decided not to proceed with her purchase. <eos/><bos/>Moreover, the defendant withdrew all of the remaining funds in the new operating account. <eos/><bos/>The defendant had not kept a formal record of her advances to the plaintiff during the time that she was managing it, and had not at the time of her departure actually reconciled the amount she and her corporation were owed. <eos/><bos/>However, the defendant insisted that her rationale for the withdrawal of funds at the time of her decision not to proceed with the transaction was that the plaintiff owed her a significant sum of money, it would still owe her money after paying what she could to herself from the plaintiff&apos;s available cash on hand, and she did not trust Schwartz enough to do the right thing by her.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Reasons Given by Court for Award:</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The defendant owed a fiduciary duty to the plaintiff and she was in breach of her duty. <eos/><bos/>The defendant was an articulate and business savvy person. <eos/><bos/>Schwartz reposed trust and confidence in her by granting her access to the new operating account, giving her full control over the plaintiff&apos;s employees, and giving her control over the plaintiff&apos;s accounts receivable and payable when he turned over management of the plaintiff&apos;s day-to-day business operation to her on May 1, 2011. <eos/><bos/>The defendant had a fiduciary duty and a duty of good faith to use the plaintiff&apos;s funds for its purposes, and her duty extended to the repayment to her of advances she and her corporation made to capitalize the plaintiff and the expenses she and her corporation incurred, to the extent reasonable and possible, in all of the circumstances. <eos/><bos/>The defendant misled Schwartz in several respects: on January 4th she told him that she had set up an automatic payment of month-end payments to Schwartz and that she did not know the reason for the fact that the payment had not been made; she told him on January 4th that she intended to go to the bank the following day to ensure payment, when in fact she did not intend to do so; she told him on January 5th that she had gone to the bank, but that there was a “glitch” and she expected that it would be corrected, which was untrue; and on January 5th in response to Schwartz&apos;s email, she responded, “I have arranged it”.<eos/><bos/> By withdrawing all of the remaining funds from the new operating account to repay herself and her corporation in preference to the other creditors of the plaintiff, the defendant was acting in breach of her fiduciary duty to the plaintiff.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The defendant&apos;s primary consideration at the time of her decision to depart from the plaintiff was to withdraw from the new operating account as much money as possible before she informed Schwartz of her decision. <eos/><bos/>The defendant&apos;s obligation during the time that she was managing the plaintiff, and at the time of her departure was to put the plaintiff&apos;s interests before her own and to be absolutely transparent with Schwartz about the plaintiff&apos;s financial circumstances, including the state of accounts receivable and payable, and work out with him the ultimate repayment of the plaintiff&apos;s debt to her and her corporation. <eos/><bos/>In fact, although she took this position in her January 6th email, it was completely disingenuous as she had already withdrawn the remaining funds from the new operating account by that time. <eos/><bos/>The defendant&apos;s personal views of Schwartz&apos;s past dealings with her or with his payment practices of the plaintiff&apos;s creditors could not serve as factors to justify her breach of fiduciary duty to the plaintiff by not acting in its best interests. <eos/><bos/>The defendant&apos;s conduct at the time of her departure was taken with the intent of furthering and preferring her own interests and those of her corporation improperly, to the detriment of the plaintiff&apos;s interests, amounting to a breach of her fiduciary duty and duty of good faith.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>On appeal, the defendant&apos;s grounds of appeal focused on four main topics -- the award of damages to MAC in the amount of $32,245 for “loss of corporate opportunity”; the award of damages to MAC in the amount of $20,000 for <begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>“loss of opportunity to earn additional income”<end.quote refid="QT_0001"/>; the defendant&apos;s claim to a payment she had made to MAC in the amount of $26,000; and the costs award. <eos/><bos/>With the exception of his order for costs, the trial judge&apos;s findings on the matters raised by the defendant were supported by the evidence and had not been shown to be clearly wrong.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The first two subjects stemmed from the trial judge&apos;s finding that because Truter had <begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>“de facto control over virtually the entirety of MAC&apos;s business operation”<end.quote refid="QT_0002"/> during the period May 1, 2011 to January 6, 2012, she was subject to a fiduciary duty to the company. <eos/><bos/>Truter suggested in her factum that the judge unreasonably extended the concepts of corporate opportunity and fiduciary duty. <eos/><bos/>In her submission the term, unreasonable was used because the strictness with which the concept of loss of corporate opportunity was imposed essentially pitted the fiduciary duties owed directly against the freedom of business people to participate in private commercial ventures, which is contemptible in today&apos;s market reality whereby the best, brightest, and more ambitious business people are those who get involved in multiple directorships. <eos/><bos/>She referred us to <cite.query w-src-number="0492175900" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2000540957" w-pub-number="0005564" ID="I416696a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Sports Villas Resort Inc., Re (2000), 562 A.P.R. 281 (Nfld. C.A.)</cite.query>, where the court suggested that the “net” of activity proscribed by the fiduciary principle should not be drawn so tightly so as to restrict the latitude given to entrepreneurs who are involved in a wide variety of business activities, in the <begin.quote ID="QT_0003"/>“overall interests of breathing life into the economy.”<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0003"/> Truter noted that the trial judge described her as an “articulate and business savvy person” in whom Schwartz, also “a hardworking and savvy businessman”, had reposed trust and confidence. <eos/><bos/>Justice Newbury observed that, if Truter was suggesting that persons with “business savvy” should not be subject to the same duties of trust and loyalty as others are, he could not accept that suggestion. <eos/><bos/>Fiduciary duties are perhaps most important where sophisticated business persons are involved. <eos/><bos/>It was unfortunate that Truter was evidently unaware that in assuming control of MAC and its assets and accounts, she was assuming the “strict” fiduciary ethic, as well as a duty of good faith. <eos/><bos/>Had she known this, she might have sought terms that would have clarified the circumstances in which she could have properly paid herself for specified services or outlays of funds, or performed work through AvantGarde. <eos/><bos/>However, no final agreement was reached and the general outline of the ‘deal’ initialled in March 2011 made no mention of these matters. <eos/><bos/>As a result, there was no viable legal defence to the assertions of breach of duty advanced by MAC.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>With respect to the award of damages to MAC in the amount of $32,245 for “loss of corporate opportunity”, Truter was in a fiduciary position vis-à-vis MAC, and thus was obliged to refrain from appropriating any opportunity to herself that properly belonged to MAC. <eos/><bos/>The evidence also supported the inference that the three jobs were “ripe” opportunities --- as opposed to theoretical possibilities.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></section.body></section><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 4:46<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
