<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 7:5<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I56d26460411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>7.</label.designator><headtext>Remedies for Breach of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I56dbb330411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>II.</label.designator><headtext>Equitable Relief</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I56dc0150411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>A.</label.designator><headtext>Interim and Interlocutory Injunctions</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f6fb956ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>7:5.</label.designator><headtext>Balance of Convenience</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The balance of convenience involves an assessment by the court of the potential consequences to the parties if an injunction is granted. <eos/><bos/>The court should consider, for example, whether the plaintiff could be adequately compensated by an award of damages at trial. <eos/><bos/>If damages would be an adequate remedy and the defendant is in a financial position to pay, an interlocutory injunction will not normally be granted regardless of the strength of the plaintiff&apos;s claim. <eos/><bos/>However, in the vast majority of restraint of trade and business secrets cases, damages are very difficult to quantify and therefore are not generally considered to be an adequate remedy.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85a26f08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In measuring the balance of convenience, the courts will consider such factors as the relative size and stability of the businesses, the reasonableness of the request for an injunction, the public interest[<footnote.reference refid="Id85a26f18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>] and the conduct of the parties.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1985262300" w-pub-number="0005459" ID="I661045018e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Eli Lilly Canada Inc. v. Shamrock Chemicals</cite.query> Ltd.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id85a4e008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">3</footnote.reference>] it was determined that the balance of convenience lay in the moving party&apos;s favour since the moving party had a substantial and well-established position on the Canadian and world markets which could be substantially damaged if the injunction were not granted, whereas the defendant&apos;s hold on the market was still in its infancy. <eos/><bos/>However, to the contrary, see <ital>Fibron Machine Corp. v. Sawley</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id85a4e018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">4</footnote.reference>] where the court relied on the fact that the defendant would likely be put out of business.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In cases involving an employee and his or her former employer, the balance of convenience may favour the employee if granting the injunction would deprive the employee of the ability to be employed in a particular field of activity. <eos/><bos/>In <ital>Mercury Marine Ltd. v. Dillon</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id85a4e028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">5</footnote.reference>] the court held that granting an injunction would deprive the defendant of the ability to use his skill and expertise in earning a living because the non-competition clause in his contract was unduly broad. <eos/><bos/>The harm that would result to the defendant would be incalculable and thus the balance of convenience lay in his favour. <eos/><bos/>The motion for an injunction was refused.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85a4e038e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">6</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Natco Manufacturers &amp; Distributors Ltd. v. Topolnitsky</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id85a4e048e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">7</footnote.reference>] the personal defendant was a director, officer, and employee of the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>He was, at the time of his resignation or dismissal from the company, the general manager of the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>The president of the company was the father of the personal defendant. <eos/><bos/>In March 2010, the personal defendant became an employee of a competing business.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85a4e058e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">8</footnote.reference>] The motions judge observed that the basic law dealing with departing employees tends to differentiate between regular employees and key employees:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>As to key or fiduciary employees, the duty was described in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2000543131" w-pub-number="0006850" ID="I661379508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sanford Evans List Brokerage v. Trauzzi</ital>, [2000] O.T.C. 280 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query> at paras. 49 and 50, which paragraphs were noted in the <ital>Carson International Inc. v. Biggar, supra</ital>, case referred to above. <eos/><bos/>These comments are as follows (at para. 63):</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext>As an overriding proposition, departing employees have an absolute right to go into direct competition with their former employer and make use of the skills and general knowledge they accumulated during their period of employment … Competition per se by a departing fiduciary is not prohibited; only unfair competition is precluded. <eos/><bos/>Thus, a departing fiduciary may advertise to the general public. <eos/><bos/>If the form[er] employer&apos;s customer[s] are notified during the course of the general advertisement campaign, where is no breach, provided there is no misuse of confidential information such as trade secrets or customer lists.<eos/><bos/></paratext></para><head parent="display.quote"><headtext>…</headtext></head><para><paratext>There are, however, parameters which must not be crossed, dictated by the circumstances of the employee&apos;s departure and the manner in which he or she engaged in the new enterprise. <eos/><bos/>An employee who is a fiduciary is precluded from directly and actively soliciting the employer&apos;s customers, for a reasonable period of time after termination of the employment. <eos/><bos/>This places a limit on the fiduciary&apos;s post-employment enticement of customers … Similarly, the courts will not condone a situation in which a fiduciary seizes a corporate opportunity of the employer, or induces others to leave the employer, or conducts new business while on the employer&apos;s premises, or takes the employer&apos;s files or other confidential information of the employer ….<eos/><bos/> In the end, each case must be determined on its own merits.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0001"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id85a75108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">9</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The court came to the conclusion that there did not exist the certainty required for the granting of an interlocutory injunction. <eos/><bos/>The basic starting point was that courts should only restrain individuals from earning their livelihood in the clearest of circumstances. <eos/><bos/>The personal defendant was a fiduciary employee and had duties that continued after his departure. <eos/><bos/>One of those duties was that he not solicit the plaintiff&apos;s customers for a period of time following his departure. <eos/><bos/>However, the word “solicit” often appears to be used in the case law without any definition. <eos/><bos/>It certainly would prohibit a man from initiating contact with the former customer by telephone, in person, or by letter with the express purpose of inducing that customer to come to the man&apos;s new place of business. <eos/><bos/>However, there was no evidence that such occurred. <eos/><bos/>The personal defendant, less than three months after his departure from being the general manager of the plaintiff, started working for the competitor, coupled with information and belief statements that the plaintiff had been going to the businesses of customers of his new employer who were also former customers of the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>The court hesitated to assume that the personal defendant induced those customers to now acquire from him those products that were formerly supplied by him while he was general manager of the plaintiff given the lack of any detail as to what went on in those visits. <eos/><bos/>The affidavits are sparse. <eos/><bos/>They lack detail on both sides. <eos/><bos/>There has been no cross-examination by either party on any of the affidavits. <eos/><bos/>It might very well have been a breach of his fiduciary duty for the personal defendant to have taken a position with a competitor which required him to personally attend at the customers&apos; businesses, even if it was simply to sell the goods that the competitor had traditionally sold to that customer, because the by-product of that attendance was to capitalize on the relationship which the personal defendant had established when he was being paid by the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>However, that issue would ultimately need to be decided by a trial judge with more details as to what went on in those attendances. <eos/><bos/>Although troubled by a situation in which a key man of a company within three months of his departure from that company, began to attend the premises of his former customers, perhaps in the guise of simply carrying on the business of a competitor to its existing customers, the court observed that this was not a situation that should be addressed on an interlocutory application.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85a75118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">10</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In terms of the obligation of all employees not to misuse confidential information of the former employer, the courts have held that trade secrets and customer lists are confidential. <eos/><bos/>However, there is some ambiguity as to whether “confidential information” includes the names of such customers, and their needs and preferences, that the employee has learned during his period of service and can recall. <eos/><bos/>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2027291812" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I661722d18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Parrish &amp; Heimbecker Ltd. v. Delmar Commodities</cite.query> Ltd</ital>.,[<footnote.reference refid="Id85a75128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">11</footnote.reference>] the plaintiff sought from both Hodgson and Delmar return of its confidential information and an injunction enjoining them from using such confidential information or soliciting its customers, particularly in an area of Manitoba described as the “northeast territory”.<eos/><bos/> The defendant Hodgson was employed by the plaintiff until September 6, 2011 when he went to work for Delmar, a supplier and competitor of the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>In the winter of 2010/11, Delmar decided that because the plaintiff had chosen not to extend its reach into the northeast territory with a facility in the area, it would do so. <eos/><bos/>It entered into an agreement to acquire land and engaged local contractors to do the construction work. <eos/><bos/>Delmar did not advise the plaintiff of its intention to build this facility until after Hodgson had joined the company. <eos/><bos/>On September 6, 2011, Hodgson resigned from his employment with the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>He had sought out other employment and as a result secured two offers, one from Delmar for the position of Territory Manager for Eastern Manitoba. <eos/><bos/>He took the job and began work shortly thereafter. <eos/><bos/>Hodgson denied that he took any customer list or other property of the plaintiff when he left its employ. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff had no evidence that he took any such documentation. <eos/><bos/>There was no formal employment contract between Hodgson and the plaintiff, although he did endorse his acknowledgement on the plaintiff&apos;s employee handbook which contained a provision obliging all employees to maintain in strict confidence information received by the plaintiff or its customers and requiring them not to disclose this information either during the period of employment or at any time thereafter.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85a75138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">12</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motions judge observed that there was limited, if any, evidence of Hodgson having or using confidential information of the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence that he had any documentation belonging to the plaintiff, including customer lists. <eos/><bos/>He had no secret information about pricing of Legend Seed, as all sellers were required to sell at the same price. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence that he had targeted the plaintiff&apos;s customers. <eos/><bos/>The names of all farmers in the area were public information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85a75148e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">13</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>It was possible that, at trial, Hodgson would not be found to have been a key employee. <eos/><bos/>However, the evidence was quite convincing that he was. <eos/><bos/>As General Manager, he was more than a sales manager. <eos/><bos/>He had general managerial responsibilities over a large facility with a substantial sales volume. <eos/><bos/>In terms of his reassignment to Customer Service Manager, he held this position for only the last two or three months of his employment with the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>In both positions, he acquired considerable knowledge about the plaintiff&apos;s customers.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85a75158e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">14</footnote.reference>] If Hodgson did no more than pass on his business card and advise of where he was working, it was possible that, at trial, this might be found not to constitute solicitation. <eos/><bos/>However, this seemed unlikely. <eos/><bos/>By personally attending at the farms, Hodgson had clearly done more than generally advertise his new employment. <eos/><bos/>He directly approached farmers, knowing that some of them were customers of the plaintiff, in an attempt to secure their business. <eos/><bos/>And he has successfully concluded sales with some of these individuals.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>However, the plaintiff had not established that it would suffer irreparable harm if the injunction were denied. <eos/><bos/>The court was not persuaded that the plaintiff&apos;s customers were moving to Delmar because of any solicitation on the part of Hodgson. <eos/><bos/>Instead, any loss of market share would appear to result from Delmar now selling Legend Seed and having a facility in the area and, probably even more importantly, from the plaintiff&apos;s decision to no longer sell Legend Seed.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The balance of convenience weighed in favour of denying an injunction. <eos/><bos/>The reality was that the sale of soybean seeds was a highly competitive business. <eos/><bos/>While Delmar hired Hodgson to assist in its entry into the northeast territory market, there was scant evidence that it or Hodgson was using confidential information or targeting the plaintiff&apos;s customers. <eos/><bos/>Further, even if Hodgson was a key employee of the plaintiff, the law provides that he could join a competitor, sell to its customers, and advertise.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85a9c208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">15</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The courts will be more inclined to grant an injunction where there has been a deliberate breach of the rights of another.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85a9c218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">16</footnote.reference>] Similarly, the court will extend the time of an order for injunctive relief where a defendant admits that there were irregularities in their compliance with the original order.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85a9c228e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">17</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Interlocutory injunctive relief was appropriate and the only appropriate relief in the circumstances in <ital>Corona Packaging Inc. v. Singh</ital>.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85a9c238e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">18</footnote.reference>] The defendants, Singh and Cascioli were former employees of Corona, a manufacturer of plastic bottles. <eos/><bos/>Both had become employees of Corona on May 18, 2006 with written employment agreements for three-year terms, which contained various restrictive terms and conditions, including the requirement of confidentiality for proprietary corporate information and the obligation to not compete with Corona and not solicit Corona&apos;s customers for a three-year period following upon the expiry of employment Corona had one major customer, Guest representing 44% of its business. <eos/><bos/>Forensic IT specialists were retained who determined that Singh on the day before his departure from his employment with Corona had used his desktop computer in the Corona offices to transfer to a portable device, likely a Blackberry, some 8,465 files containing important confidential and proprietary information of Corona. <eos/><bos/>The information accessed and downloaded by Singh included Corona&apos;s “Work Order” listing every product produced by Corona, setting out all of its products&apos; technical specifications, the Corona budget setting forth confidential information including price lists, gross profit margins, machine cycle times, and input costs; the “Pre-Form” products&apos; catalogue of Corona with all the specifications created by Corona for such products; “Bottle Drawings” which include the final form bottle specifications; the Price List Notification which includes the proprietary formula utilized by Corona to determine its price list; product-related documents such as quality control testing, sample lists and packaging layouts; work place policies; confidential customer information including customer-owned mould specifications; and financial and administrative documents. <eos/><bos/>The fact that Cascioli serviced Corona&apos;s principal customer, Guest coupled with the disclosure by Aura Packaging that it now had a supply contract with Guest, together with the fact that Corona&apos;s confidential information is now admitted to have been put on the computer server at Aura Packaging, indicated Aura Packaging is competing with Corona for the business of that customer and arguably is doing so through using the information stolen from Corona in contravention of the employment contractual obligations of Singh and Cascioli.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85a9c248e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">19</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>There was a serious issue to be tried. <eos/><bos/>The evidence suggested that Singh and Cascioli were in breach of their employment contractual obligations and common law duty of confidence to their former employer not to disclose or use trade secrets and confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The balance of convenience favoured Corona. <eos/><bos/>Aura Packaging was relatively a start-up business in a very competitive product area. <eos/><bos/>The evidence indicated Corona&apos;s former key employees Singh and Cascioli, as employees of Aura Packaging, were engaging in direct competition with Corona. <eos/><bos/>Corona invested significant time and resources in developing and creating the confidential information in the misappropriated documents. <eos/><bos/>Aura Packaging could not have entered into the supply contract with Guest but for the utilization of the proprietary confidential information stolen from Corona by Mr. Singh.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85a9c258e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">20</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>There was convincing evidence in <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2027654193" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I662728618e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Fuller Western Rubber Linings Ltd. v. Spence Corrosion Services</cite.query> Ltd.</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id85a9c268e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">21</footnote.reference>] that the individual appellant did take some confidential information with him, and may well have used it, although at least some of it was subsequently returned. <eos/><bos/>The individual appellant was employed by the respondents for approximately 22 months, and during the last seven months he was involved in sales. <eos/><bos/>He left his employment in September of 2010, and shortly thereafter began competing with his former employer. <eos/><bos/>He was able to obtain contracts from customers of his former employer, and ended up employing a number of his former co-employees. <eos/><bos/>There was also evidence that he made use of confidential proprietary information in starting his own business. <eos/><bos/>The argument in chambers appeared to have been directed primarily at the use of the confidential information, and the essence of the chambers judge&apos;s reasons appeared to be his statement that the appellants had taken an unfair advantage by using the respondent&apos;s confidential information, documents, HSE Manual, customer list and employee list and had used this information to directly compete with the respondents. <eos/><bos/>The Chambers judge concluded that if an injunction was not granted the respondents would suffer irreparable harm to their business, reputation and goodwill. <eos/><bos/>The Court of Appeal observed that this merely conclusory statement did not assist much. <eos/><bos/>There was mention of potential difficulty in calculating damages from loss of business, but no other explanation as to why the misuse of confidential information should result in an injunction against all competition for six months.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85a9c278e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">22</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The respondents demonstrated a <ital>prima facie</ital> case relating to the use of confidential information. <eos/><bos/>However, there was no satisfactory evidence of irreparable harm. <eos/><bos/>It could reasonably be concluded that the appellants did obtain some advantage by using confidential information as a springboard. <eos/><bos/>However, by the time the injunction application was heard, some of that information had been returned, and the damage done by its use to that point could not be reversed. <eos/><bos/>With respect to the balance of convenience, the injunction would have essentially shut down the appellants&apos; business from March to September of 2012. <eos/><bos/>On the assumption the non-solicitation agreement was for the period of severance pay, the injunction covered a period after the covenant had expired. <eos/><bos/>On the assumption that the covenant was for two years, the injunction interrupted the appellant&apos;s business for six months, after it had been operating for 18 months, risking the employment of 24 persons. <eos/><bos/>In all the circumstances, the parties were to be left to their remedies in damages, to be calculated after the claim and counterclaim have been properly tried. <eos/><bos/>The appeal was allowed, and the interlocutory injunction discharged.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85ac3308e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">23</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Edgetch HVAC Services Ltd. v. Ubhi</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id85ac3318e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">24</footnote.reference>] the plaintiffs sought an interim injunction restraining the defendants from competing against Edgetch and from soliciting clients and employees of Edgetch. <eos/><bos/>The defendants fell into three categories. <eos/><bos/>Jesse was a one-third owner of Edgetch. <eos/><bos/>Jesse founded Edgetch with the plaintiffs Randy and Thomas. <eos/><bos/>Edgetch was an authorized sales and service distributor for gas detection products manufactured by Honeywell. <eos/><bos/>From 2008 to 2014, Edgetch was solely in Jesse&apos;s name, as Randy and Thomas continued to work at Honeywell. <eos/><bos/>In January 2014, after Randy and Thomas were laid off from Honeywell, the three of them engaged in a corporate reorganization of Edgetch and executed a unanimous shareholder agreement. <eos/><bos/>James and Extreme were independent contractors for Edgetch. <eos/><bos/>The remaining defendants were former employees of Edgetch. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs alleged that Jesse orchestrated the resignation of the former employees, the incorporation of Extreme and the possession and control of Edgetch&apos;s confidential information for the purpose of competing against Edgetch with Extreme.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85ac3328e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">25</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiffs&apos; narrative was one of being the victim to Jesse&apos;s plan to direct the other defendants to use proprietary information to solicit clients and compete against Edgetch in a way that did not overtly offend his obligations as set out in the USA. <eos/><bos/>Jesse&apos;s narrative was one of the victim as well. <eos/><bos/>He stated that he was the victim of exclusion by the plaintiffs who purposely denied him his rights under the USA and were now relying on it to prevent him from earning a livelihood with his recently formed company. <eos/><bos/>Jesse submitted that the plaintiffs could not seek to enforce the restrictive covenants in the USA, as the plaintiffs effectively repudiated the agreement and excluded him from the business improperly. <eos/><bos/>The former employees&apos; narrative was one of good, honest people with no choice but to leave Edgetch to join Extreme in order to earn a livelihood, given the stresses created by nepotism and racism at Edgetch.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85ac3338e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">26</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motions judge was of the view that it was the plaintiffs&apos; narrative that was supported and demonstrated by the evidentiary record. <eos/><bos/>The motions judge did not accept that Jesse was a victim of exclusion by Randy and Thomas. <eos/><bos/>The exclusion efforts were conduct reactive to Jesse&apos;s efforts to defeat Edgetch by soliciting its clients and competing against it with the assistance of former employees. <eos/><bos/>The motions judge did not accept that the former employees left Edgetch <ital>en masse</ital> without notice or transition because of nepotism or racism. <eos/><bos/>The timing of the resignations coincided too conveniently with Jesse&apos;s efforts to have the restrictive covenants in the USA waived, and none of the letters of resignation detailed nepotism or racism as the reason for leaving Edgetch. <eos/><bos/>The former employees left to assist Jesse with his efforts to compete against Edgetch through Extreme. <eos/><bos/>Finally, the motions judge did not accept that James decided to rebrand and expand his business around the same time that Jesse was negotiating a way out of his restrictive covenants and the former employees resigned without notice. <eos/><bos/>The only conclusion that failed to defy common sense was that Jesse took intentional and covert steps to coordinate with James and Edgetch employees in order to compete with Edgetch through Extreme.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85ac3348e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">27</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The defendants argued that there were no proprietary marketing or business techniques that Edgetch used to solicit customers on the basis that Edgetch&apos;s start up and service reports contain information that was easily obtained directly from customers and was generally offered by customers, upon request, to any service providers, especially competitive service providers who requested it, as this facilitated customers&apos; efforts to secure competitive quotes from different service providers before awarding the work. <eos/><bos/>The motions judge disagreed with this submission. <eos/><bos/>Edgetch recorded their clients&apos; specific products, pricing and servicing requirements. <eos/><bos/>This was information critical to the company, permitting it to know the clients&apos; needs and when these needs must be addressed. <eos/><bos/>It was not sufficient to say that the remaining shareholders could have called their clients to ask about products, pricing or when servicing was due. <eos/><bos/>The defendant Neha had the database of all clients, which included all upcoming scheduling for servicing, and she would update the database every evening. <eos/><bos/>The documentary evidence reflected the use of this information, including service reports, start-up reports and the excel service database to solicit business on behalf of Extreme. <eos/><bos/>The documentary evidence reflected the use by the defendants of Edgetch&apos;s proprietary information to solicit Edgetch&apos;s clients and compete with its business. <eos/><bos/>It put them in a position to harm the business of Edgetch as it gave them the opportunity to reach out and schedule the service required in accordance with the information retained.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85ac3358e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">28</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motions judge observed that the cases focus on the result of the enforcement of the covenant when adopting the strong <ital>prima facie</ital> test. <eos/><bos/>It is the result, interfering with an individual&apos;s ability to earn a livelihood that properly informs the analysis. <eos/><bos/>In this case, the restrictive covenant was agreed to by shareholders of equal bargaining power in a commercial context and not by an employee as a condition of employment or in the context of a sale of business. <eos/><bos/>The motions judge concluded nonetheless that the strong <ital>prima facie</ital> test still applied as the consequence remained consistent in that the shareholder was restricted in his ability to make a living. <eos/><bos/>Therefore, the higher threshold of a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case was applicable to the first branch of the <ital>RJR-MacDonald</ital> test.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85aea408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">29</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Jesse was the only defendant that was contractually prohibited from soliciting Edgetch&apos;s clients or employees. <eos/><bos/>He was the president and director of Edgetch. <eos/><bos/>Jesse breached the USA and his fiduciary duties as shareholder and director by soliciting clients and employees of Edgetch and using confidential information to compete directly against Edgetch. <eos/><bos/>While the evidence remained in its early stages and there had been some reliance on hearsay, the plaintiffs established a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case as against Jesse. <eos/><bos/>This conclusion was reached in the context of reasonable restrictive covenants in the USA. <eos/><bos/>The USA was a commercial contract amongst business partners of equal bargaining power bringing different and complimenting skills to the relationship. <eos/><bos/>At the commencement of their relationship, the partners negotiated and agreed to the terms therein. <eos/><bos/>It must be presumed that they did so with knowledge of the industry and in a manner that reasonably reflected the risks inherent in their business. <eos/><bos/>The court ought not to impose its views on reasonableness years later upon the breakdown of the relationship, unless the contract was entered into unfairly or circumstances occurred in the interim that could not have been reasonably foreseen at the time of the contract. <eos/><bos/>Further, the territorial scope was limited and did not extend to all territories within which Edgetch did business.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85aea418e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">30</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>None of the remaining defendants were contractually prohibited from soliciting Edgetch&apos;s clients or employees or prohibited from competing with Edgetch upon leaving the company. <eos/><bos/>However, as they assisted Jesse in the breach of his fiduciary duties, they too were liable for the breach.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85aea428e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">31</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The remaining defendants denied possessing or misusing any information belonging to Edgetch and submitted that the information at issue was neither confidential nor proprietary. <eos/><bos/>The motions judge disagreed with this submission. <eos/><bos/>The documentary evidence demonstrated a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that Neha, Arjun, Vic and Rovind misused confidential information for the benefit of Extreme. <eos/><bos/>Aman, Vic and Micky resigned their positions without notice, in order to work for Extreme. <eos/><bos/>James incorporated Extreme. <eos/><bos/>Extreme&apos;s business was founded, at least in part, on the misuse of confidential information. <eos/><bos/>By their very employment with Extreme, therefore, the former employees could be said to have misused confidential information for the benefit of a competitor. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs established a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that the defendants misused confidential information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85aea438e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">32</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>As the plaintiffs established a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case, the second and third branches of the <ital>RJR-MacDonald</ital> test carried less emphasis. <eos/><bos/>Determining the harm to a company as a result of the misuse of confidential information to solicit clients and compete is more complex than a mathematical calculation. <eos/><bos/>The defendants used confidential information to solicit Edgetch&apos;s clients and compete against it. <eos/><bos/>In doing so, they increased Edgetch&apos;s competition and consequently reduced its market share. <eos/><bos/>The extent of this damage cannot be quantified. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs suffered irreparable harm.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85aea448e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">33</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Edgetch developed its client base and business over its years of operation. <eos/><bos/>It prepared its confidential information and worked continuously to keep it current and relevant to servicing the clients&apos; needs. <eos/><bos/>Edgetch&apos;s former employees and one of its directors established the company, at least in part, to use Edgetch&apos;s confidential information to solicit its clients and compete with Edgetch. <eos/><bos/>Some of the solicitation took place prior to the employees leaving the company. <eos/><bos/>With respect to Jesse, the balance of convenience favoured the plaintiffs.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85aea458e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">34</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiffs sought an order enjoining the remaining defendants from competing with the business of Edgetch for a period of 12 months. <eos/><bos/>Jesse was an owner and director of Edgetch. <eos/><bos/>His efforts to thwart the obligations of his restrictive covenants were not only assisted by the remaining defendants; the success of his efforts depended entirely on the participation of the remaining defendants. <eos/><bos/>The remaining defendants were not relieved of their critical conduct because their employment status might otherwise be something less than a fiduciary. <eos/><bos/>Rather, it was the conduct itself that attached them to the fiduciary and absorbed them as if they were fiduciaries themselves.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85aea468e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">35</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In terms of the remaining defendants however, if the plaintiffs&apos; request was granted, the remaining defendants would be left without an ability to earn a livelihood in their chosen line of business for a period of 12 months. <eos/><bos/>This would result in harm to the remaining defendants far greater than the consequence of their choice to use confidential information and start a new company to assist Jesse. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs submitted that unless the remaining defendants are enjoined as requested, Jesse would be permitted to do indirectly what he is not permitted to do directly because of the USA. <eos/><bos/>This concern could be addressed, however, in a less restrictive manner that balanced the legitimate concern of the plaintiffs with the need of the remaining defendants to earn a livelihood. <eos/><bos/>The remaining defendants would be enjoined from using confidential information to compete with Edgetch and enjoined from competing with Edgetch in association with or on behalf of Jesse, Extreme or Gasense.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85b11508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">36</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>At issue in <ital>2158124 Ontario Inc. v. Pitton</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id85b11518e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">37</footnote.reference>] was whether Pitton had breached his non-solicitation and confidentiality obligations under an employment agreement. <eos/><bos/>StoneRidge carried on business as an insurance brokerage. <eos/><bos/>Glenny carried on business as an insurance brokerage. <eos/><bos/>It was a family-run business whose principals included Brian and Scott. <eos/><bos/>Pitton was a long-time family friend of the principals of Glenny. <eos/><bos/>Pitton was a licensed insurance broker. <eos/><bos/>Up to April 2011, Pitton was employed as a broker with Brokerlink managing a book of business consisting of commercial and personal clients. <eos/><bos/>Pitton approached StoneRidge&apos;s principal Puccini, advising that he wished to leave Brokerlink to join StoneRidge. <eos/><bos/>Pitton proposed that StoneRidge approach Brokerlink with an offer to purchase the book of business managed by him so that he could commence his StoneRidge employment with a ready client base. <eos/><bos/>Puccini eventually purchased the book of business from Brokerlink. <eos/><bos/>The book of business was assigned to StoneRidge. <eos/><bos/>Pitton was hired by StoneRidge as a senior account executive managing the Brokerlink book of business. <eos/><bos/>Pitton signed an Employment Agreement and was employed by StoneRidge until his abrupt resignation. <eos/><bos/>Without prior notice, Pitton delivered a letter of resignation and advised Puccini that he had accepted a position as a broker with Glenny, now operating under the name Erion. <eos/><bos/>Unbeknownst to Puccini or to anyone else at StoneRidge, Pitton began to contact StoneRidge clients to advise that he was leaving. <eos/><bos/>Puccini became aware of the solicitation because StoneRidge was contacted subsequently by several clients requesting clarification of Pitton&apos;s situation.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85b11528e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">38</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Pitton&apos;s book of business at the time of termination consisted of 183 commercial client lines and 92 personal client lines. <eos/><bos/>The defendants alleged that Pitton sent an email to a small selection of his former clients. <eos/><bos/>Most of the clients who received the email had followed Pitton from Brokerlink and included close personal friends and family, the vast majority of whom resulted from relationships that pre-dated his employment with the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>The defendants alleged that Pitton restricted the email to 50 individuals and had only spoken to approximately 35 former clients. <eos/><bos/>The defendants argued that the purpose of the email was not to be a solicitation of the plaintiff&apos;s clients.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85b11538e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">39</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>There was no dispute that a brokerage&apos;s primary asset is its customer base, including names, addresses, contact information, occupation, business and insurance requirements, information that would be extremely beneficial to another brokerage.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85b11548e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">40</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Goodman observed that several things flowing from the email clearly indicated a solicitation of business. <eos/><bos/>The email from Pitton was sent two days before Puccini&apos;s discussion with Scott regarding a potential purchase of the book of business and his confirmation that the Agreement would be honoured. <eos/><bos/>The email was sent on a Saturday, indicating that Pitton was losing no time in approaching certain of StoneRidge&apos;s clients. <eos/><bos/>Before even apparently commencing his new employment, Pitton had a Glenny email address, office address and telephone number. <eos/><bos/>StoneRidge was in touch with most clients serviced by Pitton and was advised by almost all of them that they had been contacted by Pitton either by email, letter or telephone call. <eos/><bos/>Justice Goodman was satisfied that Pitton knew who his StoneRidge clients were, had their contact information on his personal cell phone, was aware of the products they had purchased, the type of insurance coverage they had and general knowledge of when client policy renewals came due. <eos/><bos/>It was somewhat self-serving to justify this conduct by claiming that certain clients would have followed Pitton in any event. <eos/><bos/>The email went far beyond simply advising clients that Pitton had left StoneRidge. <eos/><bos/>The email referenced “my clients” and clearly stated that Pitton would provide <begin.quote ID="QT_0003"/>“the best service at competitive pricing at Erion…”<end.quote refid="QT_0003"/>. <eos/><bos/>He opined that his position at Glenny as operations manager would have a <begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>“positive effect on client relations and insurance options”<end.quote refid="QT_0002"/>. <eos/><bos/>Finally, he stated that he hoped <begin.quote ID="QT_0004"/>“to continue working with you in the future”<end.quote refid="QT_0004"/>. <eos/><bos/>Justice Goodman concluded that Pitton solicited former clients of StoneRidge immediately after his resignation from the plaintiff&apos;s business.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85b11558e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">41</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Goodman was of the view that the plaintiff would be in a significantly better position to sustain any loss than the defendants and specifically Pitton, whose skills, expertise and ability to earn a living would be compromised if the injunction were granted. <eos/><bos/>While the plaintiff had suffered some harm, an injunction barring Pitton from contacting or communicating with long-standing friends, family members and former clients, some of whom may predate his relationship with StoneRidge was unduly restrictive in these circumstances. <eos/><bos/>In this regard, the balance of convenience favoursed the defendants. <eos/><bos/>However, there was cogent evidence to establish that the defendants took confidential or private information from the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>In considering where the balance of convenience lies, it would be inequitable to permit a wrongdoer who had voluntarily signed and allegedly benefitted from a breach of a confidentiality covenant to claim that he would be more hurt by the granting of an interlocutory injunction. <eos/><bos/>The balance of convenience lay with the plaintiff to restrain the defendants&apos; activities.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85b11568e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">42</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>StoneRidge could not meet its onus to obtain the extraordinary remedy of an interlocutory injunction as it pertained to the non-solicitation of the plaintiff&apos;s clients. <eos/><bos/>StoneRidge had demonstrated irreparable harm from the use of confidential information in Pitton&apos;s possession arising from his former employment. <eos/><bos/>The loss arising from such use could not be compensated for by damages or, an award of damages would be inadequate compensation for the loss of the plaintiff&apos;s position in this highly competitive market. <eos/><bos/>Therefore, the plaintiff&apos;s motion for an interlocutory injunction was granted, in part. <eos/><bos/>The personal and corporate defendants shall not use, employ or disclose any confidential or proprietary information or trade secrets of StoneRidge or any other private secrets or information. <eos/><bos/>The defendants shall return to the plaintiff any book of business or other confidential or private records or documents in whatever format.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85b38608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">43</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>An application for an interlocutory injunction preventing the Defendants from holding bull riding events in July 2019 and 2020 was dismissed in <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I664510a18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos;</cite.query> Inc.</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id85b38618e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">44</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Plaintiffs owned and operated the Ranchman&apos;s, a restaurant, bar, cookhouse and dancehall. <eos/><bos/>Each year in early July the Plaintiffs host, at the Ranchman&apos;s, a successful event known as the Ranchman&apos;s Rodeo. <eos/><bos/>The Ranchman&apos;s Rodeo was a festival event which included high-quality professional bull riding taking place in a temporary arena adjacent to the Ranchman&apos;s building. <eos/><bos/>The Defendant BBI began producing the bull riding event for Ranchman&apos;s in 2000, and did so annually through July 2018. <eos/><bos/>Although the Snyders produced a bullbustin&apos; event for Ranchman&apos;s for many years, they were not contractually committed to produce them in future. <eos/><bos/>BBI and Ranchman&apos;s did not reach contractual terms for the 2019 Stampede season and the Snyder Defendants decided to produce a bull riding event elsewhere.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85b38628e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">45</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Plaintiffs advanced numerous claims in support of the injunctions including breach of duty of confidence relating to Ranchman&apos;s information and know-how, and breach of fiduciary duty by Cody Snyder and Rhonda Snyder.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85b38638e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">46</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Plaintiffs&apos; claims on the application included a request for an order prohibiting the Defendants from using their trademarks, intellectual property and key information. <eos/><bos/>The Ranchman&apos;s intellectual property was claimed to consist of intellectual property and trade secrets including but not limited to “key information”, marketing strategies, copyrights, the Ranchman&apos;s trademarks, know-how, confidential information and instructions regarding the operation of the Ranchman&apos;s Rodeo. <eos/><bos/>There was almost no detail in Ranchman&apos;s affidavit evidence of what was contained in this generic description. <eos/><bos/>Know-how was described as Ranchman&apos;s secrets on how they successfully run their business. <eos/><bos/>The Ranchman&apos;s key information was claimed to be all data, and records relating to the customers of Ranchman&apos;s including customer lists and email lists for customers, supplier lists and other data with respect to third parties. <eos/><bos/>There was almost no detail of what was contained in this description apart from a list of past ticket buyers and sponsors including their name, contact particulars, and past bleacher assignment.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85b38648e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">47</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Under the new 2018 agreement, the parties agreed to a revised fee structure. <eos/><bos/>BBI was to receive a fixed fee and a fee based on a fixed percentage of net profit. <eos/><bos/>This revenue flow through was accomplished by creating and inserting a numbered Alberta company 207, equally owned by the Snyders through Snyco (as to 50%) and by business associates of Raspberry, the Plaintiff&apos;s witness, through the Plaintiff CUBI (as to 50%).<eos/><bos/> The objective, rationale, and reason for being of 207 was to provide a corporate vehicle under which costs and revenues could be calculated with respect to Ranchman&apos;s Rodeo. <eos/><bos/>On paper, 207 was to produce an entertainment function including three days of bull riding and a Dallas Smith concert, 207 was to handle ticket sales, and Ranchmans 2017 Ltd. was to handle alcohol sales and secure the parking lot on which to host the event.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85b38658e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">48</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Plaintiffs learned that the Snyders had sent an email to all the bulk bleacher purchasers. <eos/><bos/>Ranchman&apos;s maintained a database containing its customer email names, contact particulars and ticket purchase information for the bull riding event. <eos/><bos/>There was no dispute that the Snyder Defendants accessed this information and used it to email the customers. <eos/><bos/>The Snyder Defendants created the website codysnyderbullbustin.com, describing their 2019 event. <eos/><bos/>This site included the statement that <begin.quote ID="QT_0005"/>“Cody Snyder has decided to move the event”<end.quote refid="QT_0005"/> and contains pictures from the 2018 event. <eos/><bos/>These pictures were focused on the action in the arena, though one was an overhead photo of the Ranchman&apos;s cookhouse and arena set up.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85b38668e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">49</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>On November 21, 2018 the Snyder Defendants again emailed the customers on the list. <eos/><bos/>They stated the Snyders were not producing a 2019 bull riding event at Ranchman&apos;s, and the event Ranchman&apos;s were producing was not the same event as the Snyders had produced for the last 19 years. <eos/><bos/>Further, the Snyders had decided to move their charity bullbustin&apos; to a new location and would continue to deliver to fans, sponsors and charity partners the same amazing event they were accustomed to.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85b5f708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">50</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Eamon concluded that the balance of convenience was heavily in favour of the Defendants.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85b5f718e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">51</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Ranchman&apos;s event would be going ahead, and much of the Plaintiffs&apos; potential losses could be quantified. <eos/><bos/>If there was a prospect of irreparable harm to Ranchman&apos;s goodwill, it was far outweighed by the irreparable harm which would be suffered by the Snyder Defendants if an injunction was wrongly granted. <eos/><bos/>A Court could quantify the Snyders&apos; lost profit in the event the injunction were wrongly granted. <eos/><bos/>But the harm they would suffer from an unwarranted interlocutory injunction would go far beyond that. <eos/><bos/>Their livelihood is bull riding. <eos/><bos/>Their reputation is built on rodeo successes and their long history of staging hundreds of successful Bullbustin&apos; events across North America. <eos/><bos/>The Calgary Stampede is a significant annual event in the rodeo world. <eos/><bos/>Removing them for one or two Stampede seasons, particularly this year when they had already made arrangements to host a Cody Snyder Bullbustin&apos; event, would seriously and irreparably harm their reputation and future business prospects. <eos/><bos/>Damages pursuant to an undertaking of damages in that event would not be fair and reasonable redress. <eos/><bos/>Furthermore, an injunction in the circumstances of this case would very likely provide the Plaintiffs undue solicitude, and grant them protection all out of proportion to the harm they may suffer.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85b5f728e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">52</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Eamon also considered the strength of the Plaintiff&apos;s claims. <eos/><bos/>Their best case on confidential information was something far less than mis-appropriation of all customer identities. <eos/><bos/>The large majority of customer identities were disclosed in the publicly available 2018 day sheets and were not confidential. <eos/><bos/>Justice Eamon was of the opinion that making an injunction against the Snyders and depriving them of their rodeo livelihood, in the vicinity of the Calgary Stampede, would be heavy handed and egregiously unfair to them.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85b5f738e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">53</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Eamon also considered that third parties would be adversely affected if an injunction was granted. <eos/><bos/>There would be lost employment opportunities at the Grey Eagle Event Centre. <eos/><bos/>Charities who had been selected for support by the Snyder Bullbustin&apos; event would lose financial opportunities, and the opportunity to raise awareness of their respective causes. <eos/><bos/>Suppliers booked for the Snyder event would lose work. <eos/><bos/>The charities who stand to benefit from the Ranchman&apos;s event would be harmed in the event the Ranchman&apos;s event lost significant ticket sales. <eos/><bos/>That prospect was speculative because the Ranchman&apos;s event was proceeding and it was difficult to predict either the outcome of Ranchman&apos;s marketing efforts or whether ticket sales may be lost as a result of unlawful conduct as opposed to an inevitable result of the lost relationship between Ranchman&apos;s and the Snyders. <eos/><bos/>The potential harm to the charities chosen by Ranchman&apos;s was relatively less in comparison to the harm that would be suffered by the charities selected by the Defendants.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85b5f748e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">54</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Had Justice Eamon accepted a serious issue on the Plaintiffs&apos; claims that the Snyder Defendants were precluded from competing by reason of breach of fiduciary obligations or creating confusion, Justice Eamon would have nevertheless found the balance of convenience heavily favoured the Defendants. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiffs&apos; prospect of success on these claims lay at the low end of the scale. <eos/><bos/>The prospect of irreparable harm to the Defendants far outweighed any that could be suffered by the Plaintiffs. <eos/><bos/>The innocent third parties would continue to suffer the impact of removing Cody Snyder Charity Bullbustin&apos; from the Calgary Stampede market.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85b5f758e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">55</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>SkyCope Technologies Inc. v. Jia</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id85b5f768e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">56</footnote.reference>] the Plaintiff sought an interlocutory injunction to restrain the Defendants from various forms of activity and, in particular, from making use of its confidential information. <eos/><bos/>Specifically, the Plaintiff sought to enjoin the Defendants from making use of the source codes it had developed in the area of anti-drone technology. <eos/><bos/>The individual Defendants were all persons who formally worked for the Plaintiff in various capacities and now worked for the corporate defendant.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85b5f778e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">57</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The founder and Chief Executive Officer of the Plaintiff was Liu. <eos/><bos/>Liu was also the sole director and shareholder of the company. <eos/><bos/>The corporate defendant was incorporated in March 2018 by the Defendant Jia. <eos/><bos/>The corporate defendant also developed and marketed anti-drone technology. <eos/><bos/>Liu and Jia had known each other for more than a decade and had worked together at different companies. <eos/><bos/>In the first six months of 2016, Liu wanted to assemble a team of engineers and researchers to help develop a prototype for an anti-drone defence system. <eos/><bos/>One of the individuals that Liu reached out to was Jia who, in September 2016, joined the Plaintiff and became its Chief Technology Officer. <eos/><bos/>In the time period that followed, each of the other individual Defendants joined the Plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>Each of the individual Defendants signed identical employment contracts. <eos/><bos/>Each of these employment contracts had various confidentiality, non-solicitation, and non-competition clauses.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85b86808e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">58</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In December 2017, Liu and Jia had a falling out and Jia left the Plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>In early January 2018, the Defendant Pan announced that he was leaving the company. <eos/><bos/>In February 2018, both the Defendants Zhang and Zhuang left the Plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>Zhang left because the company had closed down the hardware development branch of its business in which he had been engaged.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85b86818e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">59</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In June 2018, Liu travelled to China and learned that what appeared to be the Plaintiff&apos;s technology was being marketed to consumers. <eos/><bos/>He learned that Jia was the vice president of a Chinese company that had been formed on March 9, 2018 and that was marketing anti-drone technology. <eos/><bos/>He subsequently learned that Jia had formed the corporate defendant. <eos/><bos/>Liu learned through one of the Plaintiff&apos;s software engineers that Jia had reached out to another software engineer, Zarei, to gauge his potential interest in a new job. <eos/><bos/>Zarei has filed an affidavit in the proceedings on behalf of the Plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>He has deposed that, on June 10, 2018, he met briefly with. <eos/><bos/>Jia and, for a more extended period of time, with Pan to discuss his joining their new company, the corporate defendant. <eos/><bos/>That company, he was told, was developing anti-drone technology. <eos/><bos/>Zarei was also told that the corporate defendant had shipped its first product to a customer in April 2018. <eos/><bos/>The Defendants, in their response materials, asserted that that statement was not true, but was simply puffery. <eos/><bos/>This information caused Liu, in late July 2018, to hire a private investigation firm. <eos/><bos/>The investigators were advised that the corporate defendant would be in a position to deliver an anti-drone system to them by mid-October 2018. <eos/><bos/>They thereafter exchanged several emails and, on August 30, 2018, they arranged for a demonstration of the corporate defendant&apos;s anti-drone technology. <eos/><bos/>That demonstration occurred with Pan and two other individuals who the investigators had seen at the corporate defendant&apos;s offices. <eos/><bos/>The investigators openly photographed and video-recorded aspects of the presentation and of the equipment that was being used.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85b86828e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">60</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A witness for the Plaintiff explained that he took a screenshot from the video that the investigators took during the demonstration. <eos/><bos/>That screenshot revealed a portion of the source code that the corporate defendant relied on for its technology. <eos/><bos/>The witness deposed that there was virtually no possibility that two people, or groups of people, working separately, would code their entries in an identical fashion, with the same capitalization and order of letters and numerical figures.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85b86838e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">61</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Plaintiff&apos;s Notice of Civil Claim alleged that each of the individual Defendants breached their respective employment contracts, that each of them was liable for a breach of confidence, and that Jia, by virtue of his senior position in the Plaintiff company, breached the fiduciary obligations that he owed to the Plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiff also alleged that the corporate defendant was liable for knowing receipt of confidential information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85b86848e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">62</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Court in <ital>RJR-MacDonald</ital> noted that the factors to be considered in an assessment of the balance of convenience are varied and numerous. <eos/><bos/>One such factor is the strength of the parties&apos; respective positions. <eos/><bos/>Here, the position of the Plaintiff appeared, at this stage, to be much stronger particularly as it related to the development and protection of its confidential information. <eos/><bos/>Its legal right to protect its confidential information and, in particular, its source codes was supported both by the express terms of the employment contracts it entered into with the individual Defendants and by the common law action of breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>Without making any findings, the Chambers judge considered it inherently unlikely that the Defendants were able to develop a competitive technology so quickly without, at least, using the Plaintiff&apos;s information as a springboard to get a head start.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85b86858e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">63</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Chambers judge also considered that balancing the potential harm that the issuance of or, alternatively, the failure to grant an injunction restraining the Defendants from using the Plaintiff&apos;s source code weighed in favour of the Plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>The evidence suggested that while the corporate defendant was involved with the development of anti-drone technology, it was also involved with the development of several other technologies. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, it appeared that granting the injunction would only affect a subset of the corporate defendant&apos;s business. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiff&apos;s business, conversely, was primarily focused on anti-drone technology. <eos/><bos/>Indeed, that was the only confidential information that it sought to protect.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85b86868e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">64</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Chambers judge made the following orders: 1. The Defendants were to deliver the source code that they were relying on in connection with their anti-drone technology to counsel for the Plaintiff within 48 hours. <eos/><bos/>They were to do so in sealed form. 2. The Defendants, and each of them, were enjoined until December 14, 2018 from: (a) contacting and/or soliciting any employee of the Plaintiff; and (b) engaging in any activity or in any undertaking or business in any capacity that develops, manufactures, or markets anti-drone technology. <eos/><bos/>The Chambers judge used December 14, 2018 because this was one year from when Jia left the Plaintiff and the one-year period aligned with the prohibition in his employment contract. 3. The Defendants, and each of them, were enjoined until the trial of the action from using or developing any anti-drone source code or software that is based on, or derived from, the source code of the Plaintiff.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85bad908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">65</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I665eb3218e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading</cite.query> Ltd.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id85bad918e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">66</footnote.reference>] the plaintiffs, Natural Trade and Global Forest were closely held “sister” companies involved in lumber trading. <eos/><bos/>Natural Trade exported lumber products from North America, South America and Europe to Mexico where Global Forest sold the products to local customers. <eos/><bos/>The defendants, Mizrach and Quintana, were former employees of Natural Trade. <eos/><bos/>Mizrach&apos;s responsibilities initially consisted of accounting and trading lumber. <eos/><bos/>Mizrach soon became an important trader and was promoted to CFO. <eos/><bos/>While he was CFO, continued to have an important sales role. <eos/><bos/>Throughout his time with Natural Trade, Quintana worked as a lumber trader. <eos/><bos/>The defendant, MYL Trading was a partnership formed by Mizrach and his spouse while Mizrach was employed by Natural Trade. <eos/><bos/>It was subsequently incorporated and now competed with Natural Trade and Global Forest. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs believed that MYL Trading was formed to directly compete with them and was a corporate vehicle through which Mizrach and Quintana misused confidential information obtained during their employment with Natural Trade. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs sought an interlocutory injunction to restrain the Mizrach defendants from using confidential information obtained in violation of duties owed to the plaintiffs; an order for recovery by the plaintiffs of its confidential information and other property from the Mizrach defendants; and orders requiring Mizrach and Quintana to attest to their eventual return of the plaintiffs&apos; property and to answer questions about their use of the plaintiffs&apos; confidential information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85bad928e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">67</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Mizrach and Quintana signed written employment agreements with Natural Trade. <eos/><bos/>In 2016, they also signed written confidentiality and non-disclosure agreements. <eos/><bos/>The employment agreements, and/or confidentiality and non-disclosure agreements included terms relating to non-disclosure of confidential information, return of company property, non-competition and non-solicitation.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85bad938e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">68</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>During their employment with Natural Trade, Mizrach and, to a lesser extent, Quintana had access to, and acquired knowledge of nearly every aspect of Natural Trade&apos;s business and operations. <eos/><bos/>This included access to gross margin reports, which included the customers, suppliers, freight and insurance providers, costs, discounts, profits and profit margins for each sale. <eos/><bos/>Collectively, this information outlined which combinations of customers, suppliers and logistics providers were the most profitable. <eos/><bos/>In performing their duties for Natural Trade, Mizrach and Quintana developed relationships with various customers.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85bad948e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">69</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiffs believed that before November 2016, and perhaps as early as the spring of 2015, Mizrach developed a plan to use their confidential information to take their customers for himself. <eos/><bos/>To support their beliefs, the plaintiffs produced documents recovered from Mizrach&apos;s Natural Trade computer. <eos/><bos/>These documents appeared to show that Mizrach, Niron and MYL Trading were, for their own benefit, utilizing one of Natural Trade&apos;s suppliers in Brazil to transact business directly with Proterey and Valley Lumber in December 2016. <eos/><bos/>Mizrach was still employed as Natural Trade&apos;s CFO at the time. <eos/><bos/>The defendants offered no explanation of these records in their affidavits. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs adduced evidence that Mizrach made a copy of Natural Trade&apos;s “ERP system”, which listed all of Natural Trade&apos;s suppliers and customers together with contact information for each. <eos/><bos/>The implication of the plaintiffs&apos; evidence is that Mizrach took a copy of the information for his own benefit to compete with the plaintiffs.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85bad958e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">70</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiffs adduced evidence that, prior to their departures, Mizrach and Quintana either copied or tried to copy their entire work email contents for their personal use. <eos/><bos/>Both Mizrach and Quitana acknowledged having or having had several months&apos; worth of work emails on their cell phones after leaving Natural Trade. <eos/><bos/>Further, Mizrach acknowledged having copies of certain of Natural Trade&apos;s gross margin reports.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85bad968e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">71</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Mizrach and Mr. Quintana offered explanations as to why they had possession of confidential information of the plaintiffs. <eos/><bos/>They explained that they copied or tried to copy the content of their work email accounts to capture personal emails. <eos/><bos/>They explained having several months&apos; worth of work emails on their cell phones as a mere consequence of their departures. <eos/><bos/>Mizrach explained his possession of gross margin reports as being to enable him to ensure he was paid for commissions he earned before his departure.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85bad978e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">72</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Since the departure of Mizrach and Quintana, the plaintiffs experienced a decline in sales to some of the plaintiffs&apos; customers which was offset by sales to these same customers by MYL Trading.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85bd4a08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">73</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Mizrach defendants had confidential information of the plaintiffs, including at least gross margin reports and months&apos; worth of work emails. <eos/><bos/>This information included key contact information for the plaintiffs&apos; customers and suppliers, costs and discounts along the supply chain, and profit margins for a wide variety of means of satisfying the needs of particular customers. <eos/><bos/>Some of this information was publicly available. <eos/><bos/>However, the publicly available information does not include any information regarding the discounts offered by the plaintiffs, who the plaintiffs&apos; key contacts were, which customers were the most credit-worthy and what combination of suppliers, and logistics and insurance providers were the most profitable. <eos/><bos/>The publicly available information also did not contain information regarding the final destination of many of the plaintiffs&apos; lumber shipments into Mexico—because the publicly available information only showed the imports by Global Forest and not Global Forest&apos;s ultimate sales to its customers.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85bd4a18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">74</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Marchand observed that only the Mizrach defendants knew at this stage for sure whether they had misused the confidential information of the plaintiffs to unfairly compete with them. <eos/><bos/>Nevertheless, the plaintiffs adduced some reasonably compelling evidence that that had occurred. <eos/><bos/>That evidence included: the unexplained evidence that the Mizrach defendants transacted business for their personal benefit while still employed by Natural Trade; Mizrach&apos;s incorporation of EYL prior to his departure from Natural Trade; the downloading or attempted downloading by Mizrach and Quintana of all of the content of their work email accounts before their departures from Natural Trade; the possession of the plaintiffs&apos; property by the Mizrach defendants, including important information which was not publicly available; the speed with which the Mizrach defendants began competing with the plaintiffs; and sales by the Mizrach defendants to the plaintiffs&apos; customers that corresponded to a decline in sales to those customers by the plaintiffs.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85bd4a28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">75</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Marchand noted that it was hard to know whether any misuse of confidential information by the Mizrach defendants had harmed the plaintiffs&apos; reputation or caused the plaintiffs to suffer a permanent loss of market share. <eos/><bos/>It also appeared that the plaintiffs had been able to quantify substantial losses that they attributed to misconduct by the Mizrach defendants. <eos/><bos/>There was, however, a real risk that, if ultimately successful, the plaintiffs would be unable to recover their damages from the Mizrach defendants.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85bd4a38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">76</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In addition, if an injunction was granted, it was not apparent how that would irreparably harm the Mizrach defendants. <eos/><bos/>The Mizrach defendants submitted that they were not using any of the plaintiffs&apos; confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs were not seeking an order prohibiting the Mizrach defendants from competing against them. <eos/><bos/>If the Mizrach defendants were ultimately successful, the plaintiffs would be in a position to pay any damage award that might be made as a result of the granting of an injunction. <eos/><bos/>Justice Marchand observed that while these factors weighed in favour of an injunction, the main factor weighing in the other direction was the passage of time. <eos/><bos/>More than 14 months had passed since Mizrach and Quintana left the employ of Natural Trade. <eos/><bos/>If the Mizrach defendants misused the confidential information of the plaintiffs, it seemed self-evident that most of the damage must already be done. <eos/><bos/>Any damage done likely could not be undone by the granting of an injunction.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85bd4a48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">77</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The other legitimate consideration weighing against the granting of an injunction was the breadth of the injunction sought by the plaintiffs. <eos/><bos/>Any concerns about ambiguity or over-breadth could be addressed by tailoring an injunction to meet the circumstances of the case. <eos/><bos/>The possession of confidential information by the Mizrach defendants put the Mizrach defendants in a position to seriously injure the plaintiffs by giving the Mizrach defendants a springboard for activities detrimental to the plaintiffs.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85bd4a58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">78</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Marchand was of the view that there was no reason why the Mizrach defendants should not be enjoined from using clearly identified confidential information of the plaintiffs. <eos/><bos/>It was just and equitable to grant a tailored interlocutory injunction to enjoin the Mizrach defendants from using specified confidential information of the plaintiffs. <eos/><bos/>Mizrach and Quintana accumulated their “know-how” over many years and not exclusively from the plaintiffs. <eos/><bos/>Any prohibition against the Mizrach defendants using the know-how they acquired during their employment with Natural Trade would be too vague to enable them to know what they could and could not do, difficult to enforce and effectively put them out of business. <eos/><bos/>Any prohibition against the Mizrach defendants using business strategies employed by the plaintiffs would be too vague to enable them to know what they could and could not do, difficult to enforce and effectively put them out of business. <eos/><bos/>Going forward, the real object of an injunction must be to prevent the misuse of the type of confidential information that could truly give the Mizrach defendants an unfair competitive advantage over the plaintiffs. <eos/><bos/>The most critical information was that found in the gross margin reports. <eos/><bos/>Given that the plaintiffs acknowledged that the Mizrach defendants were free to compete with them and that there was plenty of publicly available information regarding suppliers and consumers of lumber products, there was no basis to make an order prohibiting the defendants from contacting the customers or suppliers of the plaintiffs that the Mizrach defendants had not sold any products to, or purchased any products from.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85bd4a68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">79</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The order would not be restricted to confidential information and would cover all of the property of the plaintiffs that was in the possession of the Mizrach defendants. <eos/><bos/>There was no reason for the Mizrach defendants to have any of the plaintiffs&apos; property.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85bfbb08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">80</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00007" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I666bd2818e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity</cite.query> Corp.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id85bfbb18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">81</footnote.reference>] the plaintiff sought an interlocutory injunction restraining the defendants from disclosing or making use of client information and/or soliciting the plaintiff&apos;s clients. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff also sought an order requiring the defendants to return to it all copies of information related to clients of the plaintiff when the employment of the defendant Mann was terminated by the plaintiff; provide an affidavit setting out any uses to which the defendants have put the information; and refrain from disclosing or otherwise making use of the information, including for the purpose of soliciting the plaintiff&apos;s clients.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85bfbb28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">82</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff was a full service brokerage firm and investment dealer. <eos/><bos/>Mann moved to the plaintiff&apos;s Vancouver Branch from another brokerage firm and signed an employment agreement. <eos/><bos/>That agreement did not contain any non-solicitation clause or make reference to a code of conduct. <eos/><bos/>A few days after signing the employment agreement and commencing his employment with the plaintiff, Mann signed a document indicating that he would “accept to read” the plaintiff&apos;s Code of Conduct and Ethics. <eos/><bos/>When he joined the plaintiff, he had 100 clients and was managing $50 million in investment assets.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85bfbb38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">83</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The defendants, James and Ilia Nizker became employees of the plaintiff, the latter as a “cold caller”.<eos/><bos/> Like Mann, James&apos; employment contract did not contain a non-solicitation provision and did not refer to the Code of Conduct. <eos/><bos/>Nizker signed an employment contract one month after having qualified and becoming employed as an investment advisor. <eos/><bos/>His employment contract contained a non-solicitation provision.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85bfbb48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">84</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>By April 18, 2018, Mann held the position of Senior Vice President, Portfolio Manager, and oversaw a group of investment advisors and other employees who were known within the plaintiff as the “Mann Group”.<eos/><bos/> At that time the Mann Group serviced 2,500 clients with investment assets totaling $725,000,000. <eos/><bos/>James and Nizker were part of the Mann Group. <eos/><bos/>The growth of the Mann Group&apos;s client base over the years came about as the result of the individual efforts of the Mann Group. <eos/><bos/>The Mann Group had its own website and marketed its services through various means such as newsletters, emails, cold calls and referrals.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85bfbb58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">85</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In 2010, Mann purchased computer software called “Salesforce”, a third-party customer relationship platform. <eos/><bos/>It is a cloud-based database into which the Mann Group input the names, addresses, phone numbers and email addresses of clients as well as general notes of discussions they had with clients and prospects. <eos/><bos/>It did not include any information such as account numbers, holdings or rates of return. <eos/><bos/>Mann paid all of the licencing fees for the Salesforce software. <eos/><bos/>The Mann Group did not use the plaintiff&apos;s database to retrieve information used to communicate to clients. <eos/><bos/>It used Salesforce. <eos/><bos/>The only people who had access to the Salesforce database were members of the Mann Group.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85bfbb68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">86</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In 2016, Mann contemplated leaving the employ of the plaintiff and moving to the defendant, Canaccord. <eos/><bos/>He copied and provided to Canaccord, via flash drives, confidential and private information regarding the Mann Group&apos;s clients. <eos/><bos/>This information comprised up to 23,768 reports containing “Know Your Client” forms and other client documents. <eos/><bos/>In early 2018, Mann again copied onto flash drives a substantial amount of confidential and private information regarding clients, comprising up to 27,088 records.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85bfbb78e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">87</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>On April 18, 2018, Mann&apos;s employment was terminated by the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff now alleged that Mann was terminated for cause, in that he engaged in misconduct that was in breach of securities regulations, IIROC rules and the plaintiff&apos;s internal policies.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85c22c08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">88</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Immediately after Mann&apos;s termination, James changed the Salesforce password which resulted in the plaintiff&apos;s temporary access to the Salesforce account to be cut off. <eos/><bos/>Thereafter, the only contact information available to the plaintiff for the clients that had been managed by the Mann Group was that contained in its own database. <eos/><bos/>On April 20, 2018, James tendered his resignation to the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>On April 23, 2018, Mann and James commenced employment with Canaccord. <eos/><bos/>Also on April 23, 2018, Nizker and four other members of the Mann Group tendered their respective resignations and joined Mann and James at Canaccord. <eos/><bos/>The Mann Team immediately began to solicit the business of the clients whose assets they had managed while employed by the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>They provided information regarding why they had left the plaintiff and moved to Canaccord that was, at the very least, a failure of full disclosure as to the true reason they had left the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff was unable to correspond with or contact many of the recipients of these emails because it did not have current contact information for them.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85c22c18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">89</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The defendants had possession of seven categories of documents which fell within the plaintiff&apos;s definition of Confidential Documents: a) the 2016 USB Keys; b) documents from the 2016 USB Keys downloaded to the desktop of Canaccord&apos;s Assistant Branch Manager; c) hard copies of documents printed from the 2016 USB Keys; d) data from the hard copies used to populate Canaccord transfer forms which were kept on USB drives; e) data from the hard copies of documents loaded into a database used by Canaccord known as Dataphile; f) the 2018 USB Keys; and g) a client list, separate from that contained on Salesforce, printed by Mann shortly before his termination from the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>The defendants returned to the plaintiff the 2016 USB Keys, the hard copies of documents from the 2016 USB Keys, the Transfer Form USB Keys, the 2018 USB Keys and the client list printed by Mann in 2018. <eos/><bos/>No copies were kept of any of these documents, electronically or otherwise. <eos/><bos/>The data that was loaded to Dataphile remained there. <eos/><bos/>Dataphile is a database owned by an external vendor and Canaccord does not have the ability, on its own, to permanently remove the data.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85c22c28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">90</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Weatherill concluded that neither the necessary thresholds required to be shown by the plaintiff in respect of its case other than in respect of the 2016 USB Drive and Dataphile information nor irreparable harm had been demonstrated. <eos/><bos/>If an injunction was to be granted, the individual defendants would suffer substantial harm because they will effectively be prohibited from earning a living in their profession. <eos/><bos/>The financial harm would be devastating.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85c22c38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">91</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The financial impact on the plaintiff of losing the clients that were managed by the Mann Group would be unlikely to have the same devastating effect. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff employed over 2,700 people in 86 offices across Canada. <eos/><bos/>It had assets under its management exceeding $400 billion. <eos/><bos/>It was likely that the overall financial impact of the loss of the clients managed by the Mann Group would be relatively small. <eos/><bos/>The balance of convenience clearly favoured the defendants.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85c22c48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">92</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The defendants were required to return to the plaintiff all copies of any data from the hard copies used to populate Canaccord transfer forms which were kept on USB drives that was currently stored on Dataphile but the balance of the plaintiff&apos;s application was dismissed.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85c22c58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">93</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Quick Pass Master Tutorial School Ltd. v. Zhao</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id85c22c68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">94</footnote.reference>] Quick Pass sought an interlocutory injunction to prohibit Zhao from competing with it, from soliciting its students, and from using what it alleged was Quick Pass&apos;s confidential or proprietary information. <eos/><bos/>Quick Pass offered real estate-related tutorial programs in various Lower Mainland locations to assist Mandarin speakers in taking British Columbia&apos;s real estate licencing examinations. <eos/><bos/>It hired real estate agents who were fluent in Mandarin as instructors. <eos/><bos/>The owner of Quick Pass hired Zhao under a two-year contract as a real estate program instructor. <eos/><bos/>The contractual terms prohibited Zhao from soliciting Quick Pass&apos;s students and from competing with it for specified periods. <eos/><bos/>It also provided that Quick Pass owned all material relating to its business, including any material created by Zhao while under contract to Quick Pass, whether or not he created it at Quick Pass&apos;s direction.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85c22c78e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">95</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The day after Zhao terminated his contract, he opened a competing tutorial school in Burnaby. <eos/><bos/>He advertised and marketed his school to the Mandarin-speaking community, including to students of Quick Pass. <eos/><bos/>He used materials that he alleged he developed for use in his own program, but which he must have developed while working for Quick Pass since he opened his school the next day.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85c49d08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">96</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Iyer observed that since Zhao opened his school the day after he left Quick Pass, and the Confidential Information Clause deemed any such material created by Zhao during the term of the Contracts to be the proprietary and confidential information of Quick Pass, it was more likely than not that the material he created for the Zhao School was created while Zhao was under contract to Quick Pass. <eos/><bos/>This meant that if the Confidential Information Clause was enforceable, Zhao breached it.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85c49d18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">97</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Confidential Information Clause was not a restrictive covenant. <eos/><bos/>Rather, Justice Iyer observed that it was <begin.quote ID="QT_0006"/>“intended to protect the right of a business to keep confidential the information it hopes will help it to compete so the usual relatively low threshold applies to it”<end.quote refid="QT_0006"/> citing <cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00008" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034063927" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I668156508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Phoenix Restorations Ltd. v. Drisdelle</ital>, 2014 CarswellBC 2348, 2014 BCSC 1497</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>This meant that Quick Pass need only prove that its claim with respect to this clause was not frivolous or vexatious and the court need not engage in an extensive review of the merits of the claim.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85c49d28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">98</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Iyer concluded that the balance of convenience favoured Quick Pass. <eos/><bos/>Quick Pass&apos;s claim was relatively strong, and, if it succeeded, damages would be very hard to quantify. <eos/><bos/>Granting the injunction would only require Zhao to relocate his school to accord with the Contracts he signed. <eos/><bos/>An award of damages could compensate for the costs he incurred in doing so.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85c49d38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">99</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Iyer reached a different conclusion with respect to the Confidential Information Clause, based primarily on the strength of Quick Pass&apos;s claim and the impact of an injunction on Zhao. <eos/><bos/>The only information Quick Pass described as in issue was the teaching material. <eos/><bos/>There was a real issue as to whether this was confidential information. <eos/><bos/>Justice Iyer had doubts about the enforceability of the Confidential Information Clause because of its breadth in purporting to apply to virtually everything Zhao created while under the Contracts. <eos/><bos/>If granted, an injunction with respect to the confidential information would have a severe impact on Zhao: he could not operate his business at all. <eos/><bos/>In the circumstances, the balance of convenience favoured Zhao.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85c49d48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">100</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Iyer granted the plaintiff&apos;s application for an interlocutory injunction respecting the Non-Competition Clause. <eos/><bos/>However, Justice Iyer modified the wording of the order to correspond more precisely with the tutorial program offered by Quick Pass that he instructed. <eos/><bos/>Zhao was restrained from competing with the plaintiff in any aspect of the business of providing pre-licensing real estate training anywhere in Vancouver, Burnaby and Richmond British Columbia until the trial.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id85c49d58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">101</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Id85a26f08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00009" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1983031575" w-pub-number="0004831" ID="I668611408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Brupat Ltd. v. Sandford Marine Products Ltd.</ital>, [1983] R.P.C. 61 (C.A.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85a26f18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00010" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1981032412" w-pub-number="0003898" ID="I668686708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Schering Chemicals Ltd. v. Falkman Ltd.</ital>, [1982] Q.B. 1 (C.A.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00011" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026833645" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I668686728e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Hub International (Richmond Auto Mall) Ltd. v. Mendham</ital>, 2011 CarswellBC 3672, 2011 BCSC 1780</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85a4e008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00012" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1985262300" w-pub-number="0005459" w-pinpoint-page="12" ID="I668797e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Eli Lilly Canada Inc. v. Shamrock Chemicals Ltd.</ital> (1985), 6 C.I.P.R. 5 at pp. 12–13, 4 C.P.R. (3d) 196 (Ont. S.C.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00013" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1978155024" w-pub-number="0005652" ID="I668797e48e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Professional Maintenance Systems of Canada Ltd. v. Smits</ital></cite.query> (1978), 13 C.P.C. 144, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00014" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1978155024" w-pub-number="0005652" ID="I668797e58e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">40 C.P.R. (2d) 160 (B.C.S.C.)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>See also <cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00015" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2003060387" w-pub-number="0005158" ID="I668797e88e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Khan v. RDMI Inc.</ital></cite.query> (2001), 5 C.C.E.L. (3d) 303 (Ont. S.C.J.); <cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00016" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2003060387" w-pub-number="0005158" ID="I668797e98e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Direct Plus Food Group Inc. v. Comeau</ital> (2003), 265 N.B.R. (2d) 1 (Q.B.)</cite.query>, at paras. 16–23; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00017" w-ref-type="PM" w-serial-number="2024859787" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I668797eb8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Luen Sing Foods Inc. v. Southseas Noodles Ltd.</ital>, 2011 CarswellBC 621, 2011 BCSC 34</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85a4e018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>4</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00018" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1999482957" w-pub-number="0005653" ID="I6687e6008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Fibron Machine Corp. v. Sawley</ital> (1999), 86 C.P.R. (3d) 448 (B.C.S.C.)</cite.query>, supp. reasons 43 C.P.C. (4th) 35, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00019" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1999482957" w-pub-number="0005653" w-pinpoint-page="465" ID="I6687e6028e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">86 C.P.R. (3d) at p. 465 (B.C.S.C.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85a4e028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>5</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00020" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1986192083" w-pub-number="0003591" w-pinpoint-page="633" ID="I66880d108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Mercury Marine Ltd. v. Dillon</ital> (1986), 30 D.L.R. (4th) 627 at pp. 633–4, 56 O.R. (2d) 266 (H.C.J.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85a4e038e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>6</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00021" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1986192083" w-pub-number="0003591" w-pinpoint-page="634" ID="I668834208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Mercury Marine Ltd. v. Dillon</ital> (1986), 30 D.L.R. (4th) 627 at pp. 634, 56 O.R. (2d) 266 (H.C.J.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00022" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026581932" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I668834238e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cansafe Inc. v. Donkin</ital>, 2011 CarswellAlta 2021, 2011 ABQB 698</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85a4e048e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>7</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00023" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026062239" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I66885b308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natco Manufacturers &amp; Distributors Ltd. v. Topolnitsky</ital>, 2011 CarswellMan 444, 2011 MBQB 197</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85a4e058e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>8</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00024" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026062239" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I6688a9508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natco Manufacturers &amp; Distributors Ltd. v. Topolnitsky</ital>, 2011 CarswellMan 444, 2011 MBQB 197</cite.query>, at paras. 4 and 6.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85a75108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>9</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00025" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026062239" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I6688d0608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natco Manufacturers &amp; Distributors Ltd. v. Topolnitsky</ital>, 2011 CarswellMan 444, 2011 MBQB 197</cite.query>, at paras. 13–14.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85a75118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>10</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00026" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026062239" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I6688f7708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natco Manufacturers &amp; Distributors Ltd. v. Topolnitsky</ital>, 2011 CarswellMan 444, 2011 MBQB 197</cite.query>, at paras. 25–27 and 30.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85a75128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>11</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00027" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027291812" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I66891e808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Parrish &amp; Heimbecker Ltd. v. Delmar Commodities Ltd</ital>., 2012 CarswellMan 114, 2012 MBQB 48</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85a75138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>12</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00028" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027291812" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I668945908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Parrish &amp; Heimbecker Ltd. v. Delmar Commodities Ltd</ital>., 2012 CarswellMan 114, 2012 MBQB 48</cite.query>, at paras. 1–2, 6, 14, 18–19, and 33.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85a75148e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>13</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00029" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027291812" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I66896ca08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Parrish &amp; Heimbecker Ltd. v. Delmar Commodities Ltd</ital>., 2012 CarswellMan 114, 2012 MBQB 48, at para. 34</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85a75158e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>14</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00030" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027291812" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I668993b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Parrish &amp; Heimbecker Ltd. v. Delmar Commodities Ltd</ital>., 2012 CarswellMan 114, 2012 MBQB 48, at para. 39</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85a9c208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>15</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00031" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027291812" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I6689bac08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Parrish &amp; Heimbecker Ltd. v. Delmar Commodities Ltd</ital>., 2012 CarswellMan 114, 2012 MBQB 48</cite.query>, at paras. 44, 50 and 56.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85a9c218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>16</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00032" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1986268597" w-pub-number="0003986" ID="I668e9cc08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Hudson&apos;s Bay Co. v. McClocklin</ital>, [1986] 5 W.W.R. 29, 42 Man. R. (2d) 283 (Q.B.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00033" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1976148958" w-pub-number="0005652" ID="I668e9cc48e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Indal Ltd. v. Halko</ital></cite.query> (1976), 1 C.P.C. 121, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00034" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1976148958" w-pub-number="0005652" ID="I668e9cc58e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">28 C.P.R. (2d) 230 (Ont. H.C.J.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00035" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027659752" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I668e9cc78e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Corona Packaging Inc. v. Singh</ital>, 2012 CarswellOnt 5618, 2012 ONSC 2746</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85a9c228e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>17</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00036" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2000539618" w-pub-number="0005485" ID="I668eeae08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Apotex Fermentation Inc. v. Novopharm Ltd.</ital> (2000), 144 Man. R. (2d) 96, 4 C.P.R. (4th) 148 at p. 154 (Q.B.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85a9c238e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>18</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00037" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027659752" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I668f11f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Corona Packaging Inc. v. Singh</ital>, 2012 CarswellOnt 5618, 2012 ONSC 2746 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85a9c248e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>19</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00038" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027659752" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I668f39008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Corona Packaging Inc. v. Singh</ital>, 2012 CarswellOnt 5618, 2012 ONSC 2746 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>, at paras. 3–4, 7, 14–17.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85a9c258e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>20</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00039" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027659752" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I668f60108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Corona Packaging Inc. v. Singh</ital>, 2012 CarswellOnt 5618, 2012 ONSC 2746 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>, at paras. 32 and 41.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85a9c268e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>21</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00040" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027654193" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I668f87208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Fuller Western Rubber Linings Ltd. v. Spence Corrosion Services Ltd.</ital>, 2012 CarswellAlta 777, 2012 ABCA 137</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85a9c278e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>22</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00041" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027654193" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I668fae308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Fuller Western Rubber Linings Ltd. v. Spence Corrosion Services Ltd.</ital>, 2012 CarswellAlta 777, 2012 ABCA 137</cite.query>, at paras. 2 and 8.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85ac3308e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>23</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00042" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027654193" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I668ffc508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Fuller Western Rubber Linings Ltd. v. Spence Corrosion Services Ltd.</ital>, 2012 CarswellAlta 777, 2012 ABCA 137</cite.query>, at paras. 9–11.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85ac3318e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>24</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00043" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040515325" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I669023608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgetch HVAC Services Ltd. v. Ubhi</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 19341, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 103, 2016 ONSC 7564 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00044" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040956173" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I669023648e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellOnt 1753, 275 A.C.W.S. (3d) 706, 2017 ONSC 1004 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85ac3328e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>25</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00045" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040515325" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I66904a708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgetch HVAC Services Ltd. v. Ubhi</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 19341, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 103, 2016 ONSC 7564 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00046" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040956173" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I66904a748e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellOnt 1753, 275 A.C.W.S. (3d) 706, 2017 ONSC 1004 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 1–6.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85ac3338e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>26</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00047" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040515325" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I669098908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgetch HVAC Services Ltd. v. Ubhi</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 19341, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 103, 2016 ONSC 7564 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00048" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040956173" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I669098948e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellOnt 1753, 275 A.C.W.S. (3d) 706, 2017 ONSC 1004 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at para. 7.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85ac3348e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>27</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00049" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040515325" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6690bfa08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgetch HVAC Services Ltd. v. Ubhi</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 19341, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 103, 2016 ONSC 7564 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00050" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040956173" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6690bfa48e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellOnt 1753, 275 A.C.W.S. (3d) 706, 2017 ONSC 1004 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 9–10.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85ac3358e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>28</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00051" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040515325" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I66910dc08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgetch HVAC Services Ltd. v. Ubhi</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 19341, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 103, 2016 ONSC 7564 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00052" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040956173" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I66910dc48e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellOnt 1753, 275 A.C.W.S. (3d) 706, 2017 ONSC 1004 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 14–16.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85aea408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>29</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00053" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040515325" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I669134d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgetch HVAC Services Ltd. v. Ubhi</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 19341, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 103, 2016 ONSC 7564 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00054" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040956173" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I669134d48e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellOnt 1753, 275 A.C.W.S. (3d) 706, 2017 ONSC 1004 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at para. 28.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85aea418e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>30</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00055" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040515325" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I669182f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgetch HVAC Services Ltd. v. Ubhi</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 19341, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 103, 2016 ONSC 7564 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00056" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040956173" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I669182f48e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellOnt 1753, 275 A.C.W.S. (3d) 706, 2017 ONSC 1004 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 30–31, and 33.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85aea428e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>31</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00057" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040515325" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6691aa008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgetch HVAC Services Ltd. v. Ubhi</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 19341, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 103, 2016 ONSC 7564 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00058" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040956173" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6691aa048e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellOnt 1753, 275 A.C.W.S. (3d) 706, 2017 ONSC 1004 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at para. 34.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85aea438e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>32</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00059" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040515325" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6691f8208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgetch HVAC Services Ltd. v. Ubhi</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 19341, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 103, 2016 ONSC 7564 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00060" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040956173" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6691f8248e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellOnt 1753, 275 A.C.W.S. (3d) 706, 2017 ONSC 1004 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at para. 35.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85aea448e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>33</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00061" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040515325" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I66921f308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgetch HVAC Services Ltd. v. Ubhi</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 19341, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 103, 2016 ONSC 7564 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00062" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040956173" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I66921f348e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellOnt 1753, 275 A.C.W.S. (3d) 706, 2017 ONSC 1004 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 36, 38, and 40.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85aea458e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>34</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00063" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040515325" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I66926d508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgetch HVAC Services Ltd. v. Ubhi</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 19341, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 103, 2016 ONSC 7564 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00064" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040956173" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I66926d548e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellOnt 1753, 275 A.C.W.S. (3d) 706, 2017 ONSC 1004 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 43–45.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85aea468e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>35</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00065" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040515325" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6692bb708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgetch HVAC Services Ltd. v. Ubhi</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 19341, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 103, 2016 ONSC 7564 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00066" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040956173" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6692bb748e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellOnt 1753, 275 A.C.W.S. (3d) 706, 2017 ONSC 1004 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 46 and 50.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85b11508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>36</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00067" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040515325" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I669309908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgetch HVAC Services Ltd. v. Ubhi</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 19341, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 103, 2016 ONSC 7564 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00068" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040956173" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I669309948e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellOnt 1753, 275 A.C.W.S. (3d) 706, 2017 ONSC 1004 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at para. 51.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85b11518e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>37</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00069" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040845729" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I669330a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2158124 Ontario Inc. v. Pitton</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 1023, 2017 ONSC 411</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85b11528e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>38</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00070" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040845729" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I66937ec08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2158124 Ontario Inc. v. Pitton</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 1023, 2017 ONSC 411</cite.query>, at paras. 2–8, and 13.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85b11538e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>39</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00071" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040845729" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I66937ec38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2158124 Ontario Inc. v. Pitton</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 1023, 2017 ONSC 411, at para. 20</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85b11548e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>40</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00072" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040845729" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6693a5d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2158124 Ontario Inc. v. Pitton</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 1023, 2017 ONSC 411, at para. 24</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85b11558e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>41</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00073" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040845729" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6693f3f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2158124 Ontario Inc. v. Pitton</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 1023, 2017 ONSC 411</cite.query>, at paras. 26–28.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85b11568e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>42</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00074" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040845729" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I66941b008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2158124 Ontario Inc. v. Pitton</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 1023, 2017 ONSC 411</cite.query>, at paras. 65–66.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85b38608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>43</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00075" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040845729" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I669442108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2158124 Ontario Inc. v. Pitton</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 1023, 2017 ONSC 411</cite.query>, at paras. 68–70.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85b38618e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>44</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00076" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I669469208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc.</ital>, 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85b38628e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>45</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00077" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I669490308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc.</ital>, 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220</cite.query>, at paras. 2–4, and 8.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85b38638e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>46</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00078" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I6694b7408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc.</ital>, 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220, at para. 11</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85b38648e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>47</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00079" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I6694de508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc.</ital>, 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220</cite.query>, at paras. 53, and 55–56.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85b38658e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>48</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00080" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I669505608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc.</ital>, 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220, at para. 57</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85b38668e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>49</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00081" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I66952c708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc.</ital>, 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220</cite.query>, at paras. 62–63.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85b5f708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>50</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00082" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I669553808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc.</ital>, 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220, at para. 71</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85b5f718e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>51</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00083" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I66957a908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc.</ital>, 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220, at para. 205</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85b5f728e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>52</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00084" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I6695a1a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc.</ital>, 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220</cite.query>, at paras. 192–194.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85b5f738e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>53</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00085" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I6695c8b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc.</ital>, 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220</cite.query>, at paras. 195–196.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85b5f748e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>54</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00086" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I669616d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc.</ital>, 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220</cite.query>, at paras. 200–201.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85b5f758e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>55</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00087" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I66963de08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc.</ital>, 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220</cite.query>, at paras. 206.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85b5f768e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>56</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00088" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047090766" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I669664f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>SkyCope Technologies Inc. v. Jia</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 3343, 2018 BCSC 2204</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85b5f778e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>57</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00089" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047090766" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I66968c008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>SkyCope Technologies Inc. v. Jia</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 3343, 2018 BCSC 2204, at para. 1</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85b86808e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>58</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00090" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047090766" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I6696b3108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>SkyCope Technologies Inc. v. Jia</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 3343, 2018 BCSC 2204</cite.query>, at paras. 2–4.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85b86818e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>59</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00091" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047090766" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I6696da208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>SkyCope Technologies Inc. v. Jia</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 3343, 2018 BCSC 2204, at para. 5</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85b86828e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>60</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00092" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047090766" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I669701308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>SkyCope Technologies Inc. v. Jia</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 3343, 2018 BCSC 2204</cite.query>, at paras. 6–8.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85b86838e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>61</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00093" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047090766" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I669728408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>SkyCope Technologies Inc. v. Jia</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 3343, 2018 BCSC 2204, at para. 10</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85b86848e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>62</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00094" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047090766" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I66974f508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>SkyCope Technologies Inc. v. Jia</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 3343, 2018 BCSC 2204, at para. 12</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85b86858e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>63</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00095" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047090766" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I669776608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>SkyCope Technologies Inc. v. Jia</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 3343, 2018 BCSC 2204</cite.query>, at paras. 30–31.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85b86868e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>64</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00096" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047090766" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I66979d708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>SkyCope Technologies Inc. v. Jia</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 3343, 2018 BCSC 2204, at para. 32</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85bad908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>65</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00097" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047090766" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I6697c4808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>SkyCope Technologies Inc. v. Jia</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 3343, 2018 BCSC 2204, at para. 39</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85bad918e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>66</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00098" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I6697eb908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85bad928e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>67</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00099" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I669812a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176</cite.query>, at paras. 1–3, 5–6, and 18.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85bad938e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>68</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00100" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I669839b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176</cite.query>, at paras. 20–21.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85bad948e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>69</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00101" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I669887d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176</cite.query>, at paras. 22–23.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85bad958e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>70</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00102" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I6698aee08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176</cite.query>, at paras. 24–26.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85bad968e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>71</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00103" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I6698d5f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176, at para. 31</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85bad978e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>72</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00104" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I6698fd008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176, at para. 32</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85bd4a08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>73</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00105" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I669924108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176, at para. 33</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85bd4a18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>74</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00106" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I66994b208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176</cite.query>, at paras. 64–65.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85bd4a28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>75</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00107" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I669972308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176, at para. 66</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85bd4a38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>76</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00108" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I669999408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176, at para. 67</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85bd4a48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>77</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00109" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I6699c0508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176</cite.query>, at paras. 68–69, and 71.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85bd4a58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>78</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00110" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I6699e7608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176, at para. 73</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85bd4a68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>79</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00111" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I669a35808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176</cite.query>, at paras. 76 and 80.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85bfbb08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>80</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00112" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I669a5c908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176, at para. 83</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85bfbb18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>81</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00113" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I669a83a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity Corp.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1309, 2018 BCSC 857</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85bfbb28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>82</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00114" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I669a83a38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity Corp.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1309, 2018 BCSC 857, at para. 1</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85bfbb38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>83</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00115" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I669ad1c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity Corp.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1309, 2018 BCSC 857</cite.query>, at paras. 3, and 5–6.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85bfbb48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>84</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00116" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I669ad1c38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity Corp.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1309, 2018 BCSC 857, at para. 7</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85bfbb58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>85</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00117" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I669b1fe08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity Corp.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1309, 2018 BCSC 857</cite.query>, at paras. 11–12.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85bfbb68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>86</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00118" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I669b46f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity Corp.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1309, 2018 BCSC 857</cite.query>, at paras. 13–14, and 17–18.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85bfbb78e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>87</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00119" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I669b6e008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity Corp.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1309, 2018 BCSC 857</cite.query>, at paras. 19–20.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85c22c08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>88</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00120" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I669b95108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity Corp.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1309, 2018 BCSC 857</cite.query>, at paras. 21 and 23.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85c22c18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>89</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00121" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I669bbc208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity Corp.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1309, 2018 BCSC 857</cite.query>, at paras. 25–29.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85c22c28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>90</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00122" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I669c0a408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity Corp.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1309, 2018 BCSC 857</cite.query>, at paras. 34–35, and 37.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85c22c38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>91</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00123" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I669c31508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity Corp.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1309, 2018 BCSC 857, at para. 96</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85c22c48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>92</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00124" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I669c58608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity Corp.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1309, 2018 BCSC 857, at para. 97</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85c22c58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>93</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00125" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I669c58638e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity Corp.</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1309, 2018 BCSC 857, at para. 99</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85c22c68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>94</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00126" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044476992" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I669c7f708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Quick Pass Master Tutorial School Ltd. v. Zhao</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1038, 2018 BCSC 683</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85c22c78e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>95</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00127" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044476992" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I669ccd908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Quick Pass Master Tutorial School Ltd. v. Zhao</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1038, 2018 BCSC 683</cite.query>, at paras. 1 and 3.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85c49d08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>96</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00128" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044476992" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I669cf4a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Quick Pass Master Tutorial School Ltd. v. Zhao</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1038, 2018 BCSC 683, at para. 5</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85c49d18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>97</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00129" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044476992" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I669d1bb08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Quick Pass Master Tutorial School Ltd. v. Zhao</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1038, 2018 BCSC 683, at para. 25</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85c49d28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>98</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00130" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044476992" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I669d42c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Quick Pass Master Tutorial School Ltd. v. Zhao</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1038, 2018 BCSC 683, at para. 30</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85c49d38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>99</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00131" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044476992" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I669d69d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Quick Pass Master Tutorial School Ltd. v. Zhao</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1038, 2018 BCSC 683, at para. 50</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85c49d48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>100</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00132" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044476992" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I669d90e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Quick Pass Master Tutorial School Ltd. v. Zhao</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1038, 2018 BCSC 683, at para. 51</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id85c49d58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>101</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175958" w-seq-number="00133" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044476992" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I669db7f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Quick Pass Master Tutorial School Ltd. v. Zhao</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1038, 2018 BCSC 683, at para. 52</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 7:5<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
