<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 2:3<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I4e5fc390411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>2.</label.designator><headtext>Legal Bases Used by the Courts for the Protection of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I4e678bc0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>II.</label.designator><headtext>Property Theory</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f5c3066ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>2:3.</label.designator><headtext>Criticism—Information Is Not Scarce</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>It has been argued that confidential information should not be seen as a form of property, but, in order to further the interests of a competitive market, is better characterized using features of equity and the common law.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id0ade3608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>] The very fact that land is physical makes it a scarce resource: there is only a finite amount of land on earth. <eos/><bos/>Knowledge, on the other hand, is not a scarce resource. <eos/><bos/>It is infinite in time and space, and it can be shared by any number of people without depleting its value.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>However, although information itself may be infinite, the development of confidential business information requires the use of labour and skill, and this renders the information scarce and thus valuable. <eos/><bos/>Value is acquired by reason of the fact that the information is not accessible to and cannot be enjoyed by any except those to whom the creator of the idea chooses to impart the information. <eos/><bos/>This is true of all forms of intellectual property as there is an infinite number of expressions or forms of ideas just as there are of ideas themselves.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Id0ade3608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>D. Vaver, <begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>“Civil Liability: Trade Secrets in Canada”<end.quote refid="QT_0001"/> (1980-81), 5 C.B.L.J. 253 at pp. 261-2.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 2:3<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
