<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information ยง 8:1<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I59ba4210411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>8.</label.designator><headtext>Practical Advice for Protecting Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I59ba6920411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>I.</label.designator><headtext>Introduction</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f749a36ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>ยง </label.name><label.designator>8:1.</label.designator><headtext>Generally</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The purpose of this chapter is to provide practical advice for businesses seeking to protect their confidential information. <eos/><bos/>Many of the guidelines are general in nature, while others relate specifically to the employment relationship. <eos/><bos/>The recommendations should be adapted to meet the needs of the particular business or industry. <eos/><bos/>The recommendations are designed to:</paratext><list><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(a)</label.designator></head><paratext>assist in establishing procedures that will protect business information;</paratext></para></list.item><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(b)</label.designator></head><paratext>increase the likelihood that a court will view the information as confidential and thus offer legal protection;</paratext></para></list.item><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(c)</label.designator></head><paratext>ensure that the recipients of business information are aware of their legal obligations, including those which continue beyond the existing business or employment relationship; and</paratext></para></list.item><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(d)</label.designator></head><paratext>create and preserve evidence for use in legal proceedings.<eos/></paratext></para></list.item></list><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>As appropriate, the topics which follow should be addressed with management, employees, consultants, suppliers and others connected to one&apos;s business. <eos/><bos/>It is important to create a culture which will protect valuable business information. <eos/><bos/>Awareness, involvement and education are the key elements of any successful effort in this regard. <eos/><bos/>In fact, most security weaknesses concern issues which can be addressed easily and inexpensively, <ital>e.g.</ital>, securing sensitive information, enforcing existing security measures and ensuring awareness of policies. <eos/><bos/>Employers should not be hesitant to discuss these issues in the context of corporate transactions, negotiations, employee departures and other significant events.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Increasingly, competitors and even governments are using aggressive techniques and sophisticated technology to steal business information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id94c4f208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>] With the decline in loyalty associated with the traditional employment relationship, with increasing mobility and leverage on the part of employees, and with decreased job security, internal threats are likely to increase. <eos/><bos/>These factors, as well as the increasing importance of information to business, make it imperative that adequate steps be taken to preserve confidentiality.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Id94c4f208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>See generally, I. Winkler, <ital>Corporate Espionage</ital> (Rocklin, California: Prima Publishing, 1997).<eos/><bos/> There have been a number of highly publicized cases of alleged corporate espionage. <eos/><bos/>For example, in May 2001, U.S. Federal authorities charged two scientists working for Lucent Technologies Inc. with stealing product designs and passing them on to a Chinese government-owned company. <eos/><bos/>In the first conviction under the <ital>U.S. Economic Espionage Act</ital>, 1 USC, Ch. 2, a Taiwan-based company and two individuals were convicted of violating the Act by taking trade secrets from adhesive maker Avery Dennison Corp.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI ยง 8:1<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
