<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 4:41<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I5089a870411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>4.</label.designator><headtext>Confidential Business Information and the Employment Relationship</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I52517020411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>V.</label.designator><headtext>Fiduciary Duty</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I53a16fc0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>B.</label.designator><headtext>Remedies Table—Employment Relationship—Breach of Fiduciary Duty</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f65f526ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>4:41.</label.designator><headtext>M-I Drilling Fluids Canada, Inc v. Cottle</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><ital>M-I Drilling Fluids Canada, Inc v. Cottle</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 452, 2018 ABQB 143</headtext><eos/><eop/></head><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Award</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Disgorgement of profits in the amounts of $77,751.98 from IAL and $11,113.86</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Punitive damages of $12,000</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Summary of Facts</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Plaintiff alleged that between 2009 and 2013, Cottle took kickbacks from two of its suppliers. <eos/><bos/>In May 2009, Cottle became a business development manager for MID&apos;s Sulfatreat Unit. <eos/><bos/>Between May 1, 2009 and September 23, 2013, IAL was a supplier of Odour Control Systems to MID. <eos/><bos/>During this period, Cottle, on behalf of MID, signed purchase orders for Odour Control containers from IAL. <eos/><bos/>These purchase orders were countersigned by another MID employee. <eos/><bos/>IAL agreed to provide Cottle with a payment equal to 3-10% of the value of these purchase orders. <eos/><bos/>Cottle issued 117 invoices from CACI, the company owned by Cottle, to IAL for these payments. <eos/><bos/>CACI received payment for all but one of these invoices, the total amount paid being $77,751.98. <eos/><bos/>Indy was also a supplier of Odour Control containers to MID. <eos/><bos/>Cottle, on behalf of MID, signed purchase orders for Odour Control containers from Indy. <eos/><bos/>These purchase orders were countersigned by another MID employee. <eos/><bos/>Indy agreed that it would provide Cottle with a payment equal to 3-10% of the value of these purchase orders. <eos/><bos/>Cottle issued 7 invoices from CACI to Indy in respect of the purchase of Odour Control containers. <eos/><bos/>CACI received payment for all of these invoices, the total amount paid being $11,113.86. <eos/><bos/>On February 3, 2012, Cottle received and signed a written reprimand from MID regarding his receipt of a single payment from IAL. <eos/><bos/>Cottle understood that MID considered his taking this single payment to be a breach of the Code of Ethics. <eos/><bos/>Following this reprimand, Cottle continued to invoice IAL and Indy and to receive payments from them. <eos/><bos/>In April 2013, Cottle suffered a heart attack and went on a disability leave of absence. <eos/><bos/>During Cottle&apos;s absence, Karpovich discovered unmarked white binders in a credenza in Cottle&apos;s office which contained some of the invoices from CACI to IAL and Indy. <eos/><bos/>Based on this discovery of the payments received by Cottle through CACI, MID terminated Cottle&apos;s employment.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Reasons Given by Court for Award</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Jones observed that the courts must take a cautious approach in imposing fiduciary duties on employees. <eos/><bos/>Nevertheless, the case law is clear that fiduciary obligations may be imposed on “key” employees who, on the facts of the particular case, are in a position to affect the interests of their employers.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Jones concluded that Cottle was a key employee of MID. <eos/><bos/>He had substantial responsibility for the operation of the Sulfatreat unit and functioned quite autonomously. <eos/><bos/>While it was true that his purchase orders had to be countersigned, this did not appear to have imported a significant supervisory aspect. <eos/><bos/>Similarly, while there was no evidence that Cottle had access to the kind of confidential information so often discussed in the key employee cases, it was clear that he had the primary relationship with Sulfatreat&apos;s suppliers and possibly with its customers as well. <eos/><bos/>Justice Jones concluded that he was in a position to have a marked impact on MID&apos;s economic interests. <eos/><bos/>As a key employee, Cottle had a fiduciary obligation to act in MID&apos;s interests and to avoid placing his personal interests in conflict therewith. <eos/><bos/>He breached this obligation by taking the Payments.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Rather than the usual remedy of damages, MID sought disgorgement of the profits Cottle made from the Payments. <eos/><bos/>Justice Jones concluded that this was an appropriate case for the disgorgement of profits remedy. <eos/><bos/>Cottle had, and breached, a fiduciary duty and it would be inequitable to permit him to retain the benefits he obtained through that breach. <eos/><bos/>The full amount of the Payments both before and after the 2012 warning must be disgorged. <eos/><bos/>Cottle did not dispute that he obtained Payments in the amounts of $77,751.98 from IAL and $11,113.86 from Indy.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Cottle argued that MID should be precluded from obtaining disgorgement of the Payments by the doctrine of estoppel by representation and/or estoppel by conduct. <eos/><bos/>Estoppel requires a positive representation by one party with the intention that it be relied upon by the other and action by the second party in reliance on that representation such that it would be inequitable to allow the first party to resile from it. <eos/><bos/>Cottle asserted that he relied on the representations made by MID in both the 2012 warning letter and the 2013 termination letter. <eos/><bos/>The 2012 warning letter stated that <begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>“failure to conform to company policies and procedures in the future will lead to further disciplinary actions up to and including termination of employment.”<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0001"/> The 2013 letter stated that his position with MID was terminated immediately. <eos/><bos/>Neither letter made any reference to recovery of the Payments. <eos/><bos/>Cottle&apos;s position was that, because there was no such reference, he believed that termination of his employment was the full extent of the potential repercussions of his conduct. <eos/><bos/>Justice Jones rejected these submissions. <eos/><bos/>The 2012 warning letter was issued to Cottle when he was still an employee of MID and was intended to alter his behaviour, rather than to waive any remedies available to MID. <eos/><bos/>Further, Cottle did not have clean hands. <eos/><bos/>Justice Jones rejected his argument that he had permission to accept the Payments and found he was well aware that his conduct was dishonest. <eos/><bos/>It would not be appropriate to relieve him of the consequences, notwithstanding that they may be greater than he anticipated. <eos/><bos/>Cottle made the decision to engage in dishonest conduct because he calculated that it was “worth the risk”.<eos/><bos/> Though he may have miscalculated, he must bear the consequences of the risk he chose to run.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>An award of punitive damages was appropriate. <eos/><bos/>Cottle engaged in a course of conduct that he knew was wrongful, even after having been expressly warned against it. <eos/><bos/>To limit the consequences to the relinquishment of his ill-gotten gains would be insufficient to achieve the goal of punishment and deterrence. <eos/><bos/>In Justice Jones&apos; view, the $50,000 sought by MID was excessive. <eos/><bos/>While Cottle&apos;s conduct was certainly perfidious, his intent was to profit himself rather than to injure MID. <eos/><bos/>Thus, the malice that drove the award in Hill was absent. <eos/><bos/>Justice Jones awarded punitive damages in the amount of $12,000. <eos/><bos/>This amount represented a reasonable proportion of the overall damages award and was sufficient to express the Court&apos;s disapprobation of Cottle&apos;s conduct, but was not irrationally high.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></section.body></section><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 4:41<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
