<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 7:13<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I56d26460411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>7.</label.designator><headtext>Remedies for Breach of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I56dbb330411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>II.</label.designator><headtext>Equitable Relief</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I588e9350411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>D.</label.designator><headtext>Anton Piller Order</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f722966ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>7:13.</label.designator><headtext>Generally</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>An Anton Piller order provides immediate relief to the moving party prior to trial and sometimes prior to the commencement of legal proceedings. <eos/><bos/>It enables the moving party to enter the premises of the respondent without notice and to inspect and remove materials identified by the order.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8a190308e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>] It is usually granted on the belief that the respondent is in possession of documents that infringe on the moving party&apos;s right to confidential information and that there is reason to believe the documents would be destroyed, hidden or taken away if the respondent were given notice of the applicant&apos;s request for the documents.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The three conditions that must be met before an Anton Piller order can be granted are:</paratext><list><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(1)</label.designator></head><paratext>The plaintiff must have an extremely strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case.<eos/><bos/></paratext></para></list.item><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(2)</label.designator></head><paratext>The potential or actual damage to the plaintiff must be very serious.<eos/><bos/></paratext></para></list.item><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(3)</label.designator></head><paratext>There must be clear evidence that the defendant possesses incriminating evidence and that there is a real possibility such evidence may be destroyed before an application, on notice, is heard.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8a190318e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></list.item></list><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Since an Anton Piller order is made <ital>in camera</ital> and <ital>ex parte</ital>, the applicant has a duty to fully disclose all material facts. <eos/><bos/>Failure to do so may result in discharge of the order. <eos/><bos/>In addition, as with an interlocutory injunction, the applicant must file an undertaking to compensate the defendant for damages that might result from execution of the order.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Columbia Picture Industries Inc. v. Robinson</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id8a190328e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">3</footnote.reference>] the court stressed the necessity of full disclosure by the applicant for an Anton Piller order, suggesting that any errors in this respect ought to be made on the side of excessive disclosure:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>Any plaintiff seeking an Anton Piller order must place before the court all the information they have … which … points to the probability that in the absence of an Anton Piller order material which should be available will disappear.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0001"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id8a1b7408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">4</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><paratext>This court also concluded that when a defendant seeks to set aside an Anton Piller order obtained by inadequate disclosure, the application to do so must be made within a reasonable time after execution of the order.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In the case of <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175966" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1982168313" w-pub-number="0005505" ID="I6d1d3b518e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Bardeau Ltd. v. Crown Food Services Equipment</cite.query> Ltd.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id8a1b7418e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">5</footnote.reference>] three former employees of the plaintiff allegedly led a slowdown in the plaintiff&apos;s production and, when terminated, departed with many drawings and sketches of various products. <eos/><bos/>There was strong evidence indicating the materials were later incorporated into the products of the corporate defendant. <eos/><bos/>As well, the plans for products filed by the defendant with the Ministry of Consumer and Corporate affairs were strikingly similar to those of the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>Furthermore, the past conduct of the defendants revealed their disregard for the plaintiff&apos;s rights and a serious risk they would destroy the evidence in their possession if it was not maintained for the coming action. <eos/><bos/>It was clear that an extremely strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case existed. <eos/><bos/>The damage already incurred by the plaintiff was serious, and on these three grounds, the order was granted.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>When an Anton Piller order is granted, the plaintiff&apos;s legal councel should serve the order on the defendant and explain its significance, after which every opportunity should be given to the defendant to consult with a lawyer before the order is executed. <eos/><bos/>A list of items seized should be kept, and the documents should be retained by a neutral officer.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8a1b7428e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">6</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Although the courts take measures to ensure that Anton Piller orders are only granted in exceptional cases, one judge has commented that <begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>“a valid argument might well be made against any such general disclosure order being granted in the future, even where a general right to search by ‘Anton Piller’ order is being allowed”<end.quote refid="QT_0002"/>.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8a1b7438e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">7</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>2298679 <cite.query w-src-number="0492175966" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6d2244618e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc.</cite.query> et al.</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id8a1b7448e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">8</footnote.reference>] the Plaintiff 229 moved, without notice, for an <cite.query w-src-number="0492175966" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1975027495" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I6d2244648e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Anton Piller</ital></cite.query> Order to search and seize electronic devices from the headquarters of the Defendant Northern Homecare and from the residence of the Defendant Goldkind, who was one of the principles of Northern Homecare. <eos/><bos/>Aurum Property also requested an injunction restraining Northern Homecare, Goldkind and the other Defendants, prohibiting them from possessing or transmitting Aurum&apos;s confidential customer information in any form or through any medium whatsoever. <eos/><bos/>Justice Perell dismissed the motion for an <cite.query w-src-number="0492175966" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1975027495" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I6d2244668e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Anton Piller</ital></cite.query> Order, and granted an interim injunction and mandatory order that was to terminate ten days after the release of the Reasons for Decision.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8a1b7458e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">9</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Aurum was an industry leader in commercial window cleaning and property maintenance servicing government buildings, commercial high-rise buildings, condominium towers, hotels and hospitals across North America. <eos/><bos/>It also serviced residences and had a customer list of residential customers and leads numbering 35,000 contacts. <eos/><bos/>Aurum maintains a customer list that included: customer names, customer addresses, customer email addresses and details of past services including dates and prices.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8a1b7468e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">10</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Northern Homecare&apos;s executive included Goldkind, and Goldman. <eos/><bos/>Goldkind was the CEO and Goldman was the COO. <eos/><bos/>Northern Homecare carried on a residential window cleaning and property maintenance business.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8a1b7478e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">11</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Arous, Edward, and Hyde were former employees of Aurum. <eos/><bos/>Arous was employed as field business development representative from April 1, 2018 to July 6, 2018, when his employment was terminated. <eos/><bos/>Edwards was first employed as a field business development representative and was promoted to outbound business development representative. <eos/><bos/>He was employed from April 1, 2018 to August 2, 2018, when his employment was terminated. <eos/><bos/>Hyde was employed as a field business manager from May 1, 2017 to August 25, 2018 when he was terminated. <eos/><bos/>Arous, Edward, and Hyde signed employment agreements. <eos/><bos/>The agreements contained the confidentiality and non-disclosure provisions. <eos/><bos/>During their employment, Arous, Edward, and Hyde had access to Aurum&apos;s residential customer lists.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8a1de508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">12</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Although Aurum was not aware of it at the time: (a) after Arous was terminated, he logged into Aurum&apos;s management software, which contains Aurum&apos;s customer list, on August 29, 2018, December 13, 2018, February 5, 2019, and March 15, 19, and 26, 2019; (b) after Edwards was terminated, he logged into Aurum&apos;s management software twice on March 5, 2019, and again on March 26, 2019; and (c) after Hyde was terminated he logged into Aurum&apos;s management software on at least thirty occasions. <eos/><bos/>Aurum did not know: (a) the extent of information that was obtained by Arous, Edward, and Hyde; (b) how the information was used; and (c) with whom the information was shared. <eos/><bos/>Aurum conceded that the extent of the confidential information allegedly misappropriated by the Defendants would be an important facet of Aurum&apos;s damages claim.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8a1de518e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">13</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Up until eight months after it had terminated the employment of Arous, Edward, and Hyde, Aurum had no knowledge of these intrusions on its computer system. <eos/><bos/>In March and April 2019, however, there were a series of events that prompted Aurum to investigate: a. Customers DD, OA, ED, and AS cancelled appointments because they had already been contacted by persons presenting themselves as being Aurum. <eos/><bos/>Based on the information provided by these customers; b. Customer ND advised Arum that she had been contacted by persons presenting themselves as being Aurum. <eos/><bos/>She did not cancel her contract with Aurum. <eos/><bos/>Aurum inferred that Northern Homecare was using information provided by Arous, Edward, and Hyde to contact ND. c. Customer DS advised Aurum that he had been contacted by Goldkind who misrepresented himself as representing a reorganized Aurum. <eos/><bos/>Goldkind disparaged Arum as it had formerly existed. <eos/><bos/>DS advised Aurum of the contact. <eos/><bos/>Goldkind was lying and Aurum inferred that the wrongdoing of Goldkind was a spinoff of Arous, Edward, and Hydes&apos; disclosing confidential information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8a1de528e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">14</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Aurum suspected but did not actually know that Arous, Edward, and Hyde provided confidential information to Northern Homecare because Aurum customers reported that when solicited by Northern Homecare, the Northern Homecare representative had knowledge of past services provided to the customer.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8a1de538e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">15</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>It was not clear, however, what is the precise relationship or connection between Northern Homecare and the three former employees, who might have a connection as employees, independent contractors, dependent contractors, sales agents, or intermediators.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8a1de548e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">16</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Perell concluded that while there appeared to have been wrongdoing, most likely by Goldkind and Goldman, it was not clear whether the harm they caused was trivial or substantial. <eos/><bos/>It appeared that it was only an inference that the three former employees stole the whole data base of customer information. <eos/><bos/>However, it was not clear whether the three former employees did anything more than inform Northern Homecare of a few contacts and that Northern Homecare used those few contacts to compete for business in a wrongful way when they should and could have competed for the customers in a lawful way. <eos/><bos/>On the other hand, it was not known whether more than a few of Aurum&apos;s customers were contacted and whether Northern Homecare was more than a minor nuisance and a major threat to Aurum&apos;s residential business. <eos/><bos/>In any event, at this juncture, there was no evidence to suggest that Northern Homecare or Goldkind had Aurum&apos;s customer list on its computers or that there was reason to believe that they would destroy that evidence.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8a1de558e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">17</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Perell noted that under their employment contracts, Arous, Edward, and Hydes&apos; obligations with respect to Confidential Information did not apply to information that they could demonstrate was generally available to or known by the public other than as a result of improper disclosure to them. <eos/><bos/>At this juncture, it was impossible to say that they had no defence to a breach of contract claim for the conduct of passing on information to Northern Homecare if that was what they did.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8a1de568e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">18</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Perell was satisfied that Aurum had presented a serious issue to be tried about whether the Arous, Edward, and Hyde and whether the Defendants committed the tort of breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>Although Aurum established a <ital>prima facie</ital> case for breach of confidence with an associated claim of breach of contract, it remained to be seen whether this was a case of former employees attempting to use the knowledge and experience they gained in their former employment for the purpose of earning a living with a new employer. <eos/><bos/>There was, in any event, a serious issue to be tried.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8a205608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">19</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Aurum asserted that it had and would suffer irreparable harm because of the wrongful activities of the Defendants and it submitted that its ability to sell its residential branch had been diminished. <eos/><bos/>However, there was no evidence about Aurum&apos;s actual plans for its residential branch. <eos/><bos/>Thus, the situation with respect to irreparable harm was that at this juncture Aurum had established only a significant possibility of harm from a breach of confidence or a breach of contract. <eos/><bos/>In this regard, it was noted that at the time of the <ital>ex parte</ital> injunction motion, Aurum had only discovered the alleged wrongdoing less than a month before. <eos/><bos/>Justice Perell observed that it was a close call on irreparable harm, but nevertheless concluded that for the purposes of an interim, ten-day, injunction that Aurum had suffered irreparable harm and that the balance of convenience favours granting an interim injunction.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8a205618e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">20</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Perell explained that an <cite.query w-src-number="0492175966" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1975027495" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I6d2cf2c18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Anton Piller</ital></cite.query> order is a very intrusive and exceptional interlocutory order. <eos/><bos/>The purpose of the order is to prevent property from being lost, destroyed or removed, and to preserve relevant evidence, but it does not authorize access to privileged communications of documents. <eos/><bos/>An <cite.query w-src-number="0492175966" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1975027495" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I6d2cf2c38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Anton Piller</ital></cite.query> order is at the extremity of the court&apos;s powers and is granted only when there is no alternative way to ensure that justice may be done. <eos/><bos/>The requirements for an <cite.query w-src-number="0492175966" w-seq-number="00007" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1975027495" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I6d2cf2c58e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Anton Piller</ital></cite.query> order are: (1) there must be an extremely strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case; (2) the damage, potential or actual, must be very serious for the plaintiff; (3) there must be convincing evidence that the defendant has in his or her possession incriminating documents or objects; and (4) there is a real possibility that the material may be destroyed or secreted before the parties may put their respective rights before the court. <eos/><bos/>An <cite.query w-src-number="0492175966" w-seq-number="00008" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1975027495" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I6d2cf2c78e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Anton Piller</ital></cite.query> order is an exceptional remedy and should be granted only on clear and convincing evidence.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8a205628e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">21</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>With respect to the claim for an <cite.query w-src-number="0492175966" w-seq-number="00009" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1975027495" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I6d3298118e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Anton Piller</ital></cite.query> order Justice Perell was of the opinion that there was not an extremely strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case as against Arous, Edward, Hyde, and Goldman but Aurum was not requesting an <cite.query w-src-number="0492175966" w-seq-number="00010" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1975027495" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I6d3298138e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Anton Piller</ital></cite.query> order as against them. <eos/><bos/>Justice Perell regarded the case as against Northern Homecare and Goldkind for injurious falsehood as strong but not extremely strong. <eos/><bos/>Thus, Aurum did not satisfy the criteria for an <cite.query w-src-number="0492175966" w-seq-number="00011" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1975027495" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I6d3298158e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Anton Piller</ital></cite.query> Order. <eos/><bos/>Remembering that it was Arous, Edward, and Hyde that obtained the customer information, that the extent of the information obtained was unknown, and that there was only an inference that they passed the information to Northern Homecare, it was entirely speculative that Northern Homecare had incriminating evidence or that there was any possibility, let alone a real possibility, that material might be destroyed or secreted before the parties put their respective rights before the court. <eos/><bos/>Moreover, an <cite.query w-src-number="0492175966" w-seq-number="00012" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1975027495" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I6d3298178e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Anton Piller</ital></cite.query> order is at the extremity of the court&apos;s powers and is granted only when there is no alternative way to ensure that justice may be done. <eos/><bos/>In the immediate case, there were reasonable alternatives that would protect Aurum for the potential loss of evidence. <eos/><bos/>Therefore, Justice Perell ordered as follows: a. Goldkind and Northern Homecare shall retain any confidential information of Aurum in their possession including, without limitation, customer lists, employee lists, partnership lists, supplier contracts, customer contracts, pricing policies, patents, trademarks, and other intellectual property; and b. Goldkind and Northern Homecare shall disclose to Aurum in an Affidavit of Documents any confidential information of Aurum in their possession including, without limitation, Aurum&apos;s customer lists, employee lists, partnership lists, supplier contracts, customer contracts, pricing policies, patents, trademarks, and other intellectual property.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8a205638e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">22</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Id8a190308e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175966" w-seq-number="00013" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1975027495" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I6d32e6308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Anton Piller K.G. v. Manufacturing Processes Ltd.</ital>, [1976] 1 All E.R. 779 (C.A.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8a190318e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175966" w-seq-number="00014" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1982170812" w-pub-number="0005505" ID="I6d35f3708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Bardeau Ltd. v. Crown Food Service Equipment Ltd.</ital> (1982), 36 O.R. (2d) 355</cite.query>, 26 C.P.C. 297 (H.C.J.); <cite.query w-src-number="0492175966" w-seq-number="00015" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1982168313" w-pub-number="0005505" ID="I6d35f3728e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Bardeau Ltd. v. Crown Food Services Equipment Ltd.</ital> (1982), 38 O.R. (2d) 411, 26</cite.query> C.P.C. at p. 306 (H.C.J.); <cite.query w-src-number="0492175966" w-seq-number="00016" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1985031246" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I6d35f3748e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Columbia Picture Industries Inc. v. Robinson</ital>, [1986] 3 All E.R. 338 (Ch.), at pp. 351–78</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175966" w-seq-number="00017" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2002513740" w-pub-number="0003986" ID="I6d35f3768e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Netsmart Inc. v. Poelzer</ital>, [2003] 1 W.W.R. 698</cite.query>, 20 C.C.E.L. (3d) 195, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175966" w-seq-number="00018" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2002513740" w-pub-number="0006457" ID="I6d35f3788e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2002 ABQB 800 (Q.B.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8a190328e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175966" w-seq-number="00019" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1985031246" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I6d3a39308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Columbia Picture Industries Inc. v. Robinson</ital>, [1986] 3 All E.R. 338 (Ch.), at pp. 351 and 372</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8a1b7408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>4</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175966" w-seq-number="00020" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1985031246" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I6d4424408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Columbia Picture Industries Inc. v. Robinson</ital>, [1986] 3 All E.R. 338 (Ch.), at p. 372</cite.query>, citing <cite.query w-src-number="0492175966" w-seq-number="00021" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1985031272" w-pub-number="0004728" ID="I6d4424428e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jeffrey Rogers Knitwear Productions Ltd. v. Vinola (Knitwear) Manufacturing Co.</ital>, [1985] F.S.R. 184 (Ch.), at p. 189</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8a1b7418e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>5</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175966" w-seq-number="00022" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1982170812" w-pub-number="0005505" ID="I6d4472608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Bardeau Ltd. v. Crown Food Services Equipment Ltd.</ital> (1982), 36 O.R. (2d) 355</cite.query>, 26 C.P.C. 297 (H.C.J.); <cite.query w-src-number="0492175966" w-seq-number="00023" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1982168313" w-pub-number="0005505" ID="I6d4472628e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Bardeau Ltd. v. Crown Food Services Equipment Ltd.</ital> (1982), 38 O.R. (2d) 411, 26</cite.query> C.P.C. at p. 306 (H.C.J.).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8a1b7428e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>6</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175966" w-seq-number="00024" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1985031246" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I6d4499708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Columbia Picture Industries Inc. v. Robinson</ital>, [1986] 3 All E.R. 338 (Ch.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8a1b7438e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>7</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175966" w-seq-number="00025" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1983172986" w-pub-number="0005652" ID="I6d46e3608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Chin-Can Communication Corp. v. Chinese Video Centre Ltd.</ital> (1983), 70 C.P.R. (2d) 184 (F.C.T.D.), at p. 189</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8a1b7448e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>8</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175966" w-seq-number="00026" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6d470a708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8a1b7458e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>9</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175966" w-seq-number="00027" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6d4731808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055</cite.query>, at paras. 1–2.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8a1b7468e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>10</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175966" w-seq-number="00028" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6d4758908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055</cite.query>, at paras. 8–9.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8a1b7478e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>11</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175966" w-seq-number="00029" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6d477fa08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055, at para. 10</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8a1de508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>12</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175966" w-seq-number="00030" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6d47cdc08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055</cite.query>, at paras. 11–13.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8a1de518e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>13</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175966" w-seq-number="00031" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6d47f4d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055</cite.query>, at paras. 14–15.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8a1de528e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>14</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175966" w-seq-number="00032" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6d481be08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055, at para. 16</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8a1de538e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>15</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175966" w-seq-number="00033" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6d4842f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055, at para. 17</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8a1de548e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>16</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175966" w-seq-number="00034" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6d486a008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055, at para. 19</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8a1de558e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>17</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175966" w-seq-number="00035" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6d4891108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055</cite.query>, at paras. 3–6.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8a1de568e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>18</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175966" w-seq-number="00036" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6d48b8208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055, at para. 21</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8a205608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>19</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175966" w-seq-number="00037" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6d48df308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055</cite.query>, at paras. 27–30.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8a205618e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>20</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175966" w-seq-number="00038" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6d4906408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055</cite.query>, at paras. 31–32.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8a205628e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>21</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175966" w-seq-number="00039" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6d492d508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055, at para. 35</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8a205638e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>22</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175966" w-seq-number="00040" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I6d4954608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055</cite.query>, at paras. 37 and 39–40.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 7:13<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
