<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 4:38<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I5089a870411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>4.</label.designator><headtext>Confidential Business Information and the Employment Relationship</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I52517020411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>V.</label.designator><headtext>Fiduciary Duty</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I53a16fc0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>B.</label.designator><headtext>Remedies Table—Employment Relationship—Breach of Fiduciary Duty</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f65f496ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>4:38.</label.designator><headtext>Metalworks Canada Ltd. v. Warrack</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><ital>Metalworks Canada Ltd. v. Warrack</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 1136, 2018 ABQB 443</headtext><eos/><eop/></head><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Award</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Plaintiffs were granted judgment as against Warrack: (i) in favour of Metalworks in the amount of $905,624 in conversion and/or oppression relating to the misappropriated funds plus judgment interest on those amounts; (ii) in favour of 136 in the amount of $61,270 in conversion and/or oppression relating to the misappropriated funds plus judgment interest on those amounts; (iii) in favour of Metalworks in the amount of $802,000 relating to the theft of a corporate opportunity and breach of fiduciary and statutory duties, plus judgment interest on that amount from the date of the closing of the sale from 128 to 136; (iv) punitive damages of $250,000; and as against 128: (i) in favour of Metalworks in the amount of $610,628 in conspiracy relating to misappropriated funds plus judgment interest on those amounts; (ii) in favour of 136 in the amount of $61,270 in conspiracy relating to the misappropriated funds plus judgment interest on those amounts; (iii) in favour of Metalworks and 136 in the amount of $802,000 in conspiracy relating to the theft of corporate opportunity and/or breach of fiduciary and statutory duties plus judgment interest from the date of the closing of the sale from 128 to 136.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Summary of Facts</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Plaintiffs claimed that Metalworks hired Warrack in 2003 to act as its Vice President, Finance, and that sometime between then and early 2012, he began making illegitimate payments from Metalworks&apos; bank accounts to pay for personal expenses. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiffs alleged that Warrack did this by disguising personal expenses to look like legitimate business expenses, and failing to set them off against the total annual compensation allocated to him in his shareholder agreement. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiffs also claimed that Warrack paid Metalworks&apos; funds to his wife even though she was not an employee or a shareholder of the company. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiffs hired independent forensic accountants to review Metalworks&apos; finances, and discovered that Warrack had allegedly misappropriated a total of more than $1 million, none of which has been repaid. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiffs claimed that as a result of the financial investigation, they also discovered that Warrack had violated his duties to Metalworks and its shareholders when Metalworks&apos; business premises were sold in 2006 and again in 2007, and that Warrack allegedly made a secret profit. <eos/><bos/>In 2006, the owner of the building in which Metalworks&apos; business premises were located advised that it was planning to sell the two units that Metalworks was leasing. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiffs alleged that Metalworks discussed with Warrack the possibility of buying the units, and that Warrack advised Metalworks that it could not afford to buy them. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiffs claim that after this conversation, Warrack and his wife incorporated 128 without Metalworks&apos; knowledge, and then 128 bought the units. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiffs alleged that 128 used Metalworks&apos; money to make the initial deposit on the purchase, without Metalworks&apos; knowledge or approval. <eos/><bos/>In 2007, Metalworks&apos; directors, including Warrack, incorporated 136 for the purpose of buying Metalworks&apos; business premises. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiffs claim that they had no knowledge that 136 bought the units from 128, and not from the original owner, or that 128 was Warrack&apos;s company. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiffs alleged that Warrack, through 128, made a secret profit of $800,000 in breach of his fiduciary duties to Metalworks and 136. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiffs alleged that part of the secret profit was a purchase price that was higher than fair market value because they relied on Warrack to negotiate on their behalf, and did not know that he was “negotiating” with himself as a representative of 128.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Reasons Given by Court for Award</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge concluded that Warrack was liable for theft of a corporate opportunity. <eos/><bos/>As director of Metalworks, Warrack owed a duty of loyalty and good faith to Metalworks, and to advance Metalworks&apos; best interests. <eos/><bos/>Specifically, he was under a duty not to usurp or divert a maturing business opportunity of the company to himself or another party with which he is associated. <eos/><bos/>The opportunity was offered to Metalworks as an existing tenant. <eos/><bos/>Metalworks&apos; name was on the original purchase agreement. <eos/><bos/>The building was integrally related to Metalworks&apos; business i.e. buying its own premises. <eos/><bos/>Metalworks made no informed rejection of this opportunity. <eos/><bos/>At the time in question: 1. Waldner did not know that Metalworks could afford to pay the deposit which was in fact paid by Warrack using Metalworks&apos; funds. 2. Waldner did not know that Warrack had misappropriated $78,000 in funds from Metalworks from 2004 to 2006. 3. This amount was likely higher in 2005 and 2006. 4. Waldner did not know Warrack and his wife were behind 128. <eos/><bos/>Only a few months later investors came into the Metalworks company. <eos/><bos/>They invested $460,000 to Metalworks which could have easily financed the purchase. <eos/><bos/>Good faith efforts to find investors a few months earlier might well have caused Metalworks to consummate the corporate opportunity that 128 stole from it. 5. The reason why Metalworks did not have more of the down payment or equity was because Warrack had improperly taken more than $78,000 from Metalworks prior to the sale.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge observed that the Defendants made the point that Metalworks was financially unable to purchase the building units. <eos/><bos/>This did not allow Warrack, through 128, to take this opportunity without full disclosure to Metalworks and Metalworks would have had to clearly reject it. <eos/><bos/>Warrack must therefore account for the profits obtained from the transaction of $802,000.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Apart from the duties owed by Warrack to Metalworks on the purchase by 128, Warrack also owed separate duties on the sale to 136. <eos/><bos/>As both a director of 136 and Metalworks, Warrack owed fiduciary and statutory duties to fully disclose his interest in any transactions involving Metalworks or 136. <eos/><bos/>Section 120 (1) of the ABCA required Warrack to disclose his interest in the transaction in writing or to ensure that such interest was reflected in the Corporate Minutes. <eos/><bos/>Under Section 120 (9) failing to make such disclosure makes Warrack liable to account to the corporate Plaintiffs for his profit. <eos/><bos/>Apart from his duties under the ABCA Warrack also owed fiduciary duties to 136 to avoid conflicts of interest and disclose his interest in any transaction to the company. <eos/><bos/>Warrack did none of these. <eos/><bos/>He failed in his required duties and he was also liable on this ground to account to the Plaintiffs for earning an $802,000 profit.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Warrack&apos;s conduct in creating, carrying out, and concealing his scheme to misappropriate funds and make a secret profit was worthy of the Court&apos;s denunciation. <eos/><bos/>An award of punitive damages against Warrack was given in the amount of $250,000.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></section.body></section><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 4:38<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
