<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 3:5<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I4ed25b80411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>3.</label.designator><headtext>Defining Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I4eeaec90411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>II.</label.designator><headtext>Information Capable of Protection</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I4eecc150411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>A.</label.designator><headtext>The “Confidential” Nature of the Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f5ea1c6ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>3:5.</label.designator><headtext>The Quality of Confidence</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The central factor used to determine whether information is confidential is whether the information is actually held in confidence.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id1f753508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>] Information is not confidential simply because it is not public.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id1f753518e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>] In most cases, the information must be kept private.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id1f753528e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">3</footnote.reference>] In <cite.query w-src-number="0492175836" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2016311598" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I16da8f418e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Innovative Health Group Inc. v. Calgary Health Region</ital></cite.query>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id1f77a608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">4</footnote.reference>] where patients received both privately and publicly funded health treatment and where the information was in one hybrid file, the information on hard drives could be subject to protection only where a party was deliberately deleting relevant information. <eos/><bos/>The primary characteristic of such information is that it is generally <begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>“inaccessible”[<footnote.reference refid="Id1f77a618e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">5</footnote.reference>] to the public or to others within the relevant sphere.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id1f77a628e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">6</footnote.reference>] <ital>Saltman Engineering Co. v. Campbell Engineering Co.</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id1f77a638e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">7</footnote.reference>] is frequently cited by Canadian courts with approval. <eos/><bos/>In that case, Lord Greene set forth a general definition of confidential information:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>I think that I shall not be stating the principle wrongly, if I say this with regard to the use of confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The information, to be confidential, must, I apprehend, apart from contract, <ital>have the necessary quality of confidence about it, namely, it must not be something which is public property and public knowledge</ital>.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0002"/></paratext></para></display.quote><paratext>(Emphasis added.)<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0001"/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175836" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2043111788" w-pub-number="0007659" ID="I16dc3cf18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Brand Name Marketing Inc. v. Rogers Communications</cite.query> Inc.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id1f7a1708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">8</footnote.reference>] Justice Wilton-Spiegel observed that an important issue in respect of information, data and analysis provided to Rogers in respect of a marketing concept referred to as the “Pink Phone program” was whether the alleged confidential information had <begin.quote ID="QT_0003"/>“the necessary quality of confidence about it”<end.quote refid="QT_0003"/>. <eos/><bos/>The information fell into three broad categories: (1) a marketing concept; (2) two marketing programs to implement the marketing concept, being the Pink Phone and the Call for the Cure programs; and (3) information pertaining to the results of the survey.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id1f7a1718e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">9</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The marketing concept was that an affinity marketing program, under which a percentage of on-going long-term airtime contracts would be donated to a breast cancer charity, would create a favourable customer attachment to the offeror of the program, which the plaintiff characterized as “emotional insurance”, that would induce Rogers existing customers to extend or purchase new long-term airtime contracts as well as attract new customers. <eos/><bos/>A critical feature of this affinity marketing proposal was that it was alleged that this “emotional insurance” would result in a reduced churn rate and a lower cost of acquisition in respect of such contracts as well as in respect of contracts with new customers. <eos/><bos/>Rogers&apos; wireless product at the time was a three-year airtime contract. <eos/><bos/>Its marketing efforts were designed to attract new customers willing to commit to such contracts and to retain those customers as their contracts expired. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff&apos;s concept of affinity marketing with a breast cancer charity was also focused on selling such airtime contracts and retaining such customers beyond the term of their contracts. <eos/><bos/>It offered a marketing explanation of why customers would overcome a resistance to commit to a long-term contract, or to renew a contract upon expiration, in terms of a continuing emotional attachment based on the affinity relationship or “emotional insurance”.<eos/><bos/> The plaintiff conceived that this affinity relationship would reduce both the churn rate of Rogers&apos; existing and future customer base, as well as the cost of acquisition and retention. <eos/><bos/>In this marketing concept, the sale of cellphones was a relatively minimal component.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id1f7a1728e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">10</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>An important question to be addressed was the extent to which the information was to be regarded as “confidential information” for the purpose of the claim of breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>The information to be kept confidential must have the necessary quality of confidence about it and must not be something which is public property and public knowledge. <eos/><bos/>Justice Wilton-Siegel observed that it was tempting to suggest that, to be confidential information, the information must be of value to the recipient such that the recipient can use it to the recipient&apos;s profit with the benefit resulting therefrom to be shared in some manner between the provider and the recipient. <eos/><bos/>Justice Wilton-Siegel concluded that the information provided to Rogers had not been demonstrated to have been of value to Rogers. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, if it were open to the Court, Justice Wilton-Siegel would have found that the information did not qualify as confidential information. <eos/><bos/>However, Justice Wilton-Spiegel conceded that equity has set a relatively low threshold on what kinds of information are capable of constituting confidential information and that <begin.quote ID="QT_0004"/>“some product of the human brain applied to existing knowledge”<end.quote refid="QT_0004"/> could suffice. <eos/><bos/>In particular, Cadbury-Schweppes suggests that even information of little or no actual value may qualify as confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The value of the information will, instead, be a factor for consideration in deciding whether to grant equitable relief or as a factor affecting the quantum of damages.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id1f7a1738e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">11</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Rogers did not suggest that the plaintiff&apos;s marketing concept, as an integrated package, or either of the Pink Phone program or the Call for the Cure program as an entirety, were ever publicly disclosed. <eos/><bos/>The marketing concept communicated to Rogers was a unique marketing concept. <eos/><bos/>While there was no evidence that by 2005 any wireless carrier had run a promotion under which a portion of the purchase price of a pink cellphone was donated to a charity, the marketing of pink items and an associated point-of-sale donation to a breast cancer charity was too ubiquitous by 2005 for the Court to find that a mere application of the concept to a pink cellphone constituted a unique and therefore confidential concept. <eos/><bos/>The size of the contribution to the breast cancer charity does not, by itself, create a legal difference. <eos/><bos/>Justice Wilton-Spiegel concluded that the unique and fundamental feature of the plaintiff&apos;s marketing concept was the suggestion that customers would be willing to enter into a substantial, long-term contractual obligation, based on a continuing contribution to a breast cancer charity linked to the contract. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence that such a marketing concept had been proposed anywhere prior to the plaintiff&apos;s proposals to Rogers.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id1f7c8808e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">12</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The issue of what was unique with respect to two marketing programs to implement the marketing concept, being the Pink Phone and the Call for the Cure programs was more difficult. <eos/><bos/>The projections in the Pilot Proposal regarding anticipated subscribers, annual revenue, Rogers&apos; costs, Rogers&apos; churn savings and Rogers&apos; cost of acquisition savings were unique. <eos/><bos/>Similarly, the financial projections comprising the value proposition for the Call for the Cure program, were unique. <eos/><bos/>In addition, the segmentation of the programs into the four categories of the target audience proposed by the plaintiff, being the loyalty, retention, new acquisition and pink phone subscribers as contemplated by the Pilot Proposal and the February 2004 Presentation Deck, was also unique. <eos/><bos/>These categories established the framework for the financial projections and, as such, were a part of such projections.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id1f7c8818e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">13</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>On the other hand, however, the mere reference to certain matters in the Pilot Proposal or the February 2004 Presentation Deck was not sufficient to qualify such matters as unique or otherwise entitled to confidential treatment. <eos/><bos/>For example, the assumptions used by the plaintiff, to the extent they were based on publicly available information, could not, by their mere incorporation in the Pilot Proposal or the Call for the Cure program render such information confidential. <eos/><bos/>More contentiously, the reference to the intended implementation of common marketing activities could not, by itself, constitute such initiatives as unique or confidential merely because they were included in the Pilot Proposal or the Call for the Cure program, unless there was some further aspect of such initiatives relative to the plaintiff&apos;s marketing concept that involved a demonstrated exercise of judgment or creativity on the part of the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, Justice Wilton-Siegel found that the only elements of the Pink Phone and Call for the Cure marketing programs that were unique were the financial projections for each program, including the financial information contained therein. <eos/><bos/>In this context, information can be unique or confidential without being accurate or verifiable.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id1f7c8828e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">14</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>It was not disputed that the information respecting the results of the survey constituted confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff&apos;s calculation of the reduction in the rate of churn that would occur if the Call for the Cure program were implemented constituted confidential information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id1f7c8838e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">15</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Cameron Seafoods (2005) Ltd. v. Jumelet</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id1f7ef908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">16</footnote.reference>] the defendant argued unsuccessfully that the disclosures were no more confidential than information that was previously provided by the plaintiff to BMC in the course of discussions about potential joint ventures. <eos/><bos/>However, the court observed that the disclosure of information by the plaintiff was made by the company for its own purposes. <eos/><bos/>It was not disclosed by a key employee, director and vice-president, without the knowledge of the majority shareholder, to assist a potential competitor with whom he was in discussions for employment on his own behalf. <eos/><bos/>The circumstances were not comparable.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id1f7ef918e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">17</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Id1f753508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>See <cite.query w-src-number="0492175836" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2002452865" w-pub-number="0005628" ID="I16e16d118e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Hub Financial Inc. v. Molinaro</ital></cite.query> (2002), 26 B.L.R. (3d) 295, 18 C.C.E.L. (3d) 201, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175836" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2002452865" w-pub-number="0005628" ID="I16e16d128e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2002 C.L.L.C. ¶ 210-037 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, where the court found that since there was no agreement regarding their right to use information on termination, there was no other basis for implying a duty of confidentiality.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id1f753518e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>See <cite.query w-src-number="0492175836" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2024374187" w-pub-number="0007659" ID="I16e194208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sabre Inc. v. International Air Transport Assn.</ital>, 2011 ONSC 206</cite.query>, <case.history>affd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175836" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026608303" w-pub-number="0007352" ID="I16e194228e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2011 ONCA 747</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id1f753528e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>As to the “element of secrecy” in the American case law, see the following: <cite.query w-src-number="0492175836" w-seq-number="00007" w-ref-type="RP" w-serial-number="1948101076" w-pub-number="0000602" ID="I16e27e818e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Abdallah v. Crandall</ital>, 273 App. Div. 131, 76 N.Y.S.2d 403 (1948)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175836" w-seq-number="00008" w-ref-type="RP" w-serial-number="1967116670" w-pub-number="0000350" ID="I16e27e838e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Wilkin v. Sunbeam Corp.</ital>, 377 F.2d 344 (1967)</cite.query>, <case.history><ital>cert. denied</ital></case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175836" w-seq-number="00009" w-ref-type="RP" w-serial-number="1967202830" w-pub-number="0000780" ID="I16e27e858e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">389 U.S. 973 (1967)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175836" w-seq-number="00010" w-ref-type="RP" w-serial-number="1965107049" w-pub-number="0000162" ID="I16e27e888e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Space Aero Products Co. v. R.E. Darling Co.</ital>, 238 Md. 93, 208 A. 2d 74 (1965)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175836" w-seq-number="00011" w-ref-type="RP" w-serial-number="1966123572" w-pub-number="0000350" ID="I16e27e8b8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Underwater Storage, Inc. v. United States Rubber Co.</ital>, 125 U.S. App. D.C. 297, 371 F.2d 950 (1966)</cite.query>, <case.history><ital>cert. denied</ital></case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175836" w-seq-number="00012" w-ref-type="RP" w-serial-number="1967212766" w-pub-number="0000780" ID="I16e27e8d8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">386 U.S. 911 (1967)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id1f77a608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>4</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175836" w-seq-number="00013" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2016311598" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I16e2f3b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Innovative Health Group Inc. v. Calgary Health Region</ital> (2008), 294 D.L.R. (4th) 83 (Alta. C.A.)</cite.query>, leave to appeal to S.C.C. refused [2008] 3 S.C.R. v.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id1f77a618e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>5</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175836" w-seq-number="00014" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1988181722" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I16e368e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Attorney General v. Guardian Newspapers Ltd. (No. 2)</ital>, [1988] 3 All E.R. 545 (H.L.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id1f77a628e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>6</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175836" w-seq-number="00015" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1968018312" w-pub-number="0004831" ID="I16e38ff08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Coco v. A.N. Clark (Engineers) Ltd.</ital>, [1969] R.P.C. 41 (Ch.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175836" w-seq-number="00016" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1895411741" w-pub-number="0003898" ID="I16e38ff28e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Robb v. Green</ital>, [1895] 2 Q.B. 1</cite.query>, <case.history>affd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175836" w-seq-number="00017" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1895411784" w-pub-number="0003898" ID="I16e38ff48e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">[1895] 2 Q.B. 315 (C.A.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175836" w-seq-number="00018" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1967017736" w-pub-number="0004831" ID="I16e38ff68e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Franchi v. Franchi</ital>, [1967] R.P.C. 149 (Ch.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id1f77a638e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>7</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>Saltman Engineering Co. v. Campbell Engineering Co.</ital>, [1963] 3 All E.R. 413<ital>n</ital> (C.A.), at p. 415. <eos/><bos/>See also <cite.query w-src-number="0492175836" w-seq-number="00019" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1949034206" w-pub-number="0004707" w-pinpoint-page="609" ID="I16e760808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>R.L. Crain Ltd. v. Ashton</ital>, [1950] 1 D.L.R. 601 at p. 609, [1950] O.R. 62 (C.A.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175836" w-seq-number="00020" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1973142111" w-pub-number="0005652" ID="I16e760838e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>PPG Industries Inc. v. Green</ital> (1973), 13 C.P.R. (2d) 71 (Ont. H.C.J.), at p. 75</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175836" w-seq-number="00021" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1968018312" w-pub-number="0004831" w-pinpoint-page="51" ID="I16e760858e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Coco v. A.N. Clark (Engineers) Ltd.</ital>, [1969] R.P.C. 41, at p. 51 (Ch.)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>Most of the early English cases dealt with master and servant law, and more particularly in the context of departed employees who went into competition with their former employer. <eos/><bos/>The unique considerations relevant to the area of employment law will be fully dealt with in Chapter 4.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id1f7a1708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>8</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175836" w-seq-number="00022" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043111788" w-pub-number="0007659" ID="I16e787908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Brand Name Marketing Inc. v. Rogers Communications Inc.</ital>, 2016 ONSC 4567, 2017 CarswellOnt 17209 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id1f7a1718e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>9</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175836" w-seq-number="00023" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043111788" w-pub-number="0007659" ID="I16e7d5b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Brand Name Marketing Inc. v. Rogers Communications Inc.</ital>, 2016 ONSC 4567, 2017 CarswellOnt 17209 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 1, 200, and 202-203.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id1f7a1728e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>10</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175836" w-seq-number="00024" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043111788" w-pub-number="0007659" ID="I16e7fcc08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Brand Name Marketing Inc. v. Rogers Communications Inc.</ital>, 2016 ONSC 4567, 2017 CarswellOnt 17209 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 206-207.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id1f7a1738e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>11</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175836" w-seq-number="00025" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043111788" w-pub-number="0007659" ID="I16e823d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Brand Name Marketing Inc. v. Rogers Communications Inc.</ital>, 2016 ONSC 4567, 2017 CarswellOnt 17209 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 215-219.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id1f7c8808e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>12</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175836" w-seq-number="00026" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043111788" w-pub-number="0007659" ID="I16e84ae08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Brand Name Marketing Inc. v. Rogers Communications Inc.</ital>, 2016 ONSC 4567, 2017 CarswellOnt 17209 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 220-227.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id1f7c8818e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>13</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175836" w-seq-number="00027" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043111788" w-pub-number="0007659" ID="I16e899008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Brand Name Marketing Inc. v. Rogers Communications Inc.</ital>, 2016 ONSC 4567, 2017 CarswellOnt 17209 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paragraph 229.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id1f7c8828e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>14</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175836" w-seq-number="00028" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043111788" w-pub-number="0007659" ID="I16e8c0108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Brand Name Marketing Inc. v. Rogers Communications Inc.</ital>, 2016 ONSC 4567, 2017 CarswellOnt 17209 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 230-231.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id1f7c8838e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>15</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175836" w-seq-number="00029" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043111788" w-pub-number="0007659" ID="I16e8e7208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Brand Name Marketing Inc. v. Rogers Communications Inc.</ital>, 2016 ONSC 4567, 2017 CarswellOnt 17209 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paragraph 232.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id1f7ef908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>16</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175836" w-seq-number="00030" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026352920" w-pub-number="0005475" ID="I16e90e308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cameron Seafoods (2005) Ltd. v. Jumelet</ital>, 2011 CarswellNS 693, 2011 NSSC 365</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id1f7ef918e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>17</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175836" w-seq-number="00031" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026352920" w-pub-number="0005475" ID="I16e935408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cameron Seafoods (2005) Ltd. v. Jumelet</ital>, 2011 CarswellNS 693, 2011 NSSC 365, at para. 40</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 3:5<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
