<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 4:48<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I5089a870411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>4.</label.designator><headtext>Confidential Business Information and the Employment Relationship</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I52517020411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>V.</label.designator><headtext>Fiduciary Duty</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I53a16fc0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>B.</label.designator><headtext>Remedies Table—Employment Relationship—Breach of Fiduciary Duty</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f686456ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>4:48.</label.designator><headtext>John A. Ford &amp; Associates Inc. v. Keegan</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><ital>John A. Ford &amp; Associates Inc. v. Keegan</ital>, 2014 CarswellOnt 11892, 2014 ONSC 4989, additional reasons 2015 CarswellOnt 4418, 2015 ONSC 1747</headtext><eos/><eop/></head><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Award</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Damages of $50,082.10</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Summary of Facts:</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>After the safety consulting firm, Training Services terminated its agreement with its associate, Keegan, Keegan continued to give safety training, on his own account, to several of Training Services&apos; customers or former customers. <eos/><bos/>During Mr. Keegan&apos;s 30 day notice period, and after his departure from Training Services, he continued to deliver services to Training Services&apos; customers or former customers. <eos/><bos/>In some cases, he invoiced the customers on his own account, rather than asking Training Services to render invoices to them on its account, as the Keegan Agreement and Performance Standards required.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Keegan owed Training Services a fiduciary duty not to compete with those customers and former customers whose names he obtained from the confidential customer list that Training Services gave to him. <eos/><bos/>Training Services gave Mr. Keegan the customer list with the knowledge that he could use it, as a competitor, to target its customers or former customers. <eos/><bos/>Training Services gave him discretion as to which of his customers would be sent marketing material and the price they would be offered for training. <eos/><bos/>Training Services knew that he could use this information to undercut Training Services by offering his training at a lower price. <eos/><bos/>For the period of three years when he was an associate, Keegan enjoyed an exclusive relationship with the employees on his list. <eos/><bos/>This relationship gave him an unfair advantage when later competing with Training Services for the right to train those customers&apos; employees. <eos/><bos/>Keegan must have known that Training Services, by giving him a confidential list of 50 of its customers or former customers, left itself vulnerable to his potential use of the list to his advantage and its detriment. <eos/><bos/>This gave Training Services a reasonable expectation that Keegan would reciprocate by observing a duty, set out in the Keegan Agreement, not to compete unfairly with Training Services after their association ended by continuing to provide training to the customers on the list. <eos/><bos/>In using Training Services&apos; confidential customer lists, and exercising his discretion, before his departure, as to what marketing was sent to those customers, Keegan was able to affect Training Services&apos; practical interests in a way that made it vulnerable to his actions.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Reasons Given by Court for Award:</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Training Services failed to show that damages are the most appropriate remedy in this situation. <eos/><bos/>The $349,402.32 loss that Training Services recorded in the two years following Keegan&apos;s departure, in the revenues it had derived from the customers he had serviced during the two years prior to his departure, cannot be attributed entirely to Keegan&apos;s actions having regard to the downturn in the auto industry that took place at the material time. <eos/><bos/>Training Services&apos; loss of revenues cannot reasonably be attributed entirely, or even principally, to Keegan&apos;s departure. <eos/><bos/>It can be attributed even less to the training he undertook for Training Services&apos; former customers.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The most appropriate remedy is an order requiring Keegan to disgorge the profits he derived from Training Services&apos; former customers. <eos/><bos/>To calculate these profits, the court must deduct Keegan&apos;s expenses from the revenue he received from these customers. <eos/><bos/>Keegan earned approximately $60,000 from those customers over the two-year period following the termination of the Keegan Agreement.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Training Services&apos; damages based on Keegan&apos;s disgorging of profits must be rooted in Keegan&apos;s breach of his fiduciary duty, or his misuse of Training Services&apos; confidential business information and/or trade secrets. <eos/><bos/>The temporal limits of the profits must be determined by reference to the two year period of Keegan&apos;s post-employment fiduciary obligation, as provided for in his Associate&apos;s Agreement. <eos/><bos/>The expenses to be deducted from the revenues he received from Training Services&apos; customers during that period requires consideration of how much it would have cost Training Services to pursue the revenues it lost to Keegan, and not what it cost Keegan to generate the revenue he received.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A precise calculation is not required. <eos/><bos/>Rather an estimate of what Training Services lost due to Keegan&apos;s breach, subject to a reduction for contingencies, is the proper approach in considering its lost opportunities. <eos/><bos/>In assessing damages for a breach of a restrictive covenant, the Court must take into account contingencies that reduce the plaintiff&apos;s damages.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>After Training Services issued its Claim in June 2006, Training Services brought a motion for an injunction, and the parties attended a mediation in July 2006, as required by the Keegan Agreement. <eos/><bos/>They arrived at a settlement whereby Keegan agreed to pay $35,000.00. <eos/><bos/>Keegan did not pay the agreed upon amount and, at the end of August 2006, he declared personal bankruptcy. <eos/><bos/>Training Services then moved successfully for leave to continue the litigation.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Training Services&apos; revenues from Keegan&apos;s customers declined by $349,402.32 in the two years following his departure. <eos/><bos/>Keegan invoiced the customers $52,718.00 during the same period. <eos/><bos/>Had Keegan obtained his participant materials from Training Services and been billed for them in accordance with the terms of the Keegan Agreement, he would likely have incurred approximately 10% in expenses for materials. <eos/><bos/>However, that he adapted the training material that Training Services had developed and provided to him, and incurred only minimal expense of reproducing the adapted material for his customers. <eos/><bos/>The expense of reproduction, together with travel expenses, would not have exceeded 5% of the amount he billed to the customers.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Keegan had not tendered evidence that he actually spent any more than minimal expenses during the two year period that followed his departure. <eos/><bos/>He earned profits of $50,082.10 ($52,718 less 5%) that he must disgorge and pay to Training Services.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></section.body></section><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 4:48<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
