<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 7:19<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I56d26460411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>7.</label.designator><headtext>Remedies for Breach of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I58eb5950411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>III.</label.designator><headtext>Damages</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f722a86ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>7:19.</label.designator><headtext>Generally</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Damages have been awarded on the basis of, <ital>inter alia</ital>, infringement of property, breach of contract, tort or breach of fiduciary duty. <eos/><bos/>An award of damages is intended to compensate the plaintiff for loss and to attempt to place the plaintiff in the position it would have been in had the contract or other obligation not been breached. <eos/><bos/>However, it is usually impossible to determine precisely what the plaintiff has lost and therefore what the compensation should be.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8d682e08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>] The authorities establish that an employer is not required to choose a single remedy, but can pursue both its own loss and the fiduciary&apos;s profit.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8d682e18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A monetary remedy for a breach of confidence will not be granted in circumstances where the plaintiff is not able to show some detriment or loss as a result of those breaches. <eos/><bos/>A bald allegation that a breach of confidence caused damage without any facts to show any loss or detriment is not sufficient.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id8d682e28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">3</footnote.reference>] Catalyst claimed that West Face used confidential Catalyst information to successfully acquire an interest in WIND. <eos/><bos/>Both Catalyst and West Face were investment management firms and had been competitors on potential deals including acquiring an interest in WIND. <eos/><bos/>West Face was part of a consortium that acquired WIND. <eos/><bos/>Catalyst had been a bidder for WIND and had an exclusive right for a period of time to negotiate a purchase. <eos/><bos/>When Catalyst failed to conclude a purchase of WIND, West Face and its consortium partners acquired an indirect interest in WIND. <eos/><bos/>Moyse was an analyst at Catalyst for a little under two years. <eos/><bos/>He left Catalyst and worked at West Face for three and a half weeks. <eos/><bos/>It was alleged that at some time between when Moyse first spoke to West Face and when he stopped working at West Face he gave West Face confidential information regarding Catalyst&apos;s strategy to acquire WIND that was used by West Face to structure its bid for WIND.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8d682e38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">4</footnote.reference>] The action was dismissed on the basis that Moyse had not disclosed confidential information to West Face, and even assuming, without deciding, that some of the information said to have been passed on by Moyse to West Face was confidential, the Court would not find that West Face made use of it. <eos/><bos/>Moreover, even if a case of misuse of confidential Catalyst information were made out, the Court concluded that it did not cause Catalyst any detriment or damage by any misuse of Catalyst confidential information. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence that the bid of the consortium was even looked at by the board of VimpelCom during the period of exclusivity with Catalyst, or that it played any part in the position taken by VimpelCom with Catalyst that it wanted a break fee from Catalyst. <eos/><bos/>It was that position taken by VimpelCom that caused Catalyst to terminate discussions with VimpelCom. <eos/><bos/>Catalyst told VimpelCom that the request for a break fee was unacceptable and it shut down communications and let the period of exclusivity expire. <eos/><bos/>It was after that that VimpelCom and the consortium, including West Face, concluded a deal. <eos/><bos/>Catalyst had not established that but for the misuse by West Face of the confidential Catalyst information that it said West Face was given by Moyse it would have acquired WIND from VimpelCom.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8d6a9f08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">5</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Court also concluded that there was another reason why Catalyst had not established any damages from misuse of confidential Catalyst information. <eos/><bos/>It was clear that VimpelCom would not agree to any deal that carried any risk of the Government not approving the deal. <eos/><bos/>Catalyst would not agree to a deal without Government concessions permitting the sale of spectrum to an incumbent in five years. <eos/><bos/>Catalyst wanted to ensure that its purchase was conditional on receiving regulatory concessions from Industry Canada, but VimpelCom would not agree to the conditions Catalyst sought. <eos/><bos/>Given VimpelCom&apos;s refusal to agree to a deal that contained any such condition, there was no chance that Catalyst could have successfully concluded a deal with VimpelCom.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8d6a9f18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">6</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Ontario Court of Appeal dismissed Catalyst&apos;s appeal from the judgment dismissing the action in <ital>The Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8d6a9f28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">7</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>To succeed on the misuse of confidential information claim, Catalyst had to prove that: Moyse gave confidential information concerning Catalyst&apos;s bid to purchase WIND to West Face; West Face used that confidential information when pursuing its bid for WIND; and the misuse of that confidential information caused detriment to Catalyst. <eos/><bos/>Catalyst did not have direct evidence to support its allegations. <eos/><bos/>It relied on a body of circumstantial evidence.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8d6a9f38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">8</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>On the first issue, whether Moyse had provided confidential information about Catalyst&apos;s strategies in respect of the acquisition of WIND to West Face, Catalyst relied heavily on inferences it claimed should be drawn from Moyse&apos;s conduct while he was pursuing employment with West Face, immediately after he left Catalyst to join West Face, and after litigation was commenced. <eos/><bos/>That evidence included the following: Moyse deliberately provided Catalyst&apos;s confidential information to West Face when he was trying to get a job with West Face. <eos/><bos/>This information did not relate to WIND. <eos/><bos/>Moyse erased emails that showed he provided that confidential information to West Face; Moyse erased all of the contents of the BlackBerry Catalyst had provided to him for work purposes before he returned it to Catalyst after he quit; Moyse made inaccurate and potentially misleading statements in affidavits filed on preliminary motions in the litigation; Moyse deleted his internet browsing history from his personal computer and installed programs to scrub the computer registry where deletions could otherwise be detected, in the face of a court order requiring that he turn his computer over to his lawyer so that the computer could be forensically examined for the purposes of this litigation. <eos/><bos/>Catalyst claimed that Moyse&apos;s conduct was consistent only with him having provided confidential information about Catalyst&apos;s proposed acquisition of WIND to West Face.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8d6a9f48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">9</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Moyse gave various “innocent” explanations for his conduct. <eos/><bos/>West Face also led evidence that when Moyse was hired by West Face, extensive measures were taken to ensure that Moyse had no knowledge of, or involvement in, West Face&apos;s ongoing negotiations for the purchase of WIND shares. <eos/><bos/>The witnesses testified that there were no breaches of this confidentiality wall during the few weeks that Moyse was actually present in the West Face offices.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8d6a9f58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">10</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The respondents also introduced a body of evidence, which they claimed demonstrated that no confidential information from Catalyst had been used in the ultimately successful bid for WIND. <eos/><bos/>The respondents argued that the approach taken by West Face and its consortium to the acquisition of WIND, particularly with respect to the need to obtain certain concessions from the government, was fundamentally different than the approach taken by Catalyst. <eos/><bos/>Consequently, West Face had no use for any information pertaining to Catalyst&apos;s strategies.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8d6a9f68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">11</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The respondents also defended on the basis that the appellant had not proved any damages. <eos/><bos/>The respondents claimed that Catalyst&apos;s bid to acquire WIND in August 2014 failed, not because of any competing bid made by West Face and the consortium, but because Catalyst chose to terminate negotiations with the vendor of the WIND shares after the vendor demanded a significant break fee very late in its negotiations with Catalyst. <eos/><bos/>The respondents contended at trial that the evidence showed that Catalyst chose to end the negotiations rather than agree to the break fee demanded by the vendor. <eos/><bos/>On this argument, Catalyst suffered no damages or detriment, even if Moyse had given confidential information to West Face and West Face had attempted to use that information in its negotiations with the vendor of the WIND shares.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8d6a9f78e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">12</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge found against Catalyst on almost every contested factual issue. <eos/><bos/>Specifically, he found that the appellant chose to terminate its negotiations with the vendor of the WIND shares when the vendor demanded a substantial break fee. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge made strong credibility findings against the appellant&apos;s primary witnesses, and equally strong credibility findings in favour of the respondents&apos; witnesses, including Moyse. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge accepted the explanations offered by Moyse for his conduct. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge found, as a fact, that Moyse had not provided any confidential information to West Face in relation to the appellant&apos;s negotiations for the purchase of the WIND shares.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8d6d1008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">13</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The appellant submitted that the trial judge&apos;s factual findings could not stand, first, because they were the product of an unfair and uneven scrutiny by the trial judge of the competing versions of the relevant events and, second, because they were tainted by several material misapprehensions of the evidence.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8d6d1018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">14</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The result was almost entirely fact-driven. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge&apos;s findings of fact turned on his assessment of the credibility of the key witnesses, the reliability of their evidence, and the inferences to be drawn from certain primary findings of fact. <eos/><bos/>All of those tasks engaged a myriad of considerations by the trial judge. <eos/><bos/>His determinations were owed strong deference on appeal. <eos/><bos/>The appellant was required to overcome that deference in the face of reasons by the trial judge that displayed a strong command of the evidentiary record and a full understanding of the issues and positions of the parties.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8d6d1028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">15</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In support of the uneven scrutiny argument, counsel submitted that the credibility of the Catalyst witnesses was subject to a hypercritical microscopic examination by the trial judge. <eos/><bos/>Any misstep or inconsistency in their testimony, no matter how apparently minor, became, for the trial judge, a reason to reject the evidence of those witnesses. <eos/><bos/>In contrast, the trial judge forgave or ignored similar, and much more serious, defects in the evidence of witnesses for the respondents.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8d6d1038e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">16</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Counsel&apos;s submissions made a case for different credibility and reliability assessments than those made by the trial judge. <eos/><bos/>However, that is not enough to warrant appellate intervention. <eos/><bos/>It is not for an appellate court to consider what alternative findings may have been reasonably available on the trial record. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge approached the evidence of the respondents&apos; witnesses no differently than he did the evidence of the appellant&apos;s witnesses. <eos/><bos/>Moyse&apos;s evidence that he did not provide confidential information concerning the WIND negotiations to West Face did not stand alone. <eos/><bos/>The evidence found considerable, largely uncontradicted support in the testimony of the West Face witnesses. <eos/><bos/>It also gained some inferential support in the trial judge&apos;s findings as they related to the West Face strategy in respect of the WIND negotiations, and the ultimate reason for the breakdown of the negotiations between the appellant and the vendor of the WIND shares. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge was alive to the details of the evidence said to demonstrate Moyse&apos;s dishonesty and the unreliability of his evidence. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge examined the evidence particularly as it related to the allegation that Moyse had deliberately deleted material from his personal computer and installed programming to hide that deletion and prevent any recovery of the material. <eos/><bos/>In the end, the trial judge accepted Moyse&apos;s explanations for what he had done, and concluded that it could not be established that Moyse had actually used the programs he had installed on the computer to hide the deletions.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8d6d1048e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">17</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The evaluation of the impact on credibility and reliability of specific inconsistencies and similar flaws in a witness&apos;s testimony lies at the very core of the trial judge&apos;s function. <eos/><bos/>His conclusion that a certain inconsistency negatively impacted on the credibility of one witness, while a different inconsistency did not have the same negative impact on the credibility of a different witness testifying about an entirely different topic, did not, on its own, establish that the trial judge applied different levels of scrutiny to the evidence of those witnesses. <eos/><bos/>Instead, it demonstrated that credibility and reliability assessments are fact and witness-specific.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8d6d1058e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">18</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Court of Appeal observed no misapprehension of any material facts by the trial judge. <eos/><bos/>Most of the appellant&apos;s arguments failed because they did not reveal any misapprehension of the evidence, but instead revealed that the trial judge preferred the evidence of the respondents&apos; witnesses and the inferences that flowed from that evidence over the competing evidence and inferences relied on by the appellant.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8d6d1068e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">19</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The issue in <ital>Condon v. R</ital>.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8d6f8108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">20</footnote.reference>] was whether the Federal Court Judge erred in failing to include the claim for breach of confidence as part of the class proceeding. <eos/><bos/>The Federal Court Judge allowed the Appellants&apos; motion to certify their action as a class proceeding but only in relation to certain claims. <eos/><bos/>The Appellants were individuals who applied for and who received students loans through the Canada Student Loans Program during the period from 2002 to 2006. <eos/><bos/>Personal information of such individuals was stored on a hard drive that had been kept in a filing cabinet at the offices of Human Resources and Skills Development Canada. <eos/><bos/>This hard drive was lost and had not been recovered. <eos/><bos/>The claim for breach of confidence was treated by the Federal Court Judge as one in which damages was an essential element of the cause of action. <eos/><bos/>The Federal Court Judge concluded that it was plain and obvious that the claim based on breach of confidence would fail for lack of compensable damages. <eos/><bos/>As a result the Federal Court Judge did not include the claim for breach of confidence as part of the class proceeding.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8d6f8118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">21</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The determination of whether the pleadings disclose a reasonable cause of action is to be based on the assumption that the facts as pleaded are true. <eos/><bos/>This would mean that evidence is not to be submitted at the hearing of the motion. <eos/><bos/>Otherwise, the hearing of the motion could turn into a full hearing on the merits. <eos/><bos/>In this case, the parties submitted affidavit evidence. <eos/><bos/>It appeared that the Federal Court Judge evaluated the evidence in concluding that the Appellants had not suffered any “compensable damages”.<eos/><bos/> The Federal Court Judge noted that a summary review of the evidence led the Court to the conclusion that the Plaintiffs had not suffered any compensable damages. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiffs had not been victims of fraud or identity theft and the evidence did not support a claim for increased risk of identity theft in the future. <eos/><bos/>The determination of whether the Appellants had a reasonable cause of action in breach of confidence should have been made based on the facts as pled, not on the evidence adduced in support of the motion.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8d6f8128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">22</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Appellants claimed, in the damages section of the Consolidated Statement of Claim, damages that were common to all claims and these claimed damages included <begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/><begin.quote ID="QT_0003"/>“costs incurred in preventing identity theft”<end.quote refid="QT_0003"/><end.quote refid="QT_0001"/> and “out-of-pocket expenses”.<eos/><bos/> However, the Federal Court Judge observed that the damages sought by the Plaintiffs fell into two categories: i) compensation for wasted-time, inconvenience, frustration and anxiety resulting from the Data Loss; and ii) increased risk of identity theft in the future. <eos/><bos/>There was no indication that the Federal Court Judge considered either of these claims for damages in determining that the claim for breach of confidence had no reasonable prospect of success. <eos/><bos/>The Federal Court Judge erred in law in evaluating the merits of the claim for breach of confidence based on the evidence submitted by the parties and in failing to address the claims for special damages for “costs incurred in preventing identity theft” and “out-of-pocket expenses” in her analysis. <eos/><bos/>With respect to damages, the Rules only require that the claim specify the nature of the damages claimed. <eos/><bos/>The Appellants claimed that they suffered damages and they identified the nature of the damages that they were claiming. <eos/><bos/>In particular, the Appellant claimed special damages for “costs incurred in preventing identity theft” and “out-of-pocket expenses” and it was to be assumed that those costs had been incurred. <eos/><bos/>As a result there was no basis to not include the claim for breach of confidence as part of the class proceeding.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8d6f8138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">23</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>R. v. John Doe</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id8d6f8148e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">24</footnote.reference>] concerned an appeal by the Crown of an Order of the motions judge of the Federal Court certifying a class action proceeding against the Crown brought by two anonymous plaintiffs on behalf of participants in the Marihuana Medical Access Program. <eos/><bos/>In their motion for certification the plaintiffs alleged that from November 12 to 15, 2013, Health Canada sent them oversized envelopes addressed to their name, with a return address to the Program, thereby giving rise to a breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>Pursuant to the Regulations then in force, the plaintiffs provided a mailing address to Health Canada. <eos/><bos/>Contrary to its prior practice of simply indicating “Health Canada” on correspondence, between November 12 and 15, 2013, Health Canada sent the respondents and approximately 40,000 individuals registered in the Program envelopes visibly marked with a return address to the Program. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs claimed that by delivering letters revealing their association with the Program, Health Canada perpetuated security risks. <eos/><bos/>On November 21, 2013, the Deputy Minister of Health Canada issued a statement describing the inclusion of the phrase <begin.quote ID="QT_0004"/>“Marihuana Medical Access Program Health Canada”<end.quote refid="QT_0004"/> on the envelopes as an “administrative error”.<eos/><bos/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id8d6f8158e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">25</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In their Statement of Claim, the plaintiffs claimed that, in completing their applications, they entered into an agreement with Health Canada with express and implied confidentiality obligations, which Health Canada breached. <eos/><bos/>They alleged that Health Canada committed a breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>As a result of these infringements, the plaintiffs claimed to have suffered the following damages: costs incurred to prevent home invasion, theft, robbery and/or damage to property, costs incurred for personal security, damage to reputation, loss of employment, reduced capacity for employment, mental distress, out of pocket expenses, as well as inconvenience, frustration and anxiety from having to take security precautions.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8d6f8168e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">26</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motions judge considered whether the claim disclosed a reasonable cause of action, noting that the test was whether it was “plain and obvious” that the action could not succeed. <eos/><bos/>On breach of confidence, he found that the plaintiffs had pleaded the confidence relied on, and the breach of it, and that this was sufficient.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8d71f208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">27</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The only objection of the appellant with respect to the cause of action for breach of confidence was the lack of an adequate pleading of damages. <eos/><bos/>More specifically, the appellant argued that no material facts were pleaded in support of the allegation that either of the representative plaintiffs suffered any of the damages described in their Third Amended Statement of Claim as follows: a) costs incurred to prevent home invasion, theft, robbery and/or damage to personal property including marijuana plants and related paraphernalia; b) costs incurred for personal security; c) damage to reputation; d) loss of employment; e) reduced capacity for employment; f) mental distress; g) out of pocket expenses; h) inconvenience, frustration and anxiety associated with taking precautionary steps to reduce the likelihood of home invasion, theft, robbery and/or damage to personal property and to obtain personal security; and i) such further or other damages as counsel may advise. <eos/><bos/>The Court of Appeal concluded that its decision in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036642054" w-pub-number="0005470" ID="I70c4bf808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Condon v. R</ital>., 2015 CarswellNat 2432, 2015 FCA 159</cite.query>, was a complete answer to the Appellant&apos;s argument, stating:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0005"/>At issue in that case was a motion to certify an action as a class proceeding for the loss of a hard drive containing personal information of student loan recipients. <eos/><bos/>The Federal Court Judge had certified the action relating to the claims for breach of contract and the tort of intrusion upon seclusion, but had rejected the claims for negligence and breach of confidence for lack of compensable damages. <eos/><bos/>On appeal to this Court, Justice Webb, with whom Justices Ryer and Near agreed, overturned the Federal Court on this point, finding that Rule 182 (a) of the Rules only requires that the claim indicate the “nature of any damages claimed”, and that a general description was sufficient (<cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2036642054" w-pub-number="0005470" ID="I70c5d0f18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Condon</ital></cite.query>, at para. 20).<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0005"/></paratext></para></display.quote><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Court of Appeal observed that this was precisely what the respondents had done. <eos/><bos/>They had identified the nature of the damages that they were claiming, including costs incurred to prevent home invasion, theft, robbery and/or damage to personal property, loss of employment and reduced capacity for employment. <eos/><bos/>These damages were not negligible inconveniences nor entirely speculative, and it was to be assumed that these costs had been incurred in light of the principle that a statement of claim is to be read as generously as possible at the certification stage of a class action. <eos/><bos/>It would be up to the trial judge to determine whether those damages were truly suffered, and to what extent they were in fact caused by the appellant&apos;s conduct. <eos/><bos/>This was no reason, however, to dismiss the cause of action, and the motions judge did not err in finding that the pleading was sufficient in this respect.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8d71f218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">28</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A claim for damages by the plaintiff arising from the alleged misuse of confidential business information by the defendants was dismissed in <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2034750957" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I70c905418e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Seaway Marine Services Ltd. v. Weiwaikum General Partner</cite.query> Ltd</ital>.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8d71f228e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">29</footnote.reference>] The case concerned the ownership and operation of a marine fuel barge docked at a marina. <eos/><bos/>The fuel barge and associated equipment was owned by Esso for several years. <eos/><bos/>Esso decided to divest itself of all marine fuel dock operations on the British Columbia coast. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff was notified of Esso&apos;s intention to not renew their dealership agreement. <eos/><bos/>Shortly thereafter, the plaintiff expressed an interest to Esso in buying the fuel barge and associated equipment from Esso, and assuming Esso&apos;s lease. <eos/><bos/>The Weiwaikum board assumed management of certain marina-related assets, including the Esso lease which was soon coming to an end. <eos/><bos/>The Weiwaikum board sent letters requesting various items of information related to the lease to Esso and to the plaintiff concerning the lease and the marine fuel operation. <eos/><bos/>It received representations from the plaintiff in support of the plaintiff&apos;s plan to purchase the fuel barge and assume the lease. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff&apos;s reply to Weiwaikum enclosed a “Letter of Intent” indicating that the plaintiff was in the midst of negotiations with Esso to purchase the fuel barge and with Devco to assume Esso&apos;s leasehold. <eos/><bos/>Weiwaikum ultimately decided that the Limited Partnership would purchase the fuel barge from Esso.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8d71f238e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">30</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff alleged that the defendants breached confidence in relation to the information the plaintiff communicated, including reports on the condition and value of the fuel barge; the plaintiff&apos;s financial statements; and an outline of the plaintiff&apos;s operational plan for the marine fuel business. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge observed that equity is “quick to protect confidences” and sets a “relatively low threshold” on the type of information capable of providing the foundation for a breach of confidence claim. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge had no difficulty in concluding that the information as to the barge condition and value, the information in the financial statements, and the aspects of the “operational plan” was confidential information and accepted on that basis by Weiwaikum. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff&apos;s documents were manifestly confidential. <eos/><bos/>The information in them would have been known to very few outside of the plaintiff, was acquired by the expenditure of the plaintiff&apos;s money or its effort, and could not be easily acquired or duplicated by others. <eos/><bos/>The defendants received the information from business letters exchanged during the course of commercial negotiations. <eos/><bos/>The reasonable person standing in the shoes of the defendants would have realized on reasonable grounds that the information was being given by the plaintiff in confidence, and the equitable duty of confidence was therefore imposed.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8d71f248e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">31</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In the course of the exchange of letters, Weiwaikum stated that it was in the process of reviewing the various options available to it relating to the fuel facility. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff argued that it was objectively reasonable for its representatives to think that the word “options” related to lease options in relation to the plaintiff and that the option of the defendants choosing to run the business was not “reasonably in prospect”.<eos/><bos/> The trial judge did not accept that the language in the letter should be read down so as to include only options that would involve the plaintiff&apos;s ongoing participation in the marine fuel business. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff must be taken to have known that one of Weiwaikum&apos;s options would be to negotiate to buy the barge. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge observed that what the plaintiff knew, or a reasonable person in the plaintiff&apos;s position must be taken to have known, was important only insofar as it informed what Weiwaikum, as the recipient of the information, knew or must be taken to have known when it came into receipt of the confidential information. <eos/><bos/>There was no reason for Weiwaikum to be fixed with the knowledge that the plaintiff was sending the confidential barge information on the basis that Weiwaikum would only use it to consider business options that involved the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>Weiwaikum was entitled to use the confidential barge information it received from Seaway to consider its various options, including the option of a Band entity purchasing the fuel barge and running the business without the plaintiff&apos;s involvement.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8d71f258e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">32</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge was also inclined to find that the use of the financial statements for purposes other than determining whether the plaintiff was a viable tenant was unauthorized, absent other considerations. <eos/><bos/>However, the plaintiff replied to the defendant&apos;s letter of request by stating that it was more than capable of assuming the financial commitments of the current lease, and that it was willing to forward the financial statements if necessary and it is demonstrated that this is a standard requirement of all lessees or assignees. <eos/><bos/>The response from Weiwaikum spoke of confirming the financial status of the plaintiff and stated that requiring the financial statements of prospective lessees or assignees is common practice. <eos/><bos/>This response, and the language used by the plaintiff in its letter enclosing the financial statements would lead a reasonable recipient of the financial statements to the conclusion that they were to be used for the purpose of deciding whether the plaintiff would be a viable tenant and not otherwise.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8d746308e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">33</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge reached the same conclusion with regard to the confidential aspects of the “operational plan.” <eos/><bos/>The Weiwaikum request was specific: <begin.quote ID="QT_0006"/>“In order for the Landlord to consider your request for a ten year lease, we will need to receive a business plan from you outlining your plans for the use and operation of the Fuel Facility.”<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0006"/> The plaintiff&apos;s response was that no business plan was needed as the plan was to sell fuel for ten years plus any optional years. <eos/><bos/>Weiwaikum replied that if the plaintiff was interested in a new lease, Weiwaikum required a business plan as part of its due diligence. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff then sent the one-page “operational plan” alongside a reiteration of its position that it was seeking an assignment of the existing lease rather than a new lease. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge concluded that this exchange of correspondence would lead a reasonable recipient of the confidential aspects of the plaintiff&apos;s “operational plan” to conclude that the permitted use was in connection with deciding whether the plaintiff would be a viable tenant and not otherwise.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8d746318e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">34</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge&apos;s conclusion that the defendants were entitled to use the plaintiff&apos;s barge information when considering all of the various options for the fuel dock narrowed the issue to whether the defendants made use of the financial statements or confidential aspects of the “operational plan” for purposes other than assessing the viability of the plaintiff as a tenant. <eos/><bos/>Briefing notes prepared for a meeting with Chief Pollard included a reference to information from figures extracted from the plaintiff&apos;s 2005 income statement and reflected use of the financial statements for an unauthorized purpose. <eos/><bos/>The use of the information in the financial statements as part of a briefing note for a meeting to consider whether the Limited Partnership should take over the marine fuel dock was not a permitted use of this confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The question whether the information was actually factored in to the decision to purchase and run the fuel barge was another matter. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge considered it unlikely that there was substantive discussion at this brief meeting on the question of whether the Limited Partnership should take over the fuel dock business, and highly unlikely that any use was made during this meeting of the plaintiff&apos;s 2005 financial figures.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8d746328e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">35</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff argued that the timing of a meeting by the Weiwaikum board and Chief Pollard with Esso representatives, occurring just a few days after Weiwaikum received confidential information from the plaintiff, together with the exclusion of the plaintiff from the meeting, was powerful evidence in support of its case. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge concluded that this meeting was scheduled at the instance of Esso. <eos/><bos/>Esso had the date in mind before the plaintiff&apos;s letter was written. <eos/><bos/>There was nothing on Esso&apos;s agenda that called for the plaintiff&apos;s attendance. <eos/><bos/>It was fair to characterize Esso&apos;s agenda as that of a tenant meeting with its landlord in advance of the expiry of its lease. <eos/><bos/>There certainly was some discussion during the meeting of the terms on which Esso might deal with Weiwaikum, but there was no support for the notion that Weiwaikum or Chief Pollard made use of Seaway&apos;s financial statements or “operational plan”.<eos/><bos/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id8d746338e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">36</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff alleged that during the period from the date that Weiwaikum received the plaintiff&apos;s confidential information until the date of purchase of the fuel barge from Esso, Weiwaikum and the Band used the confidential information to assess the risk in deciding to take over the fuel dock. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge concluded that there was no evidence that pointed to the conclusion that the defendants likely made use of the financial statements or confidential aspects of the operational plan in coming to their decisions to buy the barge and run the marine fuel business.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8d746348e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">37</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The only misuse of confidential information demonstrated was very limited, namely, the inclusion of data from the 2005 financial statements in the Weiwaikum briefing note. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence that the very limited misuse of the confidential information played any part in the decision taken to acquire the fuel barge and operate the marine fuel business. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff was in no different position than it would have been in had the misuse not occurred. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff failed to prove damages on a <begin.quote ID="QT_0007"/>“common sense view of causation.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0007"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id8d746358e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">38</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff was not entitled to compensatory damages for the defendants&apos; misuse of confidential information despite the submission that this result was foreclosed by the necessary imposition on the defendants of a <begin.quote ID="QT_0010"/>“special disability in the field of competition”<end.quote refid="QT_0010"/>. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge understood the plaintiff&apos;s argument to be that this “special disability” was imposed regardless of the nature and extent of the misuse of confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge observed that the difficulty with this argument was that it lost sight of the relationship between the concept of “special disability” and the concept of using information as a “spring-board” to get an “unfair start”; stating:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0011"/>It is not every misuse of confidential information, regardless of how limited or trifling, that triggers the application of the “special disability.” <eos/><bos/>In the case at bar the defendants did not make use of the information as a <begin.quote ID="QT_0009"/>“spring-board for activities detrimental to the person who made the confidential communication”<end.quote refid="QT_0009"/> so there is no question of obtaining an unfair start and no basis for finding that the defendants were specially disabled from acquiring the marine fuel business in these particular circumstances.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0011"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0012"/>In <cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017324749" w-pub-number="0006457" ID="I70d1dee08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Aram Systems Ltd. v. NovAtel Inc</ital>., 2008 ABQB 441 (Alta. Q.B.)</cite.query>, <case.history>aff&apos;d</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2019530368" w-pub-number="0006455" ID="I70d1dee28e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2009 ABCA 262 (Alta. C.A.)</cite.query>, MacLeod J. wrote, at para. 105, that regardless of how the breach of confidence obligation is characterized, <begin.quote ID="QT_0008"/>“the Court&apos;s concern is with enforcing the reasonable expectations of the parties in the particular commercial context.”<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0008"/> From this narrow perspective, it cannot be seriously contended that it would have been within the expectation of Seaway or the defendants that the mere receipt or trifling misuse of the confidential information would result in the defendants being cleared from the field of competition for the marine fuel business.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0012"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0013"/>Moreover, there is a broader perspective to consider. <eos/><bos/>While there is no question of the importance of the policy of the law that confidences are to be respected, to impose the competitive disability on the defendants advocated for by Seaway in the absence of a finding that the defendants made use of the information as a “spring-board” would be inconsistent with the strong public interest in the maintenance of commercial competition spoken of by Smith J.A. in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2005997312" w-pub-number="0006458" ID="I70d2a2308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Expert Travel Financial Security (E.T.F.S.) Inc. v. BMS Harris &amp; Dixon Insurance Brokers Ltd</ital>., 2005 BCCA 5 (B.C. C.A.)</cite.query> at para. 79. <eos/><bos/>The proper balance between the policy of the law that encourages competition and the policy of the law that protects commercial confidences would be upset by finding that the defendants were uniquely disabled from acquiring the fuel barge business in circumstances where the confidential information played no role in its acquisition.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0013"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id8d76d408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">39</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><paratext>The trial judge observed that the result should not differ between a case where information is in fact “nothing very special” and a case where information may have value but is treated by the recipient as if it was “nothing very special”.<eos/><bos/> The trial judge concluded that the plaintiff&apos;s claim failed because the limited misuse of the confidential information by Weiwaikum made no difference to the plaintiff&apos;s position. <eos/><bos/>The breach of confidence was not sufficiently serious that the Court should invoke its equitable discretion to award damages.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8d76d418e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">40</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Spartek Systems Inc. v. Brown</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id8d76d428e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">41</footnote.reference>] the defendant Hartwell was employed by the plaintiff until he was terminated in August 2005. <eos/><bos/>In the summer of 2004, Hartwell spoke to Brown after Brown had announced his departure from Spartek. <eos/><bos/>Brown contacted Hartwell from time to time, requesting his assistance with mechanical drawings for proposed tools. <eos/><bos/>Hartwell prepared these drawings at home, after work hours. <eos/><bos/>He prepared the drawings using Spartek templates as blank forms. <eos/><bos/>It was his evidence that he did not use Spartek drawings or other confidential information. <eos/><bos/>He was not paid. <eos/><bos/>Some of these tools were similar to and would compete with Spartek products. <eos/><bos/>None of the proposed tools were manufactured in larger numbers or distributed to the market. <eos/><bos/>Hartwell admitted that he sent confidential Spartek information on one occasion. <eos/><bos/>Shortly before leaving for Tunisia, Holt lost part of a Spartek tool that was included in the production logging tool. <eos/><bos/>There was no substitute available from Spartek, so Hartwell sent Spartek&apos;s drawings to Holt so that Holt could manufacture a replacement.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8d76d438e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">42</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge concluded that Hartwell breached his duty of confidence to Spartek, as well as his contractual obligation to keep Spartek information confidential. <eos/><bos/>He admitted that he provided confidential Spartek information to replace a lost tool. <eos/><bos/>However, no damages were assessed as there was no evidence that Spartek suffered any loss as a result. <eos/><bos/>The information that Hartwell provided to Holt assisted Holt in performing a service job in Tunisia. <eos/><bos/>This was neither a business that Spartek carried on nor a geographical location where Spartek&apos;s customers carried on business.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8d76d448e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">43</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge was not satisfied that there were other breaches by Hartwell of his duty of confidence to Spartek, or that any breaches caused damage to Spartek. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge accepted Hartwell&apos;s evidence that he used Spartek blank templates when making drawings, but not their confidential information and concluded that to the extent that the templates themselves were confidential information, their use by Hartwell after work hours as blank canvases for his own drawings did not cause damage to Spartek.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8d76d458e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">44</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Id8d682e08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>See, for example, <ital>Moore International (Canada) Ltd. v. Carter</ital> (1984), 56 B.C.L.R. 207, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00007" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1984191066" w-pub-number="0005653" ID="I70e0abf08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">1 C.P.R. (3d) 171 (C.A.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00008" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1991350673" w-pub-number="0003986" ID="I70e0abf28e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Tree Savers International Ltd. v. Savoy</ital>, [1991] 6 W.W.R. 84, 81</cite.query> Alta. L.R. (2d) 325 (Q.B.); <cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00009" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1994406465" w-pub-number="0005506" ID="I70e0abf48e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Canadian Industrial Distributors Inc. v. Dargue</ital> (1994), 20 O.R. (3d) 574, 7</cite.query> C.C.E.L. (2d) 60 (Gen. Div.); <cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00010" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1982170140" w-pub-number="0005652" ID="I70e0abf78e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Teledyne Industries Inc. v. Lido Industrial Products Ltd.</ital></cite.query> (1982), 31 C.P.C. 285, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00011" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1982170140" w-pub-number="0005652" ID="I70e0abf88e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">68 C.P.R. (2d) 204 (F.C.T.D.), at p. 208</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00012" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1972022784" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I70e0abfa8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Industrial Development Consultants Ltd. v. Cooley</ital>, [1972] 2 All E.R. 162 (Assize)</cite.query>, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00013" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1984191066" w-pub-number="0005653" w-pinpoint-page="175" ID="I70e0abfc8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">at p. 175</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00014" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2019906465" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I70e0abfd8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>GasTOPS Ltd. v. Forsyth</ital> (2009), 181 A.C.W.S. (3d) 484, 2009</cite.query> CanLII 66153 (Ont. S.C.J.).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d682e18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>See <ital>Moore International (Canada) Ltd. v. Carter</ital> (1984), 56 B.C.L.R. 207, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00015" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1984191066" w-pub-number="0005653" ID="I70e2ced08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">1 C.P.R. (3d) 171 (C.A.)</cite.query>, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00016" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1996448778" w-pub-number="0005653" ID="I70e2ced38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Hanson v. Clifford</ital></cite.query> (1996), 28 B.C.L.R. (3d) 101, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00017" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1996448778" w-pub-number="0005653" ID="I70e2ced48e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">72 C.P.R. (3d) 53 (C.A.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00018" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2019906465" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I70e2ced68e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>GasTOPS Ltd. v. Forsyth</ital> (2009), 181 A.C.W.S. (3d) 484, 2009</cite.query> CanLII 66153 (Ont. S.C.J.).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d682e28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00019" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039633659" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I70e31cf08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 13362, 2016 ONSC 5271 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00020" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039995700" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I70e31cf38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 16043, 2016 ONSC 6285 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d682e38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>4</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00021" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039633659" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I70e36b108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 13362, 2016 ONSC 5271 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00022" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039995700" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I70e36b138e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 16043, 2016 ONSC 6285 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>, at paras. 1–4, and 7.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d6a9f08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>5</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00023" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039633659" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I70e392208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 13362, 2016 ONSC 5271 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00024" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039995700" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I70e392238e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 16043, 2016 ONSC 6285 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>, at paras. 126–130.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d6a9f18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>6</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00025" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039633659" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I70e3e0408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 13362, 2016 ONSC 5271 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00026" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039995700" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I70e3e0438e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 16043, 2016 ONSC 6285 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>, at para. 132.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d6a9f28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>7</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00027" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044131577" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I70e407508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>The Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 4307, 2018 ONCA 283</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00028" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044514259" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I70e407538e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2018 CarswellOnt 7267, 2018 ONCA 447</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d6a9f38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>8</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00029" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044131577" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I70e42e608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>The Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 4307, 2018 ONCA 283</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00030" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044514259" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I70e42e638e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2018 CarswellOnt 7267, 2018 ONCA 447, at para. 8</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d6a9f48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>9</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00031" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044131577" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I70e455708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>The Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 4307, 2018 ONCA 283</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00032" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044514259" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I70e455738e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2018 CarswellOnt 7267, 2018 ONCA 447</cite.query>, at paras. 10–11.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d6a9f58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>10</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00033" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044131577" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I70e47c808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>The Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 4307, 2018 ONCA 283</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00034" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044514259" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I70e47c838e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2018 CarswellOnt 7267, 2018 ONCA 447, at para. 12</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d6a9f68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>11</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00035" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044131577" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I70e4caa08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>The Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 4307, 2018 ONCA 283</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00036" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044514259" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I70e4caa38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2018 CarswellOnt 7267, 2018 ONCA 447, at para. 13</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d6a9f78e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>12</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00037" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044131577" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I70e4f1b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>The Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 4307, 2018 ONCA 283</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00038" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044514259" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I70e4f1b38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2018 CarswellOnt 7267, 2018 ONCA 447, at para. 14</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d6d1008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>13</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00039" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044131577" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I70e518c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>The Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 4307, 2018 ONCA 283</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00040" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044514259" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I70e518c38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2018 CarswellOnt 7267, 2018 ONCA 447</cite.query>, at paras. 15–16.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d6d1018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>14</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00041" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044131577" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I70e566e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>The Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 4307, 2018 ONCA 283</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00042" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044514259" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I70e566e38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2018 CarswellOnt 7267, 2018 ONCA 447, at para. 18</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d6d1028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>15</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00043" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044131577" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I70e58df08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>The Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 4307, 2018 ONCA 283</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00044" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044514259" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I70e58df38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2018 CarswellOnt 7267, 2018 ONCA 447, at para. 19</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d6d1038e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>16</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00045" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044131577" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I70e5b5008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>The Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 4307, 2018 ONCA 283</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00046" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044514259" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I70e5b5038e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2018 CarswellOnt 7267, 2018 ONCA 447, at para. 20</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d6d1048e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>17</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00047" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044131577" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I70e5dc108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>The Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 4307, 2018 ONCA 283</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00048" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044514259" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I70e5dc138e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2018 CarswellOnt 7267, 2018 ONCA 447</cite.query>, at paras. 24–26.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d6d1058e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>18</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00049" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044131577" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I70e603208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>The Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 4307, 2018 ONCA 283</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00050" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044514259" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I70e603238e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2018 CarswellOnt 7267, 2018 ONCA 447, at para. 31</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d6d1068e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>19</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00051" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044131577" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I70e651408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>The Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 4307, 2018 ONCA 283</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00052" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044514259" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I70e651438e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2018 CarswellOnt 7267, 2018 ONCA 447</cite.query>, at paras. 34 and 37.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d6f8108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>20</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00053" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036642054" w-pub-number="0005470" ID="I70e678508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Condon v. R</ital>, 2015 CarswellNat 2432, 2015 FCA 159</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d6f8118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>21</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00054" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036642054" w-pub-number="0005470" ID="I70e69f608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Condon v. R</ital>, 2015 CarswellNat 2432, 2015 FCA 159</cite.query>, at paras. 1–2, 5–6, and 8.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d6f8128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>22</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00055" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036642054" w-pub-number="0005470" ID="I70e6ed808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Condon v. R</ital>, 2015 CarswellNat 2432, 2015 FCA 159</cite.query>, at paras. 13–15.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d6f8138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>23</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00056" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036642054" w-pub-number="0005470" ID="I70e714908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Condon v. R</ital>, 2015 CarswellNat 2432, 2015 FCA 159</cite.query>, at paras. 16, 18, 20 and 22.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d6f8148e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>24</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00057" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039262855" w-pub-number="0005470" ID="I70e73ba08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>R. v. John Doe</ital>, 2016 CarswellNat 2392, 2016 FCA 191</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d6f8158e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>25</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00058" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039262855" w-pub-number="0005470" ID="I70e762b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>R. v. John Doe</ital>, 2016 CarswellNat 2392, 2016 FCA 191</cite.query>, at paras. 1, and 5–6.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d6f8168e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>26</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00059" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039262855" w-pub-number="0005470" ID="I70e789c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>R. v. John Doe</ital>, 2016 CarswellNat 2392, 2016 FCA 191</cite.query>, at paras. 7–8.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d71f208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>27</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00060" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039262855" w-pub-number="0005470" ID="I70e7b0d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>R. v. John Doe</ital>, 2016 CarswellNat 2392, 2016 FCA 191, at para. 13</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d71f218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>28</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00061" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039262855" w-pub-number="0005470" ID="I70e7d7e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>R. v. John Doe</ital>, 2016 CarswellNat 2392, 2016 FCA 191</cite.query>, at paras. 49–51.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d71f228e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>29</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00062" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034750957" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I70e7fef08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seaway Marine Services Ltd. v. Weiwaikum General Partner Ltd</ital>., 2014 CarswellBC 3311, 2014 BCSC 2102</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d71f238e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>30</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00063" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034750957" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I70e826008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seaway Marine Services Ltd. v. Weiwaikum General Partner Ltd</ital>., 2014 CarswellBC 3311, 2014 BCSC 2102</cite.query>, at paras. 2–4, 6, and 16.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d71f248e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>31</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00064" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034750957" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I70e84d108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seaway Marine Services Ltd. v. Weiwaikum General Partner Ltd</ital>., 2014 CarswellBC 3311, 2014 BCSC 2102</cite.query>, at paras. 13, and 28–29.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d71f258e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>32</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00065" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034750957" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I70e874208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seaway Marine Services Ltd. v. Weiwaikum General Partner Ltd</ital>., 2014 CarswellBC 3311, 2014 BCSC 2102</cite.query>, at paras. 31, 33, 37, and 40–41.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d746308e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>33</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00066" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034750957" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I70e8c2408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seaway Marine Services Ltd. v. Weiwaikum General Partner Ltd</ital>., 2014 CarswellBC 3311, 2014 BCSC 2102</cite.query>, at paras. 44–45.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d746318e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>34</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00067" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034750957" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I70e8e9508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seaway Marine Services Ltd. v. Weiwaikum General Partner Ltd</ital>., 2014 CarswellBC 3311, 2014 BCSC 2102</cite.query>, at paras. 46–47.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d746328e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>35</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00068" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034750957" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I70e910608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seaway Marine Services Ltd. v. Weiwaikum General Partner Ltd</ital>., 2014 CarswellBC 3311, 2014 BCSC 2102</cite.query>, at paras. 49–53.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d746338e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>36</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00069" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034750957" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I70e937708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seaway Marine Services Ltd. v. Weiwaikum General Partner Ltd</ital>., 2014 CarswellBC 3311, 2014 BCSC 2102</cite.query>, at paras. 55, 58, and 61–62.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d746348e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>37</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00070" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034750957" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I70e985908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seaway Marine Services Ltd. v. Weiwaikum General Partner Ltd</ital>., 2014 CarswellBC 3311, 2014 BCSC 2102</cite.query>, at paras. 64–65.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d746358e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>38</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00071" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034750957" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I70e9aca08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seaway Marine Services Ltd. v. Weiwaikum General Partner Ltd</ital>., 2014 CarswellBC 3311, 2014 BCSC 2102</cite.query>, at paras. 85–86.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d76d408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>39</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00072" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034750957" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I70e9d3b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seaway Marine Services Ltd. v. Weiwaikum General Partner Ltd</ital>., 2014 CarswellBC 3311, 2014 BCSC 2102</cite.query>, at paras. 87–91.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d76d418e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>40</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00073" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034750957" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I70e9fac08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seaway Marine Services Ltd. v. Weiwaikum General Partner Ltd</ital>., 2014 CarswellBC 3311, 2014 BCSC 2102, at para. 93</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d76d428e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>41</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00074" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034243613" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I70ea21d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Spartek Systems Inc. v. Brown</ital>, 2014 CarswellAlta 1496, 2014 ABQB 526</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00075" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035669022" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I70ea21d38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2015 CarswellAlta 477, 2015 ABQB 190</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d76d438e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>42</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00076" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034243613" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I70ea6ff08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Spartek Systems Inc. v. Brown</ital>, 2014 CarswellAlta 1496, 2014 ABQB 526</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00077" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035669022" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I70ea6ff38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2015 CarswellAlta 477, 2015 ABQB 190</cite.query>, at paras. 164–169.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d76d448e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>43</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00078" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034243613" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I70ea97008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Spartek Systems Inc. v. Brown</ital>, 2014 CarswellAlta 1496, 2014 ABQB 526</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00079" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035669022" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I70ea97038e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2015 CarswellAlta 477, 2015 ABQB 190, at para. 178</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8d76d458e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>44</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00080" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034243613" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I70eabe108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Spartek Systems Inc. v. Brown</ital>, 2014 CarswellAlta 1496, 2014 ABQB 526</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175972" w-seq-number="00081" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035669022" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I70eabe138e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2015 CarswellAlta 477, 2015 ABQB 190, at para. 179</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 7:19<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
