<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information ยง 8:12<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I59ba4210411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>8.</label.designator><headtext>Practical Advice for Protecting Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I59bf7230411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>II.</label.designator><headtext>Specific Steps to Protect Confidentiality</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I59e4fb90411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>C.</label.designator><headtext>Access to Confidential Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f749c46ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>ยง </label.name><label.designator>8:12.</label.designator><headtext>Access to Duplication and Transmission Equipment</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Much of modern technology is vulnerable to invasion by unauthorized third parties. <eos/><bos/>This includes message retrieval systems, modems, cellular and other mobile phones, speaker or conference phones, and other developing technology. <eos/><bos/>Thus, special attention should be paid to security in relation to the transmission of information using technology. <eos/><bos/>While training and preparation will help to prevent accidental disclosure of confidential information, it is just as important to avoid becoming the target of industrial espionage tactics. <eos/><bos/>In recent years, the following methods, among others, have been used to obtain secret business information:</paratext><list><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(a)</label.designator></head><paratext>third parties accessing internal computer systems;</paratext></para></list.item><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(b)</label.designator></head><paratext>audio or video surveillance, including tapping and bugging devices; and</paratext></para></list.item><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(c)</label.designator></head><paratext>unauthorized access to message systems such as electronic mail, voice mail and answering machines.<eos/></paratext></para></list.item></list><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Security measures are particulary important in areas where data is transmitted by electronic means such as facsimile. <eos/><bos/>Access to facsimile machines, computers and phones should be limited, in appropriate circumstances, through the use of passwords or other barriers. <eos/><bos/>When confidential documents are sent to anyone outside the business, a cover letter or fax cover sheet should be included. <eos/><bos/>The cover letter or sheet should be addressed to a specific person and contain appropriate instructions and warnings to both intended and unintended recipients.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></section.body></section><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI ยง 8:12<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
