<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 6:9<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I55e174b0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>6.</label.designator><headtext>Defences to Claims for Breach of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I564a48a0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>V.</label.designator><headtext>No Improper Use or Disclosure of the Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f6d4856ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>6:9.</label.designator><headtext>Generally</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>It is a full defence to state that there was no improper use or disclosure of confidential information or that such use or disclosure is unlikely to occur. <eos/><bos/>No improper use occurs if a party uses secret information only for the purposes for which it was communicated.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2048515624" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I597864818e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Craig v. CEO Global Network</cite.query> Inc.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id7ce13908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>] CEO Global was in the business of providing professional consulting services to corporate executives through group mentoring, expert speaker programs and executive coaching. <eos/><bos/>Wilson carried on that business previously with a competitor, TEC Canada, where he worked with the Plaintiff Craig. <eos/><bos/>After Wilson established CEO Global, he invited Craig to join. <eos/><bos/>Craig became the executive vice-president of CEO Global. <eos/><bos/>The Consulting Agreement he signed provided for a one-year term that would automatically renew on its anniversary date subject to rights of early termination. <eos/><bos/>Part way through the second term, CEO Global provided sixty days&apos; notice to Craig of termination of the Consulting Agreement. <eos/><bos/>CEO Global agreed to pay Craig six months&apos; compensation additional to the sixty days&apos; notice, consistent with its interpretation of the Consulting Agreement&apos;s provision for termination without cause. <eos/><bos/>CEO Global paid Craig the first month of notice, but then did not pay the second month of notice or the six months of additional compensation. <eos/><bos/>CEO Global&apos;s lawyer notified Craig that CEO Global was discharged from making any further payments to him because it discovered that he had breached the non-competition provision contained in the Consulting Agreement, thereby entitling CEO Global it to terminate the Consulting Agreement for cause.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7ce13918e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>On March 29, 2019, Craig produced to CEO Global a confidential client and prospective client list that he had downloaded from the CEO Global computer system four days after he was provided with notice of termination but before the expiry of the sixty-day notice period. <eos/><bos/>He also produced a copy of CEO Global&apos;s Strategic Plan created on February 4, 2011 that he had retained. <eos/><bos/>At the start of the closing submissions at trial, CEO Global amended its statement of defence to plead that it was entitled to terminate the Consulting Agreement with cause by reason of Craig&apos;s breach of the confidentiality provision of the Consulting Agreement and his breach of the duty of honesty and good faith that he owed to CEO Global in the performance of the contract. <eos/><bos/>CEO Global did not tender any evidence of any harm, or detriment of any nature, resulting from Craig having had confidential documents in his possession in the more than seven years that had passed since termination. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge concluded that CEO Global failed to establish just cause for its termination of the Consulting Agreement. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiff was entitled to judgment against CEO Global of $150,899, plus pre-judgment interest.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7ce13928e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">3</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>CEO Global contended that it was justified in terminating Craig for cause on the basis that he materially breached the Non-Competition Provision. <eos/><bos/>The burden of establishing that the Non-Competition Provision is lawful and enforceable is on the party seeking its enforcement. <eos/><bos/>The general principle applied in most common law jurisdictions is that <begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>“non-competition clauses in employment contracts are void”<end.quote refid="QT_0001"/> because a non-competition provision in an employment contract is a restraint of trade, and restraints of trade are contrary to public policy considerations because they interfere with individual liberty of action. <eos/><bos/>The Supreme Court has stated that restrictive covenants are enforceable only when they are reasonable. <eos/><bos/>The onus is on the party seeking to enforce the restrictive covenant to establish that its terms are reasonable. <eos/><bos/>The Supreme Court of Canada has drawn a distinction between restrictive covenants contained in commercial contracts and in contracts pertaining to employment, noting that different considerations are pertinent to each. <eos/><bos/>In particular, in the employment setting there may be an imbalance in power between the parties to the employment contract. <eos/><bos/>The reasonableness test for assessment of a restrictive covenant has been found to be applicable to independent contractor relationships as to employer-employee relationships.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7ce13938e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">4</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge was of the view that there were three factors that rendered the Non-Competition Provision unreasonable. <eos/><bos/>First, the Consulting Agreement contained a Non-Solicitation Provision, which prohibited Craig from soliciting, enticing or accepting work from Members and Prospective Members of CEO Global. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge did not consider that this was an exceptional case, where CEO Global reasonably required a Non-Competition Provision for the protection of its business once it already had in place the Non-Solicitation Provision that covered both Members and Prospective Members for one year. <eos/><bos/>The Non-Competition Provision would foreclose Craig from advancing his own business to service clients over whom CEO Global has not asserted any proprietary interest. <eos/><bos/>Also, Craig contracted to serve CEO Global as an independent contractor, which implied that he would operate independently and that his business would provide service to more than one client. <eos/><bos/>The Non-Solicitation Provision was sufficient to reasonably protect the interests of CEO Global, such that the Non-Competition Provision was void on this basis alone.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7ce3aa08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">5</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Second, an ambiguous restrictive covenant is <ital>prima facie</ital> unreasonable. <eos/><bos/>The ambiguity in the Non-Competition Provision was its prohibition that Craig could not engage in or carry on a “business similar to the business” carried on by CEO Global. <eos/><bos/>This presented an ambiguity in the scope of the Non-Competition Provision that was made obvious by the disproportionate amount of trial time expended in debate concerning whether Craig&apos;s provision of one-on-one executive coaching was a “business similar” to that conducted by CEO Global. <eos/><bos/>The <begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>“use of the words ‘or a business similar thereto’ introduces a massive breadth of possible interpretations and hence introduces great uncertainty and ambiguity into the clause”<end.quote refid="QT_0002"/>. <eos/><bos/>The business of CEO Global in providing professional consulting services to corporate executives was already broad in scope, and the use of the term “business similar” broadened the provision so vastly that it became ambiguous and could not be reasonable.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7ce3aa18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">6</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Third, CEO Global had not established that the geographic scope of the Non-Competition Provision, being <begin.quote ID="QT_0004"/>“the geographic area of Canada and the United States in which the Client carries on business”<end.quote refid="QT_0004"/>, was reasonable. <eos/><bos/>The reasonableness of a restrictive covenant must take into consideration the <begin.quote ID="QT_0003"/>“extent of the activity sought to be prohibited and the extent of the temporal and spatial scope of the prohibition”<end.quote refid="QT_0003"/>. <eos/><bos/>CEO Global sought to restrain the business of Craig as an independent contractor in the entirety of Canada and the United States for a year. <eos/><bos/>There must be a rational basis for the breadth of its reach in order to be reasonable, and that had not been established. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge concluded that the geographic scope of the restrictive covenant was unreasonable because its scope was broader than necessary to protect the interests of CEO Global.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7ce3aa28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">7</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Confidentiality Provision stated that Craig agreed to keep in strictest confidence all confidential information that he received while with CEO Global, and not to publish, communicate, disclose or use any such information. <eos/><bos/>CEO Global submitted that Craig materially breached the Confidentiality Provision because he obtained and kept in his possession confidential documents.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7ce3aa38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">8</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Plaintiff emphasized that the Client List was a “valuable document” that contained both actual clients and prospective clients, referred to as “leads”.<eos/><bos/> The company paid for certain of the leads and so had a monetary investment in the development and protection of the Client List. <eos/><bos/>The Client List would be very valuable to a competitor. <eos/><bos/>Craig also kept other confidential documents, such as the Business Plan and the Competitor Comparison Chart. <eos/><bos/>Craig admitted that the Client List was a “highly confidential document” that was, throughout, the property of CEO Global. <eos/><bos/>He conceded, as well, that the Business Plan was proprietary information belonging to CEO Global, as was the Competitor Comparison Chart. <eos/><bos/>Craig provided an explanation for printing the Client List after receiving notice of termination. <eos/><bos/>He stated that he printed the Client List in furtherance of the discussions that were underway wherein it was proposed that Craig would continue to provide sales and marketing consulting services. <eos/><bos/>Craig stated that he printed the Client List during these discussions to guide his assessment of the nature of the ongoing role that he would have with CEO Global, to help him understand the current leads and consider further leads that he could identify and present to CEO Global. <eos/><bos/>This explanation addressed why he printed the Client List but did not account for why he did not return it when all discussions of a post-termination relationship ended between Craig and CEO Global. <eos/><bos/>Craig swore that he did “absolutely not” ever use the Client List or the Business Plan or any other confidential information belonging to CEO Global. <eos/><bos/>Indeed, he testified that he did not even recall that he had the documents until conducting a search of documents material to CEO Global for the purpose of trial.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7ce3aa48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">9</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge accepted Craig&apos;s explanation that he printed the Client List to understand the remaining sector of leads that he could target for presentation to CEO Global apart from those already listed as prospects on the Client List because the timing of the printing of the list coincided with the discussions then-underway between the parties and because the information formed part of the ongoing analysis required by those discussions. <eos/><bos/>CEO Global did not lead any evidence that it had sustained any damage, or any harm of any nature, by reason of Craig&apos;s possession of the Confidential Documents. <eos/><bos/>CEO Global did not lead any evidence that Craig used or disclosed any of the Confidential Documents, at all.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7ce3aa58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">10</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>CEO Global was required to establish that the breach of the Confidentiality Provision was substantial, serious and consequential in nature in the context of the relationship between the parties. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge did not condone Craig&apos;s failure to return the Confidential Documents after the effective date of termination of the Consulting Agreement. <eos/><bos/>Craig breached section 4(e) of the Consulting Agreement. <eos/><bos/>However, this duty matured, and the resultant breach of duty occurred “upon the termination” of the Consulting Agreement. <eos/><bos/>As such, this breach on the part of Craig did not qualify as after-acquired cause, because it was not conduct that occurred prior to effective termination of the employment contract. <eos/><bos/>To seek a remedy from Craig for conduct that occurred post-termination, whether in the nature of failure to return documents or competing with CEO Global post-termination, CEO Global was required to do so by way of set-off in its statement of defence or by way of counterclaim.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7ce61b08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">11</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge did not condone Craig printing the Client List without the express permission and not returning it to CEO Global upon termination or, indeed at any time prior to the days before trial. <eos/><bos/>However, to constitute a material breach of the Confidentiality Provision sufficient to constitute just cause for termination, CEO Global was required to establish more. <eos/><bos/>CEO Global was required to establish that Craig: (a) breached his obligation to keep the confidential information in the “strictest of confidence”; or (b) breached his obligation <begin.quote ID="QT_0005"/>“not to publish, communicate or disclose to any unauthorized third party any such information”<end.quote refid="QT_0005"/>. <eos/><bos/>Whether confidential information was misused, and if so how, is a factual determination to be made on a case-by-case basis. <eos/><bos/>A detailed evaluation must be made of the actions of the former employee or contracting party. <eos/><bos/>CEO Global did not lead any evidence that Craig failed to keep the Confidential Documents in confidence or that he, in any manner, published, communicated or disclosed to anyone any of the Confidential Documents. <eos/><bos/>Craig throughout seven years kept the Confidential Documents in confidence and had not published, communicated or disclosed to anyone any of the Confidential Documents. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge accepted Craig&apos;s evidence on his treatment of the Confidential Documents. <eos/><bos/>CEO Global did not lead any evidence, at all, that contradicted Craig&apos;s sworn testimony, which was unshaken by cross-examination, that he had not used or disclosed the Confidential Documents. <eos/><bos/>CEO Global had no evidence that, at any time over the last seven years, it had gained any knowledge, or any indication in its market sector, that would cause it to conclude that any Confidential Documents had been disclosed or used by Craig. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence that Craig&apos;s current business activities had in any way built upon or applied the Confidential Documents. <eos/><bos/>Indeed, Craig&apos;s business activities over the last number of years did not impact CEO Global sufficiently to cause CEO Global to even plead that Craig had used its confidential information. <eos/><bos/>It was only Craig&apos;s very late return of the Confidential Documents that caused CEO Global to seize upon this issue, and not any experience by CEO Global that would lead it to suspect that Craig had misused its confidential information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7ce61b18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">12</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>CEO Global submitted that “possession” of confidential information is equivalent to “use” of confidential information, so that Craig&apos;s admitted “possession” of the Confidential Documents was sufficient to support a finding that he materially breached the Confidentiality Provision. <eos/><bos/>CEO Global did not present a single case authority in support of this submission. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge concluded that the Confidentiality Provision was not breached by possession of confidential information that was not used. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge concluded that a breach of the Confidentiality Provision, in the context of the Consulting Agreement and the relationship between the parties, required more than Craig&apos;s possession of Confidential Documents. <eos/><bos/>It required also a finding that Craig used the Confidential Documents in a way that the Confidentiality Provision did not permit.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7ce61b28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">13</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Furfari v. Pedias</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id7ce61b38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">14</footnote.reference>] the Plaintiff claimed that the defendant entered his home while he was on vacation and took some confidential documents and sought damages totaling $300,000, including aggravated and punitive damages. <eos/><bos/>The Defendant&apos;s motion to strike the claim on the basis that the claim did not plead the necessary elements and material facts to support the claim for breach of confidence, and that the claim for aggravated was not properly pleaded was allowed.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7ce61b48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">15</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Plaintiff and the Defendant had been friends until recently. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiff was also friends with the Defendant&apos;s brother, Mario. <eos/><bos/>The claim was very short and made the following allegations of fact against the Defendant:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0006"/>1. The Plaintiff owns a farm located in King City, Ontario (“Property”).<eos/><bos/> The Plaintiff from time to time would hire the Defendant to carry out a variety of handyman type projects at the Property, including installation and maintenance of internet service and security systems.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0006"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0007"/>2. The Defendant was thus familiar with the Property and enjoyed unsupervised access to it for purposes of the projects given to him by the Plaintiff but for no other purpose.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0007"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0008"/>3. The Defendant understood and agreed that the Plaintiff granted him access to his private property on the basis of the Defendant&apos;s undertaking and promise of confidence and the Defendant&apos;s promise to protect and maintain the Plaintiff&apos;s privacy at all times.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0008"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0009"/>4. On or about May 2018 when the Plaintiff was out of the country and without his knowledge or authorization, the Defendant alone or in concert with others gained access to the Property and removed personal and confidential papers, documents and records of the Plaintiff relating to his personal, financial and banking affairs (“Removed Items”).<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0009"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0010"/>5. Mario was aware that the Plaintiff was out of the country during this time.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0010"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0011"/>6. The actions by the Defendant were unauthorized and were taken without lawful authority or excuse and without colour of right.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0011"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0012"/>7. To the knowledge of the Defendant and Mario, taking of the Removed Items from the Property and any use to which they could be put would be unauthorized by the Plaintiff as well as unlawful.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0012"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0013"/>8. Also to the knowledge of the Defendant, dissemination of the Removed Items to anyone would be detrimental to the Plaintiff and his personal and financial interests.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0013"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id7ce88c08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">16</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Following the service of the statement of claim, the Defendant made a demand for particulars, including a request that the specific documents removed be identified. <eos/><bos/>In response, the Plaintiff did not provide any particulars, in some cases on the grounds that no further particulars were available and in other cases that the request was not the proper subject of a demand for particulars.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7ce88c18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">17</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A claim for breach of confidence requires a plaintiff to prove three following elements including that a. the information was confidential; b. the information was conveyed in confidence; and c. the confidential information was misused by the party to whom it was communicated to the detriment of the confider. <eos/><bos/>The Defendant argued that the statement of claim did not properly plead the first and third elements of the claim for breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>With respect to the first element, he argued that the claim did not sufficiently identify the documents to establish that they were confidential. <eos/><bos/>With respect to the third element, he argued that there was no pleading that the information was misused in a way that caused damage to the Plaintiff.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7ce88c28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">18</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>While the motions judge concluded that the first element was sufficiently pleaded, the motions judge agreed that the last element was not properly pleaded. <eos/><bos/>With respect to the first element, the requirement is that the information be confidential. <eos/><bos/>In this case, the claim described the documents as <begin.quote ID="QT_0014"/>“personal and confidential papers, documents and records of the Plaintiff relating to his personal, financial and banking affairs”<end.quote refid="QT_0014"/>. <eos/><bos/>While the claim did not identify the specific documents allegedly taken, they were described as “confidential” and as including financial and banking information, which is information typically considered as confidential. <eos/><bos/>In the motions judge&apos;s view, this was sufficient for the purposes of pleading the first element of the tort of breach of confidence.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7ce88c38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">19</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>With respect to the third element, the claim did not plead that the information was misused by the defendant to the Plaintiff&apos;s detriment. <eos/><bos/>In <ital>Lysko v. Braley</ital>, the Court of Appeal noted that the concept of “detriment” in the context of a claim for breach of confidence is broad enough <begin.quote ID="QT_0016"/>“to include the emotional or psychological distress that would result from the disclosure of intimate information”<end.quote refid="QT_0016"/>. <eos/><bos/>However, there was no pleading that the Defendant misused the information to the Plaintiff&apos;s detriment. <eos/><bos/>For example, there was no pleading that the information was conveyed to a third party and that the disclosure had a detrimental effect on the Plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>Instead, the pleading on this point was entirely speculative, stating that the Defendant knew that <begin.quote ID="QT_0015"/>“dissemination of the Removed Items to anyone would be detrimental to the Plaintiff and his personal and financial interests”<end.quote refid="QT_0015"/>.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7ce88c48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">20</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motions judge concluded that the Plaintiff should be given an opportunity to remedy the deficiencies in the claims for breach of confidence and for aggravated damages. <eos/><bos/>This was not a case where the claim was so deficient that it could not be remedied or where the Plaintiff had already been given an opportunity to amend his claim.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7ce88c58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">21</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2047688097" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I59abf7a18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>CTT Pharmaceutical Holdings v. Rapid Dose Therapeutics</ital></cite.query>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id7ce88c68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">22</footnote.reference>] the Defendant moved for summary judgment on the basis that there was no evidence in support of the Plaintiff&apos;s claim. <eos/><bos/>The principals of the Plaintiff had experience with manufacturing pharmaceuticals and the principals of the Defendant had experience in marketing various products. <eos/><bos/>The parties entered an Asset Purchase Agreement pursuant to which the Defendant was to purchase the Plaintiff&apos;s assets. <eos/><bos/>These consisted primarily of two patents relating to oral thin, dissolvable strips. <eos/><bos/>The parties proposed joining efforts to market oral dissolvable strips impregnated with cannabis, which they planned to introduce as a new product on the Canadian market once the legislation legalizing the possession, sale, and consumption of cannabis came into force. <eos/><bos/>At some point during its due diligence exercise the Defendant apparently concluded that the Plaintiff&apos;s technology was ineffective for the desired use. <eos/><bos/>The parties had a mutual falling out, and the Plaintiff issued a formal notice to the Defendant terminating the Asset Purchase Agreement.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7ceafd08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">23</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Plaintiff alleged that there were three areas of confidential information on which the claim was particularly focused: a) the identity of ODF Pharma, b) the identity of HED International, and c) patent applications prepared by the Plaintiff which had not yet been laid open to the public. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiff claimed that the Defendant misused confidential information by entering into a distribution agreement with HED International Inc. for tape casting machines. <eos/><bos/>These devices supposedly allow for oral thin film to be imbued with chemical products such as cannabis extract, and the agreement permitted the Defendant to make them available to licensed Canadian producers of cannabis products. <eos/><bos/>The Defendant&apos;s position was that HED International was well-known for this technology and that there was nothing proprietary about the Plaintiff&apos;s knowledge of this fact and thus nothing confidential about the passing on of this knowledge. <eos/><bos/>Whether or not that was the case, the Defendant&apos;s affiant deposed that the HED International machines turned out not to be effective for cannabis-imbued oral strips and so the distributorship agreement never got off the ground. <eos/><bos/>The Defendant thus incurred no gain and the Plaintiff suffered no loss. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence in the record to suggest anything to the contrary. <eos/><bos/>Justice Morgan noted that the courts have observed that for a breach of confidence claim to succeed there must be actual evidence of financial loss. <eos/><bos/>The goal of the remedy in this type of action is to restore the Plaintiff to the position it was in prior to the breach. <eos/><bos/>Failure to prove an actual loss is failure to prove the grounds for a remedy.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7ceafd18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">24</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2047411774" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I59ae8fb18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cantol v. State Chemical</ital></cite.query>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id7ceafd28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">25</footnote.reference>] the Plaintiff sued the Defendants alleging breach of fiduciary duty and breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>The Defendants Daniska and Hanick who had worked for the Plaintiff company that made and sold industrial and specialty chemicals both quit and started working for State. <eos/><bos/>Hanick felt he had been treated poorly by the company and had been denied his commissions. <eos/><bos/>He had been employed with the company for six years as a salesperson. <eos/><bos/>Daniska too felt poorly treated and subject to threats made by the owner that if he did not make his sales he would be fired. <eos/><bos/>Daniska had been a salesperson with the company for 34 years. <eos/><bos/>Neither of the men had any enforceable restrictive covenants in their Employment Agreements with the Plaintiff.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7ceafd38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">26</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Nakatsuru observed the law is quite settled that a fiduciary employee cannot solicit the employer&apos;s customers for a reasonable period of time after the end of their employment. <eos/><bos/>If one is not a fiduciary employee, they are free to solicit like any other employee. <eos/><bos/>The question of whether a fiduciary duty exists depends upon the individual facts of the case. <eos/><bos/>The question is often cast this way: Is the degree of responsibility, dependency, and vulnerability strong enough to support the finding of a fiduciary status? <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiff submitted that Daniska was effectively a part of management and he was a key employee. <eos/><bos/>By the time he resigned, he was titled VP of Marketing. <eos/><bos/>It was argued that Daniska was the head person in sales and product knowledge in a small company with few employees and an informal structure. <eos/><bos/>Daniska, along with Hanick, represented the majority of the Plaintiff&apos;s gross sales in Canada. <eos/><bos/>Given his longevity in the company and knowledge, Daniska was a primary source of knowledge about the Plaintiff&apos;s products and was responsible for training sales staff. <eos/><bos/>It was submitted that the Plaintiff entrusted its relationship with its customers to Daniska who was the face of the company for them. <eos/><bos/>Therefore, according to the Plaintiff, it was vulnerable to solicitation of its customers by Daniska upon his departure.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7ceafd48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">27</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Nakatsuru concluded that Daniska was not a fiduciary employee. <eos/><bos/>Clearly, the owner, who was the President, the only officer, the sole director, and majority shareholder was in charge. <eos/><bos/>The owner was the only person who had access to the financial and the business plans for the Plaintiff, who hired and fired staff, and to whom all sales staff ultimately reported. <eos/><bos/>The owner did not sell products or manage client relationships. <eos/><bos/>However, salespeople would ask him for approval for volume discounts or free shipping for its customers. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiff had some active 700 clients in total. <eos/><bos/>The owner testified that in Canada, outside of Quebec, Daniska serviced about 60% of the Plaintiff&apos;s clients while Hanick serviced the remaining 40%. <eos/><bos/>Quebec-based clients, which represented about 30% of all clients, were handled by Simard and Gosselin. <eos/><bos/>Simard reported to Gosselin who in turn reported to the owner.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7ceafd58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">28</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Having regard to the factual context and looking at the actual job that Daniska performed, Justice Nakatsuru concluded that he was a salesperson and explained that, of course, this finding was not determinative of the issue of whether he owed fiduciary obligations. <eos/><bos/>However, it was an important factor. <eos/><bos/>Justice Nakatsuru did not agree that based Daniska was effectively management.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7ceafd68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">29</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A claim for breach of confidence is made out when the information in question has the necessary quality of confidence about it, the information was imparted in circumstances importing an obligation of confidence, and there was an unauthorized use of that information to the detriment of the party communicating it. <eos/><bos/>In this case, the Plaintiff acknowledged that it had no documentary evidence of any breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence that Daniska misappropriated or took any customer lists or physical files with him. <eos/><bos/>Daniska returned everything to the owner when he left and did not make any copies. <eos/><bos/>Daniska testified that he found contact information of former customers through the Internet or LinkedIn. <eos/><bos/>He also made personal visits to customers he knew.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7ced6e08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">30</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>However, the Plaintiff submitted that Daniska admitted to a breach of confidence in his examination for discovery. <eos/><bos/>It argued that the purchasing habits of the Plaintiff&apos;s customers including the types of products, quantities, and prices paid, was confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiff pointed to the following answers given by Daniska as an admission that he used this confidential information to the detriment of the Plaintiff:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0017"/>Q. … was there a situation where you noticed that the State product was more expensive?<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0017"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0018"/>A. In some cases State&apos;s products were more expensive, in some cases some of their products were … it depended on the product.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0018"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0019"/>Q. Would you adjust prices so that they would be more competitive?<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0019"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0020"/>A. I could adjust prices, yes.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0020"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0021"/>Q. And did you, for some customers, because Cantol products were cheaper?<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0021"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0022"/>A. Cantol products were cheaper … well, it depends on the … I mean, I can&apos;t recall. <eos/><bos/>Yes, I adjusted certain prices for people but it depends. <eos/><bos/>Some products weren&apos;t even related to Cantol products. <eos/><bos/>You know, for example, one was a water treatment project, which Cantol doesn&apos;t even have, so that is … And I adjusted that price. <eos/><bos/>So, I … you know, it depends on the customer.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0022"/></paratext></para></display.quote><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Nakatsuru concluded that the exchange was not the admission as alleged by the Plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>On its face, Daniska did not admit that he used the Plaintiff&apos;s pricing information to price products more competitively. <eos/><bos/>Daniska testified that he “could” adjust prices, not that he did do so. <eos/><bos/>This ability to engage in competitive pricing depended on the product Daniska was dealing with, since some products were not even sold by the Plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>Essentially, Daniska admitted he “could” have adjusted prices to make them more competitive, but he really could not recall any time he did. <eos/><bos/>In Justice Nakatsuru&apos;s opinion, these answers were far too equivocal to base a factual finding that Daniska did in fact use confidential pricing information to advance the corporate defendant&apos;s interests. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiff did not secure an admission against interest during this part of its examination. <eos/><bos/>Secondly, when this passage is placed in the context of the entirety of Daniska&apos;s examination for discovery and his affidavit where he adamantly denied ever using the Plaintiff&apos;s confidential information, Justice Nakatsuru found no support for the Plaintiff&apos;s argument that Daniska had admitted to a breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>Indeed, immediately before the cited passage, Daniska denied ever telling the corporate defendant about the volume of product the Plaintiff&apos;s customers used to purchase.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7ced6e18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">31</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Regarding the evidence against Hanick in his own capacity, there was even less reason to find him a fiduciary employee than Daniska. <eos/><bos/>Further, the Plaintiff had no evidence that Hanick took or misused any confidential information. <eos/><bos/>At its core, the Plaintiff&apos;s position was that he, like Daniska in many respects, solicited its clients, whose identity he came to know through working for the Plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>In Justice Nakatsuru&apos;s view, this was not sufficient to ground a finding of breach of confidence.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7ced6e28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">32</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>OIBC v. KO</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id7ced6e38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">33</footnote.reference>] Ko had worked for OIBC, an insurance brokerage in Richmond Hill owned and operated by husband and wife, Lau and Chik. <eos/><bos/>Ko resigned saying she was tired and wanted to spend more time for herself after 23 years of service. <eos/><bos/>Ko changed her mind the next day and contacted the defendant insurance brokerage to inquire about a job. <eos/><bos/>She started actively working for them within one week. <eos/><bos/>Overtime, a significant number of OIBC&apos;s clients transferred over to Ko.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7ced6e48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">34</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Nakatsuru explained that he was not ignorant of the fact that the timing of the resignation and subsequent acceptance of employment at the defendant brokerage raised a red flag. <eos/><bos/>However, while Justice Nakatsuru did not find Ko&apos;s explanation as to why she resigned and then started working at a competitor so quickly particularly compelling, he was satisfied that this did not raise an issue requiring a trial. <eos/><bos/>The bottom line was that she moved quickly to a competitor. <eos/><bos/>Her motivation for doing so was a factor to be considered and was something that could be considered properly on a summary judgment motion.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7ced6e58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">35</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Nakatsuru concluded that Ko did not leave with the confidential information of OIBC. <eos/><bos/>If wrong about this, summary judgment should still be given as Ko did not solicit OIBC&apos;s clients or otherwise misuse this confidential information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7cefdf08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">36</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Almost immediately after Ms. Ko&apos;s resignation, the Plaintiff wrote letters to the clients that Ko had serviced advising them of her departure and the fact that Chik would take over their files. <eos/><bos/>Then Ko wrote letters to the 242 clients in the contact list on her phone. <eos/><bos/>These were generic form letters in English and Chinese. <eos/><bos/>Justice Nakatsuru concluded that the letter and the actions of Ko did not constitute solicitation. <eos/><bos/>Ko did not ask for anything. <eos/><bos/>Numbers alone do not establish solicitation. <eos/><bos/>Justice Nakatsuru concluded that a plausible and reasonable explanation for this transfer of business other than solicitation by Ms. Ko could well be her longstanding business and professional relationship with these clients built on mutual trust.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7cefdf18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">37</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2043111788" w-pub-number="0007659" ID="I59b6a6018e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Brand Name Marketing Inc. v. Rogers Communications</cite.query> Inc.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id7cefdf28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">38</footnote.reference>] Justice Wilton-Spiegel concluded that Rogers did not appropriate or misuse any significant element or component of either the Pink Phone program or the Call for the Cure program in creating and implementing the Pink Razr campaign.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7cefdf38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">39</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Pink Razr campaign had its origins in Motorola&apos;s decision to offer Rogers the exclusive opportunity to distribute, on a limited quantity basis, a new product that was intended to be attractive to younger women who were seen to be trendsetters. <eos/><bos/>Rogers contributed to the marketing campaign the suggestion that Motorola use co-op marketing funds of $150,000 to make a $25 donation to Rethink for each handset sold. <eos/><bos/>The Rethink donation was a means of obtaining favourable publicity in the market to assist in selling the handsets. <eos/><bos/>Such free publicity was intended to be the principal marketing tool for the Pink Razr campaign. <eos/><bos/>Rogers was not prepared to spend any of its money on the Pink Razr campaign, including paying an accrual fee or an airtime residual to Rethink. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, the only similarity between the proposals of the plaintiff and of the Pink Razr campaign of any significance was that each involved a donation to a breast cancer charity for each purchase of a cellphone.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7cefdf48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">40</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Wilton-Siegel concluded that Rogers did not use the marketing concept proposed by the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>The concept of a donation to a breast cancer charity in connection with the sale of a product was a well-established marketing tool by 2005 and therefore did not constitute confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff was therefore required to establish that it communicated something more to Rogers that Rogers used in the Pink Razr campaign. <eos/><bos/>Insofar as it was suggested that Rogers applied the plaintiff&apos;s marketing concept, the claim failed. <eos/><bos/>The marketing concept proposed by the plaintiff was substantially different from the marketing concept that was implemented in the Pink Razr campaign. <eos/><bos/>Three elements of the plaintiff&apos;s marketing concept were significant: (1) the focus on the sale of long-term airtime contracts; (2) the emphasis on the sale of such contracts, or extensions of existing contracts, to “loyalty” and “retention” customers, who were already existing Rogers customers; and (3) the reduced churn among Rogers&apos; subscriber base and consequential lower cost of acquisition to Rogers of such contracts said to result from the affinity relationship, which would make the concept, as implemented by the Pink Phone or the Call for the Cure programs, profitable to Rogers. <eos/><bos/>Justice Wilton-Siegel observed that none of these elements were part of the marketing concept underlying the Pink Razr campaign. <eos/><bos/>The latter focused on the sale of a limited number of cellphones for image purposes to a target audience that was not part of Rogers&apos; traditional customer base. <eos/><bos/>Further, the marketing plan did not envisage any significant number of new customers joining the Rogers&apos; network because of the affinity relationship with Rethink. <eos/><bos/>In addition, any lowered cost of acquisition of airtime contracts resulted from Motorola&apos;s financial participation and the media-focussed marketing strategy, rather than the affinity relationship.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7cefdf58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">41</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>There was also no evidence that Rogers used any of the plaintiff&apos;s information that was generated by the Survey. <eos/><bos/>In particular, there was no evidence that Rogers used the plaintiff&apos;s estimate that implementation of the Call for the Cure program would reduce the churn rate for the Rogers&apos; customer base by 0.28% monthly. <eos/><bos/>Lin, on behalf of Rogers, assumed a 1.47% churn factor for cellphones purchased pursuant to the Pink Razr campaign in the financial projections that he prepared for the campaign. <eos/><bos/>There was, however, no evidence that Lin ever saw the plaintiff&apos;s analysis, much less that Rogers ever accepted that analysis.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7cefdf68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">42</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>With respect to the suggestion that the Survey provided an indication of consumer interest in the Pink Phone program which was useful to Rogers, this was not evidence that the Survey results were used by Rogers for the Pink Razr campaign. <eos/><bos/>The Survey addressed a very different marketing program from the Pink Razr campaign. <eos/><bos/>Rogers would not have relied on the Survey results in designing and implementing any marketing program along the lines of the Pink Phone program to which it might have committed.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7cefdf78e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">43</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The extent to which Rogers used the plaintiff&apos;s information depended upon an assessment of the extent to which Rogers applied the Pink Phone program or the Call for the Cure program in conducting the Pink Razr campaign. <eos/><bos/>Rogers clearly did not apply substantially all of either program in its conduct of the Pink Razr campaign. <eos/><bos/>The points of commonality were limited to (1) the payment of an accrual fee of $25 per cellphone purchased; and (2) an affinity relationship with a breast cancer charity, as the recipient of the accrual fee by way of a $25 charitable contribution from Motorola, and certain dealers. <eos/><bos/>These points of commonality represented, in the case of the Pink Razr campaign, the essence of the campaign but, in the case of the Pink Phone and the Call for the Cure programs, only one of four elements of the campaign.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7cf25008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">44</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Pink Razr campaign was a <begin.quote ID="QT_0023"/>“narrow, manufacturer subsidized time limited promotion for a specific limited edition phone”<end.quote refid="QT_0023"/>. <eos/><bos/>Essentially, the plaintiff&apos;s information all related to a different campaign. <eos/><bos/>There was no information that the plaintiff communicated to Rogers that either provided a reason for the Pink Razr campaign or, in the case of the marketing activities, that would not otherwise have been applied in the design of such campaign. <eos/><bos/>Rogers did not conduct the Pink Razr campaign for any purpose that was derived from information presented in the Pink Phone or the Call for the Cure programs. <eos/><bos/>The object was not to secure new airtime contracts, to reduce the churn rate of existing customers, or to reduce the cost of acquisition of new or retention customers. <eos/><bos/>It could not be said that there was any loyalty, retention or new acquisition component to the Pink Razr campaign. <eos/><bos/>Further, there was nothing in any of the plaintiff&apos;s information that suggested that a stand-alone marketing program, entailing a one-time donation to a breast cancer charity would produce any of the benefits that the plaintiff suggested would have accrued to Rogers had it implemented the plaintiff&apos;s proposals. <eos/><bos/>On their own terms, the Pink Phone and the Call for the Cure programs suggested that a marketing campaign based on a point-of-sale donation would not be successful unless it were incorporated into a much larger and continuing campaign focused on Rogers&apos; existing customer base, and perhaps the particularly extensive network associated with the CBCF. The branded cellphone component of the Pilot Proposal was a very small contributor to both the projected number of airtime contracts contracted for, and the projected profitability of, the program. <eos/><bos/>Moreover, both the Pilot Proposal and the Call for the Cure program relegated marketing to the branded cellphone segment of the market to a later phase.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d0aba08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">45</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Wilton-Spiegel observed that there was nothing unique or confidential in the marketing activities contemplated by the plaintiff in respect of the Pink Phone and the Call for the Cure programs. <eos/><bos/>The marketing activities were presented at a general level. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff could not point to any particular marketing initiative that could be characterized as novel. <eos/><bos/>In any event, the Pink Razr campaign was largely conducted using very different marketing activities from the activities contemplated by the Pink Phone and Call for the Cure programs.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d0d2b08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">46</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2042570374" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I59c28ce18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Hamilton v. F&amp;M Management</cite.query> Ltd.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id7d0d2b18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">47</footnote.reference>] the essence of the plaintiffs&apos; claim was that the defendants induced them to enter into a corporate services agreement and a non-disclosure agreement in order to obtain their confidential information and use it to develop, patent, and successfully market VECTTOR. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff Hamilton was an entrepreneur in the remediation industry. <eos/><bos/>He was the principal of Enviro-Klean which produced a thermal desorption machine called the KM-4. <eos/><bos/>F&amp;M was a management firm that offered corporate advisory services to the waste management and remediation sectors. <eos/><bos/>Calaeris was incorporated to build, develop, and sell a thermal desorption machine called VECTTOR. <eos/><bos/>Bogzaran was a director of both F&amp;M and Calaeris. <eos/><bos/>His brother Ramin was a director of Calaeris but not of F&amp;M. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs retained F&amp;M and entered into the agreements for that purpose.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d0d2b28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">48</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Prior to 2011, Hamilton had known Bogzaran for some time. <eos/><bos/>Bogzaran became aware that Hamilton was considering selling his company and introduced him to his brother. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs entered into the Agreements pursuant to which F&amp;M was to assist in the sale of Enviro-Klean. <eos/><bos/>In exchange for a fee, F&amp;M would prepare a company profile based on confidential and other information received from the plaintiffs, identify potential buyers, and assist in the purchase process. <eos/><bos/>Under the non-disclosure agreement, F&amp;M did not require any rights in or licence to use confidential information received from the plaintiffs. <eos/><bos/>It could only use that information for the purposes set out in these Agreements. <eos/><bos/>The Agreements did not in any way restrict F&amp;M or its principals from contracting with other thermal desorption companies, producers, or inventors to provide them with services similar to those in the Agreements or otherwise from engaging in any activities related to thermal desorption technology.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d0d2b38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">49</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Hoffman, who knew Bogzaran and had worked with him previously on a different thermal desorption process, developed VECTTOR. <eos/><bos/>He deposed that he did so without the involvement of Bogzaran and that he received no information relating to this work from any of F&amp;M, either of the Bogzaran brothers, or Banack, who was also a principal of Calaeris. <eos/><bos/>Hoffman applied for a U.S. patent for VECTTOR on January 25, 2013, and for an international patent on January 24, 2014. <eos/><bos/>Hamilton applied for Canadian and U.S. patents for the KM-4 on June 7, 2013.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d0d2b48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">50</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In April 2014, the International Patent Office issued a non-binding opinion indicating that the Hoffman process was patentable. <eos/><bos/>On December 15, 2015, the U.S. Patent Office issued a non-final rejection of Hamilton&apos;s patent application on the basis that it was too similar to an existing patent. <eos/><bos/>The similarity was not to the Hoffman process, but to another thermal desorption process.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d0d2b58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">51</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>During his examination for discovery, Hamilton stated that the defendants used information that he had provided to them to help with the development of VECTTOR. <eos/><bos/>However, despite being asked repeatedly to specify what that information was, he was evasive and unable to do so.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d0d2b68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">52</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In preparation for the litigation, the defendants commissioned an expert report from Sadler, a chemical engineer with experience and expertise in thermal desorption, incineration, air pollution control, and waste water treatment. <eos/><bos/>He was provided with all of the material Hamilton had provided to F&amp;M under the Agreements, as well as additional information provided by Hamilton to F&amp;M and a CD containing videos of the KM-4. <eos/><bos/>In his report, Sadler reviewed the patent applications filed in support of the KM-4 and VECTTOR, identifying in detail the similarities and differences between them, as well as novel features of each. <eos/><bos/>He concluded that the Hoffman process was significantly different from the Hamilton process. <eos/><bos/>The similarities between the two processes were not unique and had been employed on other processes. <eos/><bos/>Sadler did not compare the KM-4 and VECTTOR machines in operation, because there was no KM-4 in operation that he could have observed.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d0d2b78e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">53</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The defendants did not dispute that some of the information communicated by the plaintiffs to the defendants concerning the KM-4 was confidential. <eos/><bos/>The Chambers judge observed that the question was whether there was any evidence that the defendants misused that information. <eos/><bos/>Hoffman denied receiving any such information. <eos/><bos/>The Chambers judge observed that while Sadler opined that some of the material delivered by the plaintiffs to F&amp;M could be considered confidential and could be used to develop a process similar to that used in the KM-4, that Hoffman&apos;s process did not use those aspects of Hamilton&apos;s process. <eos/><bos/>He also stated that the similarities between the two processes were not unique to them, but were also seen elsewhere in the thermal desorption industry. <eos/><bos/>The Chambers judge concluded that the plaintiffs had not shown that it was more likely than not that F&amp;M breached confidence by misusing information it received from the plaintiffs and disclosing it to Calaeris and/or Hoffman.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d0f9c08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">54</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id7d0f9c18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">55</footnote.reference>] Catalyst claimed that West Face used confidential Catalyst information to successfully acquire an interest in WIND. <eos/><bos/>Both Catalyst and West Face were investment management firms and had been competitors on potential deals including acquiring an interest in WIND. <eos/><bos/>West Face was part of a consortium that acquired WIND. <eos/><bos/>Catalyst had been a bidder for WIND and had an exclusive right for a period of time to negotiate a purchase. <eos/><bos/>When Catalyst failed to conclude a purchase of WIND, West Face and its consortium partners acquired an indirect interest in WIND. <eos/><bos/>Moyse was an analyst at Catalyst for a little under two years. <eos/><bos/>He left Catalyst and worked at West Face for three and a half weeks. <eos/><bos/>It was alleged that at some time between when Moyse first spoke to West Face and when he stopped working at West Face he gave West Face confidential information regarding Catalyst&apos;s strategy to acquire WIND that was used by West Face to structure its bid for WIND. <eos/><bos/>Catalyst acknowledged that it had no direct evidence that Moyse provided confidential information to West Face regarding WIND. <eos/><bos/>It submitted that an inference should be drawn that Moyse did so.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d0f9c28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">56</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Moyse was assigned to Catalyst&apos;s “core” telecommunications deal team and he prepared a <ital>pro-forma</ital> statement that showed a combined WIND and Mobilicity entity. <eos/><bos/>Moyse collected data which was either publicly available or known to Catalyst, and then performed basic arithmetic to yield the final product. <eos/><bos/>No knowledge of Catalyst&apos;s plans or strategy was required for Moyse to complete this assignment. <eos/><bos/>Moyse&apos;s next contribution to Catalyst&apos;s telecommunications file occurred when Catalyst prepared a PowerPoint slide deck for a presentation to be made to Industry Canada. <eos/><bos/>The PowerPoint was intended to be a framework for discussion with Government personnel. <eos/><bos/>The PowerPoint outlined the existing regulatory environment and a number of options available to the Government, and the concessions that Catalyst believed would be required. <eos/><bos/>Generally, the presentation set out three strategic options for the creation of a fourth national wireless carrier. <eos/><bos/>Moyse&apos;s role was largely administrative. <eos/><bos/>He was not involved in any discussions or debates to determine the content of the presentation. <eos/><bos/>Moyse&apos;s contributions involved layout, data input and the creation of two tables based on publicly available information, one of which was the <ital>pro-forma</ital> which Moyse had prepared.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d0f9c38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">57</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Moyse received an oral offer and a written signed employment agreement with West Face following a number of interviews. <eos/><bos/>During conversations between counsel, counsel to Catalyst informed counsel to West Face that Catalyst was particularly concerned about a specific transaction for which Catalyst and West Face had each submitted bids and identified this as a “telecom file”.<eos/><bos/> The day after learning of Catalyst&apos;s concerns about a “telecom deal” and four days before Moyse began work at West Face, the Chief Compliance Officer at West Face erected a confidentiality wall with respect to WIND and Moyse. <eos/><bos/>The confidentiality wall was disclosed to counsel for Catalyst the same day. <eos/><bos/>Pursuant to the confidentiality wall Moyse was forbidden from communicating with anyone at West Face about the ongoing WIND negotiations, and vice-versa, and West Face&apos;s IT group restricted access to all WIND-related documents so that Moyse could not access them. <eos/><bos/>Notification of the confidentiality wall and its terms was circulated to all relevant personnel at West Face including its four partners. <eos/><bos/>The chief compliance officer telephoned Moyse to discuss the terms of restrictions he would be under. <eos/><bos/>In the call, Moyse was told that he was not to talk about WIND with anyone at West Face, to ask anyone at West Face about WIND, to disclose to anyone at West Face any information about WIND or to attempt to access any of West Face&apos;s files regarding WIND. <eos/><bos/>Moyse indicated that he would comply. <eos/><bos/>West Face&apos;s head of technology confirmed that Moyse was excluded from the computer directory containing WIND related documents. <eos/><bos/>Once Moyse began working at West Face, the West Face WIND deal team only met in private, behind closed doors, and away from the trading floor area where Moyse was seated.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d0f9c48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">58</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Equity will pursue confidential information that comes into the hands of a third party who receives it with knowledge that it was communicated in breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>Thus, if West Face received confidential information of Catalyst from Moyse and used it in its acquisition of its interest in WIND to the detriment of Catalyst, relief would be available to Catalyst. <eos/><bos/>The first hurdle faced by Catalyst was to establish that West Face received any information from Moyse regarding Catalyst&apos;s involvement with WIND. <eos/><bos/>Catalyst acknowledged that it could not point to any direct evidence to demonstrate that Moyse transferred Catalyst&apos;s confidential information concerning WIND to West Face. <eos/><bos/>It submitted that the Court must look to the overall course of conduct of West Face to determine if it could be inferred that the transfer of confidential Catalyst information occurred. <eos/><bos/>Catalyst made an elaborate argument that changes made in the strategy of West Face to acquire WIND that led to an offer without any condition requiring Government concessions could reasonably be explained by West Face having obtained the confidential Catalyst information from Moyse and that an inference should be made that there was a transfer of such confidential information by Moyse to West Face. <eos/><bos/>The Court rejected this argument. <eos/><bos/>There was direct evidence that Moyse did not impart any information about Catalyst&apos;s initiative with WIND to anyone at West Face. <eos/><bos/>There was no reason not to accept the evidence of the other West Face witnesses who testified that Moyse never discussed WIND with them. <eos/><bos/>The fact that West Face took pains to impress upon Moyse before he started at West Face that his obligations of confidentiality to Catalyst were to be respected and that it set up a confidentiality wall once it was made aware of Catalyst&apos;s concerns regarding a telecom file that Catalyst said both firms were working on is contrary to the notion that West Face was interested in acquiring information regarding Catalyst&apos;s involvement in WIND.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d0f9c58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">59</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>There were reasons for West Face to make its bid that it did with the consortium other than acting on confidential Catalyst information obtained from Moyse. <eos/><bos/>Regarding West Face&apos;s view that Catalyst was a bidder for WIND, there was sufficient information in the marketplace for West Face to put two and two together to believe or presume that Catalyst was a bidder. <eos/><bos/>The Court would not infer that Moyse told West Face that Catalyst was a bidder for WIND. <eos/><bos/>The persons at West Face involved in the deal believed Catalyst was a bidder without actually knowing that.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The inference which Catalyst asked to be drawn that West Face acquired from Moyse confidential Catalyst information about its interest and strategy to acquire WIND and about its regulatory strategy and that West Face passed that information on to its partners in the consortium would amount to several witnesses purposely giving false testimony. <eos/><bos/>To the contrary, the Court found that Moyse never communicated to anyone at West Face, either in the interview process or later, anything about Catalyst&apos;s dealings with WIND or of Catalyst&apos;s regulatory or telecommunications industry strategy regarding its interest in WIND. <eos/><bos/>On that basis, the action against West Face for breach of confidence failed.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d120d08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">60</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In light of the finding that no Catalyst confidential information was given by Moyse to West Face or passed on to the consortium members, it was not necessary to deal with the issue of whether West Face made use of any Catalyst confidential information in any detail. <eos/><bos/>Assuming, without deciding, that some of the information said to have been passed on by Moyse to West Face was confidential, the Court would not find that West Face made use of it. <eos/><bos/>The price of the bid by West Face and the consortium with an enterprise value of $300 million was based on what VimpelCom and its advisor had made clear to West Face and others as to the amount that VimpelCom required. <eos/><bos/>Even if Moyse had known and told West Face of the intention of Catalyst to bid at an enterprise value of $300 million, West Face made no use of such information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d120d18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">61</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The basic strategy of Catalyst was based on its belief that WIND could not survive without Government concessions that would allow WIND to sell its spectrum to an incumbent by the end of five years. <eos/><bos/>Even had West Face or its consortium members been told of this strategy by Moyse, it played no part in the reasoning of West Face to bid as it did by itself and later with the consortium. <eos/><bos/>West Face did not hold the same view regarding the need for concessions and held the view that so long as WIND would be able to acquire additional spectrum to upgrade its network from a 3G (third generation) wireless network to an LTE network, which was made clear by the Industry Canada announcement on July 4, 2014, WIND would be a viable business. <eos/><bos/>The other consortium members held the same view. <eos/><bos/>For the same reason, even if Moyse disclosed to West Face the views that the potential litigation by some other party against the Government would force the Government to grant concessions and that the Government was therefore softening its position on concessions, that disclosure played no part in the decision of West Face to make the bids that it did. <eos/><bos/>West Face would never have based its strategy on the litigation that some unnamed party other than Catalyst would have pursued against the Federal Government over the regulatory restrictions that limited transferability of the 2008 spectrum licenses. <eos/><bos/>West Face believed that the Government was going to continue to maintain the existing restrictions on transfers of spectrum to incumbents. <eos/><bos/>West Face never understood the Government&apos;s policy stance to be a bluff. <eos/><bos/>In summary, if Moyse provided to West Face any confidential Catalyst information, such information was not used by West Face in its acquisition from VimpelCom of its interest in WIND or of its later acquisition of its shareholding in WIND. <eos/><bos/>For this reason too, the action for breach of confidence against West Face failed.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d120d28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">62</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Ontario Court of Appeal dismissed Catalyst&apos;s appeal from the judgment dismissing the action in <ital>The Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d120d38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">63</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>To succeed on the misuse of confidential information claim, Catalyst had to prove that: Moyse gave confidential information concerning Catalyst&apos;s bid to purchase WIND to West Face; West Face used that confidential information when pursuing its bid for WIND; and the misuse of that confidential information caused detriment to Catalyst. <eos/><bos/>Catalyst did not have direct evidence to support its allegations. <eos/><bos/>It relied on a body of circumstantial evidence.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d120d48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">64</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>On the first issue, whether Moyse had provided confidential information about Catalyst&apos;s strategies in respect of the acquisition of WIND to West Face, Catalyst relied heavily on inferences it claimed should be drawn from Moyse&apos;s conduct while he was pursuing employment with West Face, immediately after he left Catalyst to join West Face, and after litigation was commenced. <eos/><bos/>That evidence included the following: Moyse deliberately provided Catalyst&apos;s confidential information to West Face when he was trying to get a job with West Face. <eos/><bos/>This information did not relate to WIND. <eos/><bos/>Moyse erased emails that showed he provided that confidential information to West Face; Moyse erased all of the contents of the BlackBerry Catalyst had provided to him for work purposes before he returned it to Catalyst after he quit; Moyse made inaccurate and potentially misleading statements in affidavits filed on preliminary motions in the litigation; Moyse deleted his internet browsing history from his personal computer and installed programs to scrub the computer registry where deletions could otherwise be detected, in the face of a court order requiring that he turn his computer over to his lawyer so that the computer could be forensically examined for the purposes of this litigation. <eos/><bos/>Catalyst claimed that Moyse&apos;s conduct was consistent only with him having provided confidential information about Catalyst&apos;s proposed acquisition of WIND to West Face.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d120d58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">65</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Moyse gave various “innocent” explanations for his conduct. <eos/><bos/>West Face also led evidence that when Moyse was hired by West Face, extensive measures were taken to ensure that Moyse had no knowledge of, or involvement in, West Face&apos;s ongoing negotiations for the purchase of WIND shares. <eos/><bos/>The witnesses testified that there were no breaches of this confidentiality wall during the few weeks that Moyse was actually present in the West Face offices.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d120d68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">66</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The respondents also introduced a body of evidence, which they claimed demonstrated that no confidential information from Catalyst had been used in the ultimately successful bid for WIND. <eos/><bos/>The respondents argued that the approach taken by West Face and its consortium to the acquisition of WIND, particularly with respect to the need to obtain certain concessions from the government, was fundamentally different than the approach taken by Catalyst. <eos/><bos/>Consequently, West Face had no use for any information pertaining to Catalyst&apos;s strategies.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d147e08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">67</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The respondents also defended on the basis that the appellant had not proved any damages. <eos/><bos/>The respondents claimed that Catalyst&apos;s bid to acquire WIND in August 2014 failed, not because of any competing bid made by West Face and the consortium, but because Catalyst chose to terminate negotiations with the vendor of the WIND shares after the vendor demanded a significant break fee very late in its negotiations with Catalyst. <eos/><bos/>The respondents contended at trial that the evidence showed that Catalyst chose to end the negotiations rather than agree to the break fee demanded by the vendor. <eos/><bos/>On this argument, Catalyst suffered no damages or detriment, even if Moyse had given confidential information to West Face and West Face had attempted to use that information in its negotiations with the vendor of the WIND shares.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d147e18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">68</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge found against Catalyst on almost every contested factual issue. <eos/><bos/>Specifically, he found that the appellant chose to terminate its negotiations with the vendor of the WIND shares when the vendor demanded a substantial break fee. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge made strong credibility findings against the appellant&apos;s primary witnesses, and equally strong credibility findings in favour of the respondents&apos; witnesses, including Moyse. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge accepted the explanations offered by Moyse for his conduct. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge found, as a fact, that Moyse had not provided any confidential information to West Face in relation to the appellant&apos;s negotiations for the purchase of the WIND shares.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d147e28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">69</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The appellant submitted that the trial judge&apos;s factual findings could not stand, first, because they were the product of an unfair and uneven scrutiny by the trial judge of the competing versions of the relevant events and, second, because they were tainted by several material misapprehensions of the evidence.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d147e38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">70</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The result was almost entirely fact-driven. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge&apos;s findings of fact turned on his assessment of the credibility of the key witnesses, the reliability of their evidence, and the inferences to be drawn from certain primary findings of fact. <eos/><bos/>All of those tasks engaged a myriad of considerations by the trial judge. <eos/><bos/>His determinations were owed strong deference on appeal. <eos/><bos/>The appellant was required to overcome that deference in the face of reasons by the trial judge that displayed a strong command of the evidentiary record and a full understanding of the issues and positions of the parties.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d147e48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">71</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In support of the uneven scrutiny argument, counsel submitted that the credibility of the Catalyst witnesses was subject to a hypercritical microscopic examination by the trial judge. <eos/><bos/>Any misstep or inconsistency in their testimony, no matter how apparently minor, became, for the trial judge, a reason to reject the evidence of those witnesses. <eos/><bos/>In contrast, the trial judge forgave or ignored similar, and much more serious, defects in the evidence of witnesses for the respondents.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d147e58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">72</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Counsel&apos;s submissions made a case for different credibility and reliability assessments than those made by the trial judge. <eos/><bos/>However, that is not enough to warrant appellate intervention. <eos/><bos/>It is not for an appellate court to consider what alternative findings may have been reasonably available on the trial record. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge approached the evidence of the respondents&apos; witnesses no differently than he did the evidence of the appellant&apos;s witnesses. <eos/><bos/>Moyse&apos;s evidence that he did not provide confidential information concerning the WIND negotiations to West Face did not stand alone. <eos/><bos/>The evidence found considerable, largely uncontradicted support in the testimony of the West Face witnesses. <eos/><bos/>It also gained some inferential support in the trial judge&apos;s findings as they related to the West Face strategy in respect of the WIND negotiations, and the ultimate reason for the breakdown of the negotiations between the appellant and the vendor of the WIND shares. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge was alive to the details of the evidence said to demonstrate Moyse&apos;s dishonesty and the unreliability of his evidence. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge examined the evidence particularly as it related to the allegation that Moyse had deliberately deleted material from his personal computer and installed programming to hide that deletion and prevent any recovery of the material. <eos/><bos/>In the end, the trial judge accepted Moyse&apos;s explanations for what he had done, and concluded that it could not be established that Moyse had actually used the programs he had installed on the computer to hide the deletions.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d147e68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">73</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The evaluation of the impact on credibility and reliability of specific inconsistencies and similar flaws in a witness&apos;s testimony lies at the very core of the trial judge&apos;s function. <eos/><bos/>His conclusion that a certain inconsistency negatively impacted on the credibility of one witness, while a different inconsistency did not have the same negative impact on the credibility of a different witness testifying about an entirely different topic, did not, on its own, establish that the trial judge applied different levels of scrutiny to the evidence of those witnesses. <eos/><bos/>Instead, it demonstrated that credibility and reliability assessments are fact and witness-specific.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d16ef08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">74</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Court of Appeal observed no misapprehension of any material facts by the trial judge. <eos/><bos/>Most of the appellant&apos;s arguments failed because they did not reveal any misapprehension of the evidence, but instead revealed that the trial judge preferred the evidence of the respondents&apos; witnesses and the inferences that flowed from that evidence over the competing evidence and inferences relied on by the appellant.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d16ef18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">75</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2048188340" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a0143918e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">The Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. VimpelCom</cite.query> Ltd</ital>.,[<footnote.reference refid="Id7d16ef28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">76</footnote.reference>] after its attempt to purchase Wind failed, Catalyst sued the respondents claiming more than $1 billion in damages. <eos/><bos/>The motions judge dismissed the action on the basis of issue estoppel, cause of action estoppel, and abuse of process. <eos/><bos/>The appeal was dismissed.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d16ef38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">77</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Wind, a Canadian telecommunications provider, was owned by the respondents VimpelCom and Globalive. <eos/><bos/>VimpelCom held the majority of the total equity and Globalive held the majority of the voting equity. <eos/><bos/>Catalyst began negotiating with VimpelCom to purchase that interest. <eos/><bos/>The respondent UBS advised VimpelCom in those negotiations. <eos/><bos/>The negotiations gave rise to two agreements. <eos/><bos/>Catalyst and VimpelCom negotiated a Confidentiality Agreement providing that the existence and content of their negotiations were confidential. <eos/><bos/>Catalyst and VimpelCom signed an Exclusivity Agreement pursuant to which VimpelCom could negotiate only with Catalyst and could not solicit other bids. <eos/><bos/>The exclusivity period under this agreement expired on August 18, 2014. <eos/><bos/>By August 11, 2014, a deal seemed imminent. <eos/><bos/>However, on this date, VimpelCom advised Catalyst that it wanted a $5 million to $20 million break fee and insisted on shortening the regulatory approval period for the deal from three months to two months. <eos/><bos/>Catalyst refused to agree to these demands and ceased negotiations. <eos/><bos/>The exclusivity period expired without a deal. <eos/><bos/>After the exclusivity period expired, a group of purchasers successfully purchased VimpelCom&apos;s interest in Wind. <eos/><bos/>The Consortium concluded the deal within a month of the exclusivity period&apos;s expiry. <eos/><bos/>The Consortium had made an unsolicited purchase proposal to VimpelCom. <eos/><bos/>VimpelCom did not respond to the proposal until the exclusivity period under its Exclusivity Agreement with Catalyst expired.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d16ef48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">78</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Moyse, a junior analyst at Catalyst, left Catalyst and began working for West Face during the course of Catalyst&apos;s negotiations with VimpelCom. <eos/><bos/>He resigned from Catalyst after the signing of the Confidentiality Agreement but before the conclusion of the Exclusivity Agreement. <eos/><bos/>Catalyst commenced an action against Moyse and West Face to enforce the non-competition clause in Moyse&apos;s employment contract with Catalyst prior to the failure of Catalyst&apos;s bid to acquire Wind.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d16ef58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">79</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Following the Consortium&apos;s purchase of VimpelCom&apos;s interest in Wind, Catalyst broadened the scope of the Moyse Action. <eos/><bos/>It amended its statement of claim to allege that Moyse had communicated confidential information to West Face about Catalyst&apos;s acquisition strategy with respect to Wind. <eos/><bos/>Catalyst alleged that West Face used the confidential information it received from Moyse to successfully acquire Wind from VimpelCom. <eos/><bos/>Justice Newbould concluded that Catalyst had failed to make out each of the three elements of the breach of confidence claim. <eos/><bos/>First, Moyse did not communicate any confidential information about Catalyst&apos;s acquisition strategy to West Face. <eos/><bos/>Second, West Face made no use of such information in acquiring Wind. <eos/><bos/>Third, even if West Face made use of Catalyst&apos;s confidential information, Catalyst suffered no detriment.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d16ef68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">80</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Tulloch observed that Justice Newbould&apos;s findings in the Moyse action on the detriment requirement of the breach of confidence cause of action were most relevant to this appeal. <eos/><bos/>First, Justice Newbould found that it was Catalyst&apos;s failure to agree to the break fee that VimpelCom requested that caused Catalyst to cease negotiations with VimpelCom. <eos/><bos/>Second, Justice Newbould found that there was “no chance” that Catalyst could have closed the deal with VimpelCom because Catalyst insisted on making the deal conditional on receiving regulatory concessions from Industry Canada, a condition VimpelCom was unwilling to agree to. <eos/><bos/>The Court of Appeal dismissed Catalyst&apos;s appeal in the Moyse action.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d16ef78e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">81</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The respondents in the Current Action moved to dismiss Catalyst&apos;s claims. <eos/><bos/>Following the Court of Appeal&apos;s dismissal of Catalyst&apos;s appeal in the Moyse Action, the motions judge released reasons dismissing Catalyst&apos;s claim. <eos/><bos/>The motions judge dismissed the claim on the basis of issue estoppel and cause of action estoppel against VimpelCom and Globalive, as well as against Tennenbaum, 64NM LP, 64NM GP, and LG. While Globalive and the US Investors were not parties to the Moyse Action, the motions judge found that they were privies of West Face. <eos/><bos/>The motions judge also dismissed Catalyst&apos;s claim against all respondents as an abuse of process. <eos/><bos/>Finally, the motions judge struck Catalyst&apos;s claim of breach of contract against Globalive and UBS without leave to amend.[<footnote.reference refid="Id7d196008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">82</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Catalyst submitted that Justice Newbould&apos;s findings were in obiter and collateral because they were not necessary to his decision. <eos/><bos/>For Catalyst, the central issue in the Moyse Action was whether Moyse passed confidential information to West Face and since Justice Newbould found that Moyse had not, his other findings were collateral. <eos/><bos/>Justice Tulloch rejected this submission. <eos/><bos/>Catalyst&apos;s submission was premised on the assumption that the only fundamental issue in the Moyse Action was whether Moyse passed confidential information to West Face. <eos/><bos/>However, to succeed in its breach of confidence claim, Catalyst was also required to prove that West Face used confidential information in its bid for Wind and that this misuse caused detriment to Catalyst.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d196018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">83</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Tulloch noted that Canadian courts have consistently rejected the argument that a judicial finding is merely dictum or collateral because there was another sufficient basis for the judge&apos;s decision. <eos/><bos/>Accepting Catalyst&apos;s argument would lead to absurd consequences, because it would make the applicability of issue estoppel dependent on the order in which the court chose to address issues in its reasons.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d196028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">84</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Catalyst further submitted that Justice Newbould&apos;s findings were merely overlapping facts such that the same question was not determined. <eos/><bos/>For Catalyst, the Moyse Action was about confidential information that Moyse received and transmitted. <eos/><bos/>In contrast, Catalyst submitted that this action concerned the transmission of confidential information by VimpelCom and/or UBS to the Consortium in breach of the Confidentiality Agreement and the Exclusivity Agreement. <eos/><bos/>As a result, it follows that Justice Newbould&apos;s finding that even if Moyse did pass on confidential information to West Face, and such confidential information did not cause detriment to Catalyst, it did not mean that confidential information that VimpelCom and/or UBS leaked to the Consortium did not cause detriment to Catalyst. <eos/><bos/>Justice Tulloch did not accept this argument. <eos/><bos/>It was premised on a misunderstanding of what the parties put at issue in the Moyse Action. <eos/><bos/>The Moyse Action necessarily concerned the overall conduct of West Face and the other Consortium members. <eos/><bos/>As Catalyst had no direct evidence that Moyse gave West Face confidential information, it submitted that the court should infer from all the evidence that he did so. <eos/><bos/>As Justice Newbould recognized, this required the court to examine West Face&apos;s “overall course of conduct” to determine if there was a transfer of Catalyst&apos;s confidential information or if there were other explanations for West Face&apos;s conduct. <eos/><bos/>Therefore, whether West Face received any confidential information in breach of the Confidentiality Agreement and the Exclusivity Agreement, and whether West Face&apos;s use of confidential information caused any detriment to Catalyst, were live issues at trial. <eos/><bos/>Justice Newbould was thus required to analyze whether the conduct of West Face and other Consortium members was consistent with the use of confidential information and whether there was any evidence that the use of confidential information caused Catalyst a detriment. <eos/><bos/>He was entitled to draw inferences from the evidence as to what would likely have happened but for a misuse of confidential information. <eos/><bos/>As the motions judge noted, West Face invited Justice Newbould to make findings of fact that Catalyst failed to acquire Wind because it refused VimpelCom&apos;s demand for a break fee and because it would have been unable to obtain regulatory concessions. <eos/><bos/>Catalyst did not object to any of these proposed findings of fact as being outside of the scope of the Moyse Action. <eos/><bos/>In fact, Catalyst elicited considerable evidence on the dealings between VimpelCom and UBS, and the Consortium, and urged Justice Newbould to make certain findings in respect of these dealings. <eos/><bos/>Catalyst could not now complain that it was improper for Justice Newbould to make contrary findings or that those contrary findings were not essential to his decision. <eos/><bos/>Justice Tulloch did not accept Catalyst&apos;s argument that Justice Newbould&apos;s findings on detriment were restricted to detriment from confidential information transmitted by Moyse. <eos/><bos/>Catalyst chose to put at issue not only the Consortium&apos;s entire conduct, but also the reasons why Catalyst failed to acquire Wind and whether misuse of confidential information by the Consortium had anything to do with that failure. <eos/><bos/>Justice Newbould did not overstep his bounds in finding against Catalyst on these issues.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d196038e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">85</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Catalyst submitted that Justice Newbould&apos;s findings about why it failed to acquire Wind would not bar it from gaining a remedy for its claims. <eos/><bos/>Catalyst argued that, even accepting Justice Newbould&apos;s findings, it was nonetheless entitled to recovery. <eos/><bos/>Justice Tulloch rejected this submission. <eos/><bos/>In its argument, Catalyst, relying on certain statements in <ital>Cadbury Schweppes</ital> that establish that the court has jurisdiction to grant a remedy dictated by the facts of the case rather than strict doctrinal considerations, argued that it may be entitled to equitable remedies such as an accounting of profits even if it suffered no financial loss. <eos/><bos/>However, Justice Tulloch observed that the jurisprudence is clear that a claimant must prove detriment to establish liability for breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>There is no contradiction between this requirement to prove detriment and the passages from <ital>Cadbury Schweppes</ital> that Catalyst points to. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, Justice Newbould findings would bar Catalyst from establishing the liability of West Face, Globalive, and the US Investors for breach of confidence.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d196048e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">86</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Moreover, Justice Tulloch did not place weight on the availability of alternative remedies. <eos/><bos/>Catalyst did not plead any of the alternative remedies such as an accounting for profits that it now referred to on appeal. <eos/><bos/>Instead, it repeatedly pled that the breach of confidence and inducement of breach of contract caused it to fail to acquire Wind. <eos/><bos/>This was a precise inconsistency with Justice Newbould&apos;s findings. <eos/><bos/>In the present case, the motions judge correctly identified that the need to prove detriment, namely that the respondents&apos; conduct caused Catalyst to fail to acquire Wind, was a material fact common to the relevant causes of action Catalyst asserted in both actions.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d196058e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">87</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00007" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2038174898" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I5a24aa118e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Seyedi v. Nexen</cite.query> Inc.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id7d1bd108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">88</footnote.reference>] the following issue was raised on this appeal: (a) Can misappropriation be established where Nexen made no use of the Plan after Seyedi&apos;s departure?[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d1bd118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">89</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The appellant was an experienced foreign-trained engineer who participated in the Alberta Human Services&apos; program to provide him with Canadian engineering experience. <eos/><bos/>The program was administered by the Calgary Catholic Immigration Society. <eos/><bos/>A letter of understanding was entered into between CCIS, Seyedi and the Respondent Nexen pursuant to which Seyedi served a three-month unpaid practicum with Nexen. <eos/><bos/>At the conclusion of that practicum, Nexen did not offer employment to Seyedi as he had hoped. <eos/><bos/>He then sued Nexen claiming misappropriation of certain intellectual property he had provided to it, aimed at solving a certain environmental problem. <eos/><bos/>Nexen counterclaimed, asserting that Seyedi had misappropriated confidential information when he departed at the end of his practicum.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d1bd128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">90</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Nexen called no evidence at trial. <eos/><bos/>Seyedi called, in addition to testifying himself, two witnesses, both Nexen employees, notwithstanding the trial judge&apos;s repeated warnings about the risks of calling witnesses allied with Nexen as part of his own case. <eos/><bos/>Both of these witnesses denied that Nexen used his Plan at any time. <eos/><bos/>It had identified and adopted another approach to solving the problem to which the Plan was directed. <eos/><bos/>Seyedi unsuccessfully attempted to convince the judge otherwise, although he led no other direct evidence on this point. <eos/><bos/>Seyedi admitted to having no personal knowledge to the contrary during his own testimony, also admitting that, upon his departure from Nexen, he took Nexen documents without consent.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d1bd138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">91</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In dismissing his claim, the trial judge held that Seyedi&apos;s unpaid practicum constituted “employment”, with the result that the Plan developed while with Nexen belonged to it. <eos/><bos/>In any event, the Plan was not unique to him as the same concept had been examined and rejected twice previously by Nexen. <eos/><bos/>Most importantly, Seyedi had not proven that Nexen used the Plan, or any intellectual property that he had developed.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d1bd148e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">92</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Misappropriation of information obtained in confidence creates a cause of action only where the respondent makes use of that property. <eos/><bos/>As observed in the decision under appeal, in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00008" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1989312320" w-pub-number="0005156" ID="I5a2cc0608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>International Corona Resources Ltd. v. LAC Minerals Ltd</ital>., [1989] 2 S.C.R. 574 (S.C.C.)</cite.query> at 635 La Forest J stated:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0024"/>The test for whether there has been a breach of confidence … consists in establishing three elements: that the information conveyed was confidential, that it was communicated in confidence and that it was misused by the party to whom it was communicated.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0024"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id7d1bd158e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">93</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The uncontroverted evidence at trial was that Nexen had made no use of the Plan after his departure and had no intention to do so in the future. <eos/><bos/>Seyedi himself had no personal knowledge of what Nexen did or did not do with this information after his departure. <eos/><bos/>In particular, the uncontroverted evidence from the two witnesses called by Seyedi was that Nexen had never implemented the Plan. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge refused to draw inferences that these witnesses were lying from coincidental timing concerns, innuendo and suspicion raised by Seyedi, including inferences that the dates on certain Nexen documents were wrong based on gas pricing information contained in them. <eos/><bos/>Seyedi failed to show that the trial judge was clearly wrong in failing to draw these inferences based on what was, at best, a thin, speculative argument.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d1bd168e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">94</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Indeed, the evidence he himself led shows he wanted Nexen to use his idea; the whole purpose of his suggestion of an alternate process to solve an upgrader problem was that Nexen would adopt the process. <eos/><bos/>It did not. <eos/><bos/>His claim was not, at heart, that Nexen should not have used his idea; it was that Nexen should have used his idea and compensated him for it. <eos/><bos/>There was no basis in the evidence or law to impose such obligations on Nexen.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d1bd178e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">95</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Seyedi had not established that the trial judge made a palpable and overriding error in finding that no such misappropriation occurred.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d1e4208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">96</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A claim for damages by the plaintiff arising from the alleged misuse of confidential business information by the defendants was dismissed in <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00009" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2034750957" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I5a33c5418e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Seaway Marine Services Ltd. v. Weiwaikum General Partner</cite.query> Ltd.</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id7d1e4218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">97</footnote.reference>] The case concerned the ownership and operation of a marine fuel barge docked at a marina. <eos/><bos/>The fuel barge and associated equipment was owned by Esso for several years. <eos/><bos/>Esso decided to divest itself of all marine fuel dock operations on the British Columbia coast. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff was notified of Esso&apos;s intention to not renew their dealership agreement. <eos/><bos/>Shortly thereafter, the plaintiff expressed an interest to Esso in buying the fuel barge and associated equipment from Esso, and assuming Esso&apos;s lease. <eos/><bos/>The Weiwaikum board assumed management of certain marina-related assets, including the Esso lease which was soon coming to an end. <eos/><bos/>The Weiwaikum board sent letters requesting various items of information related to the lease to Esso and to the plaintiff concerning the lease and the marine fuel operation. <eos/><bos/>It received representations from the plaintiff in support of the plaintiff&apos;s plan to purchase the fuel barge and assume the lease. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff&apos;s reply to Weiwaikum enclosed a “Letter of Intent” indicating that the plaintiff was in the midst of negotiations with Esso to purchase the fuel barge and with Devco to assume Esso&apos;s leasehold. <eos/><bos/>Weiwaikum ultimately decided that the Limited Partnership would purchase the fuel barge from Esso.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d1e4228e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">98</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff alleged that the defendants breached confidence in relation to the information the plaintiff communicated, including reports on the condition and value of the fuel barge; the plaintiff&apos;s financial statements; and an outline of the plaintiff&apos;s operational plan for the marine fuel business. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge observed that equity is “quick to protect confidences” and sets a “relatively low threshold” on the type of information capable of providing the foundation for a breach of confidence claim. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge had no difficulty in concluding that the information as to the barge condition and value, the information in the financial statements, and the aspects of the “operational plan” was confidential information and accepted on that basis by Weiwaikum. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff&apos;s documents were manifestly confidential. <eos/><bos/>The information in them would have been known to very few outside of the plaintiff, was acquired by the expenditure of the plaintiff&apos;s money or its effort, and could not be easily acquired or duplicated by others. <eos/><bos/>The defendants received the information from business letters exchanged during the course of commercial negotiations. <eos/><bos/>The reasonable person standing in the shoes of the defendants would have realized on reasonable grounds that the information was being given by the plaintiff in confidence, and the equitable duty of confidence was therefore imposed.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d1e4238e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">99</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In the course of the exchange of letters, Weiwaikum stated that it was in the process of reviewing the various options available to it relating to the fuel facility. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff argued that it was objectively reasonable for its representatives to think that the word “options” related to lease options in relation to the plaintiff and that the option of the defendants choosing to run the business was not “reasonably in prospect”.<eos/><bos/> The trial judge did not accept that the language in the letter should be read down so as to include only options that would involve the plaintiff&apos;s ongoing participation in the marine fuel business. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff must be taken to have known that one of Weiwaikum&apos;s options would be to negotiate to buy the barge. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge observed that what the plaintiff knew, or a reasonable person in the plaintiff&apos;s position must be taken to have known, was important only insofar as it informed what Weiwaikum, as the recipient of the information, knew or must be taken to have known when it came into receipt of the confidential information. <eos/><bos/>There was no reason for Weiwaikum to be fixed with the knowledge that the plaintiff was sending the confidential barge information on the basis that Weiwaikum would only use it to consider business options that involved the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>Weiwaikum was entitled to use the confidential barge information it received from Seaway to consider its various options, including the option of a Band entity purchasing the fuel barge and running the business without the plaintiff&apos;s involvement.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d1e4248e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">100</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge was also inclined to find that the use of the financial statements for purposes other than determining whether the plaintiff was a viable tenant was unauthorized, absent other considerations. <eos/><bos/>However, the plaintiff replied to the defendant&apos;s letter of request by stating that it was more than capable of assuming the financial commitments of the current lease, and that it was willing to forward the financial statements if necessary and it is demonstrated that this is a standard requirement of all lessees or assignees. <eos/><bos/>The response from Weiwaikum spoke of confirming the financial status of the plaintiff and stated that requiring the financial statements of prospective lessees or assignees is common practice. <eos/><bos/>This response, and the language used by the plaintiff in its letter enclosing the financial statements would lead a reasonable recipient of the financial statements to the conclusion that they were to be used for the purpose of deciding whether the plaintiff would be a viable tenant and not otherwise.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d1e4258e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">101</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge reached the same conclusion with regard to the confidential aspects of the “operational plan.” <eos/><bos/>The Weiwaikum request was specific: <begin.quote ID="QT_0025"/>“In order for the Landlord to consider your request for a ten year lease, we will need to receive a business plan from you outlining your plans for the use and operation of the Fuel Facility.”<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0025"/> The plaintiff&apos;s response was that no business plan was needed as the plan was to sell fuel for ten years plus any optional years. <eos/><bos/>Weiwaikum replied that if the plaintiff was interested in a new lease, Weiwaikum required a business plan as part of its due diligence. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff then sent the one-page “operational plan” alongside a reiteration of its position that it was seeking an assignment of the existing lease rather than a new lease. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge concluded that this exchange of correspondence would lead a reasonable recipient of the confidential aspects of the plaintiff&apos;s “operational plan” to conclude that the permitted use was in connection with deciding whether the plaintiff would be a viable tenant and not otherwise.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d20b308e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">102</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge&apos;s conclusion that the defendants were entitled to use the plaintiff&apos;s barge information when considering all of the various options for the fuel dock narrowed the issue to whether the defendants made use of the financial statements or confidential aspects of the “operational plan” for purposes other than assessing the viability of the plaintiff as a tenant. <eos/><bos/>Briefing notes prepared for a meeting with Chief Pollard included a reference to information from figures extracted from the plaintiff&apos;s 2005 income statement and reflected use of the financial statements for an unauthorized purpose. <eos/><bos/>The use of the information in the financial statements as part of a briefing note for a meeting to consider whether the Limited Partnership should take over the marine fuel dock was not a permitted use of this confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The question whether the information was actually factored in to the decision to purchase and run the fuel barge was another matter. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge considered it unlikely that there was substantive discussion at this brief meeting on the question of whether the Limited Partnership should take over the fuel dock business, and highly unlikely that any use was made during this meeting of the plaintiff&apos;s 2005 financial figures.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d20b318e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">103</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff argued that the timing of a meeting by the Weiwaikum board and Chief Pollard with Esso representatives, occurring just a few days after Weiwaikum received confidential information from the plaintiff, together with the exclusion of the plaintiff from the meeting, was powerful evidence in support of its case. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge concluded that this meeting was scheduled at the instance of Esso. <eos/><bos/>Esso had the date in mind before the plaintiff&apos;s letter was written. <eos/><bos/>There was nothing on Esso&apos;s agenda that called for the plaintiff&apos;s attendance. <eos/><bos/>It was fair to characterize Esso&apos;s agenda as that of a tenant meeting with its landlord in advance of the expiry of its lease. <eos/><bos/>There certainly was some discussion during the meeting of the terms on which Esso might deal with Weiwaikum, but there was no support for the notion that Weiwaikum or Chief Pollard made use of Seaway&apos;s financial statements or “operational plan”.<eos/><bos/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id7d20b328e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">104</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff alleged that during the period from the date that Weiwaikum received the plaintiff&apos;s confidential information until the date of purchase of the fuel barge from Esso, Weiwaikum and the Band used the confidential information to assess the risk in deciding to take over the fuel dock. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge concluded that there was no evidence that pointed to the conclusion that the defendants likely made use of the financial statements or confidential aspects of the operational plan in coming to their decisions to buy the barge and run the marine fuel business.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d20b338e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">105</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The only misuse of confidential information demonstrated was very limited, namely, the inclusion of data from the 2005 financial statements in the Weiwaikum briefing note. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence that the very limited misuse of the confidential information played any part in the decision taken to acquire the fuel barge and operate the marine fuel business. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff was in no different position than it would have been in had the misuse not occurred. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff failed to prove damages on a <begin.quote ID="QT_0026"/>“common sense view of causation.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0026"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id7d20b348e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">106</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff was not entitled to compensatory damages for the defendants&apos; misuse of confidential information despite the submission that this result was foreclosed by the necessary imposition on the defendants of a <begin.quote ID="QT_0029"/>“special disability in the field of competition”<end.quote refid="QT_0029"/>. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge understood the plaintiff&apos;s argument to be that this “special disability” was imposed regardless of the nature and extent of the misuse of confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge observed that the difficulty with this argument was that it lost sight of the relationship between the concept of “special disability” and the concept of using information as a “spring-board” to get an “unfair start”; stating:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0030"/>It is not every misuse of confidential information, regardless of how limited or trifling, that triggers the application of the “special disability.” <eos/><bos/>In the case at bar the defendants did not make use of the information as a <begin.quote ID="QT_0028"/>“spring-board for activities detrimental to the person who made the confidential communication”<end.quote refid="QT_0028"/> so there is no question of obtaining an unfair start and no basis for finding that the defendants were specially disabled from acquiring the marine fuel business in these particular circumstances.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0030"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0031"/>In <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00010" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017324749" w-pub-number="0006457" ID="I5a3e4c908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Aram Systems Ltd. v. NovAtel Inc.</ital>, 2008 ABQB 441 (Alta. Q.B.)</cite.query>, <case.history>aff&apos;d</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00011" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2019530368" w-pub-number="0006455" ID="I5a3e4c928e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2009 ABCA 262 (Alta. C.A.)</cite.query>, MacLeod J. wrote, at para. 105, that regardless of how the breach of confidence obligation is characterized, <begin.quote ID="QT_0027"/>“the Court&apos;s concern is with enforcing the reasonable expectations of the parties in the particular commercial context.”<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0027"/> From this narrow perspective, it cannot be seriously contended that it would have been within the expectation of Seaway or the defendants that the mere receipt or trifling misuse of the confidential information would result in the defendants being cleared from the field of competition for the marine fuel business.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0031"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0032"/>Moreover, there is a broader perspective to consider. <eos/><bos/>While there is no question of the importance of the policy of the law that confidences are to be respected, to impose the competitive disability on the defendants advocated for by Seaway in the absence of a finding that the defendants made use of the information as a “spring-board” would be inconsistent with the strong public interest in the maintenance of commercial competition spoken of by Smith J.A. in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00012" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2005997312" w-pub-number="0006458" ID="I5a3f0fe08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Expert Travel Financial Security (E.T.F.S.) Inc. v. BMS Harris &amp; Dixon Insurance Brokers Ltd.</ital>, 2005 BCCA 5 (B.C. C.A.)</cite.query> at para. 79. <eos/><bos/>The proper balance between the policy of the law that encourages competition and the policy of the law that protects commercial confidences would be upset by finding that the defendants were uniquely disabled from acquiring the fuel barge business in circumstances where the confidential information played no role in its acquisition.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0032"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id7d232408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">107</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge observed that the result should not differ between a case where information is in fact “nothing very special” and a case where information may have value but is treated by the recipient as if it was “nothing very special”.<eos/><bos/> The trial judge concluded that the plaintiff&apos;s claim failed because the limited misuse of the confidential information by Weiwaikum made no difference to the plaintiff&apos;s position. <eos/><bos/>The breach of confidence was not sufficiently serious that the Court should invoke its equitable discretion to award damages.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d232418e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">108</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>ThyssenKrupp Elevator (Canada) Ltd. v. Amos</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id7d232428e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">109</footnote.reference>] the court had an opportunity to consider the question of how the classic “trial model” response to a motion for summary judgment is affected in a breach of confidence case by the “culture shift” mandated by the Supreme Court of Canada in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00013" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2032582324" w-pub-number="0006489" ID="I5a4132c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Combined Air Mechanical Services Inc. v. Flesch</ital>, 2014 SCC 7 (S.C.C.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff alleged that the defendant was induced to leave its employ to take up a position with the corporate defendants. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff alleged that the defendant violated the non-competition, non-solicitation and confidentiality clauses of his employment contract, a separate confidentiality agreement, and his fiduciary duties. <eos/><bos/>The defendants sought summary judgment on the basis that that plaintiff had no firsthand evidence of illicit solicitation of customers or misuse of confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff responded that the evidence of what the defendants did to solicit customers of the plaintiff was uniquely within the knowledge of the defendants. <eos/><bos/>On that basis, the plaintiff suggested that it was entitled to documentary discovery and examinations for discovery in order to compel the defendants to provide the necessary evidence. <eos/><bos/>The court could infer that there were material issues of fact requiring a trial by extrapolating or “following the dots” from the limited evidence that the plaintiffs had obtained.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d232438e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">110</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The court observed that it remains the obligation of parties responding to a motion for summary judgment to “put their best foot forward” or to “lead trump or risk losing”.<eos/><bos/> The defendant expressly denied releasing confidential information to his new employer. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff could have sought directions to compel the defendants to produce their affidavits of documents prior to the hearing of the motion. <eos/><bos/>It did not seek the right to conduct examinations for discovery or take steps to schedule other examinations. <eos/><bos/>It also did not produce its own affidavit of documents. <eos/><bos/>Under the roadmap provided in <ital>Hryniak</ital>, counsel can no longer just point to a contested issue of fact to then consign the parties to the slowest and most expensive outcome under the “trial model”.<eos/><bos/> The motion judge observed:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0033"/>… Here, it is not hard to imagine the existence of some documents that could help the plaintiff&apos;s case. <eos/><bos/>One can never dismiss peoples&apos; propensity to write emails that contain information that is harmful to their own legal interests. <eos/><bos/>It would not be hard to imagine someone emailing Mr. Amos to ask if he thinks a potential client would like this or that—with Mr. Amos then drawing upon his experience with the client to respond potentially in breach of his confidentiality obligations whether intentionally so or not.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0033"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0034"/>Where does an issue of fishing for production come into play in the <ital>Hryniak</ital> roadmap? <eos/><bos/>The question is not one for drawing inferences on the facts or assessing credibility. <eos/><bos/>I do not need to hear from the plaintiff as it has no evidence. <eos/><bos/>Mr. Amos has already been cross-examined and I have read the full transcript. <eos/><bos/>I do not need him again. <eos/><bos/>The question is whether to order production of documents, perhaps even limited production of documents, so as to give the plaintiff (and the Court) a better assurance that there is no smoking gun in circumstances where despite the lack of evidence, a degree of suspicion is reasonable.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0034"/></paratext></para></display.quote><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motions judge concluded that it can no longer suffice to put parties to the cost and imposition of litigation based on the default position of the trial model being fairer. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff, faced with several avenues to seek production from the defendants to respond to the motion for summary judgment chose to limit its investigations and just ask for the motion to be dismissed so the parties could go to discovery. <eos/><bos/>The action should be dismissed. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff had not brought forward evidence to raise a material issue of fact require a trial. <eos/><bos/>To allow some discovery of documents would be tantamount to a fishing expedition. <eos/><bos/>The motions judge was able to fairly and justly adjudicate the dispute and defaulting to the “trial model” by ordering discovery was not a timely, affordable or proportionate procedure.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d232448e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">111</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Not every case where summary judgment is sought is appropriate for summary determination. <eos/><bos/>Although a motion judge is required to assume that the parties have, in fact, placed before the court all of the evidence necessary for the judge to be able to confidently resolve the dispute, summary judgment should be denied where it is clear to the judge that there is material evidence that should be before the court but is not. <eos/><bos/>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00014" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2041145364" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a43cad18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Hamilton v. Desert Lake Family Resort</cite.query> Inc.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id7d232458e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">112</footnote.reference>] the plaintiffs&apos; claims were grounded in contract. <eos/><bos/>The counterclaim sought damages for breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>The defence position on the main action was that there were multiple triable issues and that the most just and proportionate means of resolving the dispute between the parties was by way of a trial, conducted in accordance with the simplified procedure. <eos/><bos/>Alternatively, the defence argued that if summary judgment was to be granted, the plaintiffs&apos; action should be dismissed and the defendant should have judgment on its counterclaim for breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>The motions judge declined to grant summary judgment.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d259508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">113</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiffs were two couples. <eos/><bos/>The Hamiltons and the Wilsons each owned trailers which they purchased from the defendant. <eos/><bos/>The defendant owned and operated a family campground property and also operated as a dealer of trailers. <eos/><bos/>From the time they were purchased, until 2015, the plaintiffs&apos; trailers were located on what were described as premium waterfront lots at the defendant&apos;s resort. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs&apos; dealings, in the course of their respective discussions which led to the purchase of their trailers, were with Brett Coleman. <eos/><bos/>In February 2013, the Pillays purchased the shares in the resort from the Colemans. <eos/><bos/>In 2014 and 2015, there were some discussions between Hamilton and the Pillays towards a possible acquisition to purchase a majority of the shares in the resort. <eos/><bos/>Those negotiations eventually broke down and, shortly afterwards, the relationship between the Hamiltons and the Pillays became acrimonious. <eos/><bos/>The interests of the Wilsons were largely aligned with those of the Hamiltons. <eos/><bos/>The Hamiltons were advised that their licence to occupy the waterfront site which their trailer was located on would not be renewed upon its expiry in October 2015. <eos/><bos/>The Hamiltons were also informed that the defendant did not recognize the so-called “resale guarantee” which the plaintiffs claimed was a critical factor in their decision to purchase the trailers. <eos/><bos/>The Wilsons left the resort around the same time as the Hamiltons, believing that they, too, would not be able to enforce the guarantee which they believed they had been given.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d259518e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">114</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The evidence of Pillay was that, in July 2013, she was told by Brett Coleman that no commitments or promises had been made by him to anyone about selling their trailers on waterfront lots. <eos/><bos/>However, when, following the commencement of the action, the Pillays commenced third party proceedings against the Colemans, the Colemans delivered a third party defence in which they pleaded that the agreements for the purchase of the trailers by the Hamiltons and the Wilsons expressly guaranteed that the trailers could be sold on-site. <eos/><bos/>The third party action had since been resolved. <eos/><bos/>A term of the settlement of that action precluded the Colemans from discussing with other parties, including the plaintiffs, the matters in dispute in the main action.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d259528e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">115</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motion judge observed that the absence of any evidence from Brett Coleman was troubling. <eos/><bos/>The counterclaim was just as problematic. <eos/><bos/>The basis for the counterclaim for breach of confidence was the alleged dissemination by Hamilton of confidential financial information which he obtained from the defendant during the course of his negotiations to purchase an interest in the defendant corporation. <eos/><bos/>There was also an allegation that Hamilton misused this confidential information for purposes unconnected with the possible purchase of shares. <eos/><bos/>This occurred when a company, incorporated by Hamilton for the purpose, attempted to take an assignment from the Colemans of a vendor take back mortgage on the resort. <eos/><bos/>With respect to the counterclaim, it was difficult to assess whether it was more than merely tactical. <eos/><bos/>Suffice it to say that it was not totally devoid of merit, but even if the motion judge were to find that there was a valid claim, no evidence had been adduced which would enable the Court to assess the extent to which, if at all, the defendant had suffered damages. <eos/><bos/>The motion judge did not rule out the possibility that deploying the court&apos;s fact finding powers under r. 20.04(2.1) might be sufficient to fill the evidentiary gaps but it was also possible that a tailored trial procedure employing some of the directions and terms set out in r. 20.05(2) could provide an equally efficient and, possibly, fairer process. <eos/><bos/>The parties were therefore invited to confer and consider their respective positions on the most efficient way to move forward, following which the parties should attend a directions hearing.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d259538e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">116</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Duncan Sabine Collyer Partners LLP v. Campbell</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id7d259548e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">117</footnote.reference>] the personal defendant became an employee of the plaintiff on January 1st, 2005. <eos/><bos/>The personal defendant at no held a partnership or equity position in the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>It appeared that the personal defendant was in practical terms running the firm&apos;s branch. <eos/><bos/>There was no direct evidence of the personal defendant&apos;s utilization of such things as the revenues and pricing structures of the plaintiff for his own or others financial benefit. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff made a very general allegation in its pleading: <begin.quote ID="QT_0035"/>“He used our confidential information in relation to our customer lists and his knowledge of our clients.”<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0035"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id7d259558e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">118</footnote.reference>] The defendant was clear in his absolute denial of using pricing, client lists or other records. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff was not able to give one specific example of a former client being persuaded to utilize Campbell&apos;s firm by his actual breach of his fiduciary duty to his former employer. <eos/><bos/>In addition, the court had no evidence showing that the defendants used the plaintiff&apos;s confidential information in such a fashion to benefit themselves financially or to harm the reputation or profitability of the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>The court was left with a “he said” or “she said” scenario without reference to one single client conversion. <eos/><bos/>There appeared to have been no effort on the plaintiff&apos;s part to cross-index and check its own client list at sale against the acquired business clients the next year by BDO. <eos/><bos/>An investigation or questioning of at least some of these “missing” clients as to why they did not take their accounting business to BDO would perhaps have provided at least one example of client conversion and the relevant reasons why. While the plaintiff&apos;s case was plausible and defendable in theory, there was no evidence available for consideration on the motion which would defeat the defendants&apos; motion for summary judgment. <eos/><bos/>The defendants had by pointing out the lack of evidence concerning their alleged fiduciary breach, shifted the onus to the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff simply had no evidence in this area to defeat the defendants.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d259568e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">119</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In terms of the obligation of all employees not to misuse confidential information of the former employer, the courts have held that trade secrets and customer lists are confidential. <eos/><bos/>However, there is some ambiguity as to whether “confidential information” includes the names of such customers, and their needs and preferences, that the employee has learned during his period of service and can recall. <eos/><bos/>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00015" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2027291812" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I5a4b93018e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Parrish &amp; Heimbecker Ltd. v. Delmar Commodities</cite.query> Ltd.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id7d280608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">120</footnote.reference>] the plaintiff sought from both Hodgson and Delmar return of its confidential information and an injunction enjoining them from using such confidential information or soliciting its customers, particularly in an area of Manitoba described as the “northeast territory”.<eos/><bos/> The defendant Hodgson was employed by the plaintiff until September 6, 2011 when he went to work for Delmar, a supplier and competitor of the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>In the winter of 2010/11, Delmar decided that because the plaintiff had chosen not to extend its reach into the northeast territory with a facility in the area, it would do so. <eos/><bos/>It entered into an agreement to acquire land and engaged local contractors to do the construction work. <eos/><bos/>Delmar did not advise the plaintiff of its intention to build this facility until after Hodgson had joined the company. <eos/><bos/>On September 6, 2011, Hodgson resigned from his employment with the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>He had sought out other employment and as a result secured two offers, one from Delmar for the position of Territory Manager for Eastern Manitoba. <eos/><bos/>He took the job and began work shortly thereafter. <eos/><bos/>Hodgson denied that he took any customer list or other property of the plaintiff when he left its employ. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff had no evidence that he took any such documentation. <eos/><bos/>There was no formal employment contract between Hodgson and the plaintiff, although he did endorse his acknowledgement on the plaintiff&apos;s employee handbook which contained a provision obliging all employees to maintain in strict confidence information received by the plaintiff or its customers and requiring them not to disclose this information either during the period of employment or at any time thereafter.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d280618e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">121</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motions judge observed that there was limited, if any, evidence of Hodgson having or using confidential information of the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence that he had any documentation belonging to the plaintiff, including customer lists. <eos/><bos/>He had no secret information about pricing of Legend Seed, as all sellers were required to sell at the same price. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence that he had targeted the plaintiff&apos;s customers. <eos/><bos/>The names of all farmers in the area were public information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d280628e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">122</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>It was possible that, at trial, Hodgson would not be found to have been a key employee. <eos/><bos/>However, the evidence was quite convincing that he was. <eos/><bos/>As General Manager, he was more than a sales manager. <eos/><bos/>He had general managerial responsibilities over a large facility with a substantial sales volume. <eos/><bos/>In terms of his reassignment to Customer Service Manager, he held this position for only the last two or three months of his employment with the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>In both positions, he acquired considerable knowledge about the plaintiff&apos;s customers.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d280638e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">123</footnote.reference>] If Hodgson did no more than pass on his business card and advise of where he was working, it was possible that, at trial, this might be found not to constitute solicitation. <eos/><bos/>However, this seemed unlikely. <eos/><bos/>By personally attending at the farms, Hodgson had clearly done more than generally advertise his new employment. <eos/><bos/>He directly approached farmers, knowing that some of them were customers of the plaintiff, in an attempt to secure their business. <eos/><bos/>And he has successfully concluded sales with some of these individuals.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>However, the plaintiff had not established that it would suffer irreparable harm if the injunction were denied. <eos/><bos/>The court was not persuaded that the plaintiff&apos;s customers were moving to Delmar because of any solicitation on the part of Hodgson. <eos/><bos/>Instead, any loss of market share would appear to result from Delmar now selling Legend Seed and having a facility in the area and, probably even more importantly, from the plaintiff&apos;s decision to no longer sell Legend Seed.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The balance of convenience weighed in favour of denying an injunction. <eos/><bos/>The reality was that the sale of soybean seeds was a highly competitive business. <eos/><bos/>While Delmar hired Hodgson to assist in its entry into the northeast territory market, there was scant evidence that it or Hodgson was using confidential information or targeting the plaintiff&apos;s customers. <eos/><bos/>Further, even if Hodgson was a key employee of the plaintiff, the law provides that he could join a competitor, sell to its customers, and advertise.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d280648e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">124</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In the <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00016" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1980159202" w-pub-number="0003986" ID="I5a4f63918e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Chevron Standard Ltd. v. Home Oil Co.</ital></cite.query> case,[<footnote.reference refid="Id7d280658e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">125</footnote.reference>] the court held that the defendant, Leeson, had not disclosed to his new employer, Home Oil, any information he may have known about Chevron&apos;s (his former employer&apos;s) exploration and testing for oil, and so had not breached his obligation of confidence. <eos/><bos/>The court held that the suspicion of misuse of confidential information is insufficient to impose liability; there must be real evidence of misuse of the plaintiff&apos;s confidential business information.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>It is important to bear in mind that the efficacy of ethical walls is a question of fact. <eos/><bos/>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00017" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2018314320" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I5a5026e18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Dataco Utility Services Ltd. v. Olameter</cite.query> Inc.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id7d280668e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">126</footnote.reference>] a purchase transaction did not proceed and the defendant was successful in outbidding the plaintiff for a contract with a corporation that had been the major client of the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>During the RFP process for that contract, a memorandum entitled “Ethical Wall Procedures” was circulated to various employees of the defendant. <eos/><bos/>That memorandum stated that the defendant intended <begin.quote ID="QT_0036"/>“to adopt procedures to ensure that no information that may be confidential to the plaintiff that was obtained as a result of prior discussions was used in any way in connection with the defendant&apos;s bid.”<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0036"/> The trial judge observed that, while they are by no means a panacea, it would be wrong to hold that measures such as ethical walls are never effective or that they must be in place by a designated time in order to be effective. <eos/><bos/>Each case must be decided on its own facts.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d2a7708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">127</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00018" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2033144176" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I5a50c3218e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Geophysical Service Inc. v. Nwest Energy</cite.query> Corp.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id7d2a7718e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">128</footnote.reference>] the plaintiff brought a motion to amend its statement of claim to revise its original claim against the defendants, add three new named defendants, and add 26 “John Doe” style defendants. <eos/><bos/>The claim was originally for $1,951,811.50, and the plaintiff now wanted to increase the claim to $13,658,816.00, plus advance a claim for a licence fee of $3,414,704.00 for each instance where the Defendants or other third parties disclosed the plaintiff&apos;s seismic data in whole or in part, to any other third party. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff licensed seismic data to a customer and alleged that the seismic data, or derivatives of it, had been improperly shared. <eos/><bos/>Initially it sued two parties. <eos/><bos/>The Court allowed the amendment to add one of the new parties, but dismissed the application to add the rest.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d2a7728e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">129</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The claim had its genesis in the supply of seismic data by the plaintiff to NWest, with which <ital>GSI</ital> had a contract, called the <ital>MSDL Agreement</ital>. <eos/><bos/>The MSDL Agreement required NWest to keep the information confidential and not share it with other parties except in accordance with specific terms prescribed under the MSDL Agreement. <eos/><bos/>GSI alleged that the seismic data made its way to other energy companies but GSI did not know who they are, what exactly was shared with them if anything, exactly when that occurred or how or what if anything they did with it. <eos/><bos/>It suspects that these other companies at least saw either the seismic data or at least material setting out derivatives of the data, perhaps in a PowerPoint presentation, perhaps in a thumb drive, perhaps in the DropBox software format, perhaps in some other way, if they did not actually receive a copy of the raw seismic data.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d2a7738e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">130</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The claims for breach of confidence and copyright infringement proceed from the premise that the simple receipt of information, either confidential information or copyright material, creates a liability to the owner of the confidential information or the copyright work, even if the recipient was unaware of the confidentiality claim or the copyright by the owner. <eos/><bos/>Regarding an actionable claim for breach of confidence, it cannot be the law that simple receipt creates liability. <eos/><bos/>Otherwise, in regards to the possession of confidential information, when an employee who has confidential information leaves the job (quits or is dismissed by the employer) and finds work at another employer in the same industry there is automatically a valid claim against him, and probably against his new employer, regardless of whether he or she makes any use of the confidential information, because the now former employee of the claimant has confidential information in his or her mind and works for a competitor. <eos/><bos/>That would have the effect of sterilizing the former employee from working in the same industry. <eos/><bos/>The actionable wrong is the breach of confidence, using or disclosing the information without the consent of the person to whom the duty is owed. <eos/><bos/>The person who receives it innocently has no liability until either he actually learns of the impropriety, or there is a constructive notice of impropriety. <eos/><bos/>The “constructive notice” that was put forward was that the recipients of the seismic data must have known that it was confidential <begin.quote ID="QT_0037"/>“given the valuable nature of seismic data”<end.quote refid="QT_0037"/>. <eos/><bos/>However, there was nothing to indicate that they would have, or should have, known that it was confidential to someone other than NWest who was allegedly sharing it with them. <eos/><bos/>Where Party A gives confidential information to Party B but party B does nothing with it, there is no breach. <eos/><bos/>Similarly, where party A gives information to Party B, who improperly shares it with Party C who is unaware of Party A&apos;s claim over it, and Party C does not make use of it, Party C has neither received the information with any obligation to Party A, nor has it breached the confidence. <eos/><bos/>Party B has breached the confidence, and may be liable to Party A, but there may or may not be any damages, since Party C did nothing with it.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d2a7748e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">131</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>GSI could not show that any other party had actually made use of the West Newfoundland Materials that may have been improperly disclosed but they might have used it by choosing to do nothing—that is, by not getting involved in an energy investment. <eos/><bos/>As a result, GSI wanted to add these unknown parties in hopes that it could establish that they made use of the West Newfoundland Materials by not doing anything with them, and therefore not making a profit and not earning any ill-gotten gains that should be partly disgorged to GSI as licence fees. <eos/><bos/>GSI allegedly suffered damages because it lost the ability to licence the information directly to those third parties so that they could, after paying GSI a licence fee, conclude that there was no good investment to be made. <eos/><bos/>The court observed that there is a question whether non-action could amount to use. <eos/><bos/>If it were accepted that a failure to act could be an actionable use it would be necessary for a claimant to demonstrate that the defendant had set upon a particular course of conduct from which they subsequently withdrew. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence of any of the unidentified companies withdrawing from any course of conduct. <eos/><bos/>There was only evidence of a <ital>suspicion</ital> that they may have chosen not to embark on a course of conduct at all after viewing the West Newfoundland Materials. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence that those third parties knew that the data was owned by GSI, and no evidence other than that they <ital>may</ital> have seen it—not that a decision of any meaningful kind was made by the third parties. <eos/><bos/>The recipient or recipients, if they actually received the seismic data or some derivative of it, may have simply decided to invest elsewhere, or not at all, without making any analysis of the GSI seismic data.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d2a7758e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">132</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In order to meet even the very low “modest evidence” standard for amendments, there must be some evidence of either knowledge, or at least constructive knowledge, of the confidential claim by GSI and improper use. <eos/><bos/>All of these elements were missing from the evidence. <eos/><bos/>It was suggested that the data was disseminated to one or more of 26 unknown parties, in a manner not known, at a time not known, based on a claim that is, from the outset, largely based on a faulty legal premise. <eos/><bos/>And as well there was no evidence that any of these unknown parties did anything with the data if they received it. <eos/><bos/>With this dearth of evidence the plaintiff wanted to significantly re-cast the claim. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence here that any of the 26 in this group did anything that would give rise to a cause of action. <eos/><bos/>The amendment was sought because someone is this group might have done something that gave rise to a claim by GSI.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d2ce808e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">133</footnote.reference>] There would be serious prejudice to NWest, whose entire business activities were on hold because the case has already crippled its ability to carry on, if all 29 or 30 defendants were added. <eos/><bos/>Such an amendment would significantly re-cast the claim. <eos/><bos/>These proposed amendments were hopeless because they proceeded on a faulty legal premise and because there was no evidence of wrongdoing, just suspicion.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d2ce818e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">134</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00019" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2046066636" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I5a5382418e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Geophysical Service Incorporated v. Murphy Oil Company</cite.query> Ltd</ital>.,[<footnote.reference refid="Id7d2ce828e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">135</footnote.reference>] the Defendant was one of many companies that GSI sued for the improper use of its seismic materials. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiff claimed damages from the Defendant for breach of contract, breach of copyright, breach of confidence, conversion, unjust enrichment, negligent misrepresentation and interference with GSI&apos;s contractual relations with others. <eos/><bos/>The Defendant had an interest in several oil and gas fields off the east coast of Canada. <eos/><bos/>In 2008 it withdrew from offshore Nova Scotia and the Laurentian Basin but continued to have working interests in the Hibernia and Terra Nova fields, which are in offshore Newfoundland. <eos/><bos/>Murphy partnered with others on these projects, most of whom also licensed seismic data from the Plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>Issues common to them were tried first in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00020" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038739284" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I5a5382438e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Geophysical Service Inc. v. Encana Corp</ital>., 2016 CarswellAlta 742, 2016 ABQB 230</cite.query>, <case.history>affd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00021" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041544288" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I5a5382468e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellAlta 732, 2017 ABCA 125</cite.query>, leave to appeal refused <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00022" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043309675" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I5a5382498e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellAlta 2545 (S.C.C.)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>The decision determined that copying and accessing seismic data from government sources, including the Canada-Newfoundland and Labrador Offshore Petroleum Board and the Canada-Nova Scotia Offshore Petroleum Board between October 1995 and April 1998 without paying GSI a license fee, was permissible.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d2ce838e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">136</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Plaintiff and the Defendant entered into three agreements: the 1996 Agreement, the 1999 Agreement and the 2000 MDLA. <eos/><bos/>From time to time, they also entered into supplemental agreements pursuant to which the Plaintiff licensed additional seismic data to the Defendant. <eos/><bos/>Sometimes the Plaintiff simply sent the Defendant an invoice for seismic data. <eos/><bos/>One of the primary submissions advanced by the Plaintiff was that all seismic data, regardless of when or how it was licensed, was subject to the 2000 MDLA. <eos/><bos/>The Defendant&apos;s contention was that retroactively imposing the terms and conditions of the 2000 MDLA onto the 1996 Agreement and the 1999 Agreement and to events that pre-dated the 2000 MDLA was inconsistent with the terms of the 2000 MDLA. <eos/><bos/>The Defendant succeeded in its application for summary dismissal. <eos/><bos/>The chambers judge dismissed the Plaintiff&apos;s claim because there were no issues of merit on the record and in the pleadings that genuinely required a trial: <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00023" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2046066636" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I5a54bac18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Geophysical Service Incorporated v. Murphy Oil Company</cite.query> Ltd.</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id7d2ce848e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">137</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>On appeal, the Plaintiff submitted that the chambers judge erred by dismissing the claim for breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>A close examination of the Statement of Claim reveals that the only material that could be the subject of the claims for conversion, breach of confidence and breach of contract was the seismic data that was licensed to the Defendant under the 2000 MDLA; in other words, the Agreement Materials. <eos/><bos/>The Accessed Materials were excluded because as the chambers judge reasonably concluded the Defendant was entitled to access them pursuant to the Common Issues Decision. <eos/><bos/>The Additional Materials could not be the subject of the Remaining Claims because that term, as defined and used in the Statement of Claim, meant Seismic Materials obtained by the Defendant from third party corporations and Exploration Partners but not from the Plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>Given the finding that the Plaintiff had no Additional Materials, there could be no Remaining Claims based on these materials. <eos/><bos/>This left the “Agreement Materials”.<eos/><bos/> “Agreement Materials” was defined Seismic Material <begin.quote ID="QT_0038"/>“licensed by the Defendant under the Agreement. <eos/><bos/>The definition of Agreement was <begin.quote ID="QT_0039"/>“the Master Seismic Data License Agreement dated November 27, 2000 between the Plaintiff as licensor, and the Defendant as licensee. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, Agreement Materials were those licensed under the 2000 MDLA and the three supplemental agreements. <eos/><bos/>Further, by specifically defining Agreement Materials this way, the Seismic Materials licensed by the Defendant under both the 1996 and the 1999 Agreements were excluded from all the Remaining Claims.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0038"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id7d2ce858e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">138</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The claims of conversion, breach of confidence and breach of contract relied upon a common foundation that the Defendant wrongfully shared Agreement Materials. <eos/><bos/>The 1999 Anadarko email was the only direct evidence of the Defendant sharing the Plaintiff&apos;s seismic materials with others, and it referred to events in 1998. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiff effectively contended that it was the proverbial “tip of the iceberg” and knowledge of similar situations was exclusively within the knowledge and possession of the Defendant. <eos/><bos/>At best it the Plaintiff&apos;s evidence was that <begin.quote ID="QT_0041"/>“it would be inconceivable for Murphy … not to have shared seismic data with others”<end.quote refid="QT_0041"/> in <begin.quote ID="QT_0042"/>“data rooms or during presentations for prospective venture participants and purchasers”<end.quote refid="QT_0042"/>. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiff&apos;s evidence rested on the “tip of the iceberg” Anadarko email and the speculative statements of Einarsson regarding the Defendant&apos;s transactions in 2010, 2011 and 2012. <eos/><bos/>The Court of Appeal explained that there was no way of knowing whether there were other transactions that may have attracted the obligations set out in the 2000 MDLA. <eos/><bos/>When <begin.quote ID="QT_0040"/>“determining whether there is a genuine issue requiring a trial, the court must decide whether there is an evidentiary basis for a suspicion. <eos/><bos/>At the end of the day, the question was whether the Plaintiff had established a palpable and overriding error in the chambers judge&apos;s conclusion that on a balance of probabilities there was no merit to these claims. <eos/><bos/>Apart from the Anadarko email, the bulk of the Plaintiff&apos;s case was speculative. <eos/><bos/>This was so despite the disclosure by the Defendant of its records and the Plaintiff&apos;s access to the records of all of the other companies it had sued alleging similar misconduct. <eos/><bos/>Given the standard of appellate review, the Court of Appeal was not persuaded that there was a palpable and overriding error in the chambers judge&apos;s decision dismissing the claims of conversion, breach of confidence and breach of contract associated with the Agreement Materials.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0040"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id7d2f5908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">139</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In breach of confidence cases, the plaintiff ought to specifically identify the information over which it claims a proprietary right, and the circumstances in which knowledge of the information came into the possession of the defendant such that use of the information by the defendant would be unconscionable. <eos/><bos/>In <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00024" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2011362653" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I5a5f42118e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Blue Line Hockey Acquisition Co. v. Orca Bay Hockey Ltd. Partnership</ital></cite.query>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id7d2f5918e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">140</footnote.reference>] the action concerned the sale of the Vancouver Canucks, General Motors Place and the assets relating to both. <eos/><bos/>Blue Line alleged that Gaglardi, Beedie and Aquilini formed a partnership to pursue the acquisition of an interest in the Enterprise. <eos/><bos/>According to Blue Line, the three partners agreed they would not pursue their objective without the involvement of all partners. <eos/><bos/>It was alleged that under the Partnership, Aquilini owed a fiduciary duty to the other partners to refrain from diverting opportunities to acquire an interest in the Enterprise to himself, and to refrain from using confidential information of the Partnership for his own benefit. <eos/><bos/>The Partnership entered into negotiations with the Orca Bay Defendants in November 2003. <eos/><bos/>Blue Line alleged that Aquilini left the Partnership some months later and secretly pursued the acquisition of an interest in the Enterprise with the Orca Bay Defendants. <eos/><bos/>Blue Line alleged that Aquilini, in the course of his secret negotiations with the Orca Bay Defendants, used confidential information he obtained from the Partnership. <eos/><bos/>Negotiations between Blue Line and the Orca Bay Defendants ended on November 5, 2005. <eos/><bos/>On the same day, some of the Aquilini Defendants entered into the Investment Agreement with some of the Orca Bay Defendants to acquire a 50 per cent interest in the Enterprise.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d2f5928e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">141</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Aquilini Defendants applied for an order that Blue Line provide further and better particulars as to the individual items of confidential information obtained by the Partnership which, according to the Amended Statement of Claim, the Aquilini Defendants acquired, and when and from whom each item of confidential information was acquired by the Aquilini Defendants; when, where, and of whom the Aquilini Defendants, according to the Amended Statement of Claim, requested confidential information from other members of the Partnership at the time the Aquilini Defendants left the Partnership, and what individual items of information were provided pursuant to such requests; the individual items of confidential information obtained from the Partnership which, according to the Amended Statement of Claim, the Aquilini Defendants used when negotiating with the Orca Bay Defendants.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d2f5938e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">142</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff argued that they should not required to particularize the constituent parts. <eos/><bos/>Rather, the confidential information was, in essence, the contents of the negotiations as embodied in the various drafts of the Term Sheet and the strategies of Blue Line in respect of them. <eos/><bos/>It was not each individual piece of information that was important but the bargaining positions as a whole and the negotiating strategies behind them.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d2f5948e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">143</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motions judge did not accept this submission and concluded that the particulars must delineate both the confidential information allegedly possessed by the Aquilini Defendants and the confidential information allegedly used by them to conclude the Investment Agreement.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d2f5958e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">144</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motions judge acknowledged that particularization of the information alleged to be confidential may be more difficult in this case than in many breach of confidence or “trade secret” cases. <eos/><bos/>Nevertheless, at trial the plaintiff would be required to establish more than simply that Aquilini <begin.quote ID="QT_0043"/>“knew the mind of the purchasing group”<end.quote refid="QT_0043"/>. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff would be required to identify the information that was confidential and establish the proprietary nature of that information. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff would be required to prove facts establishing that Aquilini received the proprietary information in circumstances requiring that the information remain confidential, or facts from which such an inference can reasonably be drawn. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff would also be required to establish facts which proved that the Aquilini Defendants used the information for purposes of concluding the Investment Agreement, or facts from which that inference could reasonably be drawn. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, the plaintiff must identify, by way of particulars, the information it says is confidential information, the circumstances in which the information was conveyed to the Aquilini Defendants, and the confidential information it says the Aquilini Defendants used to acquire its interest in the Enterprise. <eos/><bos/>All aspects of the breach of confidence claim must be amenable to such particularization, and the Aquilini Defendants were entitled to those particulars before trial.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d2f5968e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">145</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00025" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a661fe18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course</cite.query> Ltd.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id7d31ca08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">146</footnote.reference>] a motion for summary judgment brought by the defendant Derrydale asking that the action by the plaintiff, Endplex be dismissed was granted. <eos/><bos/>Derrydale received an unsolicited offer from Endplex to purchase the property owned by Derrydale. <eos/><bos/>The shareholders of Derrydale decided to sell the East and West portions of Derrydale&apos;s property to Endplex for its development purposes and to retain the central portion of the property. <eos/><bos/>Derrydale wanted to retain ownership of the central portion of the property for continued use as a 9-hole executive golf course enabling Endplex to take ownership of the East and West parcels for development.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d31ca18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">147</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The agreement with Endplex was conditional upon obtaining the consent of the City of Mississauga Committee of Adjustment to sever the two parcels of Derrydale&apos;s property and to permit Derrydale to retain lands which would be redeveloped for the nine-hole golf course. <eos/><bos/>The agreement provided that Endplex would pay the costs of Derrydale&apos;s application for severance to the Committee of Adjustment. <eos/><bos/>The agreement also required Derrydale and Endplex to work together in using best efforts to obtain approval for the severance of the property from the Committee of Adjustment. <eos/><bos/>In furtherance of this objective, Derrydale retained a consultant to assist in providing planning advice to Derrydale as owner/applicant. <eos/><bos/>Subsequently Endplex, and Derrydale, appointed the consultant to be responsible for the preparation of severance applications for submission to the City of Mississauga Committee of Adjustment. <eos/><bos/>At the direction of Derrydale and Endplex, the consultant submitted the Applications to the Committee of Adjustment seeking consent to sever the two parcels. <eos/><bos/>Both severances were approved subject to conditions that were to be fulfilled within one year from the date of the decision, namely, by August 12, 2005. <eos/><bos/>The consultant, acting at the direction of both Endplex and Derrydale, retained consultants for the purpose of obtaining expert reports for submission to the Region of Peel, the Committee of Adjustment, the City of Mississauga and the Credit Valley Conservation in order to satisfy the conditions for severance required by the Committee of Adjustment. <eos/><bos/>The conditions required, that a number of technical matters be addressed through the submission of expert reports to be reviewed and approved by the City and Credit Valley Conservation. <eos/><bos/>Thereafter, at the direction of both Derrydale and Endplex, the consultant coordinated the retainer of consultants for the preparation of expert reports required to satisfy the Region of Peel, the City of Mississauga and the Credit Valley Conservation. <eos/><bos/>At the direction of Derrydale and Endplex, and without any constraints on the release of such expert reports, the consultant submitted three expert reports provided to the City of Mississauga and to the Credit Valley Conservation for purposes of satisfying the conditions of the severances established by the Committee of Adjustment. <eos/><bos/>The submission of the expert reports was part of the public approval process provided for under the <ital>Planning Act</ital>.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d31ca28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">148</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>At or about the same time as the consultants&apos; reports were being filed with the City of Mississauga and the Credit Valley Conservation, Endplex, entered into discussions with the consultant with respect to potential retainer of Glenn Schnarr and Associates by Endplex to obtain land-use planning approvals related to Endplex&apos;s development plans for the West parcel. <eos/><bos/>The consultant gave Endplex an opinion that there was a low prospect for the development for residential uses of the West parcel because of existing land-use planning constraints.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d31ca38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">149</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Agreement of Purchase and Sale provided that if Endplex was not satisfied that the lands could be zoned with a zoning designation satisfactory to it, Endplex had the right to terminate the Agreement to purchase the two parcels of property. <eos/><bos/>Before making its second deposit, Endplex terminated the Agreement of Purchase and Sale and requested the return of its initial deposit pursuant to the terms of the agreement. <eos/><bos/>The initial deposit of $250,000 was returned to Endplex by Derrydale.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d31ca48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">150</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Endplex wrote to the consultant and requested all the reports that had been prepared by consultants, including the originals and copies of all reports which were prepared and filed with the City of Mississauga or distributed to any other third party, be collected and turned over to Endplex. <eos/><bos/>Endplex asserted that the reports were the property of Endplex and further that such reports were not to be disseminated or used in any fashion without the consent of Endplex. <eos/><bos/>Endplex&apos;s assertion of an entitlement to ownership and possession of all reports was contrary to the provisions of the Agreement of Purchase and Sale. <eos/><bos/>Notwithstanding the Agreement, the consultant collected the reports and forwarded them to Endplex. <eos/><bos/>Derrydale&apos;s solicitor, immediately denied Endplex&apos;s claim to ownership of the reports prepared by the consultants. <eos/><bos/>The “First” reports were never returned to Derrydale.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d31ca58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">151</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>After the termination of the agreement by Endplex, Derrydale sought a new purchaser for the two parcels of land. <eos/><bos/>Derrydale entered into an Agreement of Purchase and Sale with GWL for the East parcel. <eos/><bos/>GWL was not interested in purchasing the West parcel. <eos/><bos/>The parcel which is the subject of the agreement between GWL and Derrydale is a slightly modified version of the East parcel that Derrydale had originally agreed to sell to Endplex. <eos/><bos/>As a result, Derrydale and GWL were required to satisfy the conditions of the approved severance relating to the East parcel.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d31ca68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">152</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The initial agreement between Derrydale and GWL provided that GWL would not pursue the existing applications for severances and would make a new application for a severance to the Committee of Adjustment notwithstanding that the existing severances for the East and West parcels had already been approved by the Committee of Adjustment subject to conditions. <eos/><bos/>The purpose of this agreement between Derrydale and GWL to make a new application for severance was to accommodate concerns being expressed by Endplex as to its “property” rights in the consultants&apos; reports and the existing severance applications.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d343b08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">153</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Secretary-Treasurer of the Committee of Adjustment denied a request by Endplex to close or suspend the operation of the approved severance applications, stating that the applications were still active and available to the owner of the property before lapsing on August 12, 2005.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d343b18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">154</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In May of 2005, a number of terms of the GWL Agreement were amended by the parties. <eos/><bos/>One of the terms of the GWL contract, which was amended, was the provision that GWL pursue a new severance application to permit sale by Derrydale of the East parcel. <eos/><bos/>This amendment reflected the fact that the Committee of Adjustment had confirmed that the existing severances and applications were approved, subject to the conditions stipulated, and that such approval could not be withdrawn. <eos/><bos/>Further, the Committee of Adjustment confirmed that Derrydale, as owner of the property, was in a position to satisfy the conditions prior to the severance collapsing on August 12, 2005.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d343b28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">155</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>As the conditions for severance of the East parcel had not yet been fulfilled, through its planning consultants GWL retained its own consultants to prepare and file expert reports (hereinafter, the “Second” reports) in order to satisfy the conditions for the severance of the East parcel.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d343b38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">156</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Endplex claimed that it held a copyright interest in the “First” reports generated in support of the applications for severance of the East and West parcels, that it owned such reports and that the defendant Derrydale breached an obligation to hold in confidence and not to use information in relation to the applications for severance. <eos/><bos/>With respect to this latter allegation, it was alleged by the plaintiffs that GWL in their acquisition of the East parcel from Derrydale were provided by Derrydale with copies of various reports, information and documents that were confidential and that this is a breach of the defendant&apos;s obligation to the plaintiff.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d343b48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">157</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff asserted that, if the defendant Derrydale was not obliged by contract to hold in confidence and not use information in relation to the applications for severance, the obligations were implied terms of the agreement. <eos/><bos/>Justice Murray would not imply such a contractual restriction. <eos/><bos/>Over a month before the termination of the agreement by Endplex, various consultants&apos; reports, the “First” reports were submitted to the City of Mississauga, and to the CVC for purposes of clearing the conditions of the severances. <eos/><bos/>These reports were filed with public authorities to satisfy conditions for severance of the parcels of land which Endplex had agreed to purchase and to be available for public scrutiny in what is a public process. <eos/><bos/>There was no objection by Endplex to the filing of these reports. <eos/><bos/>Even if Endplex held a bona fide belief that Derrydale had an obligation to maintain the confidentiality of the reports, the joint filing of such reports with various public authorities in order to meet the conditions for severance imposed by the Committee of Adjustment was, by necessary implication, a waiver of any claim to confidentiality of those reports by Endplex. <eos/><bos/>Indeed, if Derrydale had prevented the filing of the reports with the authorities, it would have been in breach of the agreement with Endplex to <begin.quote ID="QT_0044"/>“cooperate in the processing of the applications and the execution of any documents required as part of the application.”<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0044"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id7d343b58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">158</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Finally, the “First” reports were not used by the defendant in satisfying the conditions for severance necessary for the sale of the East parcel to GWL. Endplex maintained possession of the “First” reports after it terminated the agreement of purchase and sale. <eos/><bos/>Derrydale did not retain possession of the first reports. <eos/><bos/>After the termination by Endplex of the Agreement of Purchase and Sale, Derrydale neither directly or indirectly employed the “First” reports for any further use or purpose. <eos/><bos/>Such reports were not used for purposes of obtaining the severance of the East parcel for purposes of sale to GWL.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d343b68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">159</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Derrydale had every right to use any information in its possession, including the “First” consultants&apos; reports, to further its application for severance and to achieve its objective of selling the East parcel to GWL. However, at it did not use such information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d36ac08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">160</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Murray concluded that there was no factual or legal basis for the claim by Endplex that Derrydale improperly used confidential information. <eos/><bos/>There were no material facts alleged in any affidavit material filed by the plaintiffs or by the defendant which supported a conclusion that the plaintiff could raise a triable issue in a claim for breach of confidence.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d36ac18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">161</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff asserted that the misuse of confidential information by Derrydale was also a breach of a fiduciary duty owed by Derrydale to Endplex. <eos/><bos/>As a result, the plaintiff asserted that it was entitled to any profits made by Derrydale including any profits from the sale of the East parcel to GWL. This claim was also completely without foundation. <eos/><bos/>The relationship between the parties was contractual and was terminated when Endplex terminated the Agreement of Purchase and Sale. <eos/><bos/>After the termination of the contract by Endplex, Derrydale had no duty to forsake its own interest to act for the benefit of the plaintiff.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7d36ac28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">162</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Id7ce13908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00026" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048515624" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a7dc6908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Craig v. CEO Global Network Inc.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 9664, 2019 ONSC 3589</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00027" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048831684" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a7dc6938e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2019 CarswellOnt 12529, 2019 ONSC 4509</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7ce13918e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00028" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048515624" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a7e14b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Craig v. CEO Global Network Inc.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 9664, 2019 ONSC 3589</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00029" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048831684" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a7e14b38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2019 CarswellOnt 12529, 2019 ONSC 4509</cite.query>, at paras. 1–5.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7ce13928e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00030" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048515624" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a7e3bc08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Craig v. CEO Global Network Inc.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 9664, 2019 ONSC 3589</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00031" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048831684" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a7e3bc38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2019 CarswellOnt 12529, 2019 ONSC 4509</cite.query>, at paras. 7–9.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7ce13938e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>4</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00032" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048515624" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a7e89e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Craig v. CEO Global Network Inc.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 9664, 2019 ONSC 3589</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00033" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048831684" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a7e89e38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2019 CarswellOnt 12529, 2019 ONSC 4509</cite.query>, at paras. 44–50.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7ce3aa08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>5</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00034" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048515624" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a7eb0f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Craig v. CEO Global Network Inc.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 9664, 2019 ONSC 3589</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00035" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048831684" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a7eb0f38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2019 CarswellOnt 12529, 2019 ONSC 4509</cite.query>, at paras. 51–53.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7ce3aa18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>6</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00036" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048515624" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a7ed8008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Craig v. CEO Global Network Inc.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 9664, 2019 ONSC 3589</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00037" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048831684" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a7ed8038e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2019 CarswellOnt 12529, 2019 ONSC 4509, at para. 54</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7ce3aa28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>7</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00038" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048515624" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a7f26208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Craig v. CEO Global Network Inc.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 9664, 2019 ONSC 3589</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00039" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048831684" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a7f26238e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2019 CarswellOnt 12529, 2019 ONSC 4509, at para. 56</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7ce3aa38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>8</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00040" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048515624" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a7f4d308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Craig v. CEO Global Network Inc.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 9664, 2019 ONSC 3589</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00041" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048831684" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a7f4d338e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2019 CarswellOnt 12529, 2019 ONSC 4509</cite.query>, at paras. 90–91.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7ce3aa48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>9</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00042" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048515624" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a7f9b508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Craig v. CEO Global Network Inc.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 9664, 2019 ONSC 3589</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00043" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048831684" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a7f9b538e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2019 CarswellOnt 12529, 2019 ONSC 4509</cite.query>, at paras. 94–99.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7ce3aa58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>10</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00044" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048515624" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a7fc2608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Craig v. CEO Global Network Inc.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 9664, 2019 ONSC 3589</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00045" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048831684" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a7fc2638e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2019 CarswellOnt 12529, 2019 ONSC 4509</cite.query>, at paras. 103–105.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7ce61b08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>11</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00046" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048515624" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8010808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Craig v. CEO Global Network Inc.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 9664, 2019 ONSC 3589</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00047" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048831684" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8010838e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2019 CarswellOnt 12529, 2019 ONSC 4509</cite.query>, at paras. 106–108.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7ce61b18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>12</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00048" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048515624" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8037908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Craig v. CEO Global Network Inc.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 9664, 2019 ONSC 3589</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00049" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048831684" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8037938e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2019 CarswellOnt 12529, 2019 ONSC 4509</cite.query>, at paras. 110–115.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7ce61b28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>13</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00050" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048515624" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8085b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Craig v. CEO Global Network Inc.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 9664, 2019 ONSC 3589</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00051" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048831684" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8085b38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2019 CarswellOnt 12529, 2019 ONSC 4509</cite.query>, at paras. 116–119.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7ce61b38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>14</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00052" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048716483" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a80acc08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Furfari v. Pedias</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 11420, 2019 ONSC 4278</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7ce61b48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>15</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00053" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048716483" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a80d3d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Furfari v. Pedias</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 11420, 2019 ONSC 4278</cite.query>, at paras. 1–3.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7ce88c08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>16</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00054" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048716483" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a80fae08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Furfari v. Pedias</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 11420, 2019 ONSC 4278, at para. 5</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7ce88c18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>17</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00055" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048716483" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8121f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Furfari v. Pedias</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 11420, 2019 ONSC 4278, at para. 10</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7ce88c28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>18</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00056" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048716483" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8149008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Furfari v. Pedias</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 11420, 2019 ONSC 4278</cite.query>, at paras. 16–17.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7ce88c38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>19</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00057" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048716483" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8170108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Furfari v. Pedias</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 11420, 2019 ONSC 4278</cite.query>, at paras. 18–19.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7ce88c48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>20</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00058" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048716483" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a81be308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Furfari v. Pedias</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 11420, 2019 ONSC 4278</cite.query>, at paras. 21–23.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7ce88c58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>21</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00059" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048716483" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a81be338e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Furfari v. Pedias</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 11420, 2019 ONSC 4278, at para. 37</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7ce88c68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>22</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00060" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047688097" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a81e5408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>CTT Pharmaceutical Holdings v. Rapid Dose Therapeutics</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 3076, 2019 ONSC 1444</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7ceafd08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>23</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00061" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047688097" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a820c508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>CTT Pharmaceutical Holdings v. Rapid Dose Therapeutics</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 3076, 2019 ONSC 1444, at para. 3</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7ceafd18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>24</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00062" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047688097" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8233608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>CTT Pharmaceutical Holdings v. Rapid Dose Therapeutics</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 3076, 2019 ONSC 1444</cite.query>, at paras. 26–28.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7ceafd28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>25</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00063" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047411774" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a825a708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cantol v. State Chemical</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 1084, 2019 ONSC 531</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7ceafd38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>26</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00064" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047411774" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a82a8908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cantol v. State Chemical</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 1084, 2019 ONSC 531</cite.query>, at paras. 1–2.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7ceafd48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>27</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00065" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047411774" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a82cfa08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cantol v. State Chemical</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 1084, 2019 ONSC 531</cite.query>, at paras. 6–8.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7ceafd58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>28</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00066" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047411774" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a82f6b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cantol v. State Chemical</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 1084, 2019 ONSC 531</cite.query>, at paras. 9–11.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7ceafd68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>29</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00067" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047411774" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a831dc08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cantol v. State Chemical</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 1084, 2019 ONSC 531, at para. 13</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7ced6e08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>30</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00068" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047411774" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8344d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cantol v. State Chemical</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 1084, 2019 ONSC 531</cite.query>, at paras. 26–27.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7ced6e18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>31</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00069" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047411774" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a836be08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cantol v. State Chemical</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 1084, 2019 ONSC 531</cite.query>, at paras. 28–29.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7ced6e28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>32</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00070" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047411774" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8392f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cantol v. State Chemical</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 1084, 2019 ONSC 531, at para. 32</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7ced6e38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>33</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00071" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2045161580" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a83ba008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>OIBC v. KO</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 12412, 2018 ONSC 4612</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7ced6e48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>34</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00072" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2045161580" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a83e1108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>OIBC v. KO</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 12412, 2018 ONSC 4612, at para. 1</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7ced6e58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>35</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00073" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2045161580" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8408208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>OIBC v. KO</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 12412, 2018 ONSC 4612, at para. 13</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7cefdf08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>36</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00074" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2045161580" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a842f308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>OIBC v. KO</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 12412, 2018 ONSC 4612, at para. 33</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7cefdf18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>37</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00075" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2045161580" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8456408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>OIBC v. KO</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 12412, 2018 ONSC 4612</cite.query>, at paras. 34–37.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7cefdf28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>38</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00076" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043111788" w-pub-number="0007659" ID="I5a847d508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Brand Name Marketing Inc. v. Rogers Communications Inc.</ital>, 2016 ONSC 4567, 2017 CarswellOnt 17209 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7cefdf38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>39</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00077" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043111788" w-pub-number="0007659" ID="I5a84a4608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Brand Name Marketing Inc. v. Rogers Communications Inc.</ital>, 2016 ONSC 4567, 2017 CarswellOnt 17209 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paragraph 312.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7cefdf48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>40</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00078" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043111788" w-pub-number="0007659" ID="I5a84cb708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Brand Name Marketing Inc. v. Rogers Communications Inc.</ital>, 2016 ONSC 4567, 2017 CarswellOnt 17209 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 237–238.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7cefdf58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>41</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00079" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043111788" w-pub-number="0007659" ID="I5a8519908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Brand Name Marketing Inc. v. Rogers Communications Inc.</ital>, 2016 ONSC 4567, 2017 CarswellOnt 17209 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 242–244.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7cefdf68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>42</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00080" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043111788" w-pub-number="0007659" ID="I5a8540a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Brand Name Marketing Inc. v. Rogers Communications Inc.</ital>, 2016 ONSC 4567, 2017 CarswellOnt 17209 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 246–248.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7cefdf78e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>43</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00081" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043111788" w-pub-number="0007659" ID="I5a8567b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Brand Name Marketing Inc. v. Rogers Communications Inc.</ital>, 2016 ONSC 4567, 2017 CarswellOnt 17209 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paragraph 250.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7cf25008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>44</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00082" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043111788" w-pub-number="0007659" ID="I5a858ec08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Brand Name Marketing Inc. v. Rogers Communications Inc.</ital>, 2016 ONSC 4567, 2017 CarswellOnt 17209 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paragraph 251.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d0aba08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>45</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00083" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043111788" w-pub-number="0007659" ID="I5a85b5d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Brand Name Marketing Inc. v. Rogers Communications Inc.</ital>, 2016 ONSC 4567, 2017 CarswellOnt 17209 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 253–255.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d0d2b08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>46</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00084" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2043111788" w-pub-number="0007659" ID="I5a85dce08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Brand Name Marketing Inc. v. Rogers Communications Inc.</ital>, 2016 ONSC 4567, 2017 CarswellOnt 17209 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paragraph 259.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d0d2b18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>47</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00085" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042570374" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I5a8603f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Hamilton v. F&amp;M Management Ltd.</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 2449, 2017 BCSC 1606</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d0d2b28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>48</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00086" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042570374" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I5a8652108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Hamilton v. F&amp;M Management Ltd.</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 2449, 2017 BCSC 1606</cite.query>, at paras. 3–6.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d0d2b38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>49</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00087" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042570374" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I5a8679208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Hamilton v. F&amp;M Management Ltd.</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 2449, 2017 BCSC 1606</cite.query>, at paras. 15–16.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d0d2b48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>50</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00088" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042570374" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I5a86a0308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Hamilton v. F&amp;M Management Ltd.</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 2449, 2017 BCSC 1606</cite.query>, at paras. 20–21.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d0d2b58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>51</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00089" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042570374" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I5a86c7408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Hamilton v. F&amp;M Management Ltd.</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 2449, 2017 BCSC 1606, at para. 22</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d0d2b68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>52</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00090" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042570374" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I5a86ee508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Hamilton v. F&amp;M Management Ltd.</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 2449, 2017 BCSC 1606, at para. 24</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d0d2b78e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>53</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00091" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042570374" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I5a8715608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Hamilton v. F&amp;M Management Ltd.</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 2449, 2017 BCSC 1606</cite.query>, at paras. 25, and 28–29.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d0f9c08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>54</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00092" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042570374" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I5a873c708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Hamilton v. F&amp;M Management Ltd.</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 2449, 2017 BCSC 1606</cite.query>, at paras. 35–38.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d0f9c18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>55</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00093" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039633659" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8763808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 13362, 2016 ONSC 5271 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00094" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039995700" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8763838e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 16043, 2016 ONSC 6285 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d0f9c28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>56</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00095" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039633659" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a878a908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 13362, 2016 ONSC 5271 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00096" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039995700" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a878a938e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 16043, 2016 ONSC 6285 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>, at paras. 1–4, and 7.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d0f9c38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>57</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00097" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039633659" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a87d8b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 13362, 2016 ONSC 5271 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00098" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039995700" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a87d8b38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 16043, 2016 ONSC 6285 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>, at paras. 40–44.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d0f9c48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>58</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00099" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039633659" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a87ffc08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 13362, 2016 ONSC 5271 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00100" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039995700" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a87ffc38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 16043, 2016 ONSC 6285 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>, at paras. 55–58, and 63–65.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d0f9c58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>59</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00101" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039633659" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a884de08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 13362, 2016 ONSC 5271 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00102" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039995700" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a884de38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 16043, 2016 ONSC 6285 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>, at paras. 68–72, and 81–84.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d120d08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>60</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00103" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039633659" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a889c008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 13362, 2016 ONSC 5271 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00104" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039995700" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a889c038e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 16043, 2016 ONSC 6285 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>, at paras. 117–118.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d120d18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>61</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00105" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039633659" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a88c3108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 13362, 2016 ONSC 5271 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00106" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039995700" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a88c3138e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 16043, 2016 ONSC 6285 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>, at paras. 119–121.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d120d28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>62</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00107" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039633659" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8911308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 13362, 2016 ONSC 5271 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00108" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039995700" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8911338e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 16043, 2016 ONSC 6285 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>, at paras. 122–124.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d120d38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>63</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00109" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044131577" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8938408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>The Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 4307, 2018 ONCA 283</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00110" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044514259" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8938438e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2018 CarswellOnt 7267, 2018 ONCA 447</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d120d48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>64</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00111" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044131577" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a895f508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>The Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 4307, 2018 ONCA 283</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00112" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044514259" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a895f538e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2018 CarswellOnt 7267, 2018 ONCA 447, at para. 8</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d120d58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>65</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00113" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044131577" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a89ad708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>The Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 4307, 2018 ONCA 283</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00114" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044514259" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a89ad738e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2018 CarswellOnt 7267, 2018 ONCA 447</cite.query>, at paras. 10–11.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d120d68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>66</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00115" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044131577" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a89d4808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>The Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 4307, 2018 ONCA 283</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00116" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044514259" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a89d4838e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2018 CarswellOnt 7267, 2018 ONCA 447, at para. 12</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d147e08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>67</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00117" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044131577" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a89fb908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>The Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 4307, 2018 ONCA 283</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00118" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044514259" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a89fb938e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2018 CarswellOnt 7267, 2018 ONCA 447, at para. 13</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d147e18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>68</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00119" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044131577" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8a22a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>The Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 4307, 2018 ONCA 283</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00120" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044514259" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8a22a38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2018 CarswellOnt 7267, 2018 ONCA 447, at para. 14</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d147e28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>69</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00121" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044131577" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8a70c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>The Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 4307, 2018 ONCA 283</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00122" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044514259" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8a70c38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2018 CarswellOnt 7267, 2018 ONCA 447</cite.query>, at paras. 15–16.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d147e38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>70</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00123" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044131577" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8a97d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>The Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 4307, 2018 ONCA 283</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00124" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044514259" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8a97d38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2018 CarswellOnt 7267, 2018 ONCA 447, at para. 18</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d147e48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>71</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00125" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044131577" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8abee08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>The Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 4307, 2018 ONCA 283</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00126" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044514259" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8abee38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2018 CarswellOnt 7267, 2018 ONCA 447, at para. 19</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d147e58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>72</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00127" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044131577" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8c6c908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>The Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 4307, 2018 ONCA 283</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00128" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044514259" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8c6c938e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2018 CarswellOnt 7267, 2018 ONCA 447, at para. 20</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d147e68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>73</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00129" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044131577" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8cbab08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>The Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 4307, 2018 ONCA 283</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00130" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044514259" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8cbab38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2018 CarswellOnt 7267, 2018 ONCA 447</cite.query>, at paras. 24–26.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d16ef08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>74</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00131" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044131577" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8ce1c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>The Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 4307, 2018 ONCA 283</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00132" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044514259" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8ce1c38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2018 CarswellOnt 7267, 2018 ONCA 447, at para. 31</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d16ef18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>75</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00133" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044131577" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8d2fe08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>The Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. Moyse</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 4307, 2018 ONCA 283</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00134" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044514259" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8d2fe38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2018 CarswellOnt 7267, 2018 ONCA 447</cite.query>, at paras. 34 and 37.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d16ef28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>76</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00135" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048188340" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8d56f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>The Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. VimpelCom Ltd</ital>., 2019 CarswellOnt 6611, 2019 ONCA 354</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d16ef38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>77</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00136" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048188340" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8d7e008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>The Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. VimpelCom Ltd</ital>., 2019 CarswellOnt 6611, 2019 ONCA 354</cite.query>, at paras. 1–2.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d16ef48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>78</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00137" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048188340" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8da5108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>The Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. VimpelCom Ltd</ital>., 2019 CarswellOnt 6611, 2019 ONCA 354</cite.query>, at paras. 3–6.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d16ef58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>79</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00138" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048188340" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8dcc208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>The Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. VimpelCom Ltd</ital>., 2019 CarswellOnt 6611, 2019 ONCA 354, at para. 8</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d16ef68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>80</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00139" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048188340" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8df3308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>The Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. VimpelCom Ltd</ital>., 2019 CarswellOnt 6611, 2019 ONCA 354</cite.query>, at paras. 9 and 15.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d16ef78e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>81</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00140" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048188340" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8e1a408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>The Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. VimpelCom Ltd</ital>., 2019 CarswellOnt 6611, 2019 ONCA 354, at para. 16</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d196008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>82</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00141" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048188340" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8e41508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>The Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. VimpelCom Ltd</ital>., 2019 CarswellOnt 6611, 2019 ONCA 354, at para. 18</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d196018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>83</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00142" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048188340" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8e68608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>The Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. VimpelCom Ltd</ital>., 2019 CarswellOnt 6611, 2019 ONCA 354</cite.query>, at paras. 30–31.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d196028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>84</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00143" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048188340" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8e8f708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>The Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. VimpelCom Ltd</ital>., 2019 CarswellOnt 6611, 2019 ONCA 354</cite.query>, at paras. 32–33.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d196038e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>85</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00144" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048188340" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8eb6808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>The Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. VimpelCom Ltd</ital>., 2019 CarswellOnt 6611, 2019 ONCA 354</cite.query>, at paras. 34–37.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d196048e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>86</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00145" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048188340" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8edd908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>The Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. VimpelCom Ltd</ital>., 2019 CarswellOnt 6611, 2019 ONCA 354</cite.query>, at paras. 39–41.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d196058e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>87</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00146" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048188340" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a8f04a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>The Catalyst Capital Group Inc. v. VimpelCom Ltd</ital>., 2019 CarswellOnt 6611, 2019 ONCA 354</cite.query>, at paras. 43–44.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d1bd108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>88</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00147" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038174898" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I5a8f2bb08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seyedi v. Nexen Inc.</ital>, 2016 CarswellAlta 98, 2016 ABCA 24</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d1bd118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>89</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00148" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038174898" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I5a8f52c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seyedi v. Nexen Inc.</ital>, 2016 CarswellAlta 98, 2016 ABCA 24, at para. 10</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d1bd128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>90</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00149" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038174898" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I5a8f79d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seyedi v. Nexen Inc.</ital>, 2016 CarswellAlta 98, 2016 ABCA 24</cite.query>, at paras. 1–2.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d1bd138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>91</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00150" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038174898" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I5a8fa0e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seyedi v. Nexen Inc.</ital>, 2016 CarswellAlta 98, 2016 ABCA 24, at para. 4</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d1bd148e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>92</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00151" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038174898" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I5a8fc7f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seyedi v. Nexen Inc.</ital>, 2016 CarswellAlta 98, 2016 ABCA 24, at para. 5</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d1bd158e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>93</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00152" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038174898" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I5a8fef008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seyedi v. Nexen Inc.</ital>, 2016 CarswellAlta 98, 2016 ABCA 24, at para. 13</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d1bd168e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>94</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00153" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038174898" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I5a9016108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seyedi v. Nexen Inc.</ital>, 2016 CarswellAlta 98, 2016 ABCA 24, at para. 15</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d1bd178e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>95</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00154" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038174898" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I5a903d208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seyedi v. Nexen Inc.</ital>, 2016 CarswellAlta 98, 2016 ABCA 24, at para. 16</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d1e4208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>96</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00155" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038174898" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I5a9064308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seyedi v. Nexen Inc.</ital>, 2016 CarswellAlta 98, 2016 ABCA 24, at para. 18</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d1e4218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>97</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00156" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034750957" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I5a9064338e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seaway Marine Services Ltd. v. Weiwaikum General Partner Ltd.</ital>, 2014 CarswellBC 3311, 2014 BCSC 2102</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d1e4228e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>98</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00157" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034750957" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I5a908b408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seaway Marine Services Ltd. v. Weiwaikum General Partner Ltd.</ital>, 2014 CarswellBC 3311, 2014 BCSC 2102</cite.query>, at paras. 2–4, 6, and 16.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d1e4238e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>99</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00158" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034750957" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I5a90d9608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seaway Marine Services Ltd. v. Weiwaikum General Partner Ltd.</ital>, 2014 CarswellBC 3311, 2014 BCSC 2102</cite.query>, at paras. 13, and 28–29.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d1e4248e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>100</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00159" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034750957" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I5a9100708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seaway Marine Services Ltd. v. Weiwaikum General Partner Ltd.</ital>, 2014 CarswellBC 3311, 2014 BCSC 2102</cite.query>, at paras. 31, 33, 37, and 40–41.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d1e4258e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>101</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00160" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034750957" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I5a9127808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seaway Marine Services Ltd. v. Weiwaikum General Partner Ltd.</ital>, 2014 CarswellBC 3311, 2014 BCSC 2102</cite.query>, at paras. 44–45.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d20b308e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>102</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00161" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034750957" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I5a914e908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seaway Marine Services Ltd. v. Weiwaikum General Partner Ltd.</ital>, 2014 CarswellBC 3311, 2014 BCSC 2102</cite.query>, at paras. 46–47.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d20b318e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>103</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00162" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034750957" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I5a919cb08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seaway Marine Services Ltd. v. Weiwaikum General Partner Ltd.</ital>, 2014 CarswellBC 3311, 2014 BCSC 2102</cite.query>, at paras. 49–53.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d20b328e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>104</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00163" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034750957" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I5a91c3c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seaway Marine Services Ltd. v. Weiwaikum General Partner Ltd.</ital>, 2014 CarswellBC 3311, 2014 BCSC 2102</cite.query>, at paras. 55, 58, and 61–62.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d20b338e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>105</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00164" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034750957" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I5a91ead08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seaway Marine Services Ltd. v. Weiwaikum General Partner Ltd.</ital>, 2014 CarswellBC 3311, 2014 BCSC 2102</cite.query>, at paras. 64–65.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d20b348e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>106</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00165" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034750957" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I5a9211e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seaway Marine Services Ltd. v. Weiwaikum General Partner Ltd.</ital>, 2014 CarswellBC 3311, 2014 BCSC 2102</cite.query>, at paras. 85–86.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d232408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>107</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00166" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034750957" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I5a9238f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seaway Marine Services Ltd. v. Weiwaikum General Partner Ltd.</ital>, 2014 CarswellBC 3311, 2014 BCSC 2102</cite.query>, at paras. 87–91.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d232418e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>108</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00167" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034750957" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I5a9260008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seaway Marine Services Ltd. v. Weiwaikum General Partner Ltd.</ital>, 2014 CarswellBC 3311, 2014 BCSC 2102, at para. 93</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d232428e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>109</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00168" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2033771551" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a9287108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>ThyssenKrupp Elevator (Canada) Ltd. v. Amos</ital>, 2014 CarswellOnt 9013, 2014 ONSC 3910</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d232438e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>110</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00169" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2033771551" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a92ae208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>ThyssenKrupp Elevator (Canada) Ltd. v. Amos</ital>, 2014 CarswellOnt 9013, 2014 ONSC 3910</cite.query>, at paras. 1–3.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d232448e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>111</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00170" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2033771551" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a92fc408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>ThyssenKrupp Elevator (Canada) Ltd. v. Amos</ital>, 2014 CarswellOnt 9013, 2014 ONSC 3910</cite.query>, at paras. 4–5, 33, 35, and 39–45.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d232458e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>112</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00171" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041145364" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a9323508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Hamilton v. Desert Lake Family Resort Inc.</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 2874, 276 A.C.W.S. (3d) 816, 2017 ONSC 1382 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d259508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>113</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00172" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041145364" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a934a608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Hamilton v. Desert Lake Family Resort Inc.</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 2874, 276 A.C.W.S. (3d) 816, 2017 ONSC 1382 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 3, 5–6, 25, and 27.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d259518e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>114</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00173" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041145364" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a9371708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Hamilton v. Desert Lake Family Resort Inc.</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 2874, 276 A.C.W.S. (3d) 816, 2017 ONSC 1382 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 8–10, and 12–15.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d259528e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>115</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00174" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041145364" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a9398808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Hamilton v. Desert Lake Family Resort Inc.</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 2874, 276 A.C.W.S. (3d) 816, 2017 ONSC 1382 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at para. 21.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d259538e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>116</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00175" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041145364" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a93e6a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Hamilton v. Desert Lake Family Resort Inc.</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 2874, 276 A.C.W.S. (3d) 816, 2017 ONSC 1382 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 31–35.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d259548e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>117</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00176" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026711477" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I5a93e6a48e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Duncan Sabine Collyer Partners LLP v. Campbell</ital>, 2011 CarswellMan 656, 2011 MBQB 302 (Man. Master)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d259558e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>118</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00177" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026711477" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I5a9434c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Duncan Sabine Collyer Partners LLP v. Campbell</ital>, 2011 CarswellMan 656, 2011 MBQB 302 (Man. Master)</cite.query>, at paras. 2, 9 and 14.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d259568e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>119</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00178" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026711477" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I5a945bd08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Duncan Sabine Collyer Partners LLP v. Campbell</ital>, 2011 CarswellMan 656, 2011 MBQB 302 (Man. Master)</cite.query>, at paras. 18–19.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d280608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>120</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00179" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027291812" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I5a9482e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Parrish &amp; Heimbecker Ltd. v. Delmar Commodities Ltd.</ital>, 2012 CarswellMan 114, 2012 MBQB 48</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d280618e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>121</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00180" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027291812" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I5a94a9f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Parrish &amp; Heimbecker Ltd. v. Delmar Commodities Ltd.</ital>, 2012 CarswellMan 114, 2012 MBQB 48</cite.query>, at paras. 1–2, 6, 14, 18–19, and 33.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d280628e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>122</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00181" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027291812" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I5a94d1008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Parrish &amp; Heimbecker Ltd. v. Delmar Commodities Ltd.</ital>, 2012 CarswellMan 114, 2012 MBQB 48, at para. 34</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d280638e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>123</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00182" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027291812" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I5a94f8108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Parrish &amp; Heimbecker Ltd. v. Delmar Commodities Ltd.</ital>, 2012 CarswellMan 114, 2012 MBQB 48, at para. 39</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d280648e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>124</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00183" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027291812" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I5a951f208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Parrish &amp; Heimbecker Ltd. v. Delmar Commodities Ltd.</ital>, 2012 CarswellMan 114, 2012 MBQB 48</cite.query>, at paras. 44, 50 and 56.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d280658e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>125</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00184" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1980159202" w-pub-number="0003986" ID="I5a956d408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Chevron Standard Ltd. v. Home Oil Co.</ital>, [1980] 5 W.W.R. 624, 22 A.R. 451 (Q.B.)</cite.query>, <case.history>affd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00185" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1982171186" w-pub-number="0003986" ID="I5a956d438e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">[1982] 3 W.W.R. 427, 35 A.R. 550 (C.A.)</cite.query>, leave to appeal to <cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00186" w-ref-type="ER" w-normalized-cite="50ARCA180n" w-pub-number="0004655" ID="I5a956d468e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">S.C.C. refused 50 A.R. 180<ital>n</ital>, 67 C.P.R. (2d) 16<ital>n</ital></cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d280668e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>126</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00187" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2018314320" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I5a9594508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Dataco Utility Services Ltd. v. Olameter Inc.</ital>, 2009 CarswellAlta 300, 2009 ABQB 116</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d2a7708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>127</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00188" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2018314320" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I5a95bb608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Dataco Utility Services Ltd. v. Olameter Inc.</ital>, 2009 CarswellAlta 300, 2009 ABQB 116, at para. 47</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d2a7718e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>128</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00189" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2033144176" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I5a95e2708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Geophysical Service Inc. v. Nwest Energy Corp.</ital>, 2014 CarswellAlta 546, 2014 ABQB 205</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d2a7728e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>129</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00190" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2033144176" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I5a9609808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Geophysical Service Inc. v. Nwest Energy Corp.</ital>, 2014 CarswellAlta 546, 2014 ABQB 205</cite.query>, at paras. 1–2, 4, and 7.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d2a7738e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>130</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00191" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2033144176" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I5a9630908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Geophysical Service Inc. v. Nwest Energy Corp.</ital>, 2014 CarswellAlta 546, 2014 ABQB 205</cite.query>, at paras. 11, 13–14 and 24.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d2a7748e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>131</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00192" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2033144176" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I5a9657a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Geophysical Service Inc. v. Nwest Energy Corp.</ital>, 2014 CarswellAlta 546, 2014 ABQB 205</cite.query>, at paras. 67–73.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d2a7758e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>132</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00193" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2033144176" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I5a96a5c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Geophysical Service Inc. v. Nwest Energy Corp.</ital>, 2014 CarswellAlta 546, 2014 ABQB 205</cite.query>, at paras. 74–77.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d2ce808e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>133</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00194" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2033144176" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I5a96ccd08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Geophysical Service Inc. v. Nwest Energy Corp.</ital>, 2014 CarswellAlta 546, 2014 ABQB 205</cite.query>, at paras. 87 and 99.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d2ce818e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>134</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00195" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2033144176" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I5a96f3e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Geophysical Service Inc. v. Nwest Energy Corp.</ital>, 2014 CarswellAlta 546, 2014 ABQB 205</cite.query>, at paras. 111 and 114.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d2ce828e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>135</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00196" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2046066636" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I5a971af08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Geophysical Service Incorporated v. Murphy Oil Company Ltd</ital>., 2018 CarswellAlta 2745, 2018 ABCA 380</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d2ce838e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>136</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00197" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2046066636" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I5a9742008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Geophysical Service Incorporated v. Murphy Oil Company Ltd</ital>., 2018 CarswellAlta 2745, 2018 ABCA 380</cite.query>, at paras. 1–3.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d2ce848e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>137</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00198" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042254148" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I5a9769108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Geophysical Service Incorporated v. Murphy Oil Company Ltd.</ital>, 2017 CarswellAlta 1321, 2017 ABQB 464</cite.query>, at paras. 4–5.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d2ce858e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>138</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00199" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2046066636" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I5a97b7308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Geophysical Service Incorporated v. Murphy Oil Company Ltd</ital>., 2018 CarswellAlta 2745, 2018 ABCA 380</cite.query>, at paras. 12, 68, and 71–72.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0039"/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d2f5908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>139</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00200" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2046066636" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I5a97de408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Geophysical Service Incorporated v. Murphy Oil Company Ltd</ital>., 2018 CarswellAlta 2745, 2018 ABCA 380</cite.query>, at paras. 73–74, 76, and 84.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d2f5918e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>140</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00201" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2011362653" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I5a9805508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Blue Line Hockey Acquisition Co. v. Orca Bay Hockey Ltd. Partnership</ital>, 2007 CarswellBC 208, 2007 BCSC 143</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d2f5928e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>141</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00202" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2011362653" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I5a982c608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Blue Line Hockey Acquisition Co. v. Orca Bay Hockey Ltd. Partnership</ital>, 2007 CarswellBC 208, 2007 BCSC 143</cite.query>, at paras. 1–2, 4–6, and 63.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d2f5938e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>142</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00203" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2011362653" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I5a9853708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Blue Line Hockey Acquisition Co. v. Orca Bay Hockey Ltd. Partnership</ital>, 2007 CarswellBC 208, 2007 BCSC 143, at para. 16</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d2f5948e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>143</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00204" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2011362653" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I5a987a808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Blue Line Hockey Acquisition Co. v. Orca Bay Hockey Ltd. Partnership</ital>, 2007 CarswellBC 208, 2007 BCSC 143, at para. 78</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d2f5958e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>144</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00205" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2011362653" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I5a98a1908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Blue Line Hockey Acquisition Co. v. Orca Bay Hockey Ltd. Partnership</ital>, 2007 CarswellBC 208, 2007 BCSC 143, at para. 86</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d2f5968e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>145</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00206" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2011362653" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I5a98c8a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Blue Line Hockey Acquisition Co. v. Orca Bay Hockey Ltd. Partnership</ital>, 2007 CarswellBC 208, 2007 BCSC 143</cite.query>, at paras. 80–81, and 84.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d31ca08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>146</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00207" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a98efb08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 5851 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d31ca18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>147</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00208" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a9916c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 5851 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 1, and 5–6.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d31ca28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>148</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00209" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a993dd08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 5851 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 9–13.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d31ca38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>149</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00210" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a9964e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 5851 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at para. 15.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d31ca48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>150</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00211" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a998bf08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 5851 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 17–18.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d31ca58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>151</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00212" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a99da108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 5851 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 19–20.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d31ca68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>152</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00213" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a9a01208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 5851 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 22 and 25.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d343b08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>153</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00214" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a9a28308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 5851 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at para. 26.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d343b18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>154</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00215" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a9a4f408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 5851 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at para. 27.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d343b28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>155</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00216" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a9a9d608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 5851 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at para. 28.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d343b38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>156</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00217" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a9ac4708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 5851 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at para. 29.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d343b48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>157</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00218" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a9aeb808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 5851 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at para. 61.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d343b58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>158</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00219" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a9b12908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 5851 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 72 and 74.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d343b68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>159</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00220" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a9b39a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 5851 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 75–76.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d36ac08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>160</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00221" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a9b87c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 5851 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at para. 77.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d36ac18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>161</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00222" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a9baed08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 5851 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 78 and 80.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7d36ac28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>162</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175944" w-seq-number="00223" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017202625" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I5a9bd5e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Endplex Investments Inc. v. Derrydale Golf Course Ltd.</ital>, 2008 CarswellOnt 5851 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 81–83.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 6:9<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
