<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 1:18<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I4d7849c0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>1.</label.designator><headtext>Confidential Business Information in Historical Context</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I4df6a180411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>III.</label.designator><headtext>Policy Considerations Governing the Protection of Intellectual Property</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I4df6efa0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>A.</label.designator><headtext>Principles Governing Intellectual Property</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f59c106ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>1:18.</label.designator><headtext>Means for Protecting Intellectual Property—Compulsory licence (as in patent)</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The primary purpose of patent law is to advance the economic welfare of the state by requiring public disclosure of new inventions so that others may learn of them and be spurred on to further discovery. <eos/><bos/>In patent law, the balance between protecting the state interest in access to information and providing an incentive for new creations is maintained by granting a limited term monopoly to those who create the invention in exchange for public disclosure of the information. <eos/><bos/>At the expiration of the monopoly period, the rights held by the owner of the patent are extinguished, and competitors are free to enter the market using the invention in question.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>It is easy to trace the infringement of patent rights since the information is a matter of public record. <eos/><bos/>The registration of patents almost totally precludes duplication of an invention and the associated economic loss. <eos/><bos/>Thus the patent owner can license the patent through comparatively straightforward contracts and assignments.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></section.body></section><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 1:18<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
