<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 4:13<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I5089a870411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>4.</label.designator><headtext>Confidential Business Information and the Employment Relationship</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I50976410411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>III.</label.designator><headtext>Confidentiality</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f611446ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>4:13.</label.designator><headtext>Use of Customer Lists and Memory</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>With regard to solicitation, a distinction was previously made between use of a physical document such as a customer list or directory removed from the former employer&apos;s premises, and use of information known and remembered by employees as a result of their employment duties. <eos/><bos/>That traditional view was set forth in the 1918 Ontario decision of <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1918039825" w-pub-number="0004707" ID="I2c368bf18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Canada Bonded Attorney and Legal Directory Ltd. v. Leonard-Parmiter</cite.query> Ltd.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id3e874f08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>] where the court held that a former employee could not solicit any customer whose name he had obtained from his former employer&apos;s materials, but that he could solicit those customers he could remember, even though he first met such customers during the course of his previous employment:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>He may, however, make use of knowledge he may have acquired … he <begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>“is perfectly entitled, when he starts as a rival in business to the plaintiff, to carry it on in the same way as his principal does. <eos/><bos/>He has learnt to do it, and he is entitled to the benefit of that knowledge:”<end.quote refid="QT_0001"/> <ital>per</ital> Lindley, L.J., in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="ER" w-normalized-cite="73LTR226" w-pub-number="0003728" w-pinpoint-page="228" ID="I2c36b3008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Louis v. Smellie</ital> (1895), 73 L.T.R. 226, at p. 228 [C.A.]</cite.query> … He may not canvass any customer whose name he has from material obtained or retained in fraud of his employer … but I can find no authority for the proposition that he may not as fair competition canvass those he may remember, even though he first met them when in the previous employ.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0002"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id3e874f18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The memory test was followed in a long line of cases.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3e874f28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">3</footnote.reference>] After examining the existing case law, the court in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1977148370" w-pub-number="0005150" ID="I2c3728318e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgar T. Alberts Ltd. v. Mountjoy</ital></cite.query> concluded:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0003"/>It appears from the law as enunciated in these authorities that whether or not an ex-employee may solicit customers of his employer turns upon the narrow question as to whether or not the solicitation is from a list of customers or clients removed from the ex-employer&apos;s premises, as against solicitation based upon the memory of the ex-employee …<end.quote refid="QT_0003"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id3e874f38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">4</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1977148370" w-pub-number="0005150" ID="I2c3887c18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Alberts</ital></cite.query> and subsequent decisions have had the effect of eroding the “memory” test. <eos/><bos/>In <ital>Axiom Services Ltd. v. Weigert</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id3e874f48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">5</footnote.reference>] the court stated that the defendant&apos;s:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0004"/>… use of the client list was, in all material respects, identical to the use of a client list in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2001360648" w-pub-number="0006459" ID="I2c38fcf08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Golden Images Management Ltd. v. Champers Enterprises Ltd.</ital>, 2001 BCSC 924 (B.C.S.C.)</cite.query>, although more egregious in that she secured the list improperly. <eos/><bos/>Ms. Weigert is liable to the plaintiffs for her taking and using the client list.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0004"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0005"/>In general, mere employees are prohibited from taking customer lists and information belonging to their former employers. <eos/><bos/>They are, however, entitled to use their own resources to attempt to contact former clients after leaving an employer …<end.quote refid="QT_0005"/></paratext></para></display.quote><paratext>Other cases have made it clear that information taken away by a former employee does not need to be reduced to writing in order to be protected.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3e89c008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">6</footnote.reference>] For example, in <ital>Quantum Management Services Ltd. v. Hann</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id3e89c018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">7</footnote.reference>] the defendants were restrained from exploiting information that they had committed to memory, but only in relation to customers with whom they had the “exclusive right” to deal:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0006"/>I am therefore satisfied that the defendants Hann and Taaffe breached their duty not to solicit their former employer&apos;s clients in that they exploited confidential information that they had committed to memory relating to those clients. <eos/><bos/>I am satisfied that the memorization of the characteristics of their exclusive clients is tantamount to the physical asportation of a client list: see <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1977148370" w-pub-number="0005150" ID="I2c3b95018e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgar T. Alberts Ltd. v. Mountjoy</ital></cite.query> … I would, however, restrict the employee&apos;s duty not to solicit or to have commercial dealings with the employer&apos;s clients only to those clients which the employee had an exclusive right to deal with.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0006"/></paratext></para></display.quote><paratext>It is questionable whether the list of customers made by former employees from memory after termination of their employment was confidential.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3e89c028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">8</footnote.reference>] In some cases, the courts have expressly stated that the departing employee is entitled to prepare a list of his or her book of business to take away.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3e89c038e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">9</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Valley First Financial Services Ltd. v. Trach</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id3e89c048e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">10</footnote.reference>] the court acknowledged that a former employee, <begin.quote ID="QT_0008"/>“other than a senior or key employee with fiduciary-like obligations, is free to compete with his or her former employer and to make use of the knowledge and experience acquired while employed.”<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0008"/> However, the employee could only do so as long as he or she did <begin.quote ID="QT_0009"/>“not disclose or make use of the former employer&apos;s confidential information, including customer lists removed from the former employer&apos;s premises.”<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0009"/> In <ital>Valley First</ital>, the judge noted that <begin.quote ID="QT_0007"/>“a former employee is entitled to solicit customers of the former employer recalled from his or her memory: see <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00007" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1988299152" w-pub-number="0006698" ID="I2c3c7f608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>TOS Insurance Services Ltd. v. Dale &amp; Co.</ital>, [1988] B.C.J. No. 504 (B.C.S.C. [In Chambers])</cite.query>”<end.quote refid="QT_0007"/>.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3e89c058e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">11</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>North Island Insultech (2017) Ltd. v. Cain</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id3e8c3108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">12</footnote.reference>] the defendant was a long-term employee of an insulation installation company. <eos/><bos/>Another company acquired its assets and the acquiring company changed its name to North. <eos/><bos/>At the time this acquisition transaction was completed, the old company terminated Cain&apos;s employment and the new company hired him. <eos/><bos/>His job duties with both companies included installing insulation. <eos/><bos/>The evidence was in conflict about the degree to which he engaged in management work. <eos/><bos/>Cain left his employment and subsequently sent a text message to various persons, including some that the company had performed work for advising that he and his grandson had established a new company.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3e8c3118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">13</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff&apos;s case was that the defendant breached a duty of confidence. <eos/><bos/>In particular, it alleged that the defendant made impermissible use of the company&apos;s customer list to prospect for work for his new enterprise. <eos/><bos/>The cause of action pleaded was that Cain breached a duty of confidence owed to his former employer. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff did not put its case either on the basis of fiduciary duty or on the basis of a breach of an implied term of the employment contract not to compete unfairly. <eos/><bos/>Cain&apos;s position was that the plaintiff was bound to lose because he owed no duty of any sort that prevented him from competing with his former employer and in doing so making use of his knowledge of the identities of the company&apos;s customers and their contact information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3e8c3128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">14</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Thompson observed that an employee is free to compete against a former employer, subject to the continuing duty not to misuse confidential information, as well as any duties arising out of fiduciary duty or restrictive covenant. <eos/><bos/>The social values of free competition and the freedom to pursue new opportunities explain the reticence to restrict former employees.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3e8c3138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">15</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The principal question on the motion for summary dismissal resolved to whether the following issue was genuinely triable: does the identity and contact information of the company&apos;s customers amount to “confidential information”?<eos/><bos/> The evidence put forward by the plaintiff was that the old company developed a list of contractors who were the customers of the business by repeated telephone calls, driving around to search for prospective construction sites, and word of mouth. <eos/><bos/>Cain was alleged to have participated in developing this customer list. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff&apos;s material indicated that the company also developed a computer database of its customers by tracking all estimates provided to contractors in the course of operating its business, including contact information. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff&apos;s evidence was that Cain had access to this database. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff&apos;s case was that this database was confidential information acquired by it when it purchased the assets of the old company, and that Cain used this information to distribute his text message.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3e8c3148e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">16</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Thompson observed that this was not a summary trial. <eos/><bos/>The defendant was obliged to persuade the Court that the plaintiff&apos;s case, taken at its highest, was bound to fail. <eos/><bos/>In practical terms, this meant that where there was a conflict in the evidence, for the purposes of the application the Court must decide on the basis of the plaintiff&apos;s version of events. <eos/><bos/>Justice Thompson&apos;s impression was that the breach of confidence case was thin. <eos/><bos/>However, it was difficult to know where to draw the line between legitimate competition and misuse of confidential information. <eos/><bos/>A careful consideration of the surrounding facts was required to properly determine whether Cain had and was permissibly competing with his former employer or whether he has misused confidential information. <eos/><bos/>It was a close call, but it was not a case that deserved to be screened out by summary judgment. <eos/><bos/>Justice Thompson was in doubt as to whether there was a genuine triable issue and was therefore obliged to dismiss the defendant&apos;s application.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3e8c3158e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">17</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>2298679 <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00008" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2c430f118e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc.</cite.query> et al.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id3e8c3168e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">18</footnote.reference>] the Plaintiff 229 moved, without notice, for an <ital>Anton Piller</ital> Order to search and seize electronic devices from the headquarters of the Defendant Northern Homecare and from the residence of the Defendant Goldkind, who was one of the principals of Northern Homecare. <eos/><bos/>Aurum Property also requested an injunction restraining Northern Homecare, Goldkind and the other Defendants, prohibiting them from possessing or transmitting Aurum&apos;s confidential customer information in any form or through any medium whatsoever. <eos/><bos/>Justice Perell dismissed the motion for an <ital>Anton Piller</ital> Order, and granted an interim injunction and mandatory order that was to terminate ten days after the release of the Reasons for Decision.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3e8ea208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">19</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Aurum was an industry leader in commercial window cleaning and property maintenance servicing government buildings, commercial high-rise buildings, condominium towers, hotels and hospitals across North America. <eos/><bos/>It also serviced residences and had a customer list of residential customers and leads numbering 35,000 contacts. <eos/><bos/>Aurum maintains a customer list that included: customer names, customer addresses, customer email addresses and details of past services including dates and prices.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3e8ea218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">20</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Northern Homecare&apos;s executive included Goldkind and Goldman. <eos/><bos/>Goldkind was the CEO and Goldman was the COO. <eos/><bos/>Northern Homecare carried on a residential window cleaning and property maintenance business.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3e8ea228e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">21</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Arous, Edward, and Hyde were former employees of Aurum. <eos/><bos/>Arous was employed as field business development representative from April 1, 2018 to July 6, 2018, when his employment was terminated. <eos/><bos/>Edwards was first employed as a field business development representative and was promoted to outbound business development representative. <eos/><bos/>He was employed from April 1, 2018 to August 2, 2018, when his employment was terminated. <eos/><bos/>Hyde was employed as a field business manager from May 1, 2017 to August 25, 2018 when he was terminated. <eos/><bos/>Arous, Edward, and Hyde signed employment agreements. <eos/><bos/>The agreements contained the confidentiality and non-disclosure provisions. <eos/><bos/>During their employment, Arous, Edward, and Hyde had access to Aurum&apos;s residential customer lists.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3e8ea238e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">22</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Although Aurum was not aware of it at the time: (a) after Arous was terminated, he logged into Aurum&apos;s management software, which contains Aurum&apos;s customer list, on six occasions; (b) after Edwards was terminated, he logged into Aurum&apos;s management software on two occasions; and (c) after Hyde was terminated he logged into Aurum&apos;s management software on at least thirty occasions. <eos/><bos/>Aurum did not know: (a) the extent of information that was obtained by Arous, Edward, and Hyde; (b) how the information was used; and (c) with whom the information was shared. <eos/><bos/>Aurum conceded that the extent of the confidential information allegedly misappropriated by the Defendants would be an important facet of Aurum&apos;s damages claim.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3eabee08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">23</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Up until eight months after it had terminated the employment of Arous, Edward, and Hyde, Aurum had no knowledge of these intrusions on its computer system. <eos/><bos/>In March and April 2019, however, there were a series of events that prompted Aurum to investigate: a. Customers DD, OA, ED, and AS cancelled appointments because they had already been contacted by persons presenting themselves as being Aurum. <eos/><bos/>Based on the information provided by these customers; b. Customer ND advised Arum that she had been contacted by persons presenting themselves as being Aurum. <eos/><bos/>She did not cancel her contract with Aurum. <eos/><bos/>Aurum inferred that Northern Homecare was using information provided by Arous, Edward, and Hyde to contact ND. c. Customer DS advised Aurum that he had been contacted by Goldkind who misrepresented himself as representing a reorganized Aurum. <eos/><bos/>Goldkind disparaged Arum as it had formerly existed. <eos/><bos/>DS advised Aurum of the contact. <eos/><bos/>Goldkind was lying and Aurum inferred that the wrongdoing of Goldkind was a spinoff of Arous, Edward, and Hydes&apos; disclosing confidential information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3eabee18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">24</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Aurum suspected but did not actually know that Arous, Edward, and Hyde provided confidential information to Northern Homecare because Aurum customers reported that when solicited by Northern Homecare, the Northern Homecare representative had knowledge of past services provided to the customer.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3eae5f08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">25</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>It was not clear, however, what the precise relationship or connection was between Northern Homecare and the three former employees, who might have a connection as employees, independent contractors, dependent contractors, sales agents, or intermediators.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3eae5f18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">26</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Perell concluded that while there appeared to have been wrongdoing, most likely by Goldkind and Goldman, it was not clear whether the harm they caused was trivial or substantial. <eos/><bos/>It appeared that it was only an inference that the three former employees stole the whole data base of customer information. <eos/><bos/>However, it was not clear whether the three former employees did anything more than inform Northern Homecare of a few contacts and that Northern Homecare used those few contacts to compete for business in a wrongful way when they should and could have competed for the customers in a lawful way. <eos/><bos/>On the other hand, it was not known whether more than a few of Aurum&apos;s customers were contacted and whether Northern Homecare was more than a minor nuisance and a major threat to Aurum&apos;s residential business. <eos/><bos/>In any event, at this juncture, there was no evidence to suggest that Northern Homecare or Goldkind had Aurum&apos;s customer list on its computers or that there was reason to believe that they would destroy that evidence.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3eae5f28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">27</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Perell noted that under their employment contracts, Arous, Edward, and Hydes&apos; obligations with respect to Confidential Information did not apply to information that they could demonstrate was generally available to or known by the public other than as a result of improper disclosure to them. <eos/><bos/>At this juncture, it was impossible to say that they had no defence to a breach of contract claim for the conduct of passing on information to Northern Homecare if that was what they did.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3eae5f38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">28</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Perell was satisfied that Aurum had presented a serious issue to be tried about whether the Arous, Edward, and Hyde and whether the Defendants committed the tort of breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>Although Aurum established a <ital>prima facie</ital> case for breach of confidence with an associated claim of breach of contract, it remained to be seen whether this was a case of former employees attempting to use the knowledge and experience they gained in their former employment for the purpose of earning a living with a new employer. <eos/><bos/>There was, in any event, a serious issue to be tried.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3eae5f48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">29</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Aurum asserted that it had and would suffer irreparable harm because of the wrongful activities of the Defendants and it submitted that its ability to sell its residential branch had been diminished. <eos/><bos/>However, there was no evidence about Aurum&apos;s actual plans for its residential branch. <eos/><bos/>Thus, the situation with respect to irreparable harm was that at this juncture Aurum had established only a significant possibility of harm from a breach of confidence or a breach of contract. <eos/><bos/>In this regard, it was noted that at the time of the <ital>ex parte</ital> injunction motion, Aurum had only discovered the alleged wrongdoing less than a month before. <eos/><bos/>Justice Perell observed that it was a close call on irreparable harm, but nevertheless concluded that for the purposes of an interim, ten-day, injunction that Aurum had suffered irreparable harm and that the balance of convenience favours granting an interim injunction.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3eae5f58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">30</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Perell explained that an <ital>Anton Piller</ital> order is a very intrusive and exceptional interlocutory order. <eos/><bos/>The purpose of the order is to prevent property from being lost, destroyed or removed, and to preserve relevant evidence, but it does not authorize access to privileged communications of documents. <eos/><bos/>An <ital>Anton Piller</ital> order is at the extremity of the court&apos;s powers and is granted only when there is no alternative way to ensure that justice may be done. <eos/><bos/>The requirements for an <ital>Anton Piller</ital> order are: (1) there must be an extremely strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case; (2) the damage, potential or actual, must be very serious for the plaintiff; (3) there must be convincing evidence that the defendant has in his or her possession incriminating documents or objects; and (4) there is a real possibility that the material may be destroyed or secreted before the parties may put their respective rights before the court. <eos/><bos/>An <ital>Anton Piller</ital> order is an exceptional remedy and should be granted only on clear and convincing evidence.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3eb0d008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">31</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>With respect to the claim for an <ital>Anton Piller</ital> order Justice Perell was of the opinion that there was not an extremely strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case as against Arous, Edward, Hyde, and Goldman but Aurum was not requesting an <ital>Anton Piller</ital> order as against them. <eos/><bos/>Justice Perell regarded the case as against Northern Homecare and Goldkind for injurious falsehood as strong but not extremely strong. <eos/><bos/>Thus, Aurum did not satisfy the criteria for an <ital>Anton Piller</ital> Order. <eos/><bos/>Remembering that it was Arous, Edward, and Hyde that obtained the customer information, that the extent of the information obtained was unknown, and that there was only an inference that they passed the information to Northern Homecare, it was entirely speculative that Northern Homecare had incriminating evidence or that there was any possibility, let alone a real possibility, that material might be destroyed or secreted before the parties put their respective rights before the court. <eos/><bos/>Moreover, an <ital>Anton Piller</ital> order is at the extremity of the court&apos;s powers and is granted only when there is no alternative way to ensure that justice may be done. <eos/><bos/>In the immediate case, there were reasonable alternatives that would protect Aurum for the potential loss of evidence. <eos/><bos/>Therefore, Justice Perell ordered as follows: a. Goldkind and Northern Homecare shall retain any confidential information of Aurum in their possession including, without limitation, customer lists, employee lists, partnership lists, supplier contracts, customer contracts, pricing policies, patents, trademarks, and other intellectual property; and b. Goldkind and Northern Homecare shall disclose to Aurum in an Affidavit of Documents any confidential information of Aurum in their possession including, without limitation, Aurum&apos;s customer lists, employee lists, partnership lists, supplier contracts, customer contracts, pricing policies, patents, trademarks, and other intellectual property.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3eb0d018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">32</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id3eb0d028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">33</footnote.reference>] the plaintiff, Capital Direct, which was in the business of providing home equity and residential mortgage financing to individuals, applied for an interim injunction restraining the defendant Blanchette, a former employee of Capital Direct and a licensed mortgage broker, from <begin.quote ID="QT_0010"/>“soliciting, serving, referring, directing, receiving business from, contacting or continuing any form of communication with any clients or active prospect of Capital Direct with whom she had contact or knowledge of during her employment with Capital Direct.”<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0010"/> Blanchette was hired and employed as a “Mortgage Salesperson” pursuant to a written employment agreement in 2005. <eos/><bos/>During her employment with Capital Direct she was also described and held out to the public as a “Mortgage Planner” or “Mortgage Advisor”.<eos/><bos/> The Original Employment Agreement contained a one-year non-competition clause, limited geographically to the <begin.quote ID="QT_0011"/>“City of Vancouver and the Lower Mainland”<end.quote refid="QT_0011"/>, and with respect to any business involving the business of private mortgage lending or private mortgage brokering. <eos/><bos/>The Original Employment Agreement contained a confidentiality clause that required Blanchette to keep all information provided to her by Capital Direct confidential, including information relating to any customer, and not to release, use, or disclose the information unless she obtained the prior written permission of Capital Direct. <eos/><bos/>The Original Employment Agreement expired on February 24, 2006. <eos/><bos/>Clause 3.2 of the Original Employment Agreement stated that the initial term could be extended for a further one-year period, on a recurring basis, upon the written agreement of both parties. <eos/><bos/>However, the Original Employment Agreement was never extended or renewed. <eos/><bos/>The parties agreed that from February 25, 2006 until her departure from Capital Direct, Blanchette&apos;s employment was not governed by a written employment agreement, nor was it subject to any express restrictive covenants or confidentiality provisions.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3eb0d038e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">34</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Capital Direct&apos;s business development efforts involved significant advertising across a wide range of media. <eos/><bos/>Blanchette was never the face of Capital Direct. <eos/><bos/>Capital Direct never used or displayed her name, contact information, picture, or bio in any of its advertising or on its website. <eos/><bos/>Blanchette did not engage in any networking activities for Capital Direct, nor was she required to do so. <eos/><bos/>Rather, potential clients who contacted Capital Direct were distributed on a rotating basis to all of the mortgage brokers.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3eb0d048e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">35</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In late 2017, Blanchette took a three-month medical leave of absence. <eos/><bos/>When she commenced her leave, she was one of three mortgage brokers. <eos/><bos/>Following her return, Blanchette&apos;s authority and discretion were significantly decreased by Capital Direct, including that she was only referred new phone leads/clients from outside the Metro Vancouver area; her authority to approve mortgages up to $500,000 was decreased to only lower value mortgages; she could no longer contact an investor directly to deal with changes to the Loan to Value ratio or the funding amount after a mortgage was approved and prior to funding; whereas she could previously initial the change without question; she no longer had authority to negotiate a repayment program; she could no longer waive or reduce NSF fees unless she had approval; she could no longer approve holds on a client&apos;s payments without approval; she needed approval before allowing clients to send and sign mortgage package documents outside the Capital Direct office; and her time/schedule was managed by the Capital Direct administrative staff and manager whereas she previously had autonomy to set her own schedule. <eos/><bos/>By the time of her return, Capital Direct had employed three new brokers, bringing the total number of active brokers to six. <eos/><bos/>The three new junior brokers were assigned to work with and train under the other two senior brokers. <eos/><bos/>Blanchette was not provided with any assistance from these new employees.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3eb34108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">36</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>On July 13, 2018, Capital Direct provided one year&apos;s working notice of termination to Blanchette. <eos/><bos/>Settlement negotiations continued until February 12, 2019, when they broke down for the final time. <eos/><bos/>Capital Direct directed Blanchette to report to work on February 13, 2019. <eos/><bos/>Blanchette did not report to work. <eos/><bos/>Capital Direct treated Blanchette&apos;s employment as having been ended by her.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3eb34118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">37</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Capital Direct discovered that Blanchette had referred a client of Capital Direct to her son. <eos/><bos/>Blanchette sent an email to this client stating that she was transferring her mortgage broker license to work independently of Capital Direct, and would be working with her son going forward. <eos/><bos/>The client later received an approval through her son but did not go ahead with that financing as the client received a better offer from Capital Direct.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3eb34128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">38</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Blanchette said that from this point until the end of February 2019, she did not initiate contact with any clients, former clients, or active prospects of Capital Direct, as she needed to wait until her Mortgage Sub Broker license had been officially transferred. <eos/><bos/>The clients she had any contact with during this period were either ones who contacted her directly or who were close friends or associates. <eos/><bos/>Once her Mortgage Sub Broker license was officially transferred to a new brokerage, Blanchette did begin contacting certain former clients she had personally serviced at Capital Direct. <eos/><bos/>She provided her new contact information, advised them that she had made a switch from working for Capital Direct, and reassured them that she was available to answer any questions or concerns they had going forward.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3eb34138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">39</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Blanchette acknowledged that she had the names, phone numbers and email addresses of some of her former clients at Capital Direct, information she personally collected over many years. <eos/><bos/>She collected this information to help her do her job better, to stay in touch and maintain relationships with her clients, and to reconcile commissions. <eos/><bos/>She collected this information on her own initiative and was not directed to do so by Capital Direct as part of her job duties. <eos/><bos/>Blanchette did not download or take any customer lists compiled by Capital Direct, nor did she possess a list of Capital Direct clients with whom she did not personally deal. <eos/><bos/>Blanchette did not take or possess any documents of Capital Direct containing detailed customer information relating to their needs or preferences, the rates they paid, their credit rating, or their income, assets or debt.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3eb34148e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">40</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Blanchette said that to date she had not benefitted financially from any of her initiated contacts with former clients. <eos/><bos/>The only amount she has been paid arising from a former client was from one person who called her to arrange financing to pay out an existing Capital Direct mortgage.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3eb34158e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">41</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Branch concluded that the heightened standard of strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case should be applied for the following reasons: the request for injunctive relief at trial would likely become moot by the time the matter reached that stage, as any duties Blanchette might owe to Capital Direct not to solicit former clients, even at a fiduciary level, would likely have expired; an injunction would clearly affect Blanchette&apos;s ability to earn a living. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff was almost 64 years old. <eos/><bos/>An injunction against any communication with individuals with whom she has worked over many years would clearly be detrimental to her ability to earn a living.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3eb34168e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">42</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Branch observed that Capital Direct initially had non-competition and confidentiality clauses in place, but those fell away as its relationship with Blanchette continued. <eos/><bos/>Absent contractual duties governing the conduct of a former employee, Capital Direct must rely on common law principles. <eos/><bos/>It first placed reliance on the concept of fiduciary duty. <eos/><bos/>Capital Direct alleged that by virtue of the trust, confidence and broad discretion possessed by Blanchette, Capital Direct was subject to a peculiar vulnerability to the exercise of her powers. <eos/><bos/>Justice Branch concluded that there was not a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that Blanchette would be found to be a fiduciary given that: she was not the general manager or broker on record, even in name only; she was no longer subjected to any restrictive covenants; she was not in management at all, having no employees under her; she was not identified on marketing materials; she did not have access to all of Capital Direct&apos;s confidential information; she was not the primary point of contact for Capital Direct&apos;s major client or group of clients; she was only one of eight brokers; she did not supervise any other employees; the defendant&apos;s reputation did not rest in Blanchette&apos;s hands; she was not the first point of contact with any clients, who were simply referred to her randomly; her client list had diminished such that she was not an integral part of the financial success of the office. <eos/><bos/>Her commissions had reduced to approximately one-half of what the other senior mortgage brokers were achieving; even according to the defendant, she had no power to make referrals to other companies without management approval; and, particularly after she was given her one-year notice, her rights and responsibilities were greatly reduced. <eos/><bos/>This showed a lack of trust, rather than to her being a repository of trust.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3eb5b208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">43</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Based on her limited discretion and authority, Justice Branch concluded that Capital Direct was not particularly vulnerable to loss, harm, and damage if Blanchette failed to perform her duties.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3eb5b218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">44</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Even if there was no fiduciary duty, there may still be other common law duties applicable to departing employees. <eos/><bos/>There was support for Capital Direct&apos;s position that there was at least a more limited duty on the part of the former employee not to misuse confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The improper use of confidential client information by an employee constitutes a breach of the employee&apos;s duty of confidence. <eos/><bos/>However, Justice Branch concluded that there was not a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that Blanchette misused confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The information that Blanchette retained was not a client list as that term is properly understood. <eos/><bos/>She did not download, take, print off or extract a client list from the plaintiff&apos;s systems. <eos/><bos/>Rather, she simply had a list of persons with whom she had had previous contact on her phone. <eos/><bos/>Further, it was only basic name, phone number or email information, and not more material information such as mortgage renewal dates, interest rates charged, current banking profiles, or other personal characteristics. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence that the defendant extracted information “in fraud of” Capital Direct or that it was intentionally <begin.quote ID="QT_0013"/>“acquired to advance his own business”<end.quote refid="QT_0013"/>. <eos/><bos/>Rather, the information was simply gathered in her phone over the many years of her employment. <eos/><bos/>Capital Direct did not assert that Blanchette took a copy of any client list, nor that she emailed a list of customer names to her personal email account. <eos/><bos/>Nor was there evidence that she made a special effort to duplicate or imprint any formal client lists or sheets into her memory or her phone. <eos/><bos/>Nor did the information include <begin.quote ID="QT_0012"/>“the clients&apos; needs, the clients&apos; preferences, and the rates that the clients were willing to pay”<end.quote refid="QT_0012"/>. <eos/><bos/>Rather, it was simply contact information already on her phone. <eos/><bos/>Hence, the relatively passive retention of name of contact information on her phone gathered over the course of her employment did not amount to the misuse of confidential information on the facts.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3eb5b228e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">45</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00009" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2045449429" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2c7765818e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Shaver-Kudell Manufacturing Inc. v. Knight Manufacturing</cite.query> Inc.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id3eb5b238e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">46</footnote.reference>] the Plaintiff SK operated a machine shop which manufactured metal sleeves of different lengths and diameters, which are used to repair the ball bearings in electric motors. <eos/><bos/>SK claimed that the tooling and manufacturing process that it developed to make the metal sleeves were trade secrets that were confidential in nature and alleged that the Defendants misappropriated its trade secrets and that the employee committed a breach of confidence in relation to SK&apos;s tooling, manufacturing process and customer list.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3eb5b248e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">47</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Lucy was SK&apos;s first employee. <eos/><bos/>Over the course of 23 years, she had regular contact with customers and held many roles within the company, including customer service and marketing. <eos/><bos/>Towards the end of her employment, she was also responsible for shipping and receiving. <eos/><bos/>In that role, she had familiarity with SK customer orders. <eos/><bos/>As the employee responsible for accounts receivable, she also had familiarity with customers&apos; credit status. <eos/><bos/>When Lucy left the family business and within months joined KM as a telemarketer, these customers remembered her. <eos/><bos/>She immediately re-connected with customers she had interacted with for two decades. <eos/><bos/>In doing so, she reported to Mr. Knecht and Mr. Ballmer that customers recognized her as “Lucy from SK”.<eos/><bos/> Lucy relied on her knowledge of SK&apos;s customers to solicit them to follow her to KM. Many of these customers followed her and transferred their business to KM.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3eb5b258e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">48</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00010" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2019906465" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2c7801c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>GasTOPS Ltd. v. Forsyth</ital>, 2009 CarswellOnt 5773, [2009] O.J. No. 3969 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at para. 120, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00011" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2024661162" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2c7801c38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2010 CarswellOnt 10494, 2010 ONSC 7068</cite.query>, <case.history>affd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00012" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027253060" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2c7801c68e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2012 CarswellOnt 2539, 2012 ONCA 134</cite.query>, the court observed that <begin.quote ID="QT_0014"/>“the confidential information need not be committed to a document that is physically removed from one&apos;s former employer. <eos/><bos/>Committing information to memory is tantamount to the physical taking of confidential information.”<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0014"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id3eb82308e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">49</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The defendants knew that they were receiving confidential information from Lucy about SK&apos;s customers. <eos/><bos/>In fact, this was why KM hired Lucy to do marketing for the sale of sleeves.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3eb82318e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">50</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Smith observed that in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00013" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1989313313" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2c78c5108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Quantum Management Services Ltd. v. Hann</ital>, 1989 CarswellOnt 124, [1989] O.J. No. 542 (H.C.)</cite.query>, the court held that in addition to trade secrets of an employer, confidential information can include special knowledge about the employer&apos;s customers and knowledge of the employer&apos;s policies and procedures that would make it possible to undercut the former employer and induce the customers to change to the new supplier as well as customer lists. <eos/><bos/>The courts have found a misuse of confidential information not only when an employee departed with a copy of the customer list, but also where an employee memorized the list. <eos/><bos/>Lucy was extensively involved in marketing, taking orders from customers and shipping and collecting accounts receivable and acquired detailed knowledge of SK&apos;s customers as a result of her employment at SK for a lengthy period of time. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiff had not alleged that Lucy took a copy of SK&apos;s customer list, but she acquired detailed knowledge of SK&apos;s customers, which was the same as if she had memorized the customer list by working regularly with SK&apos;s customers over 23 years.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3eb82328e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">51</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Smith relied on <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00014" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040845729" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2c7988608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2158124 Ontario Inc. v. Pitton</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 1023, 2017 ONSC 411</cite.query>, wherein Justice Goodman held that, in respect of confidential information, it does not make a difference if a departing employee has information that allows him to correspond with and solicit former clients, to the extent that he is doing so from memory. <eos/><bos/>Committing to memory the names of clients, their contacts, the clients&apos; needs or preferences, and the rates that the clients were willing to pay, is confidential information and exploiting such information to solicit former clients <begin.quote ID="QT_0015"/>“is tantamount to the physical asportation of a client list”<end.quote refid="QT_0015"/> and its use is prohibited. <eos/><bos/>As a result of her 23 years of regular contact with SK&apos;s customers Lucy committed many of those customers&apos; names to her memory. <eos/><bos/>Justice Smith further observed that, likewise, in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00015" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2000541558" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2c7988638e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sheehan &amp; Rosie Ltd. v. Northwood,</ital> [2000 CarswellOnt 670 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>] Justice Quinn J. did not place great weight on the distinction of “memorization” versus “remembering” with respect to an employee of 13 years, stating:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0016"/>Northwood insists that he did not take with him a client list. <eos/><bos/>How is it, therefore, that he was able to do a mailing to a number of clients? <eos/><bos/>I see nothing to be gained in going through the possible explanations. <eos/><bos/>The simple answer is that he has information which allowed him to correspond with, and solicit, some of the clients of S&amp;R Ltd. <eos/><bos/><ital>To the extent he is implying that his knowledge of the addresses of the clients is in his head, rather than from a list, I say that it does not make a difference</ital>. <eos/><bos/>In this regard, I agree with, and rely upon the following statement of Ewaschuk J. in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00016" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1989313313" w-pub-number="0005505" ID="I2c7a4bb08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Quantum Management Services Ltd. V. Hann (1989), 69 O.R. (2d) 26 (Ont. H.C.)</cite.query>, at [44].<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0016"/></paratext></para></display.quote><paratext>Justice Smith was of the view that a further look at <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00017" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1989313313" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2c7b0f018e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Quantum Management Services Ltd</ital></cite.query>. was helpful to determining what was meant by “committed to memory”, wherein Justice Ewaschuk wrote:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0017"/>It is conceded that neither Hann or Taafe took customer lists. <eos/><bos/>However, I am satisfied that both Hann and Taaffe had committed to memory, which was not difficult, the names of their exclusive clients, the contacts at these clients&apos; businesses, the clients&apos; needs, the clients&apos; preferences, and the rates that the clients were willing to pay. <eos/><bos/>After all, the placement director had to be in almost constant communication with her contact in order to obtain a job order within 31 days of the last order. <eos/><bos/>The clients were not so numerous as to invite confusion of the confidential information pertaining to each individual client. <eos/><bos/>Ms. Hann conceded that she has an exceptional memory and this was confirmed for both Hann and Taaffee by the high percentage of Quantum&apos;s former clients that the Defendants readily recruited. <eos/><bos/>This success is in marked contrast to the low percentage of new client Pinstripe recruited despite heavy advertising in the media.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0017"/></paratext></para></display.quote><paratext>The Defendants&apos; ability to remember customers&apos; names, needs, and preferences was considered to be the same as “committing to memory” and was held to be tantamount to physical asportation. <eos/><bos/>This was the situation here, as Lucy committed to memory or knew many of SK&apos;s customers as a result of working with them over 23 years. <eos/><bos/>Justice Smith stated:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0018"/>In the Stonelite (Canada) Ltd. decision at para 55 the court stated:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext>It is widely recognized that an employee can leave his employment and take the knowledge gained in that employment, and he is free to compete with his former employer. <eos/><bos/>However, he may not take or use against his previous employer any of his employer&apos;s trade secrets, confidential information or customer lists.<eos/><bos/></paratext></para><para><paratext>In GasTOPS Ltd. at para 136 the court stated that customer information was confidential information in need of protection by the court given that it is valuable, that it forms part of the goodwill of the employer, and that it was developed over time at the employer&apos;s expense. <eos/><bos/>These factors are all present in this case as SK developed goodwill with its customers over a lengthy period of time.<eos/><bos/></paratext></para><para><paratext>In RBC Dominion Securities Inc. the Supreme Court held that a duty of “good faith” is an implied term of every employment contract and making improper use of confidential information renders the former employee liable for damages.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0018"/></paratext></para></display.quote></para></display.quote><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Even though Lucy was not in a fiduciary role, she owed SK a duty of good faith as a long-time employee with extensive knowledge and a good relationship with many of SK&apos;s customers for a competitor. <eos/><bos/>As a result, Lucy had a duty not to improperly use SK&apos;s confidential information, which included her knowledge of SK&apos;s customers acquired during the course of her 23 years of employment with SK, to solicit SK&apos;s customers within a relatively short period of time after leaving her employment.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3eba9408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">52</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Lucy targeted at least 21 SK customers with free samples when she started marketing for KM. She selected these customers because she had committed these customers&apos; names to memory over the course of her employment at SK. She would also have known the ordering quantities and payment history of the clients as a result of her responsibility for accounts receivable. <eos/><bos/>Lucy breached her duty of confidence and good faith to SK by using SK&apos;s confidential information, which included her knowledge of SK&apos;s customers and their purchasing patterns and payment history for the improper purpose of soliciting SK&apos;s customers within a relatively short period after leaving for the benefit of the defendants.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3eba9418e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">53</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>OIBC v. KO</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id3eba9428e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">54</footnote.reference>] Ko had worked for OIBC, an insurance brokerage in Richmond Hill owned and operated by husband and wife, Lau and Chik. <eos/><bos/>Ko resigned saying she was tired and wanted to spend more time for herself after 23 years of service. <eos/><bos/>Ko changed her mind the next day and contacted the defendant insurance brokerage to inquire about a job. <eos/><bos/>She started actively working for them within one week. <eos/><bos/>Over time, a significant number of OIBC&apos;s clients transferred over to Ko.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3eba9438e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">55</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Nakatsuru explained that he was not ignorant of the fact that the timing of the resignation and subsequent acceptance of employment at the defendant brokerage raised a red flag. <eos/><bos/>However, while Justice Nakatsuru did not find Ko&apos;s explanation as to why she resigned and then started working at a competitor so quickly particularly compelling, he was satisfied that this did not raise an issue requiring a trial. <eos/><bos/>The bottom line was that she moved quickly to a competitor. <eos/><bos/>Her motivation for doing so was a factor to be considered and was something that could be considered properly on a summary judgment motion.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3eba9448e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">56</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Nakatsuru observed that it is well-established law that an employee cannot take an employer&apos;s customer list with them and use it to solicit customers. <eos/><bos/>The courts have considered the settled distinction between information in an employee&apos;s memory and the removal of a customer list, as well as the nature of the information as being important considerations in drawing the line between what is fair and unfair in the employment context. <eos/><bos/>OIBC produced no evidence that Ko took a client list. <eos/><bos/>Ko expressly admitted that she had clients&apos; names and contact information stored on her personal cellphone as part of a personal contact list she had developed over the years. <eos/><bos/>She did this as a means to stay in touch with the clients. <eos/><bos/>Justice Nakatsuru concluded that Ko did not take with her a written or electronic customer list. <eos/><bos/>A complicating fact was that Ko would not have been able to recreate this list from memory. <eos/><bos/>As such, it did not readily fall within this distinction made by the case law. <eos/><bos/>At the same time, all that was stored were names and contact information. <eos/><bos/>The specific details of the policies were not inputted into her phone. <eos/><bos/>Justice Nakatsuru concluded that the names and contact information taken did not amount to confidential information of OIBC.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3eba9458e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">57</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The fundamental issue was whether the information had a quality of confidence about it and whether it was communicated in circumstances where the obligation of confidence arose. <eos/><bos/>In assessing this, the nature of the information is important. <eos/><bos/>The information revealed little beyond the bare name of a client and a contact number/address. <eos/><bos/>It did not involve details about the policyholder or policy that might be important to the employer. <eos/><bos/>The names and contact information, being those of clients, could be of use to someone like Ko, a departing employee, to potentially use it as a “springboard” for her new employment. <eos/><bos/>On the other hand, she did not take the names and contacts of other OIBC clients that she herself did not deal with.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3eba9468e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">58</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>At issue in <ital>2158124 Ontario Inc. v. Pitton</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id3ebd0508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">59</footnote.reference>] was whether Pitton had breached his non-solicitation and confidentiality obligations under an employment agreement. <eos/><bos/>StoneRidge carried on business as an insurance brokerage. <eos/><bos/>Glenny carried on business as an insurance brokerage. <eos/><bos/>It was a family-run business whose principals included Brian and Scott. <eos/><bos/>Pitton was a long-time family friend of the principals of Glenny. <eos/><bos/>Pitton was a licensed insurance broker. <eos/><bos/>Up to April 2011, Pitton was employed as a broker with Brokerlink managing a book of business consisting of commercial and personal clients. <eos/><bos/>Pitton approached StoneRidge&apos;s principal Puccini, advising that he wished to leave Brokerlink to join StoneRidge. <eos/><bos/>Pitton proposed that StoneRidge approach Brokerlink with an offer to purchase the book of business managed by him so that he could commence his StoneRidge employment with a ready client base. <eos/><bos/>Puccini eventually purchased the book of business from Brokerlink. <eos/><bos/>The book of business was assigned to StoneRidge. <eos/><bos/>Pitton was hired by StoneRidge as a senior account executive managing the Brokerlink book of business. <eos/><bos/>Pitton signed an Employment Agreement and was employed by StoneRidge until his abrupt resignation. <eos/><bos/>Without prior notice, Pitton delivered a letter of resignation and advised Puccini that he had accepted a position as a broker with Glenny, now operating under the name Erion. <eos/><bos/>Unbeknownst to Puccini or to anyone else at StoneRidge, Pitton began to contact StoneRidge clients to advise that he was leaving. <eos/><bos/>Puccini became aware of the solicitation because StoneRidge was contacted subsequently by several clients requesting clarification of Pitton&apos;s situation.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3ebd0518e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">60</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Pitton&apos;s book of business at the time of termination consisted of 183 commercial client lines and 92 personal client lines. <eos/><bos/>The defendants alleged that Pitton sent an email to a small selection of his former clients. <eos/><bos/>Most of the clients who received the email had followed Pitton from Brokerlink and included close personal friends and family, the vast majority of whom resulted from relationships that pre-dated his employment with the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>The defendants alleged that Pitton restricted the email to 50 individuals and had only spoken to approximately 35 former clients. <eos/><bos/>The defendants argued that the purpose of the email was not to be a solicitation of the plaintiff&apos;s clients.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3ebd0528e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">61</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>There was no dispute that a brokerage&apos;s primary asset is its customer base, including names, addresses, contact information, occupation, business and insurance requirements, information that would be extremely beneficial to another brokerage.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3ebd0538e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">62</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Goodman observed that several things flowing from the email clearly indicated a solicitation of business. <eos/><bos/>The email from Pitton was sent two days before Puccini&apos;s discussion with Scott regarding a potential purchase of the book of business and his confirmation that the Agreement would be honoured. <eos/><bos/>The email was sent on a Saturday, indicating that Pitton was losing no time in approaching certain of StoneRidge&apos;s clients. <eos/><bos/>Before even apparently commencing his new employment, Pitton had a Glenny email address, office address and telephone number. <eos/><bos/>StoneRidge was in touch with most clients serviced by Pitton and was advised by almost all of them that they had been contacted by Pitton either by email, letter or telephone call. <eos/><bos/>Justice Goodman was satisfied that Pitton knew who his StoneRidge clients were, had their contact information on his personal cell phone, was aware of the products they had purchased, the type of insurance coverage they had and general knowledge of when client policy renewals came due. <eos/><bos/>It was somewhat self-serving to justify this conduct by claiming that certain clients would have followed Pitton in any event. <eos/><bos/>The email went far beyond simply advising clients that Pitton had left StoneRidge. <eos/><bos/>The email referenced “my clients” and clearly stated that Pitton would provide <begin.quote ID="QT_0019"/>“the best service at competitive pricing at Erion …”<end.quote refid="QT_0019"/>. <eos/><bos/>He opined that his position at Glenny as operations manager would have a <begin.quote ID="QT_0020"/>“positive effect on client relations and insurance options”<end.quote refid="QT_0020"/>. <eos/><bos/>Finally, he stated that he hoped <begin.quote ID="QT_0021"/>“to continue working with you in the future”<end.quote refid="QT_0021"/>. <eos/><bos/>Justice Goodman concluded that Pitton solicited former clients of StoneRidge immediately after his resignation from the plaintiff&apos;s business.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3ebd0548e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">63</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In respect of confidential information, Justice Goodman observed that it does not make a difference if a departing employee has information that allows him to correspond with and solicit former clients, to the extent that he is doing so from memory. <eos/><bos/>Committing to memory the names of clients, their contacts, the clients&apos; needs or preferences, and the rates that the clients were willing to pay, is confidential information and exploiting such information to solicit former clients <begin.quote ID="QT_0022"/>“is tantamount to the physical asportation of a client list”<end.quote refid="QT_0022"/> and its use is prohibited.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3ebd0558e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">64</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The non-solicitation provision in the Agreement was reasonable and not vague when applying the evidence of the industry standard. <eos/><bos/>Furthermore, the language of the e-mail from Pitton to StoneRidge clients clearly and objectively showed an intention to solicit business. <eos/><bos/>The use of confidential StoneRidge information to facilitate solicitation was a breach in and of itself. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff had not only shown a serious issue to be tried but that it had a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3ebf7608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">65</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Edgetch HVAC Services Ltd. v. Ubhi</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id3ebf7618e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">66</footnote.reference>] the plaintiffs sought an interim injunction restraining the defendants from competing against Edgetch and from soliciting clients and employees of Edgetch. <eos/><bos/>The defendants fell into three categories. <eos/><bos/>Jesse was a one-third owner of Edgetch. <eos/><bos/>Jesse founded Edgetch with the plaintiffs Randy and Thomas. <eos/><bos/>Edgetch was an authorized sales and service distributor for gas detection products manufactured by Honeywell. <eos/><bos/>From 2008 to 2014, Edgetch was solely in Jesse&apos;s name, as Randy and Thomas continued to work at Honeywell. <eos/><bos/>In January 2014, after Randy and Thomas were laid off from Honeywell, the three of them engaged in a corporate reorganization of Edgetch and executed a unanimous shareholder agreement. <eos/><bos/>James and Extreme were independent contractors for Edgetch. <eos/><bos/>The remaining defendants were former employees of Edgetch. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs alleged that Jesse orchestrated the resignation of the former employees, the incorporation of Extreme and the possession and control of Edgetch&apos;s confidential information for the purpose of competing against Edgetch with Extreme.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3ebf7628e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">67</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiffs&apos; narrative was one of being the victim to Jesse&apos;s plan to direct the other defendants to use proprietary information to solicit clients and compete against Edgetch in a way that did not overtly offend his obligations as set out in the USA. <eos/><bos/>Jesse&apos;s narrative was one of the victim as well. <eos/><bos/>He stated that he was the victim of exclusion by the plaintiffs who purposely denied him his rights under the USA and were now relying on it to prevent him from earning a livelihood with his recently formed company. <eos/><bos/>Jesse submitted that the plaintiffs could not seek to enforce the restrictive covenants in the USA, as the plaintiffs effectively repudiated the agreement and excluded him from the business improperly. <eos/><bos/>The former employees&apos; narrative was one of good, honest people with no choice but to leave Edgetch to join Extreme in order to earn a livelihood, given the stresses created by nepotism and racism at Edgetch.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3ebf7638e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">68</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motions judge was of the view that it was the plaintiffs&apos; narrative that was supported and demonstrated by the evidentiary record. <eos/><bos/>The motions judge did not accept that Jesse was a victim of exclusion by Randy and Thomas. <eos/><bos/>The exclusion efforts were conduct reactive to Jesse&apos;s efforts to defeat Edgetch by soliciting its clients and competing against it with the assistance of former employees. <eos/><bos/>The motions judge did not accept that the former employees left Edgetch <ital>en masse</ital> without notice or transition because of nepotism or racism. <eos/><bos/>The timing of the resignations coincided too conveniently with Jesse&apos;s efforts to have the restrictive covenants in the USA waived, and none of the letters of resignation detailed nepotism or racism as the reason for leaving Edgetch. <eos/><bos/>The former employees left to assist Jesse with his efforts to compete against Edgetch through Extreme. <eos/><bos/>Finally, the motions judge did not accept that James decided to rebrand and expand his business around the same time that Jesse was negotiating a way out of his restrictive covenants and the former employees resigned without notice. <eos/><bos/>The only conclusion that failed to defy common sense was that Jesse took intentional and covert steps to coordinate with James and Edgetch employees in order to compete with Edgetch through Extreme.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3ebf7648e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">69</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The defendants argued that there were no proprietary marketing or business techniques that Edgetch used to solicit customers on the basis that Edgetch&apos;s start up and service reports contain information that was easily obtained directly from customers and was generally offered by customers, upon request, to any service providers, especially competitive service providers who requested it, as this facilitated customers&apos; efforts to secure competitive quotes from different service providers before awarding the work. <eos/><bos/>The motions judge disagreed with this submission. <eos/><bos/>Edgetch recorded their clients&apos; specific products, pricing and servicing requirements. <eos/><bos/>This was information critical to the company, permitting it to know the clients&apos; needs and when these needs must be addressed. <eos/><bos/>It was not sufficient to say that the remaining shareholders could have called their clients to ask about products, pricing or when servicing was due. <eos/><bos/>The defendant Neha had the database of all clients, which included all upcoming scheduling for servicing, and she would update the database every evening. <eos/><bos/>The documentary evidence reflected the use of this information, including service reports, start-up reports and the excel service database to solicit business on behalf of Extreme. <eos/><bos/>The documentary evidence reflected the use by the defendants of Edgetch&apos;s proprietary information to solicit Edgetch&apos;s clients and compete with its business. <eos/><bos/>It put them in a position to harm the business of Edgetch as it gave them the opportunity to reach out and schedule the service required in accordance with the information retained.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3ebf7658e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">70</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motions judge observed that the cases focus on the result of the enforcement of the covenant when adopting the strong <ital>prima facie</ital> test. <eos/><bos/>It is the result, interfering with an individual&apos;s ability to earn a livelihood that properly informs the analysis. <eos/><bos/>In this case, the restrictive covenant was agreed to by shareholders of equal bargaining power in a commercial context and not by an employee as a condition of employment or in the context of a sale of business. <eos/><bos/>The motions judge concluded nonetheless that the strong <ital>prima facie</ital> test still applied as the consequence remained consistent in that the shareholder was restricted in his ability to make a living. <eos/><bos/>Therefore, the higher threshold of a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case was applicable to the first branch of the <ital>RJR MacDonald</ital> test.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3ec1e708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">71</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Jesse was the only defendant that was contractually prohibited from soliciting Edgetch&apos;s clients or employees. <eos/><bos/>He was the president and director of Edgetch. <eos/><bos/>Jesse breached the USA and his fiduciary duties as shareholder and director by soliciting clients and employees of Edgetch and using confidential information to compete directly against Edgetch. <eos/><bos/>While the evidence remained in its early stages and there had been some reliance on hearsay, the plaintiffs established a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case as against Jesse. <eos/><bos/>This conclusion was reached in the context of reasonable restrictive covenants in the USA. <eos/><bos/>The USA was a commercial contract amongst business partners of equal bargaining power bringing different and complimenting skills to the relationship. <eos/><bos/>At the commencement of their relationship, the partners negotiated and agreed to the terms therein. <eos/><bos/>It must be presumed that they did so with knowledge of the industry and in a manner that reasonably reflected the risks inherent in their business. <eos/><bos/>The court ought not to impose its views on reasonableness years later upon the breakdown of the relationship, unless the contract was entered into unfairly or circumstances occurred in the interim that could not have been reasonably foreseen at the time of the contract. <eos/><bos/>Further, the territorial scope was limited and did not extend to all territories within which Edgetch did business.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3ec1e718e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">72</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>None of the remaining defendants were contractually prohibited from soliciting Edgetch&apos;s clients or employees or prohibited from competing with Edgetch upon leaving the company. <eos/><bos/>However, as they assisted Jesse in the breach of his fiduciary duties, they too were liable for the breach.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3ec1e728e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">73</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The remaining defendants denied possessing or misusing any information belonging to Edgetch and submitted that the information at issue was neither confidential nor proprietary. <eos/><bos/>The motions judge disagreed with this submission. <eos/><bos/>The documentary evidence demonstrated a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that Neha, Arjun, Vic and Rovind misused confidential information for the benefit of Extreme. <eos/><bos/>Aman, Vic and Micky resigned their positions without notice, in order to work for Extreme. <eos/><bos/>James incorporated Extreme. <eos/><bos/>Extreme&apos;s business was founded, at least in part, on the misuse of confidential information. <eos/><bos/>By their very employment with Extreme, therefore, the former employees could be said to have misused confidential information for the benefit of a competitor. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs established a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that the defendants misused confidential information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3ec1e738e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">74</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>As the plaintiffs established a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case, the second and third branches of the <ital>RJR-MacDonald</ital> test carried less emphasis. <eos/><bos/>Determining the harm to a company as a result of the misuse of confidential information to solicit clients and compete is more complex than a mathematical calculation. <eos/><bos/>The defendants used confidential information to solicit Edgetch&apos;s clients and compete against it. <eos/><bos/>In doing so, they increased Edgetch&apos;s competition and consequently reduced its market share. <eos/><bos/>The extent of this damage cannot be quantified. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs suffered irreparable harm.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3ec1e748e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">75</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Edgetch developed its client base and business over its years of operation. <eos/><bos/>It prepared its confidential information and worked continuously to keep it current and relevant to servicing the clients&apos; needs. <eos/><bos/>Edgetch&apos;s former employees and one of its directors established the company, at least in part, to use Edgetch&apos;s confidential information to solicit its clients and compete with Edgetch. <eos/><bos/>Some of the solicitation took place prior to the employees leaving the company. <eos/><bos/>With respect to Jesse, the balance of convenience favoured the plaintiffs.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3ec1e758e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">76</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiffs sought an order enjoining the remaining defendants from competing with the business of Edgetch for a period of 12 months. <eos/><bos/>Jesse was an owner and director of Edgetch. <eos/><bos/>His efforts to thwart the obligations of his restrictive covenants were not only assisted by the remaining defendants; the success of his efforts depended entirely on the participation of the remaining defendants. <eos/><bos/>The remaining defendants were not relieved of their critical conduct because their employment status might otherwise be something less than a fiduciary. <eos/><bos/>Rather, it was the conduct itself that attached them to the fiduciary and absorbed them as if they were fiduciaries themselves.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3ec45808e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">77</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In terms of the remaining defendants however, if the plaintiffs&apos; request was granted, the remaining defendants would be left without an ability to earn a livelihood in their chosen line of business for a period of 12 months. <eos/><bos/>This would result in harm to the remaining defendants far greater than the consequence of their choice to use confidential information and start a new company to assist Jesse. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs submitted that unless the remaining defendants are enjoined as requested, Jesse would be permitted to do indirectly what he is not permitted to do directly because of the USA. <eos/><bos/>This concern could be addressed, however, in a less restrictive manner that balanced the legitimate concern of the plaintiffs with the need of the remaining defendants to earn a livelihood. <eos/><bos/>The remaining defendants would be enjoined from using confidential information to compete with Edgetch and enjoined from competing with Edgetch in association with or on behalf of Jesse, Extreme or Gasense.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3ec45818e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">78</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Id3e874f08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00018" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1918039825" w-pub-number="0004707" w-pinpoint-page="356" ID="I2c9d3d008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Canada Bonded Attorney and Legal Directory Ltd. v. Leonard-Parmiter Ltd.</ital> (1918), 42 D.L.R. 342 at p. 356, 42 O.L.R. 141 (S.C.A.D.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3e874f18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>See also <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00019" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1887305700" w-pub-number="0004910" ID="I2c9d64108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Helmore v. Smith</ital> (1886), 35 Ch. D. 449 (C.A.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3e874f28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>See, for example, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00020" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1974147187" w-pub-number="0005652" ID="I2c9d8b208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Dominion Al-Chrome Corp. v. Stoll</ital> (1974), 14 C.P.R. (2d) 174 (Ont. H.C.J.)</cite.query>, and the comments in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00021" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1984185977" w-pub-number="0005505" ID="I2c9d8b228e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesta Manufacturing Ltd. v. Babey</ital> (1984), 48 O.R. (2d) 94, 29</cite.query> B.L.R. 36 (H.C.J.).<eos/><bos/> Historically, the test was also followed by the English courts: see, for example, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00022" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1895411784" w-pub-number="0003898" ID="I2c9d8b248e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Robb v. Green</ital>, [1895] 2 Q.B. 315 (C.A.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00023" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1972022562" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I2c9d8b268e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Roberts v. Elwells Engineers Ltd.</ital>, [1972] 2 All E.R. 890 (C.A.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3e874f38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>4</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00024" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1977148370" w-pub-number="0005150" w-pinpoint-page="113" ID="I2c9dd9408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgar T. Alberts Ltd. v. Mountjoy</ital> (1977), 79 D.L.R. (3d) 108, at p. 113, 16 O.R. (2d) 682 (H.C.J.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3e874f48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>5</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00025" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2006204149" w-pub-number="0007214" ID="I2c9eeab08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Axiom Services Ltd. v. Weigert</ital> (2005), 2 B.L.R. (4th) 185 (B.C.S.C.)</cite.query> at paras. 51-52, judgment on costs <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00026" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2006541852" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I2c9eeab28e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">139 A.C.W.S. (3d) 235 (B.C.S.C.)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>See also <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00027" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1999482256" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I2c9eeab48e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Barton Insurance Brokers Ltd. v. Irwin</ital> (1999), 170 D.L.R. (4th) 69 (B.C.C.A.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00028" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2001360648" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I2c9eeab68e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Golden Images Management Ltd. v. Champers Enterprises Ltd.</ital> (2001), 105 A.C.W.S. (3d) 1059 (B.C.S.C.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00029" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2011192292" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I2c9eeab98e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>RBC Dominion Securities Inc. v. Merrill Lynch Canada Inc.</ital></cite.query> (2003), 55 C.C.E.L. (3d) 179 (B.C.S.C.), supp. reasons 55 C.C.E.L. (3d) 208 (B.C.S.C.), <case.history>appeal allowed in part</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00030" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2011192292" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I2c9eeaba8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">275 D.L.R. (4th) 385 (B.C.C.A.)</cite.query>, <case.history>appeal allowed in part</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00031" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017227608" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I2c9eeabc8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">298 D.L.R. (4th) 1 (S.C.C.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3e89c008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>6</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>See for example, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00032" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2000541558" w-pub-number="0005628" ID="I2c9f5fe08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sheehan and Rosie Ltd. v. Northwood</ital> (2000), 2000 C.L.L.C. ¶ 210-037, [2000] O.J. No. 716 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3e89c018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>7</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00033" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1989313313" w-pub-number="0005505" w-pinpoint-page="34" ID="I2c9fd5108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Quantum Management Services Ltd. v. Hann</ital> (1989), 69 O.R. (2d) 26 at p. 34, 43</cite.query> B.L.R. 93 (H.C.J.), <case.history>affd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00034" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1992370529" w-pub-number="0005506" ID="I2c9fd5128e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">11 O.R. (3d) 639, 45 C.P.R. (3d) 498 (C.A.)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>See also <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00035" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1984192374" w-pub-number="0004655" w-pinpoint-page="152" ID="I2c9fd5158e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Monarch Messenger Services Ltd. v. Houlding</ital> (1984), 56 A.R. 147 at p. 152, 5</cite.query> C.C.E.L. 219 (Q.B.), affd 13 C.C.E.L. xxxvi (Alta. C.A.).<eos/><bos/> However, see <ital>R.T. Investment Counsel Inc. v. Werry</ital> (1999) 46 B.L.R. (2d) 66 (B.C.S.C.) where, due to the absence of a fiduciary duty or any improper activity, it was held that the defendants could contact clients whose names they recalled from memory. <eos/><bos/>See also <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00036" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2020159714" w-pub-number="0003986" ID="I2c9fd5178e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Soost v. Merrill Lynch Canada Inc.</ital>, [2010] 3 W.W.R. 94, 2009 ABQB 591</cite.query>, <case.history>revd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00037" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2022888984" w-pub-number="0006455" ID="I2c9fd51a8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2010 ABCA 251</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00038" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2023883812" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I2c9fd51c8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2010 CarswellAlta 2286</cite.query>, leave to appeal refused <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00039" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2025089168" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I2c9fd51e8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2011 CarswellAlta 582</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3e89c028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>8</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00040" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2025850996" w-pub-number="0006455" ID="I2ca023308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Globex Foreign Exchange Corp. v. Kelcher</ital>, 2011 ABCA 240</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3e89c038e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>9</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00041" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2011192292" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I2ca071508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>RBC Dominion Securities Inc. v. Merrill Lynch Canada Inc.</ital> (2007), 275 D.L.R. (4th) 385 (B.C.C.A.)</cite.query>, at paras. 79-84. <eos/><bos/>Note that this case was successfully appealed to the Supreme Court of Canada as to the damages awarded: <case.history>appeal allowed in part</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00042" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017227608" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I2ca071528e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">298 D.L.R. (4th) 1 (S.C.C.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3e89c048e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>10</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>Valley First Financial Services Ltd. v. Trach</ital> (2004), 30 B.C.L.R. (4th) 73 (C.A.), at para. 72.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3e89c058e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>11</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00043" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2030699569" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2ca182c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Eagle Professional Resources Inc. v. MacMullin</ital>, 2013 CarswellOnt 7745, 2013 ONSC 2501</cite.query>, <case.history>affirmed</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00044" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2031807121" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2ca182c38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2013 CarswellOnt 14173, 2013 ONCA 639</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00045" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2025787341" w-pub-number="0005481" ID="I2ca182c68e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Exfo inc. c. Réseaux Accedian inc. (Duplessis)</ital>, 2011 CarswellQue 7760, 2011 QCCS 3767</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00046" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2030930033" w-pub-number="0006821" ID="I2ca182c98e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Whitmar Publications Ltd. v. Gamage &amp; Ors</ital>, [2013] EWHC 1881 (Ch. D.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3e8c3108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>12</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00047" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047509400" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I2ca1d0e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>North Island Insultech (2017) Ltd. v. Cain</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 240, 2019 BCSC 159</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3e8c3118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>13</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00048" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047509400" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I2ca1f7f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>North Island Insultech (2017) Ltd. v. Cain</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 240, 2019 BCSC 159</cite.query>, at paras. 2-4.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3e8c3128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>14</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00049" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047509400" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I2ca246108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>North Island Insultech (2017) Ltd. v. Cain</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 240, 2019 BCSC 159</cite.query>, at paras. 5 and 7.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3e8c3138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>15</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00050" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047509400" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I2ca26d208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>North Island Insultech (2017) Ltd. v. Cain</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 240, 2019 BCSC 159, at para. 9</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3e8c3148e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>16</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00051" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047509400" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I2ca294308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>North Island Insultech (2017) Ltd. v. Cain</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 240, 2019 BCSC 159</cite.query>, at paras. 11-12.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3e8c3158e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>17</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00052" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047509400" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I2ca2bb408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>North Island Insultech (2017) Ltd. v. Cain</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 240, 2019 BCSC 159</cite.query>, at paras. 14-16.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3e8c3168e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>18</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00053" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2ca2e2508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3e8ea208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>19</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00054" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2ca309608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055</cite.query>, at paras. 1-2.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3e8ea218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>20</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00055" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2ca330708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055</cite.query>, at paras. 8-9.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3e8ea228e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>21</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00056" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2ca357808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055, at para. 10</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3e8ea238e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>22</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00057" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2ca3a5a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055</cite.query>, at paras. 11-13.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3eabee08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>23</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00058" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2ca3ccb08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055</cite.query>, at paras. 14-15.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3eabee18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>24</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00059" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2ca3f3c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055, at para. 16</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3eae5f08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>25</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00060" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2ca41ad08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055, at para. 17</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3eae5f18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>26</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00061" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2ca441e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055, at para. 19</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3eae5f28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>27</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00062" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2ca468f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055</cite.query>, at paras. 3-6.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3eae5f38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>28</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00063" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2ca490008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055, at para. 21</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3eae5f48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>29</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00064" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2ca4b7108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055</cite.query>, at paras. 27-30.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3eae5f58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>30</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00065" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2ca4de208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055</cite.query>, at paras. 31-32.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3eb0d008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>31</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00066" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2ca52c408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055, at para. 35</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3eb0d018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>32</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00067" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2ca553508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al.</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055</cite.query>, at paras. 37 and 39-40.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3eb0d028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>33</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00068" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048642413" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I2ca57a608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 1906, 2019 BCSC 1068</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3eb0d038e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>34</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00069" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048642413" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I2ca5a1708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 1906, 2019 BCSC 1068</cite.query>, at paras. 1-4.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3eb0d048e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>35</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00070" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048642413" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I2ca5ef908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 1906, 2019 BCSC 1068</cite.query>, at paras. 6-7.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3eb34108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>36</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00071" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048642413" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I2ca616a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 1906, 2019 BCSC 1068</cite.query>, at paras. 8-10.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3eb34118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>37</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00072" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048642413" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I2ca63db08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 1906, 2019 BCSC 1068, at para. 21</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3eb34128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>38</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00073" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048642413" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I2ca664c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 1906, 2019 BCSC 1068, at para. 22</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3eb34138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>39</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00074" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048642413" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I2ca68bd08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 1906, 2019 BCSC 1068</cite.query>, at paras. 23-24.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3eb34148e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>40</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00075" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048642413" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I2ca6b2e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 1906, 2019 BCSC 1068, at para. 25</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3eb34158e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>41</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00076" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048642413" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I2ca6d9f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 1906, 2019 BCSC 1068, at para. 26</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3eb34168e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>42</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00077" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048642413" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I2ca701008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 1906, 2019 BCSC 1068, at para. 27</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3eb5b208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>43</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00078" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048642413" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I2ca728108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 1906, 2019 BCSC 1068</cite.query>, at paras. 38-43.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3eb5b218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>44</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00079" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048642413" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I2ca74f208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 1906, 2019 BCSC 1068, at para. 44</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3eb5b228e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>45</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00080" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048642413" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I2ca776308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Capital Direct Lending Corp. v. Blanchette</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 1906, 2019 BCSC 1068</cite.query>, at paras. 45-49, 52, and 54.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3eb5b238e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>46</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00081" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2045449429" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2ca79d408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Shaver-Kudell Manufacturing Inc. v. Knight Manufacturing Inc.</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 14599, 2018 ONSC 5206</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00082" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2046054502" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2ca79d438e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2018 CarswellOnt 19235, 2018 ONSC 6895</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3eb5b248e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>47</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00083" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2045449429" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2ca7c4508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Shaver-Kudell Manufacturing Inc. v. Knight Manufacturing Inc.</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 14599, 2018 ONSC 5206</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00084" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2046054502" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2ca7c4538e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2018 CarswellOnt 19235, 2018 ONSC 6895, at para. 2</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3eb5b258e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>48</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00085" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2045449429" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2ca812708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Shaver-Kudell Manufacturing Inc. v. Knight Manufacturing Inc.</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 14599, 2018 ONSC 5206</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00086" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2046054502" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2ca812738e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2018 CarswellOnt 19235, 2018 ONSC 6895</cite.query>, at paras. 9 and 13.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3eb82308e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>49</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00087" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2045449429" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2ca839808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Shaver-Kudell Manufacturing Inc. v. Knight Manufacturing Inc.</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 14599, 2018 ONSC 5206</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00088" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2046054502" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2ca839838e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2018 CarswellOnt 19235, 2018 ONSC 6895</cite.query>, at paras. 38-39.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3eb82318e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>50</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00089" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2045449429" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2ca887a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Shaver-Kudell Manufacturing Inc. v. Knight Manufacturing Inc.</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 14599, 2018 ONSC 5206</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00090" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2046054502" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2ca887a38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2018 CarswellOnt 19235, 2018 ONSC 6895, at para. 78</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3eb82328e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>51</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00091" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2045449429" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2ca8aeb08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Shaver-Kudell Manufacturing Inc. v. Knight Manufacturing Inc.</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 14599, 2018 ONSC 5206</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00092" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2046054502" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2ca8aeb38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2018 CarswellOnt 19235, 2018 ONSC 6895</cite.query>, at paras. 88-89.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3eba9408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>52</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00093" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2045449429" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2ca8fcd08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Shaver-Kudell Manufacturing Inc. v. Knight Manufacturing Inc.</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 14599, 2018 ONSC 5206</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00094" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2046054502" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2ca8fcd38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2018 CarswellOnt 19235, 2018 ONSC 6895</cite.query>, at paras. 90-97.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3eba9418e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>53</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00095" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2045449429" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2ca923e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Shaver-Kudell Manufacturing Inc. v. Knight Manufacturing Inc.</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 14599, 2018 ONSC 5206</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00096" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2046054502" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2ca923e38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2018 CarswellOnt 19235, 2018 ONSC 6895</cite.query>, at paras. 100 and 103.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3eba9428e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>54</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00097" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2045161580" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2ca972008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>OIBC v. KO</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 12412, 2018 ONSC 4612</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3eba9438e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>55</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00098" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2045161580" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2ca972038e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>OIBC v. KO</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 12412, 2018 ONSC 4612, at para. 1</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3eba9448e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>56</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00099" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2045161580" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2ca999108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>OIBC v. KO</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 12412, 2018 ONSC 4612, at para. 13</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3eba9458e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>57</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00100" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2045161580" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2ca9c0208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>OIBC v. KO</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 12412, 2018 ONSC 4612</cite.query>, at paras. 19-26.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3eba9468e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>58</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00101" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2045161580" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2ca9e7308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>OIBC v. KO</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 12412, 2018 ONSC 4612, at para. 28</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3ebd0508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>59</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00102" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040845729" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2caa0e408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2158124 Ontario Inc. v. Pitton</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 1023, 2017 ONSC 411</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3ebd0518e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>60</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00103" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040845729" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2caa35508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2158124 Ontario Inc. v. Pitton</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 1023, 2017 ONSC 411</cite.query>, at paras. 2-8, and 13.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3ebd0528e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>61</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00104" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040845729" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2caa5c608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2158124 Ontario Inc. v. Pitton</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 1023, 2017 ONSC 411, at para. 20</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3ebd0538e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>62</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00105" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040845729" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2caa83708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2158124 Ontario Inc. v. Pitton</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 1023, 2017 ONSC 411, at para. 24</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3ebd0548e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>63</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00106" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040845729" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2caaaa808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2158124 Ontario Inc. v. Pitton</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 1023, 2017 ONSC 411</cite.query>, at paras. 26-28.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3ebd0558e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>64</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00107" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040845729" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2caad1908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2158124 Ontario Inc. v. Pitton</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 1023, 2017 ONSC 411, at para. 43</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3ebf7608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>65</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00108" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040845729" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2caaf8a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2158124 Ontario Inc. v. Pitton</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 1023, 2017 ONSC 411, at para. 44</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3ebf7618e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>66</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00109" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040515325" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2cab1fb08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgetch HVAC Services Ltd. v. Ubhi</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 19341, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 103, 2016 ONSC 7564 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00110" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040956173" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2cab1fb48e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellOnt 1753, 275 A.C.W.S. (3d) 706, 2017 ONSC 1004 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3ebf7628e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>67</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00111" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040515325" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2cab6dd08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgetch HVAC Services Ltd. v. Ubhi</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 19341, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 103, 2016 ONSC 7564 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00112" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040956173" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2cab6dd48e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellOnt 1753, 275 A.C.W.S. (3d) 706, 2017 ONSC 1004 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 1-6.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3ebf7638e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>68</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00113" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040515325" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2cab94e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgetch HVAC Services Ltd. v. Ubhi</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 19341, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 103, 2016 ONSC 7564 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00114" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040956173" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2cab94e48e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellOnt 1753, 275 A.C.W.S. (3d) 706, 2017 ONSC 1004 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at para. 7.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3ebf7648e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>69</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00115" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040515325" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2cabe3008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgetch HVAC Services Ltd. v. Ubhi</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 19341, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 103, 2016 ONSC 7564 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00116" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040956173" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2cabe3048e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellOnt 1753, 275 A.C.W.S. (3d) 706, 2017 ONSC 1004 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 9-10.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3ebf7658e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>70</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00117" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040515325" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2cac0a108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgetch HVAC Services Ltd. v. Ubhi</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 19341, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 103, 2016 ONSC 7564 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00118" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040956173" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2cac0a148e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellOnt 1753, 275 A.C.W.S. (3d) 706, 2017 ONSC 1004 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 14-16.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3ec1e708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>71</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00119" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040515325" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2cac58308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgetch HVAC Services Ltd. v. Ubhi</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 19341, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 103, 2016 ONSC 7564 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00120" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040956173" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2cac58348e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellOnt 1753, 275 A.C.W.S. (3d) 706, 2017 ONSC 1004 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at para. 28.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3ec1e718e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>72</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00121" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040515325" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2cac7f408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgetch HVAC Services Ltd. v. Ubhi</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 19341, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 103, 2016 ONSC 7564 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00122" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040956173" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2cac7f448e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellOnt 1753, 275 A.C.W.S. (3d) 706, 2017 ONSC 1004 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 30-31, and 33.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3ec1e728e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>73</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00123" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040515325" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2caccd608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgetch HVAC Services Ltd. v. Ubhi</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 19341, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 103, 2016 ONSC 7564 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00124" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040956173" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2caccd648e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellOnt 1753, 275 A.C.W.S. (3d) 706, 2017 ONSC 1004 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at para. 34.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3ec1e738e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>74</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00125" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040515325" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2cad1b808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgetch HVAC Services Ltd. v. Ubhi</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 19341, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 103, 2016 ONSC 7564 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00126" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040956173" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2cad1b848e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellOnt 1753, 275 A.C.W.S. (3d) 706, 2017 ONSC 1004 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at para. 35.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3ec1e748e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>75</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00127" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040515325" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2cad42908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgetch HVAC Services Ltd. v. Ubhi</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 19341, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 103, 2016 ONSC 7564 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00128" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040956173" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2cad42948e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellOnt 1753, 275 A.C.W.S. (3d) 706, 2017 ONSC 1004 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 36, 38, and 40.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3ec1e758e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>76</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00129" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040515325" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2cad90b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgetch HVAC Services Ltd. v. Ubhi</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 19341, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 103, 2016 ONSC 7564 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00130" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040956173" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2cad90b48e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellOnt 1753, 275 A.C.W.S. (3d) 706, 2017 ONSC 1004 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 43-45.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3ec45808e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>77</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00131" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040515325" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2cadb7c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgetch HVAC Services Ltd. v. Ubhi</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 19341, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 103, 2016 ONSC 7564 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00132" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040956173" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2cadb7c48e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellOnt 1753, 275 A.C.W.S. (3d) 706, 2017 ONSC 1004 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 46 and 50.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3ec45818e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>78</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00133" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040515325" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2cae05e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgetch HVAC Services Ltd. v. Ubhi</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 19341, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 103, 2016 ONSC 7564 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175867" w-seq-number="00134" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040956173" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2cae05e48e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellOnt 1753, 275 A.C.W.S. (3d) 706, 2017 ONSC 1004 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at para. 51.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 4:13<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
