<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 7:6<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I56d26460411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>7.</label.designator><headtext>Remedies for Breach of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I56dbb330411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>II.</label.designator><headtext>Equitable Relief</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I56dc0150411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>A.</label.designator><headtext>Interim and Interlocutory Injunctions</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f722816ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>7:6.</label.designator><headtext>Irreparable Harm</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Irreparable harm has been defined as injury which cannot be adequately compensated in damages.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id86f35908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>] Most successful injunction cases involve business secrets which, if used or disclosed, would result in the loss of a competitive business advantage which would be impossible to measure for purposes of assessing damages.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id86f35918e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>] In <ital>Ovation Gifts and Greetings Inc. v. Raiskums</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id86f35928e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">3</footnote.reference>] a clause stating that the defendant acknowledged that damages might not be an adequate remedy to compensate was sufficient to establish irreparable harm. <eos/><bos/>However, <ital>Jet Print Inc. v. Cohen</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id86f5ca08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">4</footnote.reference>] confirms that an “irreparable harm” clause by itself will not lead a court to grant an injunction.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In considering irreparable harm, some courts have rephrased the applicable question:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>Where the alleged harm involves damages from a departing employee in competition with his former employer, the courts have recognized that the employer generally cannot be adequately compensated in damages because it is difficult to know or prove the impact of the conduct of the employee. <eos/><bos/>In such situations, the irreparable harm test may be rephrased by asking the question: <begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>“Is it just to leave the [employer] to its remedy of damages in the circumstances?”<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0001"/> This rephrased test was first articulated by Lord Justice Sachs in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1968017732" w-pub-number="0004891" w-pinpoint-page="369" ID="I693c09808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Evans Marshall &amp; Co. v. Bertola S.A.</ital>, [1973] 1 W.L.R. 349 at 369</cite.query> and has been referred to approvingly in a number of Ontario decisions, including <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1977149578" w-pub-number="0005505" ID="I693c09838e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Yule Inc. v. Atlantic Pizza Delight Franchise (1968) Ltd.</cite.query> et al.</ital> (1977), <cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1977149578" w-pub-number="0005505" w-pinpoint-page="509" ID="I693c09848e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">17 O.R. (2d) 505 at 509 (Div. Ct.)</cite.query>.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0002"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id86f5ca18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">5</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Irreparable harm may also be established, in the case of smaller, more vulnerable businesses, as a result of improper acts by competitors.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id86f5ca28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">6</footnote.reference>] In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1968018312" w-pub-number="0004831" ID="I693cccd18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Coco v. A.N. Clark (Engineers)</cite.query> Ltd.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id86f5ca38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">7</footnote.reference>] Megarry J. held that:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0003"/>If the duty is a duty not to use the information without consent, then it may be the proper subject of an injunction restraining its use, even if there is an offer to pay a reasonable sum for the use. <eos/><bos/>If, on the other hand, the duty is merely a duty not to use the information without paying a reasonable sum for it, then no such injunction should be granted.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0003"/></paratext></para></display.quote><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>At issue in <ital>2158124 Ontario Inc. v. Pitton</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id86f5ca48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">8</footnote.reference>] was whether Pitton had breached his non-solicitation and confidentiality obligations under an employment agreement. <eos/><bos/>StoneRidge carried on business as an insurance brokerage. <eos/><bos/>Glenny carried on business as an insurance brokerage. <eos/><bos/>It was a family-run business whose principals included Brian and Scott. <eos/><bos/>Pitton was a long-time family friend of the principals of Glenny. <eos/><bos/>Pitton was a licensed insurance broker. <eos/><bos/>Up to April 2011, Pitton was employed as a broker with Brokerlink managing a book of business consisting of commercial and personal clients. <eos/><bos/>Pitton approached StoneRidge&apos;s principal Puccini, advising that he wished to leave Brokerlink to join StoneRidge. <eos/><bos/>Pitton proposed that StoneRidge approach Brokerlink with an offer to purchase the book of business managed by him so that he could commence his StoneRidge employment with a ready client base. <eos/><bos/>Puccini eventually purchased the book of business from Brokerlink. <eos/><bos/>The book of business was assigned to StoneRidge. <eos/><bos/>Pitton was hired by StoneRidge as a senior account executive managing the Brokerlink book of business. <eos/><bos/>Pitton signed an Employment Agreement and was employed by StoneRidge until his abrupt resignation. <eos/><bos/>Without prior notice, Pitton delivered a letter of resignation and advised Puccini that he had accepted a position as a broker with Glenny, now operating under the name Erion. <eos/><bos/>Unbeknownst to Puccini or to anyone else at StoneRidge, Pitton began to contact StoneRidge clients to advise that he was leaving. <eos/><bos/>Puccini became aware of the solicitation because StoneRidge was contacted subsequently by several clients requesting clarification of Pitton&apos;s situation.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id86f5ca58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">9</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Pitton&apos;s book of business at the time of termination consisted of 183 commercial client lines and 92 personal client lines. <eos/><bos/>The defendants alleged that Pitton sent an email to a small selection of his former clients. <eos/><bos/>Most of the clients who received the email had followed Pitton from Brokerlink and included close personal friends and family, the vast majority of whom resulted from relationships that pre-dated his employment with the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>The defendants alleged that Pitton restricted the email to 50 individuals and had only spoken to approximately 35 former clients. <eos/><bos/>The defendants argued that the purpose of the email was not to be a solicitation of the plaintiff&apos;s clients.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id86f83b08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">10</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>There was no dispute that a brokerage&apos;s primary asset is its customer base, including names, addresses, contact information, occupation, business and insurance requirements, information that would be extremely beneficial to another brokerage.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id86f83b18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">11</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Goodman observed that several things flowing from the email clearly indicated a solicitation of business. <eos/><bos/>The email from Pitton was sent two days before Puccini&apos;s discussion with Scott regarding a potential purchase of the book of business and his confirmation that the Agreement would be honoured. <eos/><bos/>The email was sent on a Saturday, indicating that Pitton was losing no time in approaching certain of StoneRidge&apos;s clients. <eos/><bos/>Before even apparently commencing his new employment, Pitton had a Glenny email address, office address and telephone number. <eos/><bos/>StoneRidge was in touch with most clients serviced by Pitton and was advised by almost all of them that they had been contacted by Pitton either by email, letter or telephone call. <eos/><bos/>Justice Goodman was satisfied that Pitton knew who his StoneRidge clients were, had their contact information on his personal cell phone, was aware of the products they had purchased, the type of insurance coverage they had and general knowledge of when client policy renewals came due. <eos/><bos/>It was somewhat self-serving to justify this conduct by claiming that certain clients would have followed Pitton in any event. <eos/><bos/>The email went far beyond simply advising clients that Pitton had left StoneRidge. <eos/><bos/>The email referenced “my clients” and clearly stated that Pitton would provide <begin.quote ID="QT_0005"/>“the best service at competitive pricing at Erion…”<end.quote refid="QT_0005"/>. <eos/><bos/>He opined that his position at Glenny as operations manager would have a <begin.quote ID="QT_0004"/>“positive effect on client relations and insurance options”<end.quote refid="QT_0004"/>. <eos/><bos/>Finally, he stated that he hoped <begin.quote ID="QT_0006"/>“to continue working with you in the future”<end.quote refid="QT_0006"/>. <eos/><bos/>Justice Goodman concluded that Pitton solicited former clients of StoneRidge immediately after his resignation from the plaintiff&apos;s business.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id86f83b28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">12</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>StoneRidge&apos;s evidence in support of irreparable harm in relation to the measure of damages regarding the solicitation of clients was less than compelling. <eos/><bos/>If damages would be an adequate remedy and the defendants would be in a financial position to pay them, no interlocutory injunction should normally be granted, no matter how strong a plaintiff&apos;s claim appears to be. <eos/><bos/>Even where a plaintiff demonstrates that damages might be difficult to ascertain, the moving party will not have discharged their onus of proving irreparable loss and that damages would not be an adequate remedy. <eos/><bos/>While the assessment of the measure of damages could not be readily ascertained at this stage that did not mean to say that it could not be so quantified at trial. <eos/><bos/>In this case, a finite number of clients was being considered and the value of the business lost, if any, was quantifiable. <eos/><bos/>Even if there was a loss of a customer base or business, Justice Goodman was persuaded that such damages could be ascertained and compensated with an award of monetary damages. <eos/><bos/>The Agreement provided that if a client chose to freely seek out Pitton and obtain his services, the provision required a fee of two times annual commissions to be paid to StoneRidge. <eos/><bos/>If Pitton was found to have breached enforceable provisions of his Agreement with the plaintiff, their entitlement to damages would likely be determined by applying a multiple of the annual commission for each client solicited or serviced. <eos/><bos/>Justice Goodman was persuaded that damages were not only ascertainable, but were presumed and, to a degree, quantified by virtue of the language found in the Agreement, the nature of the commissions along with the renewal processes of client business. <eos/><bos/>On this specific component of non-solicitation, the plaintiff failed in its onus to satisfy the irreparable harm factor.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id86f83b38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">13</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>With respect to the issue of the alleged misuse of confidential business and personal information, the preponderance of the jurisprudence provides that irreparable harm is presumed. <eos/><bos/>The Agreement between Pitton and the plaintiff did not define “confidential information”.<eos/><bos/> There was some reference in the Agreement to customers&apos; names and addresses. <eos/><bos/>Justice Goodman disagreed with the defendants&apos; assertions that the scope or description of this information as framed in the Agreement was not proprietary, or not highly sensitive and would otherwise be available to Pitton. <eos/><bos/>The Agreement also referred to the plaintiff&apos;s customers <begin.quote ID="QT_0007"/>“needs and preferences, their cycles or other particular business requirements”<end.quote refid="QT_0007"/> as constituting part of the goodwill of the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>While there was no direct evidence that Pitton had misused any information about customer needs, preferences, cycles or other business requirements, Justice Goodman was able to draw a reasonable inference that such information was available and had been or may be employed. <eos/><bos/>With respect to the assessment of damages from the availability or use of any confidential or private information for competitive advantage and pricing, loss of market share, impairment to goodwill or to solicit new clients, the nature of these damages goes beyond lost sales commissions and may not be readily quantifiable at trial. <eos/><bos/>Premised on these elements, the probability of irreparable harm from the improper use of confidential or private information was established.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id86f83b48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">14</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>2298679 <cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I694a61618e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc.</cite.query> et al</ital>.,[<footnote.reference refid="Id86f83b58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">15</footnote.reference>] the Plaintiff 229 moved, without notice, for an <ital>Anton Piller</ital> Order to search and seize electronic devices from the headquarters of the Defendant Northern Homecare and from the residence of the Defendant Goldkind, who was one of the principals of Northern Homecare. <eos/><bos/>Aurum Property also requested an injunction restraining Northern Homecare, Goldkind and the other Defendants, prohibiting them from possessing or transmitting Aurum&apos;s confidential customer information in any form or through any medium whatsoever. <eos/><bos/>Justice Perell dismissed the motion for an <ital>Anton Pillar</ital> Order, and granted an interim injunction and mandatory order that was to terminate ten days after the release of the Reasons for Decision.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id86f83b68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">16</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Aurum was an industry leader in commercial window cleaning and property maintenance servicing government buildings, commercial high-rise buildings, condominium towers, hotels and hospitals across North America. <eos/><bos/>It also serviced residences and had a customer list of residential customers and leads numbering 35,000 contacts. <eos/><bos/>Aurum maintains a customer list that included: customer names, customer addresses, customer email addresses and details of past services including dates and prices.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id86faac08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">17</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Northern Homecare&apos;s executive included Goldkind and Goldman. <eos/><bos/>Goldkind was the CEO and Goldman was the COO. <eos/><bos/>Northern Homecare carried on a residential window cleaning and property maintenance business.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id86faac18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">18</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Arous, Edward, and Hyde were former employees of Aurum. <eos/><bos/>Arous was employed as field business development representative from April 1, 2018 to July 6, 2018, when his employment was terminated. <eos/><bos/>Edwards was first employed as a field business development representative and was promoted to outbound business development representative. <eos/><bos/>He was employed from April 1, 2018 to August 2, 2018, when his employment was terminated. <eos/><bos/>Hyde was employed as a field business manager from May 1, 2017 to August 25, 2018 when he was terminated. <eos/><bos/>Arous, Edward, and Hyde signed employment agreements. <eos/><bos/>The agreements contained the confidentiality and non-disclosure provisions. <eos/><bos/>During their employment, Arous, Edward, and Hyde had access to Aurum&apos;s residential customer lists.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id86faac28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">19</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Although Aurum was not aware of it at the time: (a) after Arous was terminated, he logged into Aurum&apos;s management software, which contains Aurum&apos;s customer list, on six occasions; (b) after Edwards was terminated, he logged into Aurum&apos;s management software twice on two occasions; and (c) after Hyde was terminated he logged into Aurum&apos;s management software on at least thirty occasions. <eos/><bos/>Aurum did not know: (a) the extent of information that was obtained by Arous, Edward, and Hyde; (b) how the information was used; and (c) with whom the information was shared. <eos/><bos/>Aurum conceded that the extent of the confidential information allegedly misappropriated by the Defendants would be an important facet of Aurum&apos;s damages claim.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id86faac38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">20</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Up until eight months after it had terminated the employment of Arous, Edward, and Hyde, Aurum had no knowledge of these intrusions on its computer system. <eos/><bos/>In March and April 2019, however, there were a series of events that prompted Aurum to investigate: a. Customers DD, OA, ED, and AS cancelled appointments because they had already been contacted by persons presenting themselves as being Aurum. <eos/><bos/>Based on the information provided by these customers; b. Customer ND advised Arum that she had been contacted by persons presenting themselves as being Aurum. <eos/><bos/>She did not cancel her contract with Aurum. <eos/><bos/>Aurum inferred that Northern Homecare was using information provided by Arous, Edward, and Hyde to contact ND. c. Customer DS advised Aurum that he had been contacted by Goldkind who misrepresented himself as representing a reorganized Aurum. <eos/><bos/>Goldkind disparaged Arum as it had formerly existed. <eos/><bos/>DS advised Aurum of the contact. <eos/><bos/>Goldkind was lying and Aurum inferred that the wrongdoing of Goldkind was a spinoff of Arous, Edward, and Hydes&apos; disclosing confidential information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id86faac48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">21</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Aurum suspected but did not actually know that Arous, Edward, and Hyde provided confidential information to Northern Homecare because Aurum customers reported that when solicited by Northern Homecare, the Northern Homecare representative had knowledge of past services provided to the customer.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id86faac58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">22</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>It was not clear, however, what the precise relationship or connection was between Northern Homecare and the three former employees, who might have a connection as employees, independent contractors, dependent contractors, sales agents, or intermediators.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id86faac68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">23</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Perell concluded that while there appeared to have been wrongdoing, most likely by Goldkind and Goldman, it was not clear whether the harm they caused was trivial or substantial. <eos/><bos/>It appeared that it was only an inference that the three former employees stole the whole data base of customer information. <eos/><bos/>However, it was not clear whether the three former employees did anything more than inform Northern Homecare of a few contacts and that Northern Homecare used those few contacts to compete for business in a wrongful way when they should and could have competed for the customers in a lawful way. <eos/><bos/>On the other hand, it was not known whether more than a few of Aurum&apos;s customers were contacted and whether Northern Homecare was more than a minor nuisance and a major threat to Aurum&apos;s residential business. <eos/><bos/>In any event, at this juncture, there was no evidence to suggest that Northern Homecare or Goldkind had Aurum&apos;s customer list on its computers or that there was reason to believe that they would destroy that evidence.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id86fd1d08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">24</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Perell noted that under their employment contracts, Arous, Edward, and Hydes&apos; obligations with respect to Confidential Information did not apply to information that they could demonstrate was generally available to or known by the public other than as a result of improper disclosure to them. <eos/><bos/>At this juncture, it was impossible to say that they had no defence to a breach of contract claim for the conduct of passing on information to Northern Homecare if that was what they did.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id86fd1d18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">25</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Aurum asserted that it had and would suffer irreparable harm because of the wrongful activities of the Defendants and it submitted that its ability to sell its residential branch had been diminished. <eos/><bos/>However, there was no evidence about Aurum&apos;s actual plans for its residential branch. <eos/><bos/>Thus, the situation with respect to irreparable harm was that at this juncture Aurum had established only a significant possibility of harm from a breach of confidence or a breach of contract. <eos/><bos/>In this regard, it was noted that at the time of the <ital>ex parte</ital> injunction motion, Aurum had only discovered the alleged wrongdoing less than a month before. <eos/><bos/>Justice Perell observed that it was a close call on irreparable harm, but nevertheless concluded that for the purposes of an interim, ten-day, injunction that Aurum had suffered irreparable harm and that the balance of convenience favours granting an interim injunction.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id86fd1d28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">26</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>An application for an interlocutory injunction preventing the Defendants from holding bull riding events in July 2019 and 2020 was dismissed in <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I6953b0318e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos;</cite.query> Inc.</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id86fd1d38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">27</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Plaintiffs owned and operated the Ranchman&apos;s, a restaurant, bar, cookhouse and dancehall. <eos/><bos/>Each year in early July the Plaintiffs host, at the Ranchman&apos;s, a successful event known as the Ranchman&apos;s Rodeo. <eos/><bos/>The Ranchman&apos;s Rodeo was a festival event which included high-quality professional bull riding taking place in a temporary arena adjacent to the Ranchman&apos;s building. <eos/><bos/>The Defendant BBI began producing the bull riding event for Ranchman&apos;s in 2000, and did so annually through July 2018. <eos/><bos/>Although the Snyders produced a bullbustin&apos; event for Ranchman&apos;s for many years, they were not contractually committed to produce them in future. <eos/><bos/>BBI and Ranchman&apos;s did not reach contractual terms for the 2019 Stampede season and the Snyder Defendants decided to produce a bull riding event elsewhere.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id86fd1d48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">28</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Plaintiffs advanced numerous claims in support of the injunctions including breach of duty of confidence relating to Ranchman&apos;s information and know-how, and breach of fiduciary duty by Cody Snyder and Rhonda Snyder.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id86fd1d58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">29</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Plaintiffs&apos; claims on the application included a request for an order prohibiting the Defendants from using their trademarks, intellectual property and key information. <eos/><bos/>The Ranchman&apos;s intellectual property was claimed to consist of intellectual property and trade secrets including but not limited to “key information”, marketing strategies, copyrights, the Ranchman&apos;s trademarks, know-how, confidential information and instructions regarding the operation of the Ranchman&apos;s Rodeo. <eos/><bos/>There was almost no detail in Ranchman&apos;s affidavit evidence of what was contained in this generic description. <eos/><bos/>Know-how was described as Ranchman&apos;s secrets on how they successfully run their business. <eos/><bos/>The Ranchman&apos;s key information was claimed to be all data, and records relating to the customers of Ranchman&apos;s including customer lists and email lists for customers, supplier lists and other data with respect to third parties. <eos/><bos/>There was almost no detail of what was contained in this description apart from a list of past ticket buyers and sponsors including their name, contact particulars, and past bleacher assignment.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id86fd1d68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">30</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Under the new 2018 agreement, the parties agreed to a revised fee structure. <eos/><bos/>BBI was to receive a fixed fee and a fee based on a fixed percentage of net profit. <eos/><bos/>This revenue flow through was accomplished by creating and inserting a numbered Alberta company 207, equally owned by the Snyders through Snyco (as to 50%) and by business associates of Raspberry, the Plaintiff&apos;s witness, through the Plaintiff CUBI (as to 50%).<eos/><bos/> The objective, rationale, and reason for being of 207 was to provide a corporate vehicle under which costs and revenues could be calculated with respect to Ranchman&apos;s Rodeo. <eos/><bos/>On paper, 207 was to produce an entertainment function including three days of bull riding and a Dallas Smith concert, 207 was to handle ticket sales, and Ranchmans 2017 Ltd. was to handle alcohol sales and secure the parking lot on which to host the event.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id86fd1d78e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">31</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Plaintiffs learned that the Snyders had sent an email to all the bulk bleacher purchasers. <eos/><bos/>Ranchman&apos;s maintained a database containing its customer email names, contact particulars and ticket purchase information for the bull riding event. <eos/><bos/>There was no dispute that the Snyder Defendants accessed this information and used it to email the customers. <eos/><bos/>The Snyder Defendants created the website codysnyderbullbustin.com, describing their 2019 event. <eos/><bos/>This site included the statement that <begin.quote ID="QT_0008"/>“Cody Snyder has decided to move the event”<end.quote refid="QT_0008"/> and contains pictures from the 2018 event. <eos/><bos/>These pictures were focused on the action in the arena, though one was an overhead photo of the Ranchman&apos;s cookhouse and arena set up.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id86ff8e08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">32</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>On November 21, 2018 the Snyder Defendants again emailed the customers on the list. <eos/><bos/>They stated the Snyders were not producing a 2019 bull riding event at Ranchman&apos;s, and the event Ranchman&apos;s were producing was not the same event as the Snyders had produced for the last 19 years. <eos/><bos/>Further, the Snyders had decided to move their charity bullbustin&apos; to a new location and would continue to deliver to fans, sponsors and charity partners the same amazing event they were accustomed to.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id86ff8e18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">33</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Eamon observed that the matter of irreparable harm might be easily established if there were a serious issue that the Snyder&apos;s were competing, stating:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0010"/>In breach of fiduciary obligation cases, the matter of remedy may be drastically affected because <begin.quote ID="QT_0009"/>“[t]he law takes a hard line against faithless fiduciaries”<end.quote refid="QT_0009"/> and the claims may be elevated to proprietary ones even where the information used by the Snyder Defendants was publicly known or does not meet the requirements of confidential information …<end.quote refid="QT_0010"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id86ff8e28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">34</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>However, that claim had no merit. <eos/><bos/>The Snyders were entitled to pursue their livelihood by producing an event. <eos/><bos/>Absent the fiduciary breach claim, Justice Eamon was mindful that granting the judicial monopoly claimed by the Plaintiffs would probably circumvent the fundamental principle that a plaintiff is only entitled to protection against losses caused by the defendant&apos;s unlawful activity. <eos/><bos/>That requirement applies as much to claims for mis-using confidential information as others. <eos/><bos/>In this case, there were many other plausible competing causes for any loss of sales suffered by the Plaintiffs. <eos/><bos/>These included competition by the Snyders, and the Snyder&apos;s personal goodwill and longstanding reputation and relationships in professional rodeo. <eos/><bos/>There was a serious prospect that granting the injunction the Plaintiffs requested would provide the Plaintiffs much more protection than their claims warranted.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id86ff8e38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">35</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Eamon found that there was no serious issue that the Snyders were precluded from competing and no serious issue that supplier identities were secret or confidential from the Snyders. <eos/><bos/>Even if there were such claims, the evidence about challenges in finding supplies like bleachers would not demonstrate irreparable harm because (1) there was no evidence that Ranchman&apos;s had not been able to secure the necessary suppliers for its upcoming bull riding event; and (2) Ranchmans confirmed that the Ranchman&apos;s bull riding would be taking place.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id86ff8e48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">36</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Plaintiffs had demonstrated a claim for misuse of limited confidential information, mainly contact particulars for some customers not available from their records, and identity of pre-2018 customers to the extent the Snyders did not have that information available from other sources. <eos/><bos/>The claim for mis-using particulars from the list for customers known to the Snyders was a springboard claim. <eos/><bos/>The list was confidential, but the customer identities were not. <eos/><bos/>The Snyder Defendants could still contact customers if they had other records or knowledge of them, and they had the 2018 public day sheets naming the 2018 customers, as well as the 2018 public bleacher maps or the notes for the public announcements recording the bleacher assignments. <eos/><bos/>On the scale of confidential information recognized by the Courts, this information in organized list form was “nothing very special”.<eos/><bos/> It should not have taken long to call the customer, get connected to the responsible representative and make the ask. <eos/><bos/>In the meantime, the Plaintiffs were taking steps to place their product before the same customers. <eos/><bos/>The loss of sales resulting from confusion in October/November 2018 was capable of being quantified. <eos/><bos/>By early December 2018, the prospect of any additional irreparable harm was highly unlikely or at best speculative.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id86ff8e58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">37</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The claim relating to listed customers who were not otherwise known to the Snyders was not a springboard claim. <eos/><bos/>The Snyder Defendants might never have been able to contact pre-2018 customers for which they did not have any records or memory. <eos/><bos/>That would depend on their other sources of knowledge, if any. <eos/><bos/>The number of potential customers in this pre-2018 category who were named in the list was relatively small. <eos/><bos/>The evidence did not address the Snyder&apos;s knowledge of them so clearly as to eliminate a serious issue to be tried. <eos/><bos/>If there were such cases, a lost sale could be identified on the balance of probabilities and quantified. <eos/><bos/>The lost sale was not irreparable harm.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id86ff8e68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">38</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In both cases, Justice Eamon was not satisfied that a Court could not address fair and reasonable redress for lost food and beverage sales with a damages award. <eos/><bos/>This potential loss was not irreparable harm.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8701ff08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">39</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In both cases, it was also possible that each lost sale might deprive Ranchman&apos;s of the spin off effect which might add to its goodwill. <eos/><bos/>That would be difficult to quantify and compensate in damages. <eos/><bos/>However, the prospect of irreparable harm was also speculative, because there were so many variables at play on the facts: (a) It was as yet unknown whether Ranchman&apos;s would achieve historic sales levels. (b) If it did achieve those levels, it had not lost the spin off effect. (c) If it failed to achieve historic sales levels, and lost the spin off effect, a Court would need to consider the vexing question of causation of a lost sale. <eos/><bos/>It could not assume the lost sale was caused by unlawful conduct or unreasonably attribute all lost sales to unlawful conduct. (d) It would be difficult to ascertain whether lost sales resulted from the mis-use of confidential information. <eos/><bos/>Some loss of market share was probably an inevitable by-product of losing the contract due to the break-down of the business relationship. <eos/><bos/>The Snyder Defendants already had a strong position in the market due to their long history of success in professional rodeo and their Bullbustin&apos; business, and there was no merit to the contention that they could not compete with Ranchman&apos;s. <eos/><bos/>Going forward, Ranchman&apos;s would use a different bull riding producer. <eos/><bos/>That producer was also very well known in the rodeo world. <eos/><bos/>A Court would probably not be able to compare apples with apples and ascertain the causes of the lost spin off effect. (e) Consequently, granting an injunction would be arbitrary and may well provide Ranchman&apos;s undue solicitude for its nothing very special information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8701ff18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">40</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In all the circumstances, this was probably a case where the Court would have to estimate damages as best it could, based on an imperfect record. <eos/><bos/>There are many cases where the Court is faced with such a challenge.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8701ff28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">41</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>SkyCope Technologies Inc. v. Jia</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id8701ff38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">42</footnote.reference>] the Plaintiff sought an interlocutory injunction to restrain the Defendants from various forms of activity and, in particular, from making use of its confidential information. <eos/><bos/>Specifically, the Plaintiff sought to enjoin the Defendants from making use of the source codes it had developed in the area of anti-drone technology. <eos/><bos/>The individual Defendants were all persons who formally worked for the Plaintiff in various capacities and now worked for the corporate defendant.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8701ff48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">43</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The founder and Chief Executive Officer of the Plaintiff was Liu. <eos/><bos/>Liu was also the sole director and shareholder of the company. <eos/><bos/>The corporate defendant was incorporated in March 2018 by the Defendant Jia. <eos/><bos/>The corporate defendant also developed and marketed anti-drone technology. <eos/><bos/>Liu and Jia had known each other for more than a decade and had worked together at different companies. <eos/><bos/>In the first six months of 2016, Liu wanted to assemble a team of engineers and researchers to help develop a prototype for an anti-drone defence system. <eos/><bos/>One of the individuals that Liu reached out to was Jia who, in September 2016, joined the Plaintiff and became its Chief Technology Officer. <eos/><bos/>In the time period that followed, each of the other individual Defendants joined the Plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>Each of the individual Defendants signed identical employment contracts. <eos/><bos/>Each of these employment contracts had various confidentiality, non-solicitation, and non-competition clauses.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8701ff58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">44</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In December 2017, Liu and Jia had a falling out and Jia left the Plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>In early January 2018, the Defendant Pan announced that he was leaving the company. <eos/><bos/>In February 2018, both the Defendants Zhang and Zhuang left the Plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>Zhang left because the company had closed down the hardware development branch of its business in which he had been engaged.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8701ff68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">45</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In June 2018, Liu travelled to China and learned that what appeared to be the Plaintiff&apos;s technology was being marketed to consumers. <eos/><bos/>He learned that Jia was the vice president of a Chinese company that had been formed on March 9, 2018 and that was marketing anti-drone technology. <eos/><bos/>He subsequently learned that Jia had formed the corporate defendant. <eos/><bos/>Liu learned through one of the Plaintiff&apos;s software engineers that Jia had reached out to another software engineer, Zarei, to gauge his potential interest in a new job. <eos/><bos/>Zarei has filed an affidavit in the proceedings on behalf of the Plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>He has deposed that, on June 10, 2018, he met briefly with. <eos/><bos/>Jia and, for a more extended period of time, with Pan to discuss his joining their new company, the corporate defendant. <eos/><bos/>That company, he was told, was developing anti-drone technology. <eos/><bos/>Zarei was also told that the corporate defendant had shipped its first product to a customer in April 2018. <eos/><bos/>The Defendants, in their response materials, asserted that that statement was not true, but was simply puffery. <eos/><bos/>This information caused Liu, in late July 2018, to hire a private investigation firm. <eos/><bos/>The investigators were advised that the corporate defendant would be in a position to deliver an anti-drone system to them by mid-October 2018. <eos/><bos/>They thereafter exchanged several emails and, on August 30, 2018, they arranged for a demonstration of the corporate defendant&apos;s anti-drone technology. <eos/><bos/>That demonstration occurred with Pan and two other individuals who the investigators had seen at the corporate defendant&apos;s offices. <eos/><bos/>The investigators openly photographed and video-recorded aspects of the presentation and of the equipment that was being used.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id87047008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">46</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A witness for the Plaintiff explained that he took a screenshot from the video that the investigators took during the demonstration. <eos/><bos/>That screenshot revealed a portion of the source code that the corporate defendant relied on for its technology. <eos/><bos/>The witness deposed that there was virtually no possibility that two people, or groups of people, working separately, would code their entries in an identical fashion, with the same capitalization and order of letters and numerical figures.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id87047018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">47</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Plaintiff&apos;s Notice of Civil Claim alleged that each of the individual Defendants breached their respective employment contracts, that each of them was liable for a breach of confidence, and that Jia, by virtue of his senior position in the Plaintiff company, breached the fiduciary obligations that he owed to the Plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiff also alleged that the corporate defendant was liable for knowing receipt of confidential information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id87047028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">48</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In most cases, an interlocutory injunction should not be granted unless an applicant has satisfied the Court that there is doubt as to whether damages would be an adequate remedy. <eos/><bos/>Liu deposed that if the corporate defendant was able to go to market with the Plaintiff&apos;s technology, the money the Plaintiff had invested in its technology would be wasted and this might cause the Plaintiff to fold. <eos/><bos/>The Chambers judge cited the decision in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00007" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1996452660" w-pub-number="0005506" ID="I696786508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Omega Digital Data Inc. v. Airos Technology Inc</ital>. (1996), 32 O.R. (3d) 21, 1996 CarswellOnt 5491 (Ont. Gen. Div.)</cite.query>, where the plaintiff was a start-up technology company that sought to enjoin the use of the technological and confidential information that it had developed. <eos/><bos/>Sharpe J., stated:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0012"/>I turn accordingly to the next stage in the analysis and that is the question of irreparable harm. <eos/><bos/>There is, in my view, no question but that the plaintiff has invested significant money and time in research and development on its product. <eos/><bos/>There is some debate as to the precise amount the plaintiff has invested but there is no question that a significant investment has been made. <eos/><bos/>There is also evidence that Omega has reached a particularly sensitive point in its development. <eos/><bos/>It is ready to enter the mass production and it is also ready to go into the capital public markets to raise funds to support its initiative. <eos/><bos/>The evidence satisfies me that the value of Omega and of its financial prospects lies precisely in the specific opportunity which it has been pursuing, namely, to market a product which has certain unique features and to enter a market niche which has been recognized as ripe for filling.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0012"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0013"/>I am satisfied that the loss of the right of the plaintiff to exploit that market opportunity with the advantages of being the first and only entrant into the market without competition from the defendants&apos; very similar product would result in irreparable harm to the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>It would be, in my view, extremely difficult to quantify the damage the plaintiff would suffer if an injunction were not granted. <eos/><bos/>It is clear that in cases of this precise kind the type of harm complained of by the plaintiff has repeatedly been recognized as constituting irreparable harm within the meaning of the test for an interlocutory injunction. <eos/><bos/>I refer here in particular to the judgment of Justice Blair in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00008" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1991348640" w-pub-number="0005653" w-pinpoint-page="477" ID="I696c68508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>M.D. Prescriptions Inc. v. Gandey</ital> (1991), 37 C.P.R. (3d) 472 … at p. 477</cite.query>, where Justice Blair adopted a decision of the English Court of Appeal in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00009" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1968017732" w-pub-number="0004891" w-pinpoint-page="369" ID="I696c68528e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Evans Marshall &amp; Co. v. Bertola S.A</ital>., [1973] 1 W.L.R. 349 at p. 369</cite.query>, where Lord Justice Sachs stated <cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00010" w-ref-type="ER" w-serial-number="1968017732" w-pub-number="0004891" w-pinpoint-page="349" ID="I696c68548e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">at p. 349</cite.query>:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext>Applying this test it seems just to say to the defendants, you cannot breach your fiduciary duties and then expect the plaintiff to prove the damages suffered by loss of revenue, loss of share of the market, when these are difficult to accurately determine.<eos/><bos/></paratext></para><para><paratext>Justice Blair went on to say:</paratext></para><para><paratext>I do not see how it can be said that the plaintiffs can be adequately compensated in damages for this kind of a situation when no one can know, or in fact prove, what actual impact the conduct of Mr. Gandey, assuming he is a fiduciary, may have had.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0013"/></paratext></para></display.quote></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0014"/>Lord Justice Sachs also said in the same case that the irreparable harm test might be rephrased by asking the question, <begin.quote ID="QT_0011"/>“Is it just to leave the plaintiff to its remedy of damages in the circumstances?”<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0011"/> In my opinion, in this case it is not and I would adopt that statement as applicable to the circumstances before me. <eos/><bos/>I note as well that similar statements have been made in the case-law with respect to the losses that result from breach of obligations of confidentiality: see <cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00011" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1971137544" w-pub-number="0005213" ID="I696da0d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Polyresins Ltd. v. Stein-Hall Ltd</ital>., [1972] 2 O.R. 188 …<end.quote refid="QT_0014"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id87047038e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">49</footnote.reference>]</cite.query></paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Chambers judge observed that there was no information in the record about the financial well-being of the Defendants. <eos/><bos/>The corporate defendant was, however, a start-up company that had been incorporated for less than eight months. <eos/><bos/>There might be some question about the ability of the Defendants to pay an award of damages. <eos/><bos/>Though an inability to pay damages is not determinative, it is a relevant consideration.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id87047048e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">50</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Chambers judge concluded that this was a case where the balance of convenience strongly favoured an injunction. <eos/><bos/>The Chambers judge also considered the harm that the Defendants might suffer if the injunction sought was granted. <eos/><bos/>This harm was less clear and more attenuated. <eos/><bos/>This was both because the Defendant appeared to be involved in the development of various products apart from anti-drone technology and because the Plaintiff had offered an undertaking as to damages whose worth or value was not questioned. <eos/><bos/>The Chambers judge was satisfied that the Plaintiff had established that it would suffer irreparable harm if an injunction was not granted.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8706e108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">51</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Chambers judge made the following orders: 1. The Defendants were to deliver the source code that they were relying on in connection with their anti-drone technology to counsel for the Plaintiff within 48 hours. <eos/><bos/>They were to do so in sealed form. 2. The Defendants, and each of them, were enjoined until December 14, 2018 from: (a) contacting and/or soliciting any employee of the Plaintiff; and (b) engaging in any activity or in any undertaking or business in any capacity that develops, manufactures, or markets anti-drone technology. <eos/><bos/>The Chambers judge used December 14, 2018 because this was one year from when Jia left the Plaintiff and the one-year period aligned with the prohibition in his employment contract. 3. The Defendants, and each of them, were enjoined until the trial of the action from using or developing any anti-drone source code or software that is based on, or derived from, the source code of the Plaintiff.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8706e118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">52</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00012" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I6975b7218e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading</cite.query> Ltd</ital>.,[<footnote.reference refid="Id8706e128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">53</footnote.reference>] the plaintiffs, Natural Trade and Global Forest were closely held “sister” companies involved in lumber trading. <eos/><bos/>Natural Trade exported lumber products from North America, South America and Europe to Mexico where Global Forest sold the products to local customers. <eos/><bos/>The defendants, Mizrach and Quintana, were former employees of Natural Trade. <eos/><bos/>Mizrach&apos;s responsibilities initially consisted of accounting and trading lumber. <eos/><bos/>Mizrach soon became an important trader and was promoted to CFO. <eos/><bos/>While he was CFO, continued to have an important sales role. <eos/><bos/>Throughout his time with Natural Trade, Quintana worked as a lumber trader. <eos/><bos/>The defendant, MYL Trading was a partnership formed by Mizrach and his spouse while Mizrach was employed by Natural Trade. <eos/><bos/>It was subsequently incorporated and now competed with Natural Trade and Global Forest. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs believed that MYL Trading was formed to directly compete with them and was a corporate vehicle through which Mizrach and Quintana misused confidential information obtained during their employment with Natural Trade. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs sought an interlocutory injunction to restrain the Mizrach defendants from using confidential information obtained in violation of duties owed to the plaintiffs; an order for recovery by the plaintiffs of its confidential information and other property from the Mizrach defendants; and orders requiring Mizrach and Quintana to attest to their eventual return of the plaintiffs&apos; property and to answer questions about their use of the plaintiffs&apos; confidential information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8706e138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">54</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Mizrach and Quintana signed written employment agreements with Natural Trade. <eos/><bos/>In 2016, they also signed written confidentiality and non-disclosure agreements. <eos/><bos/>The employment agreements, and/or confidentiality and non-disclosure agreements included terms relating to non-disclosure of confidential information, return of company property, non-competition and non-solicitation.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8706e148e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">55</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>During their employment with Natural Trade, Mizrach and, to a lesser extent, Quintana had access to, and acquired knowledge of nearly every aspect of Natural Trade&apos;s business and operations. <eos/><bos/>This included access to gross margin reports, which included the customers, suppliers, freight and insurance providers, costs, discounts, profits and profit margins for each sale. <eos/><bos/>Collectively, this information outlined which combinations of customers, suppliers and logistics providers were the most profitable. <eos/><bos/>In performing their duties for Natural Trade, Mizrach and Quintana developed relationships with various customers.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8706e158e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">56</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiffs believed that before November 2016, and perhaps as early as the spring of 2015, Mizrach developed a plan to use their confidential information to take their customers for himself. <eos/><bos/>To support their beliefs, the plaintiffs produced documents recovered from Mizrach&apos;s Natural Trade computer. <eos/><bos/>These documents appeared to show that Mizrach, Niron and MYL Trading were, for their own benefit, utilizing one of Natural Trade&apos;s suppliers in Brazil to transact business directly with Proterey and Valley Lumber in December 2016. <eos/><bos/>Mizrach was still employed as Natural Trade&apos;s CFO at the time. <eos/><bos/>The defendants offered no explanation of these records in their affidavits. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs adduced evidence that Mizrach made a copy of Natural Trade&apos;s “ERP system”, which listed all of Natural Trade&apos;s suppliers and customers together with contact information for each. <eos/><bos/>The implication of the plaintiffs&apos; evidence is that Mizrach took a copy of the information for his own benefit to compete with the plaintiffs.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8706e168e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">57</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiffs adduced evidence that, prior to their departures, Mizrach and Quintana either copied or tried to copy their entire work email contents for their personal use. <eos/><bos/>Both Mizrach and Quitana acknowledged having or having had several months&apos; worth of work emails on their cell phones after leaving Natural Trade. <eos/><bos/>Further, Mizrach acknowledged having copies of certain of Natural Trade&apos;s gross margin reports.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8706e178e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">58</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Mizrach and Mr. Quintana offered explanations as to why they had possession of confidential information of the plaintiffs. <eos/><bos/>They explained that they copied or tried to copy the content of their work email accounts to capture personal emails. <eos/><bos/>They explained having several months&apos; worth of work emails on their cell phones as a mere consequence of their departures. <eos/><bos/>Mizrach explained his possession of gross margin reports as being to enable him to ensure he was paid for commissions he earned before his departure.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id87095208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">59</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Since the departure of Mizrach and Quintana, the plaintiffs experienced a decline in sales to some of the plaintiffs&apos; customers which was offset by sales to these same customers by MYL Trading.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id87095218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">60</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Marchand was unable to conclude that the plaintiffs were in any real jeopardy of suffering future harms which could not be quantified or being driven out of business unless an injunction was granted. <eos/><bos/>There was evidence of a specific and quantifiable transaction to the personal benefit of the Mizrach defendants while Mizrach and Quintana were employed by Natural Trade. <eos/><bos/>There was evidence that the Mizrach defendants had certain confidential information of the plaintiffs. <eos/><bos/>There was also evidence that, since the departure of Mizrach and Quintana, MYL Trading had been doing business with customers of the plaintiffs which corresponded with a decline in the plaintiffs&apos; business with those customers. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs quantified these losses.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id87095228e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">61</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Marchand observed that the plaintiffs relied on hearsay and inference to conclude that the Mizrach defendants misused the plaintiffs&apos; confidential information to undercut the plaintiffs, harm their reputation and take their customers. <eos/><bos/>If that has happened, the harm had already been done and likely could not be undone by the granting of an injunction. <eos/><bos/>Any damage already done to the plaintiffs through the misuse of confidential information by the Mizrach defendants would have to be quantified.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id87095238e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">62</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In terms of the present risk to the plaintiffs, the plaintiffs relied on evidence adduced by the Mizrach defendants to establish that the Mizrach defendants had not contacted all of the plaintiffs&apos; customers. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs asserted that the injunction was necessary to prevent the Mizrach defendants from pursuing these remaining unsolicited customers through a misuse of confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs offered no direct and specific evidence to establish any ongoing misuse of the plaintiffs&apos; confidential information. <eos/><bos/>While the plaintiffs had lost the business of some customers, the plaintiffs&apos; gross sales remained in the same range as prior to the departure of Mizrach and Quintana. <eos/><bos/>Finally, the plaintiffs had a very substantial business in comparison to the fledgling business of the Mizrach defendants.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id87095248e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">63</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>While unable to conclude that the plaintiffs were in any real jeopardy of being driven out of business unless an injunction was granted, Justice Marchand observed that on the Mizrach defendants&apos; own evidence, there was a real risk that if the plaintiffs succeeded in the litigation they would be unable to collect from the Mizrach defendants. <eos/><bos/>It was that risk that raised the spectre of irreparable harm.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id87095258e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">64</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00013" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I698017618e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity</cite.query> Corp</ital>.,[<footnote.reference refid="Id87095268e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">65</footnote.reference>] the plaintiff sought an interlocutory injunction restraining the defendants from disclosing or making use of client information and/or soliciting the plaintiff&apos;s clients. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff also sought an order requiring the defendants to return to it all copies of information related to clients of the plaintiff when the employment of the defendant Mann was terminated by the plaintiff; provide an affidavit setting out any uses to which the defendants have put the information; and refrain from disclosing or otherwise making use of the information, including for the purpose of soliciting the plaintiff&apos;s clients.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id87095278e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">66</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff was a full service brokerage firm and investment dealer. <eos/><bos/>Mann moved to the plaintiff&apos;s Vancouver Branch from another brokerage firm and signed an employment agreement. <eos/><bos/>That agreement did not contain any non-solicitation clause or make reference to a code of conduct. <eos/><bos/>A few days after signing the employment agreement and commencing his employment with the plaintiff, Mann signed a document indicating that he would “accept to read” the plaintiff&apos;s Code of Conduct and Ethics. <eos/><bos/>When he joined the plaintiff, he had 100 clients and was managing $50 million in investment assets.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id870bc308e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">67</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The defendants, James and Ilia Nizker became employees of the plaintiff, the latter as a “cold caller”.<eos/><bos/> Like Mann, James&apos; employment contract did not contain a non-solicitation provision and did not refer to the Code of Conduct. <eos/><bos/>Nizker signed an employment contract one month after having qualified and becoming employed as an investment advisor. <eos/><bos/>His employment contract contained a non-solicitation provision.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id870bc318e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">68</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>By April 18, 2018, Mann held the position of Senior Vice President, Portfolio Manager, and oversaw a group of investment advisors and other employees who were known within the plaintiff as the “Mann Group”.<eos/><bos/> At that time the Mann Group serviced 2,500 clients with investment assets totaling $725,000,000. <eos/><bos/>James and Nizker were part of the Mann Group. <eos/><bos/>The growth of the Mann Group&apos;s client base over the years came about as the result of the individual efforts of the Mann Group. <eos/><bos/>The Mann Group had its own website and marketed its services through various means such as newsletters, emails, cold calls and referrals.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id870bc328e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">69</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In 2010, Mann purchased computer software called “Salesforce”, a third-party customer relationship platform. <eos/><bos/>It is a cloud-based database into which the Mann Group input the names, addresses, phone numbers and email addresses of clients as well as general notes of discussions they had with clients and prospects. <eos/><bos/>It did not include any information such as account numbers, holdings or rates of return. <eos/><bos/>Mann paid all of the licencing fees for the Salesforce software. <eos/><bos/>The Mann Group did not use the plaintiff&apos;s database to retrieve information used to communicate to clients. <eos/><bos/>It used Salesforce. <eos/><bos/>The only people who had access to the Salesforce database were members of the Mann Group.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id870bc338e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">70</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In 2016, Mann contemplated leaving the employ of the plaintiff and moving to the defendant, Canaccord. <eos/><bos/>He copied and provided to Canaccord, via flash drives, confidential and private information regarding the Mann Group&apos;s clients. <eos/><bos/>This information comprised up to 23,768 reports containing “Know Your Client” forms and other client documents. <eos/><bos/>In early 2018, Mann again copied onto flash drives a substantial amount of confidential and private information regarding clients, comprising up to 27,088 records.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id870bc348e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">71</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>On April 18, 2018, Mann&apos;s employment was terminated by the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff now alleged that Mann was terminated for cause, in that he engaged in misconduct that was in breach of securities regulations, IIROC rules and the plaintiff&apos;s internal policies.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id870bc358e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">72</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Immediately after Mann&apos;s termination, James changed the Salesforce password which resulted in the plaintiff&apos;s temporary access to the Salesforce account to be cut off. <eos/><bos/>Thereafter, the only contact information available to the plaintiff for the clients that had been managed by the Mann Group was that contained in its own database. <eos/><bos/>On April 20, 2018, James tendered his resignation to the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>On April 23, 2018, Mann and James commenced employment with Canaccord. <eos/><bos/>Also on April 23, 2018, Nizker and four other members of the Mann Group tendered their respective resignations and joined Mann and James at Canaccord. <eos/><bos/>The Mann Team immediately began to solicit the business of the clients whose assets they had managed while employed by the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>They provided information regarding why they had left the plaintiff and moved to Canaccord that was, at the very least, a failure of full disclosure as to the true reason they had left the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff was unable to correspond with or contact many of the recipients of these emails because it did not have current contact information for them.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id870bc368e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">73</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The defendants had possession of seven categories of documents which fell within the plaintiff&apos;s definition of Confidential Documents: a) the 2016 USB Keys; b) documents from the 2016 USB Keys downloaded to the desktop of Canaccord&apos;s Assistant Branch Manager; c) hard copies of documents printed from the 2016 USB Keys; d) data from the hard copies used to populate Canaccord transfer forms which were kept on USB drives; e) data from the hard copies of documents loaded into a database used by Canaccord known as Dataphile; f) the 2018 USB Keys; and g) a client list, separate from that contained on Salesforce, printed by Mann shortly before his termination from the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>The defendants returned to the plaintiff the 2016 USB Keys, the hard copies of documents from the 2016 USB Keys, the Transfer Form USB Keys, the 2018 USB Keys and the client list printed by Mann in 2018. <eos/><bos/>No copies were kept of any of these documents, electronically or otherwise. <eos/><bos/>The data that was loaded to Dataphile remained there. <eos/><bos/>Dataphile is a database owned by an external vendor and Canaccord does not have the ability, on its own, to permanently remove the data.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id870e3408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">74</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>While it might be difficult, it would not be impossible for the plaintiff at trial to separate damages caused by the misuse of confidential information and/or improper solicitation from losses resulting from normal, fair competition. <eos/><bos/>The court would be able to determine the loss attributable to the proven misconduct of the defendants by reviewing the business conducted by the Mann Team and Canaccord relating to the clients formerly managed by the Mann Group while at the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>In Justice Weatherill&apos;s view, the damages claimed by the plaintiff were not irreparable.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id870e3418e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">75</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Quick Pass Master Tutorial School Ltd. v. Zhao</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id870e3428e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">76</footnote.reference>] Quick Pass sought an interlocutory injunction to prohibit Zhao from competing with it, from soliciting its students, and from using what it alleged was Quick Pass&apos;s confidential or proprietary information. <eos/><bos/>Quick Pass offered real estate-related tutorial programs in various Lower Mainland locations to assist Mandarin speakers in taking British Columbia&apos;s real estate licencing examinations. <eos/><bos/>It hired real estate agents who were fluent in Mandarin as instructors. <eos/><bos/>The owner of Quick Pass hired Zhao under a two-year contract as a real estate program instructor. <eos/><bos/>The contractual terms prohibited Zhao from soliciting Quick Pass&apos;s students and from competing with it for specified periods. <eos/><bos/>It also provided that Quick Pass owned all material relating to its business, including any material created by Zhao while under contract to Quick Pass, whether or not he created it at Quick Pass&apos;s direction.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id870e3438e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">77</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The day after Zhao terminated his contract, he opened a competing tutorial school in Burnaby. <eos/><bos/>He advertised and marketed his school to the Mandarin-speaking community, including to students of Quick Pass. <eos/><bos/>He used materials that he alleged he developed for use in his own program, but which he must have developed while working for Quick Pass since he opened his school the next day.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id870e3448e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">78</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Iyer observed that since Zhao opened his school the day after he left Quick Pass, and the Confidential Information Clause deemed any such material created by Zhao during the term of the Contracts to be the proprietary and confidential information of Quick Pass, it was more likely than not that the material he created for the Zhao School was created while Zhao was under contract to Quick Pass. <eos/><bos/>This meant that if the Confidential Information Clause was enforceable, Zhao breached it.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id870e3458e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">79</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Confidential Information Clause was not a restrictive covenant. <eos/><bos/>Rather, Justice Iyer observed that it was <begin.quote ID="QT_0015"/>“intended to protect the right of a business to keep confidential the information it hopes will help it to compete so the usual relatively low threshold applies to it”<end.quote refid="QT_0015"/> citing <cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00014" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034063927" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I699155708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Phoenix Restorations Ltd. v. Drisdelle</ital>, 2014 CarswellBC 2348, 2014 BCSC 1497</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>This meant that Quick Pass need only prove that its claim with respect to this clause was not frivolous or vexatious and the court need not engage in an extensive review of the merits of the claim.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id870e3468e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">80</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Quick Pass experienced a noticeable decline in the number of its clients and some former Quick Pass clients had switched over to the Zhao School. <eos/><bos/>Justice Iyer accepted that the harm to Quick Pass would be irreparable if it was successful at trial on its claim based on the Non-Competition Clause in that it would not be possible to distinguish between legitimate competition and prohibited competition. <eos/><bos/>Similarly, release of confidential information creates a type of harm to business reputation that is difficult to quantify. <eos/><bos/>Justice Iyer was satisfied that Quick Pass had established this element in respect of the Confidential Information Clause.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id870e3478e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">81</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Nu Image v. Seager</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id870e3488e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">82</footnote.reference>] a motion for an interim injunction was dismissed. <eos/><bos/>The defendant Michael was the nephew of Doug, the principal of Nu Image. <eos/><bos/>Michael was employed by Nu Image for 17 years until he was terminated from his employment as vice president of operations. <eos/><bos/>Nu Image alleged that Michael was terminated for cause while Michael alleged the dismissal was without cause and had counter claimed for damages for wrongful dismissal. <eos/><bos/>At the time of his termination Michael was described as Doug&apos;s second in command and took care of the day to day business because Doug was semi-retired.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8710a508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">83</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Nu Image had a list of clients, for the most part commercial and industrial properties, for whom it supplied landscaping services including lawn cutting and snow removal in the winter. <eos/><bos/>The customer contracts were repeat seasonal or annual contracts. <eos/><bos/>Nu Image alleged that Michael had intimate knowledge of virtually all aspects of its business operations and client list. <eos/><bos/>He was familiar with the pricing model and how to quote contracts. <eos/><bos/>He had a personal relationship with most of the clients. <eos/><bos/>Michael was the keeper of Nu Image&apos;s computer passwords and knowledgeable about the security system.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8710a518e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">84</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>However, prior to his termination, Michael had incorporated Superb and registered the business name. <eos/><bos/>Superb was to operate business in direct competition with Nu Image. <eos/><bos/>Michael developed an email address for the new company and likely, before his termination, had placed a business add in a publication. <eos/><bos/>After his termination Michael, in part using Nu Image&apos;s client list, sent out a mass email soliciting business. <eos/><bos/>After termination Michael changed Nu Images computer password without, for a time, disclosing the new passwords to Nu Image. <eos/><bos/>He would log into Nu Images computers and could, until February 2017, see the locations of all of Nu Image&apos;s vehicles. <eos/><bos/>He would quote new jobs knowing Nu Image&apos;s manner of pricing. <eos/><bos/>It was alleged that Michael would use quote and contract templates similar to those used by Nu Image. <eos/><bos/>After his termination, Michael attended at Nu-Image and downloaded a number of pictures of work completed by Nu Image and used those images to market his own company.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8710a528e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">85</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiffs submitted that Michael had a fiduciary duty to Nu Image, a submission not disputed by the defendants. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs submitted that Michael breached his fiduciary duty. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs sought to restrain the defendants from using any and all information obtained from Nu Image and to restrain them from contacting or soliciting business from anyone with whom Nu Image did business from three years prior to the termination to today.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8710a538e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">86</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In response, it was not denied that Michael solicited Nu Image&apos;s clients and had access to the client list.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motions judge was of the view that that it was likely that Michael had and may still have had eleven months following his dismissal a fiduciary duty to the plaintiffs. <eos/><bos/>As a result, there was a serious issue to be tried. <eos/><bos/>After employment ends, a fiduciary is entitled to compete with the former employer, but must do so fairly. <eos/><bos/>They are prohibited from using confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The duty includes not competing unfairly by soliciting customers of a former employer. <eos/><bos/>There appeared no doubt that the defendants took advantage of confidential information and property belonging to the plaintiffs.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8710a548e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">87</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>However, the motions judge concluded that the plaintiffs had not established irreparable harm. <eos/><bos/>While they quoted significant numbers in relation to lost business they failed to attribute this loss to the defendants. <eos/><bos/>Admissions by Doug under cross-examination suggested a lack of such a loss and thereby a lack of such harm. <eos/><bos/>The delay of 11 months is also a factor, further negating the irreparable harm claim.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8710a558e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">88</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Had the motions judge found irreparable harm, the motions judge would have ruled the balance of convenience favoured the plaintiffs. <eos/><bos/>Michael had a fiduciary duty to the plaintiffs and had they suffered harm that could not be adequately compensated by damages an injunction would have been granted.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8710a568e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">89</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00015" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2038061488" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I69a049918e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">SyberWorks Inc. v. Organization Metrics</cite.query> Inc</ital>.,[<footnote.reference refid="Id8710a578e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">90</footnote.reference>] SyberWorks was granted an interlocutory injunction restraining the defendants from using and making any further use of the LMS, Derivative Works, and SyberWorks&apos; customer list and related materials. <eos/><bos/>In addition, each of the defendants was required to comply with the documentary discovery obligations set out in Rule 30 of the <ital>Rules of Civil Procedure</ital>. <eos/><bos/>Given the disregard of the process demonstrated by the defendants and the finding of irreparable harm made, the matter was ordered to an expedited trial.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id87131608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">91</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In 2012, SyberWorks entered into a licence agreement with OMI with respect to the Learning Management System, a software application that SyberWorks had developed. <eos/><bos/>SyberWorks alleged that the defendants committed breaches of confidence by reason of the disclosure by Murray and OMI of SyberWorks&apos; confidential information to Clear Picture and the misuse by Clear Picture of that information. <eos/><bos/>The overall effect of the Agreement was that in consideration for the payment of the licence fees for a period of five years OMI was granted a <begin.quote ID="QT_0016"/>“perpetual, non-exclusive, transferrable, worldwide licence of the LMS, Source Code and Documentation”<end.quote refid="QT_0016"/>. <eos/><bos/>OMI was permitted to create “Derivative Works” and, absent a material breach of the Agreement by OMI, to retain all right, title and interest in and to the Derivative Works. <eos/><bos/>OMI and SyberWorks also agreed that they would essentially not compete with one another for business during the five-year term of the Agreement. <eos/><bos/>OMI failed to make licence fee payments on August 31, 2014 and December 31, 2014. <eos/><bos/>SyberWorks treated the failure to make the licence fee payments as a fundamental breach of the Agreement and notified OMI of same. <eos/><bos/>OMI failed to rectify the breach within the time frame provided by the Agreement and, relying on that failure, SyberWorks terminated the Agreement. <eos/><bos/>In addition, SyberWorks became aware of what it believed to be use being made by Clear Picture of at least a portion of the LMS in providing support services to former customers of OMI—customers transferred from SyberWorks to OMI as part of the Agreement. <eos/><bos/>Clear Picture had the same office address, telephone number, and fax number in the City of Ottawa as OMI. <eos/><bos/>The action was commenced in April 2015 and was undefended. <eos/><bos/>SyberWorks obtained a default judgment solely against OMI and with respect only to the liquidated damages claimed in the action.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id87131618e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">92</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Murray&apos;s involvement in both OMI and Clear Picture was uncontroverted. <eos/><bos/>An inference was drawn that Clear Picture was a pro-active participant in the alleged breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>On the basis of the deemed admissions, the the admissions made by Murray when examined in aid of execution, as the representative of OMI, and the inference drawn, there was a serious case to be tried with respect to the following matters: a) Did OMI, through its sole potential actor, Murray, convey information to Clear Picture that is confidential? b) Was the information conveyed by OMI to Clear Picture initially conveyed by SyberWorks to OMI in confidence? c) Given Murray&apos;s involvement in both Clear Picture and OMI, is the former aware that it is, without colour of right, using the information conveyed (<ital>i.e</ital>. misuse of the information by Clear Picture)?<eos/><bos/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id87131628e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">93</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Assuming that OMI had paid the licence fees in full and there had been no material breach of the Agreement by either OMI or SyberWorks on or before December 31, 2015, the end date of the Agreement, then there would have been a competitive post-agreement environment in which OMI and SyberWorks were in competition for business with respect to the use of software applications such as LMS, the Derivative Works, and similar products developed by SyberWorks. <eos/><bos/>That business could well have included OMI licencing its products to Clear Picture. <eos/><bos/>That OMI and SyberWorks both contemplated a competitive post-agreement environment did not detract from the fact that SyberWorks, <begin.quote ID="QT_0017"/>“did not bargain for the unfair competition of having their know-how, imparted in confidence, used against them. <eos/><bos/>The [Agreement] cannot be read as negating the duty of confidence imposed by law”<end.quote refid="QT_0017"/>: see <cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00016" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1999428661" w-pub-number="0005156" ID="I69a63d008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cadbury Schweppes Inc. v. FBI Foods Ltd</ital>., [1999] 1 S.C.R. 142 (S.C.C.)</cite.query>, at para. 38.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id87131638e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">94</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The continuing, unlawful exploitation of SyberWorks&apos; confidential and proprietary information had and would continue to: a) cause SyberWorks a substantial loss of revenue and of good will; and b) damage SyberWorks&apos; place in the marketplace. <eos/><bos/>The admissions which the defendants were deemed to have made, in combination with Murray&apos;s admission that OMI was licencing an LMS product to Clear Picture, supported a finding that SyberWorks was suffering irreparable harm by reason of the conduct of the defendants.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id87131648e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">95</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>SyberWorks&apos; know-how, which had arguably been imparted in breach of confidence or the Agreement, or pursuant to a conspiracy, was being used in competition against it. <eos/><bos/>Murray&apos;s conduct flew in the face of the terms of the Agreement—an Agreement which he negotiated on behalf of OMI. <eos/><bos/>The defendants failed to defend the action and, in doing so, demonstrated disregard for the process. <eos/><bos/>Unless an interlocutory injunction was granted, the irreparable harm which SyberWorks alleged it was suffering would continue indefinitely. <eos/><bos/>The balance of convenience favoured SyberWorks.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id87131658e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">96</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Enviro Trace Ltd. v. Sheichuk</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id87158708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">97</footnote.reference>] the applicant was granted a continuation of an interlocutory injunction previously granted on an interim interim basis against the defendant former employees of the plaintiff and the company which they set up. <eos/><bos/>The applicant requested only an order preventing the respondents from using the applicant&apos;s trade secrets and confidential information rather than one which prevented them from carrying on business.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The court concluded that the applicant had proved that it would suffer irreparable harm if the injunction were not granted. <eos/><bos/>The motions judge suggested that it would be illogical for a court to require proof of irreparable harm when something is stolen from another. <eos/><bos/>The theft speaks for itself. <eos/><bos/>On the other hand, it may be necessary to prove irreparable harm as a prerequisite to the granting of an injunction of the type requested because the case law relating to injunctions based on misuse of confidential information requires an applicant to prove detriment to the confider. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, the court assumed for the purposes of its decision that irreparable harm must be proved in order to satisfy the tripartite test.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id87158718e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">98</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motions judge observed that harm which cannot be cured by, or quantified in, money is irreparable harm. <eos/><bos/>The loss of a trade secret is harm which cannot be cured by money. <eos/><bos/>If a secret is divulged, money cannot make it a secret again. <eos/><bos/>Loss of business reputation is also harm which cannot be cured by money. <eos/><bos/>It is an intangible loss which might even affect a business&apos; ability to continue. <eos/><bos/>Such a loss might result here because the corporate defendant was perceived by clients as testing in the same way as the applicant whereas the evidence indicated that the defendant did not have the technical capacity to ensure that its testing technique remains appropriate and verified by an independent third party. <eos/><bos/>Therefore, any failure of the corporate defendants&apos; certifications would harm the business reputation of the applicant. <eos/><bos/>There was also a danger to the public and to the environment if unverified techniques were the only basis for the issuance by the corporate defendant of no leak certificates.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id87158728e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">99</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The court concluded that the applicant would suffer the greater harm from the refusal of an interlocutory injunction. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff merely requested that the defendants not use any of the plaintiff&apos;s trade secrets. <eos/><bos/>The defendants would not be negatively affected by the injunction if they were not using the plaintiff&apos;s trade secrets and confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The trade secret in question was more than a “nothing very special” kind of trade secret. <eos/><bos/>In addition to information that is known in the oil and gas industry, the applicant had been involved in double blind testing of its technique with a recognized, independent, scientific authority. <eos/><bos/>It was noteworthy that, even while engaging in this verification of its technique, the applicant preserved the secrecy of the technique itself.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id87158738e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">100</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>RBC Dominion Securities Inc. v. Macdonald</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id87158748e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">101</footnote.reference>] the court concluded that the identities and contact particulars of RBCDS clients was, <ital>prima facie</ital>, confidential information that the employee acquired in the course of his employment. <eos/><bos/>Pursuant to the terms of his employment contract it was also information he was obliged, <ital>prima facie</ital>, not to disclosure or use following his departure. <eos/><bos/>This was so regardless of whether the employment contract included a non-solicitation or non-competition clause. <eos/><bos/>The court also concluded that RBCDS would suffer irreparable harm unless an interlocutory injunction was granted regarding the use of confidential information for targeted solicitation of I&apos;s clients who were not Primary Contact Clients. <eos/><bos/>If a breach was established regarding the Primary Contact Clients damages would be calculable because their portfolios can be valued and their prior connection with the employee was readily apparent. <eos/><bos/>In contrast, however, it might be impossible to tell whether I&apos;s other clients left RBCDS due to legitimate competition or because the employee used confidential information regarding their identities and contact particulars for purposes of targeted solicitation. <eos/><bos/>It may also be impossible to quantify the reputational damage RBCDS would suffer if I&apos;s other clients were directly solicited by the employee: a former RBCDS advisor with whom they had no prior working relationship. <eos/><bos/>The defendants were not likely to be harmed irreparably by an interlocutory injunction preventing targeted solicitation of such a small and identifiable group of individuals. <eos/><bos/>They remained free to compete generally in the investment business marketplace and to engage in targeted solicitation of other prospective clients. <eos/><bos/>The impact of the interlocutory order was simply to prevent them for soliciting in a targeted manner, I&apos;s clients with whom the employee had no prior working relationship. <eos/><bos/>This would avoid the risk that, in so doing, private contact particulars or other forms of confidential information belonging to RBCDS and those clients might be accessed or used. <eos/><bos/>The court granted some but not all of the relief sought by RBCDS. In particular, the court ordered the defendants to return all documents recording information that the employee obtained while employed by RBCDS except for the names of Primary Contact Clients or publicly available information obtained independent of his employment. <eos/><bos/>The defendants were also enjoined from using RBCDS confidential information or initiating contact with any RBCDS client for whom I was the designated advisor for purposes of targeted solicitation, except that they could initiate contact with Primary Contact Clients.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>There was convincing evidence in <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00017" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2027654193" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I69ac30718e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Fuller Western Rubber Linings Ltd. v. Spence Corrosion Services</cite.query> Ltd.</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id87158758e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">102</footnote.reference>] that the individual appellant did take some confidential information with him, and may well have used it, although at least some of it was subsequently returned. <eos/><bos/>The individual appellant was employed by the respondents for approximately 22 months, and during the last seven months he was involved in sales. <eos/><bos/>He left his employment in September of 2010, and shortly thereafter began competing with his former employer. <eos/><bos/>He was able to obtain contracts from customers of his former employer, and ended up employing a number of his former co-employees. <eos/><bos/>There was also evidence that he made use of confidential proprietary information in starting his own business. <eos/><bos/>The argument in chambers appeared to have been directed primarily at the use of the confidential information, and the essence of the chambers judge&apos;s reasons appeared to be his statement that the appellants had taken an unfair advantage by using the respondent&apos;s confidential information, documents, HSE Manual, customer list and employee list and had used this information to directly compete with the respondents. <eos/><bos/>The Chambers judge concluded that if an injunction was not granted the respondents would suffer irreparable harm to their business, reputation and goodwill. <eos/><bos/>The Court of Appeal observed that this merely conclusory statement did not assist much. <eos/><bos/>There was mention of potential difficulty in calculating damages from loss of business, but no other explanation as to why the misuse of confidential information should result in an injunction against all competition for six months.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id87158768e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">103</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The respondents demonstrated a <ital>prima facie</ital> case relating to the use of confidential information. <eos/><bos/>However, there was no satisfactory evidence of irreparable harm. <eos/><bos/>It could reasonably be concluded that the appellants did obtain some advantage by using confidential information as a springboard. <eos/><bos/>However, by the time the injunction application was heard, some of that information had been returned, and the damage done by its use to that point could not be reversed. <eos/><bos/>With respect to the balance of convenience, the injunction would have essentially shut down the appellants&apos; business from March to September of 2012. <eos/><bos/>On the assumption the non-solicitation agreement was for the period of severance pay, the injunction covered a period after the covenant had expired. <eos/><bos/>On the assumption that the covenant was for two years, the injunction interrupted the appellant&apos;s business for six months, after it had been operating for 18 months, risking the employment of 24 persons. <eos/><bos/>In all the circumstances, the parties were to be left to their remedies in damages, to be calculated after the claim and counterclaim have been properly tried. <eos/><bos/>The appeal was allowed, and the interlocutory injunction discharged.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8717f808e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">104</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In terms of the obligation of all employees not to misuse confidential information of the former employer, the courts have held that trade secrets and customer lists are confidential. <eos/><bos/>However, there is some ambiguity as to whether “confidential information” includes the names of such customers, and their needs and preferences, that the employee has learned during his period of service and can recall. <eos/><bos/>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00018" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2027291812" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I69af16a18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Parrish &amp; Heimbecker Ltd. v. Delmar Commodities</cite.query> Ltd</ital>.,[<footnote.reference refid="Id8717f818e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">105</footnote.reference>] the plaintiff sought from both Hodgson and Delmar return of its confidential information and an injunction enjoining them from using such confidential information or soliciting its customers, particularly in an area of Manitoba described as the “northeast territory”.<eos/><bos/> The defendant Hodgson was employed by the plaintiff until September 6, 2011 when he went to work for Delmar, a supplier and competitor of the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>In the winter of 2010/11, Delmar decided that because the plaintiff had chosen not to extend its reach into the northeast territory with a facility in the area, it would do so. <eos/><bos/>It entered into an agreement to acquire land and engaged local contractors to do the construction work. <eos/><bos/>Delmar did not advise the plaintiff of its intention to build this facility until after Hodgson had joined the company. <eos/><bos/>On September 6, 2011, Hodgson resigned from his employment with the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>He had sought out other employment and as a result secured two offers, one from Delmar for the position of Territory Manager for Eastern Manitoba. <eos/><bos/>He took the job and began work shortly thereafter. <eos/><bos/>Hodgson denied that he took any customer list or other property of the plaintiff when he left its employ. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff had no evidence that he took any such documentation. <eos/><bos/>There was no formal employment contract between Hodgson and the plaintiff, although he did endorse his acknowledgement on the plaintiff&apos;s employee handbook which contained a provision obliging all employees to maintain in strict confidence information received by the plaintiff or its customers and requiring them not to disclose this information either during the period of employment or at any time thereafter.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8717f828e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">106</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motions judge observed that there was limited, if any, evidence of Hodgson having or using confidential information of the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence that he had any documentation belonging to the plaintiff, including customer lists. <eos/><bos/>He had no secret information about pricing of Legend Seed, as all sellers were required to sell at the same price. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence that he had targeted the plaintiff&apos;s customers. <eos/><bos/>The names of all farmers in the area were public information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8717f838e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">107</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>It was possible that, at trial, Hodgson would not be found to have been a key employee. <eos/><bos/>However, the evidence was quite convincing that he was. <eos/><bos/>As General Manager, he was more than a sales manager. <eos/><bos/>He had general managerial responsibilities over a large facility with a substantial sales volume. <eos/><bos/>In terms of his reassignment to Customer Service Manager, he held this position for only the last two or three months of his employment with the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>In both positions, he acquired considerable knowledge about the plaintiff&apos;s customers.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8717f848e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">108</footnote.reference>] If Hodgson did no more than pass on his business card and advise of where he was working, it was possible that, at trial, this might be found not to constitute solicitation. <eos/><bos/>However, this seemed unlikely. <eos/><bos/>By personally attending at the farms, Hodgson had clearly done more than generally advertise his new employment. <eos/><bos/>He directly approached farmers, knowing that some of them were customers of the plaintiff, in an attempt to secure their business. <eos/><bos/>And he has successfully concluded sales with some of these individuals.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>However, the plaintiff had not established that it would suffer irreparable harm if the injunction were denied. <eos/><bos/>The court was not persuaded that the plaintiff&apos;s customers were moving to Delmar because of any solicitation on the part of Hodgson. <eos/><bos/>Instead, any loss of market share would appear to result from Delmar now selling Legend Seed and having a facility in the area and, probably even more importantly, from the plaintiff&apos;s decision to no longer sell Legend Seed.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The balance of convenience weighed in favour of denying an injunction. <eos/><bos/>The reality was that the sale of soybean seeds was a highly competitive business. <eos/><bos/>While Delmar hired Hodgson to assist in its entry into the northeast territory market, there was scant evidence that it or Hodgson was using confidential information or targeting the plaintiff&apos;s customers. <eos/><bos/>Further, even if Hodgson was a key employee of the plaintiff, the law provides that he could join a competitor, sell to its customers, and advertise.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8717f858e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">109</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Id86f35908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00019" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1972022359" w-pub-number="0003898" ID="I69b139808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Hubbard v. Vosper</ital>, [1972] 2 Q.B. 84 (C.A.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00020" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1979092475" w-pub-number="0005150" ID="I69b139828e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Schauenburg Industries Ltd. v. Borowski</ital> (1979), 101 D.L.R. (3d) 701, 25 O.R. (2d) 737 (H.C.J.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00021" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2031151873" w-pub-number="0005475" ID="I69b139858e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Down East Vending Inc. v. Lockerbie</ital>, 2013 CarswellNS 542, 2013 NSSC 229</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id86f35918e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>See <cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00022" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1973145636" w-pub-number="0005150" w-pinpoint-page="678" ID="I69b30e408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jiffy Foods Ltd. v. Chomski</ital> (1973), 38 D.L.R. (3d) 675 at pp. 678–81, [1973] 3 O.R. 955 (Div. Ct.)</cite.query>, where an injunction protected the plaintiff from the misuse and disclosure of its sales routes and customer lists, and <cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00023" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1985262300" w-pub-number="0005459" w-pinpoint-page="12" ID="I69b30e438e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Eli Lilly Canada Inc. v. Shamrock Chemicals Ltd.</ital> (1985), 6 C.I.P.R. 5 at pp. 12–13, 4 C.P.R. (3d) 196 (Ont. S.C.)</cite.query>, where the defendants were restrained from manufacturing and marketing a product of the plaintiffs, although the formulation process had been given to one of the defendants in good faith. <eos/><bos/>Here, disclosure of the process would have rendered damages “virtually impossible” to calculate and highly unlikely to be paid. <eos/><bos/>See also <cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00024" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1971137618" w-pub-number="0005150" ID="I69b30e468e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Tenatronics Ltd. v. Hauf</ital> (1971), 23 D.L.R. (3d) 60, [1972] 1 O.R. 329 (H.C.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00025" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1971137544" w-pub-number="0005150" w-pinpoint-page="159" ID="I69b30e498e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Polyresins Ltd. v. Stein-Hall Ltd.</ital> (1971), 25 D.L.R. (3d) 152 at pp. 159–60, [1972] 2 O.R. 188 (H.C.J.)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>In <cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00026" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2011601481" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I69b30e4c8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jardine Lloyd Thompson Canada Inc. v. Fogal</ital> (2007), 155 A.C.W.S. (3d) 1129 (B.C.S.C.)</cite.query>, an injunction was granted to enforce non-competition and non-solicitation obligations after an employee left one specialty insurance brokerage firm and moved to another. <eos/><bos/>The court found that the goodwill and market share of a strategically valuable business in a shrinking forestry insurance market was not easily calculable. <eos/><bos/>Therefore damages were not readily quantifiable, with the result that irreparable harm would be suffered if an injunction was refused. <eos/><bos/>On the other hand, in industries where damages are easily quantified, that should be part of the court&apos;s consideration: see <cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00027" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2012635557" w-pub-number="0006729" ID="I69b30e4f8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>BMO Nesbitt Burns Inc. v. Ord</ital> (2007), 158 A.C.W.S. (3d) 760, [2007] O.J. No. 2620 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>; <ital>MD Funds Management Inc. v. Gaumond</ital> (unreported, April 16, 2004, Court File No. 04-CV-26564, Ont. S.C.J.); <cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00028" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017310767" w-pub-number="0007214" ID="I69b30e518e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>ATB Securities Inc. v. RBC Dominion Securities Inc.</ital> (2008), 50 B.L.R. (4th) 178, [2008] A.J. No. 1111 (Q.B.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00029" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2015777328" w-pub-number="0005485" ID="I69b30e548e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sun Life Financial Distributors (Canada) Inc. v. Sanche</ital> (2008), 227 Man. R. (2d) 227, [2008] M.J. No. 122 (Q.B.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00030" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2000541912" w-pub-number="0006729" ID="I69b30e588e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Nesbitt Burns Inc. v. Lange</ital></cite.query> (2000), 16 C.C.E.L. (3d) 317, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00031" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2000541912" w-pub-number="0006729" ID="I69b30e598e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">[2000] O.J. No. 842 (S.C.J.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00032" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2021951177" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I69b30e5b8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>MD Management Ltd. v. Campbell</ital> (2010), 188 A.C.W.S. (3d) 1145, 2010 ONSC 2315</cite.query>, leave to appeal to Ont. C.A. <eos/><bos/><case.history>granted</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00033" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2022792348" w-pub-number="0007659" ID="I69b30e5e8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2010 ONSC 4217 (Div. Ct.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id86f35928e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00034" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1989313113" w-pub-number="0005653" ID="I69b61b808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ovation Gifts and Greetings Inc. v. Raiskums</ital> (1989), 24 C.P.R. (3d) 527 (Ont. H.C.J.), at p. 532</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00035" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027180487" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69b61b828e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>6180 Fraser Holdings Inc. v. Ali</ital>, 2012 CarswellBC 495, 2012 BCSC 247</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>Although, see the earlier case of <cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00036" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1993381699" w-pub-number="0005653" ID="I69b61b868e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>London Life Insurance Co. v. Heaps</ital></cite.query> (1993), 48 C.C.E.L. 260, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00037" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1993381699" w-pub-number="0005653" ID="I69b61b878e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">50 C.P.R. (3d) 438</cite.query> (Ont. Ct. (Gen. Div.)), which seems to argue the contrary.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id86f5ca08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>4</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00038" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1999491293" w-pub-number="0006729" ID="I69b72cf18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jet Print Inc. v. Cohen</ital></cite.query> (1999), 43 C.P.C. (4th) 123, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00039" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1999491293" w-pub-number="0006729" ID="I69b72cf28e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">[1999] O.J. No. 2864 (S.CJ.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00040" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028350994" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I69b72cf48e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Altus Group Ltd. v. Yeoman</ital>, 2012 CarswellOnt 9503, 2012 ONSC 4406</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id86f5ca18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>5</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00041" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2000541558" w-pub-number="0005628" ID="I69b77b108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sheehan and Rosie Ltd. v. Northwood</ital>, 2000 C.L.L.C. ¶ 210-037, 95 A.C.W.S. (3d) 552 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at para. 38; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00042" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2020991139" w-pub-number="0006457" ID="I69b77b138e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Easyhome Ltd. v. Casey</ital> (2009), 20 Alta. L.R. (5th) 199, 2009 ABQB 735, at para. 42</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00043" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2030642293" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I69b77b158e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jardine Lloyd Thompson Canada Inc. v. Harke-Hunt</ital>, 2013 CarswellAlta 861, 2013 ABQB 313</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id86f5ca28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>6</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00044" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1978155024" w-pub-number="0005652" ID="I69b817518e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Professional Maintenance Systems of Canada Ltd. v. Smits</ital></cite.query> (1978), 13 C.P.C. 144 at p. 148, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00045" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1978155024" w-pub-number="0005652" ID="I69b817528e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">40 C.P.R. (2d) 160 (B.C.S.C.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id86f5ca38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>7</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00046" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1968018312" w-pub-number="0004831" ID="I69c780a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Coco v. A.N. Clark (Engineers) Ltd.</ital>, [1969] R.P.C. 41 (Ch.), at p. 50</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>See also <ital>Husky Injection Molding Systems Ltd. v. Li</ital> (2006), 50 C.C.E.L. (3d) 295 (Ont. S.C.J.).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id86f5ca48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>8</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00047" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040845729" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I69c7cec08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2158124 Ontario Inc. v. Pitton</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 1023, 2017 ONSC 411</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id86f5ca58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>9</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00048" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040845729" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I69c7f5d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2158124 Ontario Inc. v. Pitton</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 1023, 2017 ONSC 411</cite.query>, at paras. 2–8, and 13.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id86f83b08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>10</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00049" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040845729" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I69c81ce08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2158124 Ontario Inc. v. Pitton</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 1023, 2017 ONSC 411, at para. 20</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id86f83b18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>11</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00050" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040845729" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I69c81ce38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2158124 Ontario Inc. v. Pitton</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 1023, 2017 ONSC 411, at para. 24</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id86f83b28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>12</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00051" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040845729" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I69c843f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2158124 Ontario Inc. v. Pitton</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 1023, 2017 ONSC 411</cite.query>, at paras. 26–28.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id86f83b38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>13</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00052" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040845729" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I69c892108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2158124 Ontario Inc. v. Pitton</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 1023, 2017 ONSC 411</cite.query>, at paras. 53–56.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id86f83b48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>14</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00053" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040845729" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I69c8b9208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2158124 Ontario Inc. v. Pitton</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 1023, 2017 ONSC 411</cite.query>, at paras. 57–61.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id86f83b58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>15</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00054" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I69c8e0308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al</ital>., 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id86f83b68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>16</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00055" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I69c907408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al</ital>., 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055</cite.query>, at paras. 1–2.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id86faac08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>17</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00056" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I69c92e508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al</ital>., 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055</cite.query>, at paras. 8–9.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id86faac18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>18</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00057" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I69c955608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al</ital>., 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055, at para. 10</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id86faac28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>19</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00058" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I69c97c708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al</ital>., 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055</cite.query>, at paras. 11–13.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id86faac38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>20</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00059" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I69c9ca908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al</ital>., 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055</cite.query>, at paras. 14–15.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id86faac48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>21</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00060" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I69c9ca938e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al</ital>., 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055, at para. 16</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id86faac58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>22</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00061" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I69c9f1a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al</ital>., 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055, at para. 17</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id86faac68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>23</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00062" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I69ca18b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al</ital>., 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055, at para. 19</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id86fd1d08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>24</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00063" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I69ca3fc08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al</ital>., 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055</cite.query>, at paras. 3–6.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id86fd1d18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>25</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00064" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I69ca66d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al</ital>., 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055, at para. 21</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id86fd1d28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>26</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00065" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2048322817" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I69ca8de08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>2298679 Ontario Inc. et al. v. Northern Homecare Solutions Inc. et al</ital>., 2019 CarswellOnt 7579, 2019 ONSC 3055</cite.query>, at paras. 31–32.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id86fd1d38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>27</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00066" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I69cab4f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc.</ital>, 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id86fd1d48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>28</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00067" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I69cadc008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc.</ital>, 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220</cite.query>, at paras. 2–4, and 8.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id86fd1d58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>29</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00068" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I69cb03108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc.</ital>, 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220, at para. 11</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id86fd1d68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>30</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00069" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I69cb2a208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc.</ital>, 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220</cite.query>, at paras. 53, and 55–56.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id86fd1d78e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>31</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00070" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I69cb51308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc.</ital>, 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220, at para. 57</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id86ff8e08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>32</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00071" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I69cb78408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc.</ital>, 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220</cite.query>, at paras. 62–63.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id86ff8e18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>33</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00072" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I69cb9f508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc.</ital>, 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220, at para. 71</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id86ff8e28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>34</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00073" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I69cbc6608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc.</ital>, 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220, at para. 175</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id86ff8e38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>35</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00074" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I69cbed708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc.</ital>, 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220</cite.query>, at paras. 176–178.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id86ff8e48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>36</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00075" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I69cc14808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc.</ital>, 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220, at para. 180</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id86ff8e58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>37</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00076" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I69cc3b908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc.</ital>, 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220</cite.query>, at paras. 181–183.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id86ff8e68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>38</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00077" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I69cc62a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc.</ital>, 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220</cite.query>, at paras. 184–185.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8701ff08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>39</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00078" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I69cc89b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc.</ital>, 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220, at para. 186</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8701ff18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>40</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00079" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I69ccb0c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc.</ital>, 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220, at para. 187</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8701ff28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>41</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00080" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047911217" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I69ccd7d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ranchman&apos;s Holding Inc. v. Bull Bustin&apos; Inc.</ital>, 2019 CarswellAlta 610, 2019 ABQB 220, at para. 188</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8701ff38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>42</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00081" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047090766" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69ccfee08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>SkyCope Technologies Inc. v. Jia</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 3343, 2018 BCSC 2204</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8701ff48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>43</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00082" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047090766" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69cd25f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>SkyCope Technologies Inc. v. Jia</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 3343, 2018 BCSC 2204, at para. 1</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8701ff58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>44</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00083" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047090766" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69cd4d008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>SkyCope Technologies Inc. v. Jia</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 3343, 2018 BCSC 2204</cite.query>, at paras. 2–4.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8701ff68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>45</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00084" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047090766" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69cd74108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>SkyCope Technologies Inc. v. Jia</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 3343, 2018 BCSC 2204, at para. 5</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id87047008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>46</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00085" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047090766" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69cd9b208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>SkyCope Technologies Inc. v. Jia</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 3343, 2018 BCSC 2204</cite.query>, at paras. 6–8.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id87047018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>47</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00086" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047090766" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69cdc2308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>SkyCope Technologies Inc. v. Jia</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 3343, 2018 BCSC 2204, at para. 10</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id87047028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>48</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00087" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047090766" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69cde9408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>SkyCope Technologies Inc. v. Jia</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 3343, 2018 BCSC 2204, at para. 12</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id87047038e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>49</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00088" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047090766" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69ce10508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>SkyCope Technologies Inc. v. Jia</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 3343, 2018 BCSC 2204</cite.query>, at paras. 23 and 25.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id87047048e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>50</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00089" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047090766" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69ce37608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>SkyCope Technologies Inc. v. Jia</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 3343, 2018 BCSC 2204, at para. 26</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8706e108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>51</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00090" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047090766" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69ce5e708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>SkyCope Technologies Inc. v. Jia</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 3343, 2018 BCSC 2204, at para. 28</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8706e118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>52</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00091" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047090766" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69ce5e738e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>SkyCope Technologies Inc. v. Jia</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 3343, 2018 BCSC 2204, at para. 39</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8706e128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>53</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00092" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69ce85828e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd</ital>., 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8706e138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>54</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00093" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69ced3a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd</ital>., 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176</cite.query>, at paras. 1–3, 5–6, and 18.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8706e148e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>55</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00094" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69cefab08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd</ital>., 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176</cite.query>, at paras. 20–21.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8706e158e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>56</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00095" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69cf21c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd</ital>., 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176</cite.query>, at paras. 22–23.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8706e168e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>57</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00096" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69cf48d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd</ital>., 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176</cite.query>, at paras. 24–26.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8706e178e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>58</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00097" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69cf6fe08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd</ital>., 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176, at para. 31</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id87095208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>59</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00098" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69cf96f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd</ital>., 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176, at para. 32</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id87095218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>60</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00099" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69cf96f38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd</ital>., 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176, at para. 33</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id87095228e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>61</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00100" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69cfbe008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd</ital>., 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176</cite.query>, at paras. 54–55.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id87095238e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>62</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00101" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69cfe5108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd</ital>., 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176, at para. 56</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id87095248e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>63</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00102" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69d00c208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd</ital>., 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176</cite.query>, at paras. 57 and 59.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id87095258e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>64</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00103" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044987913" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69d033308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Natural Trade Ltd. v. MYL Trading Ltd</ital>., 2018 CarswellBC 1850, 2018 BCSC 1176, at para. 61</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id87095268e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>65</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00104" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69d05a408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity Corp</ital>., 2018 CarswellBC 1309, 2018 BCSC 857</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id87095278e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>66</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00105" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69d081508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity Corp</ital>., 2018 CarswellBC 1309, 2018 BCSC 857, at para. 1</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id870bc308e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>67</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00106" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69d0a8608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity Corp</ital>., 2018 CarswellBC 1309, 2018 BCSC 857</cite.query>, at paras. 3, and 5–6.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id870bc318e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>68</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00107" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69d0cf708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity Corp</ital>., 2018 CarswellBC 1309, 2018 BCSC 857, at para. 7</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id870bc328e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>69</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00108" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69d0f6808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity Corp</ital>., 2018 CarswellBC 1309, 2018 BCSC 857</cite.query>, at paras. 11–12.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id870bc338e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>70</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00109" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69d144a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity Corp</ital>., 2018 CarswellBC 1309, 2018 BCSC 857</cite.query>, at paras. 13–14, and 17–18.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id870bc348e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>71</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00110" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69d16bb08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity Corp</ital>., 2018 CarswellBC 1309, 2018 BCSC 857</cite.query>, at paras. 19–20.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id870bc358e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>72</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00111" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69d192c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity Corp</ital>., 2018 CarswellBC 1309, 2018 BCSC 857</cite.query>, at paras. 21 and 23.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id870bc368e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>73</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00112" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69d1b9d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity Corp</ital>., 2018 CarswellBC 1309, 2018 BCSC 857</cite.query>, at paras. 25–29.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id870e3408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>74</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00113" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69d1e0e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity Corp</ital>., 2018 CarswellBC 1309, 2018 BCSC 857</cite.query>, at paras. 34–35, and 37.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id870e3418e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>75</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00114" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044622847" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69d207f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>National Bank Financial Inc. v. Canaccord Genuity Corp</ital>., 2018 CarswellBC 1309, 2018 BCSC 857</cite.query>, at paras. 92–93.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id870e3428e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>76</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00115" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044476992" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69d22f008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Quick Pass Master Tutorial School Ltd. v. Zhao</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1038, 2018 BCSC 683</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id870e3438e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>77</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00116" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044476992" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69d27d208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Quick Pass Master Tutorial School Ltd. v. Zhao</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1038, 2018 BCSC 683</cite.query>, at paras. 1 and 3.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id870e3448e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>78</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00117" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044476992" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69d27d238e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Quick Pass Master Tutorial School Ltd. v. Zhao</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1038, 2018 BCSC 683, at para. 5</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id870e3458e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>79</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00118" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044476992" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69d2a4308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Quick Pass Master Tutorial School Ltd. v. Zhao</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1038, 2018 BCSC 683, at para. 25</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id870e3468e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>80</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00119" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044476992" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69d2cb408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Quick Pass Master Tutorial School Ltd. v. Zhao</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1038, 2018 BCSC 683, at para. 30</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id870e3478e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>81</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00120" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044476992" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69d2f2508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Quick Pass Master Tutorial School Ltd. v. Zhao</ital>, 2018 CarswellBC 1038, 2018 BCSC 683</cite.query>, at paras. 45–46.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id870e3488e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>82</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00121" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042882399" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I69d319608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Nu Image v. Seager</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 15864, 2017 ONSC 6101 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8710a508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>83</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00122" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042882399" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I69d340708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Nu Image v. Seager</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 15864, 2017 ONSC 6101 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 2–4.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8710a518e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>84</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00123" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042882399" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I69d367808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Nu Image v. Seager</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 15864, 2017 ONSC 6101 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 5–7.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8710a528e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>85</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00124" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042882399" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I69d38e908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Nu Image v. Seager</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 15864, 2017 ONSC 6101 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 8–11.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8710a538e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>86</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00125" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042882399" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I69d3b5a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Nu Image v. Seager</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 15864, 2017 ONSC 6101 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 15–16.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8710a548e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>87</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00126" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042882399" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I69d3dcb08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Nu Image v. Seager</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 15864, 2017 ONSC 6101 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 27–31.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8710a558e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>88</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00127" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042882399" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I69d42ad08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Nu Image v. Seager</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 15864, 2017 ONSC 6101 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paragraphs 41–43.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8710a568e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>89</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00128" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042882399" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I69d451e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Nu Image v. Seager</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 15864, 2017 ONSC 6101 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paragraph 47.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8710a578e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>90</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00129" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038061488" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I69d478f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>SyberWorks Inc. v. Organization Metrics Inc</ital>., 2016 CarswellOnt 447, 2016 ONSC 333</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id87131608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>91</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00130" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038061488" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I69d4a0008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>SyberWorks Inc. v. Organization Metrics Inc</ital>., 2016 CarswellOnt 447, 2016 ONSC 333, at para. 14</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id87131618e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>92</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00131" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038061488" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I69d4c7108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>SyberWorks Inc. v. Organization Metrics Inc</ital>., 2016 CarswellOnt 447, 2016 ONSC 333</cite.query>, at paras. 1–2, and 6–9.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id87131628e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>93</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00132" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038061488" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I69d4ee208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>SyberWorks Inc. v. Organization Metrics Inc</ital>., 2016 CarswellOnt 447, 2016 ONSC 333, at para. 26</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id87131638e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>94</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00133" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038061488" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I69d515308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>SyberWorks Inc. v. Organization Metrics Inc</ital>., 2016 CarswellOnt 447, 2016 ONSC 333</cite.query>, at paras. 29–30.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id87131648e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>95</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00134" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038061488" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I69d53c408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>SyberWorks Inc. v. Organization Metrics Inc</ital>., 2016 CarswellOnt 447, 2016 ONSC 333</cite.query>, at paras. 31 and 38.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id87131658e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>96</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00135" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038061488" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I69d563508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>SyberWorks Inc. v. Organization Metrics Inc</ital>., 2016 CarswellOnt 447, 2016 ONSC 333, at para. 39</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id87158708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>97</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00136" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2033737736" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I69d58a608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Enviro Trace Ltd. v. Sheichuk</ital>, 2014 CarswellAlta 1073, 2014 ABQB 381</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00137" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035261741" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I69d58a638e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2015 CarswellAlta 35, 2015 ABQB 28</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id87158718e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>98</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00138" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2033737736" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I69d5b1708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Enviro Trace Ltd. v. Sheichuk</ital>, 2014 CarswellAlta 1073, 2014 ABQB 381</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00139" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035261741" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I69d5b1738e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2015 CarswellAlta 35, 2015 ABQB 28</cite.query>, at paras. 30–33.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id87158728e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>99</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00140" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2033737736" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I69d5ff908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Enviro Trace Ltd. v. Sheichuk</ital>, 2014 CarswellAlta 1073, 2014 ABQB 381</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00141" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035261741" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I69d5ff938e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2015 CarswellAlta 35, 2015 ABQB 28</cite.query>, at paras. 34–36.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id87158738e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>100</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00142" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2033737736" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I69d626a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Enviro Trace Ltd. v. Sheichuk</ital>, 2014 CarswellAlta 1073, 2014 ABQB 381</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00143" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035261741" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I69d626a38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2015 CarswellAlta 35, 2015 ABQB 28</cite.query>, at paras. 38–39, and 41.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id87158748e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>101</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00144" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2030681325" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I69d674c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>RBC Dominion Securities Inc. v. Macdonald</ital>, 2013 CarswellBC 1669, 2013 BCSC 992</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id87158758e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>102</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00145" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027654193" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I69d674c38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Fuller Western Rubber Linings Ltd. v. Spence Corrosion Services Ltd.</ital>, 2012 CarswellAlta 777, 2012 ABCA 137</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id87158768e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>103</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00146" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027654193" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I69d69bd08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Fuller Western Rubber Linings Ltd. v. Spence Corrosion Services Ltd.</ital>, 2012 CarswellAlta 777, 2012 ABCA 137</cite.query>, at paras. 2 and 8.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8717f808e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>104</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00147" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027654193" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I69d6e9f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Fuller Western Rubber Linings Ltd. v. Spence Corrosion Services Ltd.</ital>, 2012 CarswellAlta 777, 2012 ABCA 137</cite.query>, at paras. 9–11.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8717f818e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>105</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00148" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027291812" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I69d711008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Parrish &amp; Heimbecker Ltd. v. Delmar Commodities Ltd</ital>., 2012 CarswellMan 114, 2012 MBQB 48</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8717f828e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>106</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00149" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027291812" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I69d738108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Parrish &amp; Heimbecker Ltd. v. Delmar Commodities Ltd</ital>., 2012 CarswellMan 114, 2012 MBQB 48</cite.query>, at paras. 1–2, 6, 14, 18–19, and 33.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8717f838e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>107</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00150" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027291812" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I69d75f208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Parrish &amp; Heimbecker Ltd. v. Delmar Commodities Ltd</ital>., 2012 CarswellMan 114, 2012 MBQB 48, at para. 34</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8717f848e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>108</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00151" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027291812" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I69d786308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Parrish &amp; Heimbecker Ltd. v. Delmar Commodities Ltd</ital>., 2012 CarswellMan 114, 2012 MBQB 48, at para. 39</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8717f858e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>109</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175959" w-seq-number="00152" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027291812" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I69d7ad408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Parrish &amp; Heimbecker Ltd. v. Delmar Commodities Ltd</ital>., 2012 CarswellMan 114, 2012 MBQB 48</cite.query>, at paras. 44, 50 and 56.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 7:6<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
