<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information ยง 4:3<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I5089a870411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>4.</label.designator><headtext>Confidential Business Information and the Employment Relationship</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I5090fb70411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>II.</label.designator><headtext>Duty of Good Faith</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f611266ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>ยง </label.name><label.designator>4:3.</label.designator><headtext>Notice of Resignation</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Although often overlooked by both employers and employees, employees have a duty to provide reasonable notice of resignation to their employers. <eos/><bos/>Generally, the more senior an employee is, the longer the required period of reasonable notice of departure. <eos/><bos/>For almost all junior and lower level employees, reasonable notice will be expected to be two weeks. <eos/><bos/>The law usually sets an expected length of notice of resignation that is commensurate with the degree of responsibility of the employee&apos;s position. <eos/><bos/>The primary purpose of such notice is to allow a diligent employer enough time to replace the employee without jeopardizing its business interests and relationships. <eos/><bos/>Specifically, the employer must be able to find and train a replacement employee, as well as ensure that its customer relationships and employee situation are solidified.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></section.body></section><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI ยง 4:3<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
