<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information ยง 1:9<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I4d7849c0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>1.</label.designator><headtext>Confidential Business Information in Historical Context</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I4dd89230411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>II.</label.designator><headtext>Modern Concept of Intellectual Property</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f59bf56ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>ยง </label.name><label.designator>1:9.</label.designator><headtext>Patent</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Patent and copyright law protect the expression of an idea rather than the idea itself. <eos/><bos/>A patent is, in substance, a contract between the government and the inventor under which the inventor discloses to the public the specifications of an invention, which might otherwise have been kept secret, so that the public may benefit by the disclosure and use the invention after the patent has expired. <eos/><bos/>Society grants the holder the exclusive right to exploit the information for a given period in return for the inventor&apos;s agreement to allow the information to be used by the public after the given period has expired.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The <ital>Patent Act</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Icdf9bfe08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>] protects a work only if it is a novel work which has an industrial or commercial use. <eos/><bos/>This includes discoveries that are useful, novel and not obvious to a person having ordinary skill in the technical field related to the discovery. <eos/><bos/>For example, patents may be granted for a new process, machine, manufacture, composition of matter or other invention. <eos/><bos/>No patent will be granted for methods of doing business, newly discovered laws of nature or purely mental processes, but must fit into a recognized category such as art, process, manufacture or composition of matter.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Icdf9bfe18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Icdf9bfe08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>R.S.C. 1985, c. P-4.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Icdf9bfe18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>R.S.C. 1985, c. P-4, s. 27. <eos/><bos/>See also G.F. Henderson, <ital>Trade-Marks Law of Canada</ital> (Scarborough: Carswell, 1993), p. 6.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI ยง 1:9<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
