<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information ยง 8:18<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I59ba4210411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>8.</label.designator><headtext>Practical Advice for Protecting Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I59fa7f60411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>III.</label.designator><headtext>Employment Duties and Written Contracts</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I59facd80411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>A.</label.designator><headtext>Review of Duties and Acknowledgment by Employee</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f749d66ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>ยง </label.name><label.designator>8:18.</label.designator><headtext>Signing an Agreement</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>With respect to the actual execution of an employment agreement, the employer should ensure that the employee clearly understands what he or she is signing. <eos/><bos/>The employer should review the contract with the employee on a paragraph by paragraph basis and should specifically address each clause relating to the use of confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The employee should be given the opportunity to read and understand each of the terms of the agreement. <eos/><bos/>Finally, the employee should be given reasonable time to consider the terms of the agreement and to obtain appropriate legal advice. <eos/><bos/>In most cases, the courts will be sympathetic to an employee where it appears that the employee was under any duress or pressure to sign an agreement.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Employers should consider the impact on the employee of each clause relating to the use of confidential information. <eos/><bos/>This is particularly true of non-competition clauses. <eos/><bos/>For example, where an employee will not be able to work in a certain geographic area, industry or business, and will be unable to find alternative employment or even earn a living, the employer should consider narrowing the clause. <eos/><bos/>Most clauses should be worded to cover a defined territory and to prevent the employee from attacking specific corporate opportunities or customer connections as a result of information obtained during the employment relationship.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Where possible, standard form contracts should be avoided. <eos/><bos/>Every employment contract should be adjusted to reflect the particular terms of the individual employment relationship. <eos/><bos/>At the very least, the basic terms, including the employee&apos;s name, position, remuneration, duties, etc., should be specifically set forth as part of the agreement, as opposed to merely being filled in on a pre-printed contract. <eos/><bos/>In addition, the terms of the agreement must be consistent with all corporate policies. <eos/><bos/>A copy of the contract and relevant company policies should be provided to the employee.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Employees should sign an agreement before starting employment in order to avoid a claim for constructive dismissal. <eos/><bos/>Similarly, where an employee receives a promotion, the employee should sign any new agreement prior to the change actually occurring.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></section.body></section><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI ยง 8:18<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
