<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 4:53<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I5089a870411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>4.</label.designator><headtext>Confidential Business Information and the Employment Relationship</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I52517020411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>V.</label.designator><headtext>Fiduciary Duty</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I53a16fc0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>B.</label.designator><headtext>Remedies Table—Employment Relationship—Breach of Fiduciary Duty</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f686546ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>4:53.</label.designator><headtext>De Rose &amp; Associates Ltd. v. Brugnano</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><ital>De Rose &amp; Associates Ltd. v. Brugnano</ital>, 2005 CarswellOnt 2937 (Ont. S.C.J.), reversed in part 2007 CarswellOnt 7122 (Ont. Div. Ct.)</headtext><eos/><eop/></head><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Award</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Judgment in the amount of $12,971.12</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Summary of Facts:</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff was a paralegal firm assisting persons having been injured in an accident to obtain benefits and recovery from insurers. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff claimed that its former employee Cariati left her employment and joined the defendant Krylov&apos;s law firm. <eos/><bos/>There she and Krylov solicited clients of the plaintiff and had them move their files to Krylov&apos;s law firm. <eos/><bos/>In mid November 2000, Cariati was hired by the plaintiff and trained as a paralegal. <eos/><bos/>While working for the plaintiff, she opened over a hundred files, all through her own contacts and through her promotion. <eos/><bos/>In some cases, a referral fee was approved and paid to Cariati&apos;s referral source by the plaintiff.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Reasons Given by Court for Award:</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>There is no hard and fast rule as to who is a fiduciary. <eos/><bos/>While fiduciaries are often top management in a business, this is not a necessary feature in order to find an employee to be a fiduciary. <eos/><bos/>Cariati owed a fiduciary duty to her former employer. <eos/><bos/>From early on in her employment, she was almost exclusively responsible for the recruitment, interview and servicing of her clients. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff authorized her to enter into contracts with them and, according to Cariati, she was authorized to modify the terms of the retainer agreement between the plaintiff and the client as she saw fit. <eos/><bos/>She had almost exclusive contact with these clients and acquired a good deal of confidential information from them. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff trusted that she would act in the best interest of the employer in her dealings with these clients. <eos/><bos/>The employer paid the referral fees as directed by Cariati and was dependant on Cariati to generate the revenue for the firm from these files. <eos/><bos/>When Cariati left, the employer was vulnerable to losing all of these files as Ms. Cariati had the trust of the clients, had virtually exclusive contact with them, knew what needed to be done for each of these clients, and she knew the potential value of the files. <eos/><bos/>She was a key employee of the plaintiff with a high degree of control over the client files under her care.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A departing employee cannot, for a reasonable period of time, target and directly solicit clients of the former employer. <eos/><bos/>The number of files transferred in October suggest that the change over did not occur randomly but rather was coordinated and the result of clients being targeted. <eos/><bos/>She did, in fact, call and solicit former clients. <eos/><bos/>The number of clients successfully solicited was the 32 files that Cariati handled prior to leaving her employment, and that ended up at Krylov&apos;s firm within a relatively short period of time following her departure.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>It is unrealistic to expect a precise calculation of damages. <eos/><bos/>Damages are calculated based on the evidence presented and a reasonable and fair assessment of the likely loss based on this evidence.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The bills for 27 of the files were put in evidence and totalled $27,733.11. <eos/><bos/>On the assumption that the five additional files transferred would have had a similar amount of time and disbursements, five twenty-sevenths of this figure were added to arrive at an assumed billing figure of $32,868.87. <eos/><bos/>This figure was used as a starting figure representing the lost investment made by the plaintiff in the 32 transferred files. <eos/><bos/>This figure will then be adjusted to take into account certain errors and duplication in the accounts, the fact that some accounts had generated revenue, sometimes substantial, prior to their transfer to Krylov, and the fact that some files would have been lost even if the clients had not been contacted by Cariati. <eos/><bos/>Finally, the figure was reduced by an estimate of the amount which will be recovered in the small claims court actions, net of unrecoverable expenses to be incurred in those proceedings. <eos/><bos/>Taking all of these into account, the court applied an assumed net recovery which on average was $250 per file for the 27 files for a total of $6,750. <eos/><bos/>The damages were therefore assessed at $12,971.12.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></section.body></section><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 4:53<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
