<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 7:28<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I56d26460411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>7.</label.designator><headtext>Remedies for Breach of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I59b0a520411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>V.</label.designator><headtext>International Developments</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f749a06ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>7:28.</label.designator><headtext>Generally</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Despite various reports that the Canadian government has considered enacting criminal sanctions to combat the growing problem of economic espionage, including the theft of confidential business information, there has been no formal legislative action to date. <eos/><bos/>On the other hand, there have been major developments in the United States, which may impact Canadian businesses. <eos/><bos/>Specifically, on October 11, 1996, the United States signed into law the <ital>Economic Espionage Act of 1996</ital> (the “EEA”).<eos/><bos/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id942d9408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The EEA&apos;s definition of “trade secret” is very similar to the one set forth in the <ital>Uniform Trade Secrets Act</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id942d9418e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>] but was broadened to recognize the impact of new technology on information storage.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id942d9428e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">3</footnote.reference>] The EEA makes the theft of trade secrets a federal criminal offence and provides broad authority to prosecute offences committed both inside and outside the United States, including crimes committed via the Internet. <eos/><bos/>The EEA also makes it a criminal offence for a third party to knowingly receive trade secrets that were taken as a result of such an offence.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Of relevance from the Canadian perspective is the fact that the EEA applies to American individuals, corporations and organizations that commit offences outside the United States. <eos/><bos/>Further, the EEA applies to offences committed outside the United States where an act in furtherance of the offence was committed in the United States.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Significantly, the EEA provides for:</paratext><list><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(a)</label.designator></head><paratext>prison terms of up to 10 years;</paratext></para></list.item><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(b)</label.designator></head><paratext>fines of up to $500,000 for individuals and $5 million for corporations and organizations;</paratext></para></list.item><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(c)</label.designator></head><paratext>increased prison terms and fines if a foreign power is to benefit from the crime;</paratext></para></list.item><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(d)</label.designator></head><paratext>criminal forfeiture of property derived from the proceeds of violations or used to facilitate a violation; and</paratext></para></list.item><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(e)</label.designator></head><paratext>civil actions to obtain injunctive relief.<eos/></paratext></para></list.item></list><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>There is an increasing international focus on the protection of confidential business information, with many countries enacting legislation. <eos/><bos/>There is also added recognition of trade secret law principles in various international agreements such as the North American Free Trade Agreement and the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade. <eos/><bos/>Under NAFTA and GATT, trade secrets are defined in a manner very similar to Canadian legal principles, and both agreements require member nations to implement remedies for misappropriation, including damages and injunctive relief.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Id942d9408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Enacting 18 U.S.C. §§ 1831 to 1839.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id942d9418e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>For further discussion of this Act and a comparison of the Act with the American common law of trade secrets, see R. Klitze, “The Uniform Trade Secrets Act” (1980), 64 Marq. <eos/><bos/>L. Rev. 277. <eos/><bos/>See also S. Davidson and R. DeMay, <begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>“Application of Trade Secret Law to New Technology—Unwinding the Tangled Web”<end.quote refid="QT_0001"/> (1986), 12 Wm. Mitchell L. Rev. 579.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id942d9428e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>For further information regarding the American legislation, see <cite.query w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="NA" w-normalized-cite="ELLTHORBURNBIs3:3" w-pub-number="0236187" ID="Id94300508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">section 3:3</cite.query> and Mark Halligan&apos;s “Trade Secrets” home page on-line at http://www.rmarkhalligan.com (accessed December 1, 2008).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 7:28<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
