<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 2:4<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I4e5fc390411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>2.</label.designator><headtext>Legal Bases Used by the Courts for the Protection of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I4e678bc0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>II.</label.designator><headtext>Property Theory</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f5c3096ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>2:4.</label.designator><headtext>Criticism—Information May Be Shared Without Losing Possession</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Those critical of the property theory have also argued that confidential business information, in order to be “possessed”, must be able to be excluded from the possession of others. <eos/><bos/>In our economic system, this is a primary factor in determining value. <eos/><bos/>Because it is capable of universal possession, information does not derive its value from inherent scarcity; its value derives from the creation and preservation of scarcity.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id0b473108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>It is true that knowledge may be shared and others may obtain copies of it while the information is still in the hands of the owner. <eos/><bos/>Furthermore, a property right in confidential business information does not preclude the independent creation by another of the same idea, in much the same manner that it is possible for a copyrighted work to be independently created by two individuals. <eos/><bos/>When information is shared, there is no permanent deprivation, but only a loss or reduction of market advantage and market power.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id0b473118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>] Furthermore, information cannot be “stolen” in the traditional sense, as something cannot be returned when it has not been taken away. <eos/><bos/>In sum, what differentiates information from property is its capacity for universal possession.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id0b473128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">3</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>On the other hand, confidential business information may be said to be property inasmuch as it generates income for its owner, it is competed for by other individuals in society, and in some measure the law establishes scarcity just as it does with tangible property. <eos/><bos/>Confidential business information belongs only to the individual or individuals who created or inherited it.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id0b473138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">4</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A property right in confidential business information precludes others from the unauthorized use or appropriation of the information. <eos/><bos/>Where copies are taken and used without the consent of the owner, the value of the property and the ability to sell it are permanently diminished. <eos/><bos/>The focus on possession would seem to be misguided, as value in all forms of intangible property, including intellectual property such as patents and copyright, derives from the use which may be made of the property and not from physical possession of the property. <eos/><bos/>This latter concept is not unknown with respect to the issue of property in land. <eos/><bos/>Where an individual with no rights to the land uses it, the user develops rights to the land, such as easements, which thereby diminish the value of the land to the rightful owner.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Id0b473108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>R.J. Roberts, “Is Information Property?” (1987), 3 I.P.J. 209.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id0b473118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A. Birrell, <ital>Seven Lectures on the Law and History of Copyright in Books</ital> (New Jersey: Rothman Reprints Inc., 1971), pp. 12-13.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id0b473128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>R.J. Roberts, “Is Information Property?” (1987), 3 I.P.J. 209.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id0b473138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>4</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A. Alchian, “Some Economics of Property Rights”, <ital>Il Politico</ital>, No. 4 (1965), p. 30.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 2:4<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
