<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 7:26<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I56d26460411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>7.</label.designator><headtext>Remedies for Breach of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I58eb5950411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>III.</label.designator><headtext>Damages</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I59918460411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>B.</label.designator><headtext>Determining the Quantum of Damages</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f7499a6ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>7:26.</label.designator><headtext>Damages Based on the Type of Confidential Information Appropriated</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>There seems to be no single standard for the assessment of damages for breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>Damages may be fixed using the method that seems most appropriate in the circumstances. <eos/><bos/>This may be done assessing:</paratext><list><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(a)</label.designator></head><paratext>the amount of the diminished value of the information in the hands of the plaintiff after the breach occurred;[<footnote.reference refid="Id93803d08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></list.item><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(b)</label.designator></head><paratext>the remuneration the defendant should have paid to the plaintiff for use of the information (as in a <ital>quantum meruit</ital> claim);[<footnote.reference refid="Id9382ae08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>] or</paratext></para></list.item><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(c)</label.designator></head><paratext>the market value of the information based on a valuation between a willing buyer and a willing seller.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id9382ae18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">3</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></list.item></list><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1967018556" w-pub-number="0004891" ID="I7785b8b18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Seager v. Copydex</cite.query> Ltd.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id9382ae28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">4</footnote.reference>] the English Court of Appeal held that the market value of the information in question depended on whether the information involved a true inventive step, or whether it could have been provided by any competent expert. <eos/><bos/>If it were a true invention, damages would be calculated on the basis of the royalties payable on the sale of the invention. <eos/><bos/>If the information were easily provided by an expert, damages would be assessed on the basis of the fee payable to the expert for the information.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1969019738" w-pub-number="0004891" ID="I77862de18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Seager v. Copydex Ltd. (No.</cite.query> 2)</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id9382ae38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">5</footnote.reference>] Lord Denning said that damages were to be assessed on the basis of the value of the information which the defendant company took, and that the value of information falls into one of three categories:</paratext><list><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(1)</label.designator></head><paratext>information which involves no particular inventive step but is the sort of information which can be obtained by employing a competent consultant. <eos/><bos/>In such cases, damages should be equivalent to the consultant&apos;s fee since <begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>“the defendant company, by taking the information, would only have saved themselves the time and trouble of employing a consultant”<end.quote refid="QT_0001"/>;</paratext></para></list.item><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(2)</label.designator></head><paratext>information which involves an inventive step or something so unusual that it could not be obtained by employing a consultant. <eos/><bos/>In this case, the quantum of damages is to be assessed on the basis of the price which a willing buyer would pay for it and which a willing seller in the plaintiff&apos;s position would accept for it;</paratext></para></list.item><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(3)</label.designator></head><paratext>confidential information which is “very special indeed”.<eos/><bos/> In such a case, it may be proper to calculate damages as a capitalized royalty.<eos/></paratext></para></list.item></list><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Once damages are paid, the property in the information vests in the defendant in the same way as it does in cases where damages are awarded for conversion. <eos/><bos/>This reasoning, however, would seem to allow a defendant to buy the right to infringe the plaintiff&apos;s right to its information, something that could affect not only the rightful user of the information, but also any licensees.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The <cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1967018556" w-pub-number="0004891" ID="I7787db918e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seager</ital></cite.query> decision was distinguished in <ital>Dowson &amp; Mason Ltd. v. Potter,</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id93851f08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">6</footnote.reference>] where the court held that the proper basis for assessment of damages was the plaintiffs&apos; loss of profits resulting from the wrongful disclosure and the use of the confidential information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id93851f18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">7</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The central issue on the appeal in <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2040732478" w-pub-number="0005506" ID="I778ae8d18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Nissen v. Durham Regional Police Services</cite.query> Board</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id93851f28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">8</footnote.reference>] was: what are the required elements for a claim for damages against the police for breach of a promise of confidentiality made to a citizen reporting criminal wrongdoing? <eos/><bos/>Stack was awarded damages against the Police for what was pleaded as breach of informer privilege. <eos/><bos/>Stack went to the Police to tell them that she had learned that the teenaged son of her neighbours had broken into another neighbour&apos;s house and stolen some guns. <eos/><bos/>Stack asserted that she had asked the Police and been promised by them that her identity and the fact that she had reported the theft of the guns would be treated as confidential. <eos/><bos/>Unbeknownst to Stack, the Police videotaped her interview. <eos/><bos/>Her neighbours&apos; sons were charged and a recording of Stack&apos;s interview was included in the disclosure provided in the criminal proceedings. <eos/><bos/>Stack was subsequently subjected to threatening and harassing conduct by the parents of the accused. <eos/><bos/>Stack and her family were so distressed by this conduct that they sold their home and moved to another community. <eos/><bos/>As a result of these events, Stack had been diagnosed as having post-traumatic stress disorder.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id93851f38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">9</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge found as a fact that the Officer had promised Stack anonymity and confidentiality. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge found that the police owed a common law duty not to disclose the identity of an informer, and that even if the duty was not absolute, reasonable care had not been taken in the circumstances. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge rejected the claim for damages arising from the sale of the Whitby home and purchase of the new home, as no expert evidence was called as to loss of value. <eos/><bos/>He also rejected a claim for <ital>Charter</ital> damages, and the claims Stack and her husband had asserted for lost income or lost opportunity. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge did, however, award Stack general damages for emotional and psychological injury. <eos/><bos/>That claim was supported by her own evidence, that of her family and friends, and that of Dr. Silver, who had diagnosed her with post-traumatic stress disorder, an opinion that was not contradicted by the expert retained by the Police. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge found that the psychological injury Stack had suffered rose above the level of ordinary upset or anxiety, and was therefore compensable at law. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge found that the failure of the Police to act after they learned of the neighbour&apos;s harassing behaviour, other than the one brief telephone conversation, was an aggravating factor. <eos/><bos/>He rejected the claim for punitive damages and fixed the general damages in the amount of $345,000. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge also awarded <ital>Family Law Act</ital>, damages for loss of guidance, care and companionship, in the amount of $65,000 to the husband, and $25,000 to each child.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id93851f48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">10</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Court of Appeal was not referred to any case in which damages for breach of informer privilege had been awarded. <eos/><bos/>However, in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1983169041" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I778d32c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Bisaillon c. Keable</ital> (1983), 2 D.L.R. (4th) 193, [1983] 2 S.C.R. 60, 4</cite.query> Admin. L.R. 205, 37 C.R. (3d) 289, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1983169041" w-pub-number="0005466" ID="I778d32c38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">51 N.R. 81, 7 C.C.C. (3d) 385, 1983 CarswellQue 384, 1983 CarswellQue 28, 10 W.C.B. 359, [1983] A.C.S. No. 65, [1983] S.C.J. No. 65 (S.C.C.)</cite.query>, Beetz J. stated that although there was no precedent on the point, he would have no difficulty in finding that an action for damages for such a breach would lie. <eos/><bos/>The Police do not dispute that proposition. <eos/><bos/>However, the Police did argue that the trial judge erred by finding that a plaintiff only need prove that the police made a promise of confidentiality in exchange for information in order to establish the privilege. <eos/><bos/>They submitted that the elements for a civil claim for damages for breach of a promise of confidentiality by the police will not lie without proof of two other elements, namely, (1) that the information provided must be difficult or impossible to obtain; and (2) that the informer must be likely to suffer harm or danger if his or her identity is disclosed.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id93851f58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">11</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Sharpe disagreed with the Police submission that the trial judge erred with respect to the necessary elements for the claim, concluding that should be decided as a civil claim for damages for breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>The fundamental point was that, on the findings of the trial judge, the Officer made a promise of confidentiality and anonymity to Stack in exchange for the information she provided. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge found that the promise was breached and Stack suffered damages as a result. <eos/><bos/>Those findings brought the case squarely within the long-recognized cause of action for breach of confidence, and Stack was accordingly entitled to recover on that basis. <eos/><bos/>While other considerations may come into play in a criminal case where the prosecution is resisting disclosure of the identity of a confidential informer to an accused, this was a civil case between the police and an individual who was promised confidentiality. <eos/><bos/>That promise gave rise to a common law and equitable right entitling Stack to have her identity kept confidential. <eos/><bos/>Her right was not contingent upon other ways the Police may have had to get the information she provided, or on what the Police thought about the danger she faced. <eos/><bos/>Difficulty in obtaining the information and fear of harm to the witness may well be the rationales underlying the doctrine of informer privilege in criminal law, but Justice Sharpe was not persuaded that they are necessary elements to sustain the privilege, even in a criminal case. <eos/><bos/>There is no reason to qualify the right to sue for breach of confidence by adding additional elements necessary to establish a civil claim for damages. <eos/><bos/>To do so would put the citizen interacting with the police in an impossible situation. <eos/><bos/>Stack had no way of determining whether the Police could obtain from another source the information she was offering. <eos/><bos/>Nor did she have any way of gauging what the Police considered to be the risk of harm she faced should her identity be disclosed. <eos/><bos/>She explained her fear of harm to the Officer and that fear ultimately proved to be well-founded. <eos/><bos/>She was entitled to rely on the Officer&apos;s promise of confidentiality in exchange for her cooperation in giving him the information she had.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id93879008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">12</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Sharpe also did not accept the submission that because the Police did not follow their own Directive for confidential informers, Stack&apos;s civil claim for damages was defeated. <eos/><bos/>While the Officer may have thought that Stack was not a confidential informer within the meaning of the Directive, Justice Sharpe failed to see how that could affect her right to claim for breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>Her claim rested upon the promise of confidentiality that the Officer made, and the exchange of information that followed as a result. <eos/><bos/>She had no way of determining whether she fit within the terms of the Directive, and it would be obviously unfair to deny her claim on the basis of a Directive that had never been explained or brought to her attention.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id93879018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">13</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Police submitted that the damages awarded by the trial judge were excessive. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge observed that it was difficult to fix a reasonable amount for the damages Stack and her family had suffered. <eos/><bos/>He found that the effect on Stack had been “severe”, that her life had been “irretrievably altered”, and he was satisfied by the evidence of Dr. Silver <begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>“that it is unlikely that she will ever be the same as she was before these incidents.”<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0002"/> The trial judge raised the issue of whether the “cap” on personal injury damages applied to damages for psychological injury. <eos/><bos/>Stack&apos;s counsel cited two Supreme Court of Canada decisions in which damages for psychological injury were claimed: <cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00007" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2032366845" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I77965a808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Robinson c. Films Cinar inc.</ital> (2013), 366 D.L.R. (4th) 193</cite.query>, (<case.history><ital>sub nom.</ital></case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00008" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2032366845" w-pub-number="0005156" ID="I77965a828e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Cinar Corp. v. Robinson) [2013] 3 S.C.R. 1168, 8</cite.query> C.C.L.T. (4th) 1, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00009" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2032366845" w-pub-number="0006462" ID="I77965a848e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">118 C.P.R. (4th) 1, 452 N.R. 123, 297 C.R.R. (2d) 299, 2013 CarswellQue 12345, 2013 CarswellQue 12346, 235 A.C.W.S. (3d) 495, [2013] S.C.J. No. 73, 2013 SCC 73 (S.C.C.)</cite.query>, and <ital>Bella v. Young</ital> (2006), (<case.history><ital>sub nom.</ital></case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00010" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2008054582" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I77965a8d8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Young v. Bella) 261 D.L.R. (4th) 516, [2006] 1 S.C.R. 108, 254 Nfld. &amp; P.E.I.R. 26, 37</cite.query> C.C.L.T. (3d) 161, 21 C.P.C. (6th) 1, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00011" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2008054582" w-pub-number="0005466" ID="I77965a918e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">343 N.R. 360, 764 A.P.R. 26</cite.query>, (<case.history><ital>sub nom.</ital></case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00012" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2008054582" w-pub-number="0005356" ID="I77965a948e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Young c. Bella) [2006] R.R.A. 1, 2006 CarswellNfld 19, 2006 CarswellNfld 20, 145 A.C.W.S. (3d) 343, [2006] S.C.J. No. 2, 2006 SCC 3 (S.C.C.)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>In both those cases, the Supreme Court held that the “cap” did not apply and awarded damages for psychological injury of $400,000 in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00013" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2032366845" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I77965a9c8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cinar</ital></cite.query> and $430,000 in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00014" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2008054582" w-pub-number="0005466" ID="I77965aa68e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Young</ital></cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge stated that the damages were not as severe as the damages in those two decisions, that something less would be appropriate, and awarded $345,000. <eos/><bos/>As that amount was below the cap, the issue of whether the cap applied did not have to be decided.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id93879028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">14</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Sharpe was not persuaded by the submission that the trial judge placed too much reliance on <cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00015" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2032366845" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I779ff7718e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cinar</ital></cite.query> and <cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00016" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2008054582" w-pub-number="0005466" ID="I779ff77b8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Young</ital></cite.query>, as the harm suffered by the plaintiffs in both <cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00017" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2032366845" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I779ff77e8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cinar</ital></cite.query> and <cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00018" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2008054582" w-pub-number="0005466" ID="I779ff7888e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Young</ital></cite.query> involved more than just psychological injury. <eos/><bos/>First, the trial judge explicitly recognized that the harm suffered was less than that suffered in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00019" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2032366845" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I779ff78b8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cinar</ital></cite.query> and <cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00020" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2008054582" w-pub-number="0005466" ID="I779ff7958e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Young</ital></cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>Second, in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00021" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2032366845" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I779ff7988e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cinar</ital></cite.query>, the damage award consisted of several components, including a compensatory award of over $600,000 for pecuniary loss and over $1.7 million in disgorgement of profits, both awards for the copyright infringement, and $500,000 in punitive damages. <eos/><bos/>An additional $400,000 was awarded for psychological injury. <eos/><bos/>The award for psychological injury was a discrete award in addition to the damages awarded for the breach of copyright. <eos/><bos/>While the Supreme Court agreed that the damages for psychological injury were analogous to those claimed by the victim of defamation, it was clear that the award was not for loss of reputation. <eos/><bos/>Justice Sharpe did not see why an award for psychological harm resulting from a copyright infringement could not shed some light on an award for a similar harm arising under a different cause of action. <eos/><bos/>Third, while <cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00022" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2008054582" w-pub-number="0005466" ID="I779ff7a28e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Young</ital></cite.query> was pleaded as both a defamation and negligence action, the claim for defamation was struck and the action proceeded as one for negligence. <eos/><bos/>The psychological injury complained of was not unlike that suffered by Stack. <eos/><bos/>Justice Sharpe did not agree that the fact that a similar harm was caused by a different wrongful act made <cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00023" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2008054582" w-pub-number="0005466" ID="I779ff7a58e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Young</ital></cite.query> so different in quality that the trial judge erred in using it as a reference point when assessing damages. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge was faced with what he properly recognized to be a difficult task. <eos/><bos/>On the evidence, he found that Stack had suffered a severe psychological injury that had radically affected her outlook and enjoyment of life. <eos/><bos/>Her friends and her family testified that she was a different person since the injury, and she presented unchallenged expert evidence that she had suffered from post-traumatic stress disorder that was difficult to treat and likely to be permanent. <eos/><bos/>While the damages awarded by the trial judge were very generous, his reasons did not reveal any error of law or principle that would justify appellate intervention.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id93879038e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">15</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Police submitted that the trial judge erred in awarding aggravated damages without making a finding of “reprehensible or outrageous conduct”.<eos/><bos/> Aggravated damages aim not at punishing wrongful behaviour but at compensating the injured plaintiff for the full extent of the plaintiff&apos;s loss. <eos/><bos/>Very often, aggravation of the plaintiff&apos;s loss will be caused by outrageous or reprehensible conduct, as it is that quality of the defendant&apos;s conduct that causes additional distress or humiliation that calls for compensation not captured by a purely conventional award. <eos/><bos/>Justice Sharpe was not persuaded, however, that a trial judge can only take aggravating features into account where there has been outrageous or reprehensible conduct. <eos/><bos/>Justice Sharpe agreed with the observation made by this court in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00024" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2006792767" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I77a304b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Weingerl v. Seo</ital> (2005), 256 D.L.R. (4th) 1, 199 O.A.C. 172, 2005 CarswellOnt 2474, 140 A.C.W.S. (3d) 400, [2005] O.J. No. 2467 (Ont. C.A.)</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00025" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2006977514" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I77a304b68e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2005 CarswellOnt 3323 (Ont. C.A.)</cite.query> that <begin.quote ID="QT_0003"/>“post-incident conduct which aggravates the harm to the victim”<end.quote refid="QT_0003"/> may also be taken into account. <eos/><bos/>Justice Sharpe agreed with the Police that the first factor mentioned by the trial judge, failure to protect Stack&apos;s anonymity, was not aggravating. <eos/><bos/>However, it was open to the trial judge to find that the failure of the Police to take any meaningful steps to protect Stack and her family from the harm they were suffering as a result of the wrongful disclosure of her identity did aggravate the damages she suffered. <eos/><bos/>The Police had promised Stack confidentiality in order to gain her cooperation. <eos/><bos/>Their duty to her did not cease once they broke that promise. <eos/><bos/>The promise they made as police officers included a duty to protect Stack from the consequences of wrongful disclosure. <eos/><bos/>The Police failed to carry out that duty.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id93879048e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">16</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Cruise Connections Canada v. Cancellieri</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id938a0108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">17</footnote.reference>] the defendant cruise booking specialists in breach of both the good faith and confidentiality provisions of the contractor agreements, misappropriated client lists from the plaintiff and then used them for the purpose of conducting business on behalf of Vision 2000.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>An award of damages for losses flowing from the defendants&apos; misappropriation and use of Cruise Connections&apos; confidential information involved an assessment of the plaintiff&apos;s loss, rather than a mathematical calculation of those damages.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id938a0118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">18</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff&apos;s claim for compensatory damages had two parts. <eos/><bos/>First, the plaintiff claimed damages for bookings the defendants wrongfully transferred, or cancelled and rebooked through Vision 2000. <eos/><bos/>Second, the plaintiff sought compensation for the loss of future bookings resulting from the defendants&apos; misuse of its confidential client information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id938a0128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">19</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff claimed damages for 241 cancelled, transferred and discounted bookings in the amount of $183,000. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff had not produced any agreements with the cruise lines or other documents to support its claims for the loss of incentive fees and advertising contributions. <eos/><bos/>The amounts claimed were significant. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff had not suggested that no records existed. <eos/><bos/>In the circumstances, the plaintiff failed to prove its claims for lost incentive fees and advertising contributions on the balance of probabilities. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, the plaintiff&apos;s claim was reduced by $40,000 to remove the amounts sought for incentive fees and advertising contributions. <eos/><bos/>Further adjustments were necessary to allow for bookings cancelled or transferred for reasons unconnected with the defendants&apos; misuse of the plaintiff&apos;s confidential information, and to deduct cancelled or transferred cruises of customers who were personal contacts of the sales agents. <eos/><bos/>The damages under this head were assessed $120,000.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id938a0138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">20</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff&apos;s damages flowing from the defendants&apos; past and anticipated future use of the plaintiff&apos;s client contact information were estimated at $1,568,000. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff&apos;s loss was calculated by the plaintiffs for a period of seven years and four months. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge concluded that the quantification of the plaintiff&apos;s damages over so long a period was excessive. <eos/><bos/>Even without the misappropriation of any customer contact information, the cruise specialists, with the assistance of the corporate defendants&apos; advertising resources would have re-established contact with many of their key customers in a short time. <eos/><bos/>The customers&apos; primary loyalty is to the particular agent with whom they have a relationship. <eos/><bos/>The determination of an attrition rate is specific to the facts in each case. <eos/><bos/>Here, the close personal connection between client and cruise booking specialists, the loyalty of the client to the cruise booking specialist rather than the travel agency, and the ease of mobility of client and cruise booking specialist all militated in favour of an attrition rate greater than 15%. <eos/><bos/>An attrition rate of 25% was realistic. <eos/><bos/>Because it was unlikely that the plaintiff would have retained 100% of its clients in 2006, the use of 1,670 client bookings as a starting point for the determination of the plaintiff&apos;s loss was flawed. <eos/><bos/>The assumptions by the plaintiff&apos; expert witness that but for the individual defendants&apos; misappropriation of confidential client information, the plaintiff would have retained 100% of its customers, and that the plaintiff&apos;s loss extended over seven years and four months were neither sound nor supported by the evidence. <eos/><bos/>Further, the selection of a 15% annual attrition rate failed to adequately reflect the loyalty of customers to particular cruise specialists with whom they deal and the ease of mobility of both customer and cruise specialist. <eos/><bos/>The report did not provide a reliable estimate of the plaintiff&apos;s actual loss. <eos/><bos/>The duration of the plaintiff&apos;s compensable loss should reflect the principle that an award of damages is intended to restore the plaintiff to the position it would have enjoyed had the tort not occurred and/or the contract had been performed. <eos/><bos/>The factors specific to that determination included the normal rate of attrition of clients, the mobility of sales agents in the travel industry, the effect of other competition in the market place, the strength and duration of the relationship between sales agents and their clients, the time required for departing sales agents to find a new travel agency and begin to compete fairly, the ability of departed sales agents to solicit and acquire customers, including former customers through lawful advertising and the principle that the public interest in promoting free competition militates against unduly extending the duration of the damages. <eos/><bos/>Weighing all of these factors, the reasonable period for the assessment of damages was from September 2006 through December 2009.The assessment of damages began by adjusting the estimate to reflect the 60% retention rate, 25% client attrition rate commencing in 2007 and compounding from year to year, and the duration period of three years and four months. <eos/><bos/>Damages must be assessed rather than calculated with precision. <eos/><bos/>The adoption of a 60% retention rate and a 25% attrition rate gives considerable weight to the negative contingencies. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff was awarded damages for lost bookings from September 2006 through December 2009 in the amount of $470,000.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id938a0148e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">21</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Id93803d08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00026" w-ref-type="U2" w-serial-number="1981032033" w-pub-number="0004888" ID="I77a575b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Talbot v. General Television Corporation Pty. Ltd.</ital>, [1980] V.R. 224 (S.C. Vict.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id9382ae08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00027" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1971023469" w-pub-number="0004697" ID="I77a660108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Stovin-Bradford v. Volpoint Properties Ltd.</ital>, [1971] Ch. 1007 (C.A.)</cite.query>; <ital>Interfirm Comparison (Australia) Pty. Ltd. v. The Law Society of New South Wales</ital> (1975), <cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00028" w-ref-type="U2" w-serial-number="1975144274" w-pub-number="0004654" ID="I77a660128e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">6 A.L.R. 445 (S.C. N.S.W.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id9382ae18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00029" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1967018556" w-pub-number="0004891" ID="I77a6ae308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seager v. Copydex Ltd.</ital>, [1967] 1 W.L.R. 923 (C.A.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id9382ae28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>4</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00030" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1967018556" w-pub-number="0004891" ID="I77a6ae328e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seager v. Copydex Ltd.</ital>, [1967] 1 W.L.R. 923 (C.A.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id9382ae38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>5</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00031" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1969019738" w-pub-number="0004891" ID="I77a6fc508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seager v. Copydex Ltd. (No. 2)</ital>, [1969] 1 W.L.R. 809 (C.A.)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>See also, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00032" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2001348305" w-pub-number="0005460" ID="I77a6fc528e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>McCormick Delisle &amp; Thompson Inc. v. Ballantyne</ital> (2001), 145 O.A.C. 379</cite.query>, 12 B.L.R. (3d) 257, 9 C.C.E.L. (3d) 50 (<cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00033" w-ref-type="ER" w-normalized-cite="158OACCA196n" w-pub-number="0005460" ID="I77a6fc548e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">C.A.), leave to appeal to S.C.C. refused 158 O.A.C. 196<ital>n</ital>, 285 N.R. 397<ital>n</ital></cite.query>, where the court held that given the nature of the defendants&apos; breach of duty, it was inappropriate to unduly limit the length of time for calculating loss of profits. <eos/><bos/>Rather, since the misappropriated contracts in question were long-term in nature, the appropriate measure of damages should be calculated using the revenues received by the defendants.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id93851f08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>6</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00034" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1969019738" w-pub-number="0004891" ID="I77a798918e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seager</ital></cite.query> decision was distinguished in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00035" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1986024967" w-pub-number="0004891" ID="I77a798928e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Dowson &amp; Mason Ltd. v. Potter,</ital> [1986] 1 W.L.R. 1419 (C.A.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id93851f18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>7</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The decision was upheld by the Court of Appeal. <eos/><bos/>Sir Edward Eveleigh said that the particular position of the plaintiff in each case had to be considered. <eos/><bos/>When dealing with someone who would have licensed the use of confidential information, the measure of damages will be the price that he or she could have commanded for that information, and no question of loss of manufacturing profits will arise as he or she was always ready to allow someone else to manufacture at a price. <eos/><bos/>If the plaintiff is a manufacturer who would have licensed another to use the secret, then he or she would be in the same position as the inventor who had sold it because the manufacturer would have exposed him or herself to competition and loss of profits for a price, the price for which the secret was sold. <eos/><bos/>If, on the other hand, the manufacturer would not have licensed the secret&apos;s use, then he or she would not have been exposed to competition at the time when he or she was exposed because of the defendant&apos;s wrongdoing. <eos/><bos/>See generally the Supreme Court of Canada decision in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00036" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2011192292" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I77a946418e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>RBC Dominion Securities Inc. v. Merrill Lynch Canada Inc.</ital></cite.query> (2003), 55 C.C.E.L. (3d) 179 (B.C.S.C.), supp. reasons 55 C.C.E.L. (3d) 208 (B.C.S.C.), appeal allowed in part <cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00037" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2011192292" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I77a946428e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">275 D.L.R. (4th) 385 (B.C.C.A.)</cite.query>, <case.history>appeal allowed in part</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00038" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017227608" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I77a96d508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">298 D.L.R. (4th) 1 (S.C.C.)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>See also <cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00039" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2001348305" w-pub-number="0005460" ID="I77a96d528e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>McCormick Delisle &amp; Thompson Inc. v. Ballantyne</ital> (2001), 145 O.A.C. 379</cite.query>, 12 B.L.R. (3d) 257, 9 C.C.E.L. (3d) 50 (<cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00040" w-ref-type="ER" w-normalized-cite="158OACCA196n" w-pub-number="0005460" ID="I77a96d548e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">C.A.), leave to appeal to S.C.C. refused 158 O.A.C. 196<ital>n</ital>, 285 N.R. 397<ital>n</ital></cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00041" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2005431910" w-pub-number="0005460" ID="I77a96d588e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>KJA Consultants Inc. v. Soberman</ital></cite.query> (2003), 29 C.C.E.L. (3d) 47, 36 B.L.R. (3d) 19 (<cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00042" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2005431910" w-pub-number="0005460" ID="I77a96d598e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Ont. S.C.J.), affd 192 O.A.C. 116, 39</cite.query> C.C.E.L. (3d) 13 (C.A.); <cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00043" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2019906465" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I77a96d5b8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>GasTOPS Ltd. v. Forsyth</ital> (2009), 181 A.C.W.S. (3d) 484, 2009</cite.query> CanLII 66153 (Ont. S.C.J.).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id93851f28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>8</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00044" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040732478" w-pub-number="0005506" ID="I77a9e2808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Nissen v. Durham Regional Police Services Board</ital> (2017), 134 O.R. (3d) 81, 2017 CarswellOnt 114, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 426, 2017 ONCA 10 (Ont. C.A.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id93851f38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>9</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00045" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040732478" w-pub-number="0005506" ID="I77aa09908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Nissen v. Durham Regional Police Services Board</ital> (2017), 134 O.R. (3d) 81, 2017 CarswellOnt 114, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 426, 2017 ONCA 10 (Ont. C.A.)</cite.query>, at paras. 1–2.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id93851f48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>10</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00046" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040732478" w-pub-number="0005506" ID="I77aa57b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Nissen v. Durham Regional Police Services Board</ital> (2017), 134 O.R. (3d) 81, 2017 CarswellOnt 114, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 426, 2017 ONCA 10 (Ont. C.A.)</cite.query>, at paras. 16, 19, and 21–22.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id93851f58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>11</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00047" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040732478" w-pub-number="0005506" ID="I77aa7ec08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Nissen v. Durham Regional Police Services Board</ital> (2017), 134 O.R. (3d) 81, 2017 CarswellOnt 114, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 426, 2017 ONCA 10 (Ont. C.A.)</cite.query>, at paras. 26–27.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id93879008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>12</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00048" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040732478" w-pub-number="0005506" ID="I77aaa5d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Nissen v. Durham Regional Police Services Board</ital> (2017), 134 O.R. (3d) 81, 2017 CarswellOnt 114, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 426, 2017 ONCA 10 (Ont. C.A.)</cite.query>, at paras. 31–34.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id93879018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>13</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00049" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040732478" w-pub-number="0005506" ID="I77aacce08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Nissen v. Durham Regional Police Services Board</ital> (2017), 134 O.R. (3d) 81, 2017 CarswellOnt 114, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 426, 2017 ONCA 10 (Ont. C.A.)</cite.query>, at para. 36.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id93879028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>14</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00050" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040732478" w-pub-number="0005506" ID="I77ab1b008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Nissen v. Durham Regional Police Services Board</ital> (2017), 134 O.R. (3d) 81, 2017 CarswellOnt 114, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 426, 2017 ONCA 10 (Ont. C.A.)</cite.query>, at paras. 37–39.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id93879038e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>15</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00051" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040732478" w-pub-number="0005506" ID="I77ab42108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Nissen v. Durham Regional Police Services Board</ital> (2017), 134 O.R. (3d) 81, 2017 CarswellOnt 114, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 426, 2017 ONCA 10 (Ont. C.A.)</cite.query>, at paras. 40–45.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id93879048e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>16</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00052" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040732478" w-pub-number="0005506" ID="I77ab69208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Nissen v. Durham Regional Police Services Board</ital> (2017), 134 O.R. (3d) 81, 2017 CarswellOnt 114, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 426, 2017 ONCA 10 (Ont. C.A.)</cite.query>, at paras. 52, and 55–56.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id938a0108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>17</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00053" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026899479" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I77ab90308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cruise Connections Canada v. Cancellieri</ital>, 2012 CarswellBC 137, 2012 BCSC 53</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00054" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2029582840" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I77ab90338e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2013 CarswellBC 2, 2013 BCSC 1</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id938a0118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>18</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00055" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026899479" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I77abb7408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cruise Connections Canada v. Cancellieri</ital>, 2012 CarswellBC 137, 2012 BCSC 53</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00056" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2029582840" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I77abb7438e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2013 CarswellBC 2, 2013 BCSC 1, at para. 293</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id938a0128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>19</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00057" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026899479" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I77abde508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cruise Connections Canada v. Cancellieri</ital>, 2012 CarswellBC 137, 2012 BCSC 53</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00058" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2029582840" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I77abde538e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2013 CarswellBC 2, 2013 BCSC 1, at para. 311</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id938a0138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>20</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00059" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026899479" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I77ac2c708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cruise Connections Canada v. Cancellieri</ital>, 2012 CarswellBC 137, 2012 BCSC 53</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00060" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2029582840" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I77ac2c738e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2013 CarswellBC 2, 2013 BCSC 1</cite.query>, at paras. 341–343.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id938a0148e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>21</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00061" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026899479" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I77ac7a908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cruise Connections Canada v. Cancellieri</ital>, 2012 CarswellBC 137, 2012 BCSC 53</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175979" w-seq-number="00062" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2029582840" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I77ac7a938e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2013 CarswellBC 2, 2013 BCSC 1</cite.query>, at paras. 344, 356, 358, 380–381 and 388.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 7:26<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
