<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 4:51<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I5089a870411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>4.</label.designator><headtext>Confidential Business Information and the Employment Relationship</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I52517020411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>V.</label.designator><headtext>Fiduciary Duty</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I53a16fc0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>B.</label.designator><headtext>Remedies Table—Employment Relationship—Breach of Fiduciary Duty</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f6864e6ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>4:51.</label.designator><headtext>Zesta Engineering Ltd. v. Cloutier</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><ital>Zesta Engineering Ltd. v. Cloutier</ital>, 2010 CarswellOnt 7953, 2010 ONSC 5810 (Ont. S.C.J.), additional reasons 2013 CarswellOnt 410, 2013 ONSC 385, reversed in part 2014 CarswellOnt 15051, 2014 ONCA 762</headtext><eos/><eop/></head><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Award</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Damages against Cloutier and Kelvin, jointly and severally, of $100,000 in relation to Cloutier&apos;s further breaches of fiduciary duty and the resulting losses to Zesta and benefits to Kelvin</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Punitive damages against Cloutier of $75,000</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Punitive damages against Peatling of $10,000</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Summary of Facts:</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff Zesta carried on business as a distributor of electrical heaters, temperature controls, temperature sensors called thermocouples, power controls and similar equipment for industrial applications. <eos/><bos/>The shares of Zesta were owned by Vincent Eastman and his wife Ruth. <eos/><bos/>Vincent Eastman was the founder, President and controlling mind of Zesta.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The defendant David Cloutier was the son-in-law of Vincent and Ruth Eastman, being the husband of their daughter Mary. <eos/><bos/>Cloutier and Mary had lived separately since 1998. <eos/><bos/>Mary was estranged from her parents and siblings, many of whom were Zesta employees. <eos/><bos/>Cloutier was the Vice-President and Assistant General Manager of Zesta at the time of the events in issue.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The defendant Kelvin was incorporated in early 2000. <eos/><bos/>It carried on a business similar to and in many ways competitive with that of Zesta. <eos/><bos/>Kelvin was incorporated by Durante, who originally owned 70% of its shares, while the remaining 30% were owned by the defendant Peatling. <eos/><bos/>All of Cloutier, Durante, Sanger and White were associated in some capacity with the business of Kelvin.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A large measure of Zesta&apos;s success was attributable to Cloutier. <eos/><bos/>In addition to being Vincent Eastman&apos;s son-in-law, he was his right-hand man and they worked very closely together. <eos/><bos/>Over the years their responsibilities diverged, with Cloutier assuming responsibility for the sales and manufacturing aspects of the business, while Vincent Eastman oversaw the finance and administration aspects. <eos/><bos/>They consulted frequently and there was a free flow of information between them that contributed to the success of the operation.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A reason why the absence of a formal succession plan proved problematic was the position in which it left Cloutier. <eos/><bos/>Up until 1997 or so, he had a close working relationship with Vincent Eastman. <eos/><bos/>He had spent his entire working life helping to build Zesta. <eos/><bos/>While he earned a significant income, he was a mere employee and had no equity position in the company.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The deterioration in the marital relationship between Cloutier and his wife was accompanied by deterioration in the business relationship between Cloutier and Vincent Eastman. <eos/><bos/>Cloutier&apos;s attendances at the Zesta premises became less and less frequent. <eos/><bos/>Matters approached the level of animosity in the fall of 1999 as a result of an incident involving a Zesta salesman named Marcel Jones. <eos/><bos/>The Jones incident triggered a series of events that ultimately resulted in litigation that commenced in November 1999. <eos/><bos/>Jones was one of Zesta&apos;s most successful salesmen. <eos/><bos/>Despite Jones&apos; success as a salesman, he was not trusted by Cloutier or by the members of his senior management team. <eos/><bos/>The disagreement between Cloutier and Vincent Eastman regarding Jones came to a head in late August and early September of 1999. <eos/><bos/>Despite Cloutier&apos;s directive that he not do so, Jones went to France and made a solo sales call on Nortel France, a Zesta customer. <eos/><bos/>Vincent Eastman approved of the trip. <eos/><bos/>This managerial conflict added to the tensions between Cloutier and Vincent Eastman and undoubtedly fuelled the events that followed. <eos/><bos/>There is considerable controversy about the proper characterization of those events. <eos/><bos/>According to Cloutier, he decided to plan a “sting” whereby he would involve Jones in a false plan to solicit business from Zesta customers for a newly-created competing business. <eos/><bos/>His idea was to entrap Jones in this improper conduct, and thus prove his point about Jones&apos; disloyalty towards Zesta to Vincent Eastman, once and for all, and accomplish Jones&apos;s firing. <eos/><bos/>When he become concerned that Jones needed even further persuasion to participate in the new venture, Cloutier arranged to not only solicit, but to obtain an actual order for Hi-Cap, from a U.S. customer of Zesta. <eos/><bos/>As a result of Cloutier&apos;s efforts, Jones supposedly agreed to use the Hi-Cap quotation to try and get Nortel France to place an order with Hi-Cap. <eos/><bos/>As events unfolded, however, Jones did not procure a Nortel France order for Hi-Cap. <eos/><bos/>Jones reported Cloutier&apos;s activities to Vincent Eastman&apos;s sons. <eos/><bos/>Vincent and Bernard Eastman believed and Zesta continues to maintain to the present day the solicitation of Jones was part of an elaborate plan by Cloutier and the others to take away the core of Zesta&apos;s business and to compete unlawfully. <eos/><bos/>Zesta&apos;s perspective triggered a series of employee terminations and departures. <eos/><bos/>Cloutier was fired. <eos/><bos/>According to Durante, once he found himself unexpectedly unemployed after having spent his entire working life with Zesta, he decided to try his hand at setting up his own small distribution business in the same sphere as Zesta, the only field of business he knew. <eos/><bos/>At Sanger&apos;s suggestion, Durante met with Peatling who agreed to invest in the new enterprise. <eos/><bos/>Kelvin was incorporated at the end of January 2000, with Peatling as a 30% shareholder; Durante owned the rest of the shares. <eos/><bos/>Although Durante&apos;s claimed plan was to open a small distribution business, Kelvin evolved into a much more substantial operation with the financial backing of Peatling. <eos/><bos/>The new Kelvin premises were outfitted with virtually the same equipment found in the Zesta manufacturing plant, in order to enable Kelvin to go into the business of manufacturing thermocouples.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Reasons Given by Court for Award:</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A central issue in the case was whether Cloutier took active steps while he was employed at Zesta to plan and implement a scheme to compete unfairly, and thereby breached his fiduciary duties. <eos/><bos/>On November 5, 1999 Cloutier met with Christie and presented a detailed outline of a plan to leave Zesta, create a new business with financing from Peatling, and involve Durante and Sanger in an enterprise that would compete with Zesta and take over its relationships with Watlow and Husky. <eos/><bos/>Peatling was present for at least part of the meeting and was aware of its purpose and the topics discussed. <eos/><bos/>In advance of the termination of his employment by Zesta, Cloutier took active steps to plan to set up a competing business. <eos/><bos/>He arranged for Watlow to terminate specific ongoing arrangements with Zesta, in anticipation that he would pick up that business in his new enterprise. <eos/><bos/>He carried out a plan designed to have Vincent Eastman fire Zesta&apos;s top salesman.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>It was conceded by the defendants that Cloutier, as Vice President, Assistant General Manager and the most senior employee at Zesta, had and owed fiduciary duties to the company. <eos/><bos/>By planning as he did to leave Zesta and set up a competing enterprise, by communicating with Watlow to arrange for the termination of the Watlow-Gordon holdover commissions and the Watlow-Zesta-Husky relationship, by further taking steps to attempt to cause the termination of Jones&apos; employment by Zesta, Cloutier breached his fiduciary duties.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A more challenging question was whether, in light of the fact that Cloutier&apos;s plans were halted in mid-execution, Zesta suffered any damage as a result.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>There was no dispute but that Cloutier had and owed fiduciary duties to Zesta while he served as its Vice-President and Assistant General Manager. <eos/><bos/>The fiduciary obligations of a senior executive such as Cloutier do not automatically cease upon the termination of his/her employment, rather, one must consider the circumstances under which the relationship was terminated. <eos/><bos/>Where an employee is terminated for cause, his or her fiduciary obligations would ordinarily continue. <eos/><bos/>To hold otherwise would be illogical, because it would permit a former employee who was guilty of misconduct sufficient to justify dismissal, to benefit by his/her misconduct by thereby obtaining a release from his/her fiduciary obligations. <eos/><bos/>The employer would be doubly wronged, first by the employee&apos;s initial misconduct, and then by the ex-employee&apos;s post-termination breach of fiduciary duty. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, Cloutier&apos;s fiduciary obligations to Zesta survived after his employment was terminated at the end of November 1999 and remained in place at the time of his dealings with Nicol in January 2000. <eos/><bos/>Cloutier in responding as he did to Nicol&apos;s enquiry did not comply with his ongoing obligations to Zesta. <eos/><bos/>As a fiduciary with a high level of responsibility and the corresponding high level of loyalty to Zesta, and with a long-standing connection with a key Zesta customer, Cloutier should have declined completely to respond to the enquiry he received from Nicol. <eos/><bos/>As a fiduciary, Cloutier owed an undivided duty of loyalty to Zesta. <eos/><bos/>There can be no dispute that, while he was the Vice-President and Assistant General Manager of Zesta, Cloutier would have breached his duties to Zesta by referring a Zesta customer to a competitor instead of encouraging the customer to continue to do business with Zesta. <eos/><bos/>Although he asserts that he had no participation in the creation of Kelvin&apos;s new business, plainly Cloutier steered Nicol and Husky towards Sanger and Kelvin, thus advancing and preferring the interests of the latter over the interests of Zesta: in so doing, Cloutier knowingly facilitated contact between Husky and a new business that he knew would be competing with Zesta. <eos/><bos/>Given his ongoing obligations to his former employer, Cloutier should have either attempted to dissuade Husky from diverting its business away from Zesta to Kelvin or, at the very least, refrained from providing any information or facilitating the contact that he did. <eos/><bos/>Regardless of whether Nicol was solicited or approached Cloutier on his own, Cloutier breached his fiduciary duties to Zesta by reason of the fashion in which he responded to Nicol&apos;s approach. <eos/><bos/>In turn, Cloutier&apos;s referral of Husky to Sanger resulted in contacts between Husky and Sanger and an exploratory meeting in February 2000 that led to a quote from Kelvin to Husky. <eos/><bos/>Although there was no evidence that Cloutier directly participated in the February 2000 discussions with Husky, the response of Cloutier to the January 2000 enquiry from Husky paved the way for that business opportunity for Kelvin. <eos/><bos/>Thus, Kelvin benefited from Cloutier&apos;s breach of duty. <eos/><bos/>Kelvin must be fixed with knowledge of Cloutier&apos;s breach of duty.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In mid-February 2000, Cloutier, Durante, Sanger, White and Jefferies went on a 4-day “road trip” to the United States to visit potential suppliers for Kelvin. <eos/><bos/>As a result of these meetings, Kelvin got a distribution contract for Heatron, thus enabling it to sell products that were competitive with some offered by Zesta. <eos/><bos/>Cloutier participated in the trip, together with his fellow ex-Zesta employees, knowing that its business purpose was to facilitate Kelvin going into direct competition with Zesta. <eos/><bos/>Cloutier had ongoing fiduciary obligations to Zesta. <eos/><bos/>Cloutier&apos;s participation in the “road trip” with other ex-Zesta employees, designed to secure suppliers for a business competitive with that of Zesta, and his assistance in facilitating recruitment by Durante of other former Zesta employees, was contrary to the interests of Zesta and a breach of Cloutier&apos;s obligations. <eos/><bos/>Kelvin was able to secure a source of supply (from Heatron) and hired White as a key employee. <eos/><bos/>Once again, Kelvin knowingly benefited from Cloutier&apos;s breach of duty.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The basic thrust of Zesta&apos;s confidential information claim is that “know-how”, information and documents regarding the design and manufacture of thermocouples that it had developed through trial and error over many years, were valuable information that Kelvin unlawfully used to springboard its new business into competition with Zesta. <eos/><bos/>Zesta points to the fact that, within two to three months of setting up business, Kelvin was manufacturing thermocouples that were identical to those produced by Zesta. <eos/><bos/>In doing so, Kelvin utilized a production system that was modeled on the one created at Zesta over the course of many years, utilizing equipment, supplies, suppliers and techniques developed and refined by Zesta through years of effort, experimentation, trial and error.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Kelvin knowingly benefited from Cloutier&apos;s breach of fiduciary duty. <eos/><bos/>A party who knowingly participates in a breach of fiduciary duty of another is liable to compensate the wrong party to the same extent as the fiduciary who committed the wrong Kelvin and Cloutier are jointly and severally liable to Zesta to compensate it in this regard.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Zesta presented a detailed damage calculation prepared by a forensic accountant who quantified its losses from these activities of the defendants at $2,397,738. <eos/><bos/>This sum was said to represent Zesta&apos;s lost profits arising from sales by Kelvin to Zesta customers for the 7 year period from 2000 through 2006. <eos/><bos/>For several reasons, the court did not consider that calculation to be a proper assessment of the plaintiff&apos;s damages.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The court did not accept the underlying premise upon which the calculation was based, namely, that Kelvin&apos;s entire business was the illegitimate product of unlawful conduct by the defendants. <eos/><bos/>Kelvin&apos;s creation and operations breached no rights of There was thus no basis for the claim for equitable ownership of Kelvin&apos;s business, nor an accounting for 7 years&apos; worth of sales.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>With respect to quantifying the damage award in favour of Zesta arising from Cloutier&apos;s breaches of fiduciary duty in referring the Husky enquiries to Sanger and in participating in the road trip, Zesta did not present its damage claim by reference to specific activities of the defendants and losses flowing from them. <eos/><bos/>Rather, Zesta pointed to its overall financial performance, as well as the financial results for Kelvin. <eos/><bos/>The court was not prepared to find any readily quantifiable loss to Zesta arising from or attributable to this specific conduct by Cloutier. <eos/><bos/>As it had in the past, Zesta&apos;s financial performance continued to experience ups and downs such as one would expect in the ordinary turns of the business cycle. <eos/><bos/>It was difficult to find any link or cause and effect relationship between the activities of the defendants and the financial performance of Zesta following their departure. <eos/><bos/>That said, it was likely that Kelvin did achieve some benefit from the breaches by Cloutier: it procured a US supplier to represent at the commencement of its operations, and it developed a contact at Husky. <eos/><bos/>While it is difficult to quantify those benefits in precise monetary terms, both contributed to Kelvin&apos;s ability to “get up and running” as a distributor/manufacturer sooner than it otherwise might have. <eos/><bos/>The court quantified that benefit as having a value of $100,000 and ordered Cloutier and Kelvin to pay that sum, jointly and severally, as damages to Zesta.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Zesta sought punitive damages in the amount of $2 million as against Cloutier, Durante, Sanger, Peatling and White. <eos/><bos/>Cloutier was the senior-most employee at Zesta. <eos/><bos/>Due to his falling-out with Vincent Eastman, Cloutier determined, in effect, to “sabotage” certain aspects of Zesta&apos;s business by, for example, inducing Marcel Jones to solicit Nortel, and by inducing Watlow to terminate the Watlow-Gordon holdover commissions and the Watlow-Zesta-Husky arrangements. <eos/><bos/>He also took steps to set up a proposed corporate structure and to arrange financing with Peatling. <eos/><bos/>But for the decision by Jones to reveal Cloutier&apos;s overtures to the Eastman family, his plan might well have succeeded. <eos/><bos/>As events unfolded, Cloutier&apos;s plans went no further than the termination of the two Watlow arrangements. <eos/><bos/>There could be no doubt that Cloutier&apos;s position and authority at Zesta were such as to hold him to the highest standards of a fiduciary. <eos/><bos/>Given his key position and long service with the company, Zesta was particularly vulnerable to Cloutier&apos;s misdeeds. <eos/><bos/>His misconduct departed to a marked degree from ordinary standards of decent behaviour. <eos/><bos/>Having regarding to the seriousness of his conduct in attempting to undermine the business of Zesta, to create a competing enterprise, his actual disruption of certain business relationships and his receipt of secret commissions at Zesta&apos;s expense, this was an appropriate case for an award of punitive damages. <eos/><bos/>Zesta was awarded punitive damages in the amount of $75,000. <eos/><bos/>Peatling was aware of a significant portion of Cloutier&apos;s misconduct and was willing to support him. <eos/><bos/>Others who might be similarly minded should be discouraged from facilitating breaches of duty by persons in senior corporate positions, such as that held by Cloutier. <eos/><bos/>An award of punitive damages against Peatling in the amount of $10,000 was warranted in the circumstances.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></section.body></section><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 4:51<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
