<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 4:55<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I5089a870411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>4.</label.designator><headtext>Confidential Business Information and the Employment Relationship</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I52517020411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>V.</label.designator><headtext>Fiduciary Duty</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I53a16fc0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>B.</label.designator><headtext>Remedies Table—Employment Relationship—Breach of Fiduciary Duty</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f6865a6ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>4:55.</label.designator><headtext>Anderson Preece &amp; Associates Inc. v. Dominium Appraisal Group Inc.</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><ital>Anderson Preece &amp; Associates Inc. v. Dominium Appraisal Group Inc.</ital>, 2001 CarswellAlta 1873, 2001 ABQB 1073</headtext><eos/><eop/></head><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Award</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Plaintiffs were entitled to receive as equitable compensation for the unlawful conduct of the Defendants Osske, Desmoreau, Bramley and Dominium an award of damages in the amount of $150,000.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Plaintiffs were entitled to recover damages from the Defendant Thiem in the several amount of $15,000 for the wrongful removal and conversion of APA&apos;s property for the benefit of her future employer</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Summary of Facts:</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>APA operated a full spectrum appraisal business. <eos/><bos/>Osske, Desmoreau and Bramley had each articled as appraisers to Preece of APA, learning and applying the APA system for the completion of appraisals for residential, acreage and, in the case of Osske and Bramley, agricultural properties in Red Deer and surrounding area. <eos/><bos/>Thiem was co-office manager for APA with particular responsibility for the computer systems.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>On December 16, 1997 Thiem gave two week&apos;s notice to APA to terminate her employment. <eos/><bos/>On the afternoon of December 31, 1997 Osske, Desmoreau and Bramley left their employment with APA without notice. <eos/><bos/>On January 5, 1998 Dominium opened for business in competition with APA in Red Deer and area. <eos/><bos/>Dominium was owned equally by Osske, Desmoreau and Bramley. <eos/><bos/>Thiem had been hired by Dominium as office manager effective January 1, 1998. <eos/><bos/>Prior to their departure, the individual Defendants had surreptitiously copied extensively from the files and computer records of APA for the purpose of facilitating the operation of the business of Dominium.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>None of the Defendant appraisers had had any appraisal experience prior to their engagement by APA. <eos/><bos/>In the fall of 1997, the individual Defendants including Thiem undertook a systematic operation to copy and remove from the premises of APA master files, appraisal comparables, and forms and precedents which APA had established, including copies of the software programs for systems and storage of data in use by APA for the operation of its appraisal business. <eos/><bos/>This copying and removal was done by each of the Defendants while employed with APA, both during and after working hours. <eos/><bos/>Most of the hard copy duplication was performed on the photocopier of APA using APA paper as well as paper brought in for that purpose by the Defendants. <eos/><bos/>Computer data was copied by Thiem onto 25 disks provided by Osske for that purpose. <eos/><bos/>They continually utilized the materials removed from APA in the business of Dominium until receipt of a notice of the Anton Pillar Order which was served upon them November 27, 1998. <eos/><bos/>Dominium relied on the APA precedents and systems in the creation of its appraisal reports. <eos/><bos/>Dominium completed 973 appraisals in 1998, which included 20 farms and 9 four plexes and generated $230,662 in revenues. <eos/><bos/>In 1999, 1380 appraisals were completed including 15 farms and 8 four plexes generating gross revenues of $298,225. <eos/><bos/>In 2000, Dominium did 1018 appraisals including 19 farms and 8 four plexes realizing gross revenues of $212,506.94.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Reasons Given by Court for Award:</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Each of the individual Defendants was in breach of a fiduciary duty they owed to their employer APA. <eos/><bos/>The employees had scope for the exercise of some discretion or power. <eos/><bos/>Each of the individual Defendants had keys to the business premises of APA and complete access to the business records of APA. <eos/><bos/>Upon the recruitment of Thiem, they gained complete access to all the computer records and programs of APA. <eos/><bos/>With that access, they gained very considerable power to affect the business of their employer. <eos/><bos/>The Defendants could and did unilaterally exercise that power to affect the legal interests of APA by copying and removing business records and systems from APA to assist the operations of Dominium. <eos/><bos/>The employer was peculiarly vulnerable to the wrongful actions of the Defendants. <eos/><bos/>APA had provided each of those Defendants with keys to the office premises, free access to the records of the business during and after business hours, and the right of use of the equipment of APA. <eos/><bos/>This was all provided with the expectation and belief that APA&apos;s employees would utilize this access for the sole benefit of the employer&apos;s business. <eos/><bos/>The actions of the Defendants Osske, Bramley, Desmoreau and Thiem constituted a breach of the fiduciary duty they owed to the employer APA.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>There can be no question that the actions of each of the individual Defendants constituted a misuse of the confidential information belonging to APA. <eos/><bos/>That information was secretly assembled by the Defendants acting in concert for the specific purpose of facilitating the establishment of Dominium, as a competitor to APA. <eos/><bos/>The Defendants knew it was the property of their employer and that APA would not give them permission for its copying. <eos/><bos/>The Defendant Osske testified that the Defendants would have been fired immediately had Preece known their intention to establish Dominium. <eos/><bos/>He admitted that none of the appraisers gave notice because they feared immediate termination. <eos/><bos/>He acknowledged that the Defendants continued to copy and remove the property of APA right up to the time of their quitting. <eos/><bos/>What was taken unlawfully was the operating systems, library resources and appraisal precedents all of which were the confidential property of APA. <eos/><bos/>Dominium fully utilized these operating systems, library resources and precedents in the conduct of its appraisal business, at least until November 27, 1998 when the Anton Pillar Order was served. <eos/><bos/>Dominium applied the APA system “holus bolus” to the conduct of its business from the time that company opened for business to and even after service of the Anton Pillar Order.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Any attempt to award damages to APA for actual losses incurred as a result of the misconduct of the Defendants would be an entirely inappropriate response to their breach of duty. <eos/><bos/>Dominium and the individual Defendant appraisers had been unjustly enriched by their use of the property of APA in competition with that company. <eos/><bos/>The only appropriate remedy in the circumstances was to require those Defendants to disgorge completely the benefit of that unjust enrichment. <eos/><bos/>By misappropriating APA&apos;s property, Dominium was clearly in an advantaged position over any other competitor entering the appraisal business in that market. <eos/><bos/>In addition, some portions of the APA property would simply have been unavailable to Dominium. <eos/><bos/>Master files of area complexes, maps and neighbourhood descriptions, comparables for residential and farm files could not have been created from within the knowledge of the Defendant appraisers or any consultant they may have hired. <eos/><bos/>Dominium&apos;s ability to perform appraisals in the formats expected by their clients on a prompt basis was fundamentally dependent on the availability of the library of comparables and other information forming part of the APA property. <eos/><bos/>Dominium and its shareholder owners were undoubtedly enriched by the immediate access to the systems and programs of APA and utilization of their library of information. <eos/><bos/>That enrichment was unjust because it resulted from their unlawful taking and conversion of the property of their employer. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiff is entitled to equitable relief requiring the appraiser Defendants and Dominium to disgorge the benefit flowing from their wrongful acts.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The primary factor to consider is the outright dependence of Dominium upon the APA materials for the establishment of its business. <eos/><bos/>It seems likely that these Defendants, working together and with the assistance of Thiem could have accessed general appraisal information available to them from the Institute and other existing appraisal firms and, by reference, created the necessary forms, materials and formats to support their business. <eos/><bos/>Utilizing the computer knowledge of Thiem and available market software such as KRAL and employing computer consultants they likely could have created their own systems and precedents. <eos/><bos/>That would of course have taken some period of time. <eos/><bos/>However, those Defendants could not have created a broad range of comparables for residential properties in all the neighbourhoods of Red Deer and the outlying areas or the library of information contained in the 331 farm files, for anything approaching immediate use by Dominium. <eos/><bos/>Similarly, although this APA property was not actually used by Dominium, information contained in the APA Industrial Commercial files could not have been reproduced for Dominium. <eos/><bos/>These comparables, in particular, were critical to the ability of Dominium to produce fast, effective real estate appraisals to customers who were mainly financial institutions in the format which those institutions required for lending and sale purposes. <eos/><bos/>Historical information could be acquired from other sources but a great deal of non-productive time and effort would be necessary to build up those libraries. <eos/><bos/>Throughout that period of development Dominium would have been severely handicapped in the delivery of appraisal services and the marketing of those services. <eos/><bos/>Dominium simply would not have been in a position to deliver a quick return of appraisal work without access to extensive and relevant comparables which form a key component particularly to residential appraisals. <eos/><bos/>Each target site would therefore need to be individually researched with the attendant delay and expenditure of non-productive effort. <eos/><bos/>The strong initial success of the business of Dominium would have been severely compromised had the wrongful conversion of APA confidential information not occurred. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, the benefit of the confidential property of APA to the Dominium business had been clearly proven and is very substantial. <eos/><bos/>The totality of the APA systems and libraries was indeed of the “very special” variety of confidential information because without access to it, Dominium could not have been an effective competitor to APA. <eos/><bos/>The utilization by Dominium of all the confidential information of APA was fundamentally responsible for the initial and continued success of Dominium&apos;s appraisal business. <eos/><bos/>It was the almost immediate creation of a prompt reliable competitor to APA which allowed Dominium to take advantage of the appraisal boom beginning in mid 1998 and accelerating in 1999. <eos/><bos/>Dominium&apos;s ability to hit the ground running through the appropriation of APA property was critical to the success enjoyed by the Defendants.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Approximately 75% of the income generated by Dominium in the first four months of its operation should be considered a benefit to be regurgitated. <eos/><bos/>Approximately 50% of the revenues generated by Dominium for the next six month period should also be considered to be a benefit to be regurgitated. <eos/><bos/>The ability of Dominium to perform more than half of the appraisals they did actually undertake would have been severely constrained by the lack of the library of comparables and other data and the necessary time which would have had to be expended in the research efforts for appraisals undertaken. <eos/><bos/>Finally, an additional 25% of the income generated by Dominium of the next six months of its operation should also be considered to be a benefit to be regurgitated. <eos/><bos/>While the Dominium data bank would have been developing to a much greater extent in this time frame through the actual experiences of Dominium in appraisal and the program of research through MLS, some restrictions in the company&apos;s ability to perform appraisal work at the volume actually undertaken would necessarily continue. <eos/><bos/>By calculating the number of appraisals ordered in each month as a percentage of the total number of appraisals completed in the relevant year, the Court can reach an approximate determination of the percentage of gross income generated in each of the periods identified by the Court. <eos/><bos/>That percentage is applied to the gross revenue for the relevant year to identify the approximate gross revenue for each period. <eos/><bos/>By then applying the appropriate percentage of earnings to be regurgitated, in each of the respective periods, the approximate total of the earnings to be regurgitated, being the total of this benefit unjustly received by Dominium can be determined. <eos/><bos/>In addition Dominium and the appraiser Defendants benefited by the savings of the cost of generation of most of the computer systems and reference libraries during that period. <eos/><bos/>That cost was at least $10,000 which must been included in the global figure of damages awarded. <eos/><bos/>An award of $150,000 is the fair and equitable compensation required to redress the wrongful acts of Dominium and the appraiser Defendants.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>It was not established that Thiem was unjustly enriched by her participation with the other Defendants in the unauthorized copying and use of the property of APA. <eos/><bos/>Thiem was liable for the wrongful removal and conversion of APA&apos;s property for the benefit of her future employer.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></section.body></section><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 4:55<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
