<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 7:15<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I56d26460411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>7.</label.designator><headtext>Remedies for Breach of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I56dbb330411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>II.</label.designator><headtext>Equitable Relief</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I58af3ab0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>F.</label.designator><headtext>Constructive Trust</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f7229c6ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>7:15.</label.designator><headtext>Generally</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Constructive trust is available as a remedy for breach of confidence where the innocent party can establish that the confidential information was intended to be held in trust by the offending party for the innocent party.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8afc1008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>] In order to support a claim for constructive trust, the innocent party must establish that:</paratext><list><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(1)</label.designator></head><paratext>The offending party was under an equitable obligation in relation to the activities which gave rise to the acquisition of the assets by the defendant.<eos/><bos/></paratext></para></list.item><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(2)</label.designator></head><paratext>The assets were obtained from the deemed or actual agency activities of the defendant in breach of the defendant&apos;s equitable obligation to the innocent party.<eos/><bos/></paratext></para></list.item><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(3)</label.designator></head><paratext>There is a reason for seeking return of the asset wrongfully acquired.<eos/><bos/></paratext></para></list.item><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(4)</label.designator></head><paratext>There is no reason why it would be unjust to impose a remedy of constructive trust.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8afc1018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></list.item></list><paratext>As the law of constructive trust stems from the law of restitution, the moving party must also be able to show that, but for the wrongful activities of the offending party, the offending party would not have acquired the assets.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8afc1028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">3</footnote.reference>] The moving party must also be able to show that there is a nexus between the duty owed and the property over which the constructive trust is sought.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8afc1038e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">4</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175968" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2039181989" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I6e32a2f18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">XY, LLC v. Canadian Topsires Selection</cite.query> Inc.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id8afc1048e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">5</footnote.reference>] the major issue was the determination of damages with respect to: firstly, Tang, Zhang and Ai De, if liability was established; and, secondly, the other defendants against whom liability had already been established. <eos/><bos/>XY sought compensatory damages arising in the period after that considered by the Court in the Original Action after the end of 2008, on the basis of conspiracy and breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>In the original action, the Court had granted judgment in favour of XY against JingJing, Zhu, and two of his employees, Tang and Zhou in the amount of $8.5 million on the basis of breach of contract, breach of confidence, conspiracy and deceit. <eos/><bos/>The Court had also granted a permanent and mandatory injunction designed to protect XY&apos;s intellectual property and technology rights.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8afe8108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">6</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Original Action concerned a licencing arrangement between XY and JingJing, one of Zhu&apos;s companies. <eos/><bos/>XY granted a licence to JingJing in February 2004 which required JingJing to pay certain royalties to XY for its use of its technology relating to sexed semen and sexed embryos. <eos/><bos/>In accordance with arrangements between the parties, JingJing originally acquired two SX cytometers for use in its semen-sorting business. <eos/><bos/>XY terminated the Licence in November 2008 after disputes with JingJing arose. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge in the original action found that XY&apos;s technology included certain confidential matters including a number of specified components of the SX cytometer, including its configuration; XY&apos;s protocols, and all other information and techniques imparted from XY during training, or otherwise, to any of the defendants in the Original Action or their employees relating to the use and operation of SX cytometers; and, XY&apos;s confidential patent information. <eos/><bos/>Having found a breach of confidence by the widespread misuse of XY&apos;s technology and protocols, the trial judge in the original action issued a prohibitory injunction against the defendants, including Zhu and others, to prevent future use of the Confidential Information, either directly or indirectly. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge also issued a mandatory injunction by which Zhu, Tang and others were to deliver all Confidential Information in their possession, power or control to XY.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8afe8118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">7</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The foundation of XY&apos;s present claims rested on its now-proven allegations that the defendants in the Original Action were in possession of information confidential to XY, and that they breached their duty in respect of that confidence. <eos/><bos/>In particular, XY relied on the trial judge&apos;s findings concerning what he defined as XY&apos;s “Confidential Information” in the Trial Order. <eos/><bos/>In the present action, XY alleged that Zhu and Tang continued to breach that duty of confidence to XY after the events that were addressed in the Original Action, and even during the trial itself and beyond. <eos/><bos/>In addition, XY alleged that many other persons, being the other defendants in this action, assisted Zhu and Tang in breaching this duty, and they also benefitted or were unjustly enriched from their actions, although in differing degrees.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8afe8128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">8</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In the Original Action, the trial judge found that there had been “widespread misuse” of XY&apos;s Confidential Information. <eos/><bos/>XY, and hence the Court, were not fully aware of the misuse that was occurring at the time of the Original Action. <eos/><bos/>Indeed, to some degree, Zhu used the course of the Original Action to aid in the execution of his plan, assisted by the non-disclosure of his true activities. <eos/><bos/>During the course of the Original Action, Zhu and the other defendants continued to assert that JingJing had been put out of business. <eos/><bos/>XY did not know that the IND Group continued to use the three cytometers in their possession to sort semen during the course of the Original Action despite the termination of the Licence. <eos/><bos/>Zhu considered the termination of the Licence, in November 2008, to be entirely irrelevant. <eos/><bos/>It was business as usual for Zhu&apos;s semen-sorting operations after November 2008.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8afe8138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">9</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The evidence overwhelming supported the following findings of fact: a) Zhu, along with his key employees in the IND Group, used XY&apos;s Confidential Information to continue JingJing&apos;s operations past the date of termination of the Licence in late 2008 to create sexed semen. <eos/><bos/>They did so until Zhu and the IND Group&apos;s key employees concocted a plan in 2010 that would place JingJing into bankruptcy with a view to disguising their ongoing operations and use of XY&apos;s Confidential Information; b) concurrent with placing JingJing into bankruptcy, the IND Group companies (IND, IEI, IDI, CTS and FBI), its employees and Zhu expressly planned to use XY&apos;s Confidential Information for their own purposes in the future. <eos/><bos/>They succeeded in doing so by January 2012, which saw a resurrection of their operations in the Lower Mainland (through CTS), and either a continuation or commencement of their operations in China. <eos/><bos/>These activities arose, in part, from their use of both “real” SX parts withheld from XY and the Trustee, and also the copying of manufactured SX parts (the BSO and tips) based on further misuse of XY&apos;s Confidential Information; and c) the plan was implemented by Zhu and his key IND Group employees, while knowing full well as to the confidential nature of XY&apos;s technology, and to exacerbate matters, while doing so in the face of litigation (i.e. the Original Action) commenced by XY to protect its interests in its technology.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8afe8148e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">10</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The fact that Zhu and the IND Group employees, both in Canada and China, took such pains to keep their plans secret, indicated that all these individuals were well-aware that their actions were breaches of confidence. <eos/><bos/>In execution of this plan, Zhu and his employees made extensive efforts to hide their efforts. <eos/><bos/>This included: a) lying to the Trustee and XY in various respects and, in particular, misleading XY and the Court about who was the true purchaser of the cytometers; b) making misrepresentations as to the Missing Parts and withholding the Missing Parts for their future (mis)use; c) using false names, in terms of sourcing materials and parts for the retrofitting process of the cytometers, all in aid of hiding the IND Group&apos;s efforts from XY; and d) attempting to remove the serial numbers from the SX parts and making counterfeit labels for the newly-copied parts and machines.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8afe8158e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">11</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In addition to copying the SX cytometer parts, the defendants used the newly-retrofitted SX cytometers to make substantial quantities of sexed semen and sexed embryos, all in breach of confidence relating to XY&apos;s Confidential Information. <eos/><bos/>All of the defendants received XY&apos;s Confidential Information knowing that it had been provided by XY to JingJing in confidence. <eos/><bos/>Their surreptitious actions and misrepresentations taken in relation to the Court, the Trustee, and XY to avoid detection of their true activities were indicative of this knowledge. <eos/><bos/>Equity will pursue the information into the hands of a third party who receives it knowing, or later learns, it was communicated in breach of confidence and impose its remedies. <eos/><bos/>Zhu, both personally and through his various companies, being IND, IDI, IEI, FBI, CTS and Ai De, all participated in this breach of confidence.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8afe8168e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">12</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Zhu, both personally and through his various companies by which he operated, received the Confidential Information and expressly and improperly misused it for his own purposes through the corporate actions of IND, IDI, IEI, FBI, CTS and Ai De. <eos/><bos/>While the evidence was not sufficient to specify clearly the exact roles of some of the companies, Zhu was acting in his capacity as owner of these corporations in directing their improper activities through the means of the various IND Group employees. <eos/><bos/>All of these corporations took some action in aid of Zhu&apos;s goals, and while in possession of knowledge that it was acting for the purpose of improperly using XY&apos;s Confidential Information. <eos/><bos/>In addition, Zhu and Zhang were participating as “directors” or directing minds of various IND Group companies, and their actions amounted to a deliberate knowing pursuit or conduct to commit acts which could not be said to be in the best interests of the companies through whom they acted. <eos/><bos/>As such, they were personally liable for those acts. <eos/><bos/>FBI and CTS, were involved (and in CTS&apos; case, created) for the express purpose of acting to improperly use and exploit XY&apos;s Confidential Information. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence that IND, IDI, IEI and Ai De were expressly created for the purpose of using XY&apos;s Confidential Information, but corporate actions taken by them were used to further the improper activities relating to XY&apos;s technology, as directed by their owner, Zhu. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, Zhu and the IND Group companies, being IND, IDI, IEI, FBI, CTS and Ai De, and Zhang, as a director of CTS, are all liable to XY for breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>The evidence, as to Tang&apos;s involvement in the plan to misuse XY&apos;s technology, was manifestly clear. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, Tang was liable to XY for breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>As with Tang, the involvement of Ai De and Zhang in the intentional misuse of XY&apos;s Confidential Information had been clearly proven. <eos/><bos/>Zhang and Ai De both played a direct role in receiving and misusing XY&apos;s Confidential Information. <eos/><bos/>Zhu, IND, IDI, IEI, FBI, CTS, Tang, Ai De and Zhang were all jointly liable for breach of confidence by reason of their conduct.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8b00f208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">13</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>An order that all of the Confidential Information in the possession, power or control of the Enjoined Parties, and each of them, was impressed with a constructive trust for the benefit of XY was also appropriate in the circumstances. <eos/><bos/>This relief recognized the proprietary nature of XY&apos;s Confidential Information and was consistent with enforcing XY&apos;s rights until (and if) the defendants complied with the injunctive relief granted and the injunctive relief that remained in place per the Trial Order.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175968" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2035428008" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I6e4a97c18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Scott &amp; Associates Engineering Ltd. v. Finavera Renewables</cite.query> Inc.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id8b00f218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">14</footnote.reference>] the plaintiff appealed only the trial judge&apos;s conclusion that damages and not the proprietary remedy of a constructive trust were the appropriate remedy for the defendant&apos;s unjust enrichment. <eos/><bos/>The focus in oral submissions on the appeal was on the “moral quality” of the defendant&apos;s conduct. <eos/><bos/>That is, the plaintiff argued that moral culpability was a factor in determining whether a constructive trust was available. <eos/><bos/>However, the Court of Appeal observed that in the absence of a fiduciary relationship or a relationship giving rise to confidence or a contractual relationship, it was doubtful that moral culpability becomes a factor. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge expressly found no fiduciary duty to engage the duty of loyalty. <eos/><bos/>This eliminated <cite.query w-src-number="0492175968" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1997409384" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I6e4a97c48e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Soulos</ital></cite.query> and the cases awarding constructive trusts for a breach of a fiduciary duty. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge also expressly found no breach of confidence, which eliminated the <ital>Lac Minerals</ital> breach of confidence line of cases that considered moral quality, and on which the appellant relied. <eos/><bos/>The circumstances considered in awarding a constructive trust in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175968" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2000545513" w-pub-number="0005506" ID="I6e4a97c68e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Visagie v. TVX Gold Inc</ital>. (2000), 49 O.R. (3d) 198, 132 O.A.C. 231 (Ont. C.A.)</cite.query> were also distinguishable. <eos/><bos/>There were critical differences which made that case entirely inapplicable. <eos/><bos/>The remedy upheld by the Court of Appeal of Ontario was based on the successful claim of breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175968" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2000545513" w-pub-number="0005506" ID="I6e4a97ca8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>TVX Gold</ital></cite.query> was distinguishable, the trial judge here having expressly found that there was no breach of confidence.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id8b00f228e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">15</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Id8afc1008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175968" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1986268645" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I6e4c45708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>LAC Minerals Ltd. v. International Corona Resources Ltd.</ital> (1986), 25 D.L.R. (4th) 504, 53 O.R. (2d) 737 (H.C.J.)</cite.query>, <case.history>affd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175968" w-seq-number="00007" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1987290799" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I6e4c45738e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">44 D.L.R. (4th) 592, 62 O.R. (2d) 1 (C.A.)</cite.query>, <case.history>affd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175968" w-seq-number="00008" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1989312320" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I6e4c45768e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">61 D.L.R. (4th) 14, [1989] 2 S.C.R. 574, at pp. 16</cite.query> and 44–5; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175968" w-seq-number="00009" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1985194847" w-pub-number="0005459" w-pinpoint-page="221" ID="I6e4c45798e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>I.C.L. Engineering Ltd. v. Associated Corrosion Contractors, Inc.</ital> (1985), 8 C.I.P.R. 217 at p. 221, 10 C.P.R. (3d) 313 (B.C.S.C.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175968" w-seq-number="00010" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1966075793" w-pub-number="0005149" ID="I6e4c457c8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Pre-Cam Exploration &amp; Development Ltd. v. McTavish</ital> (1966), 57 D.L.R. (2d) 557 (S.C.C.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175968" w-seq-number="00011" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2009574073" w-pub-number="0003986" ID="I6e4c457e8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Minera Aquiline Argentina SA v. IMA Exploration Inc.</ital>, [2007] 1 W.W.R. 43</cite.query> at paras. 245–246 (B.C.S.C.), <case.history>affd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175968" w-seq-number="00012" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2012444302" w-pub-number="0003986" ID="I6e4c45808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">[2007] 10 W.W.R. 648 (B.C.C.A.)</cite.query>, leave to appeal to <cite.query w-src-number="0492175968" w-seq-number="00013" w-ref-type="ER" w-normalized-cite="384NRCA383n" w-pub-number="0005466" ID="I6e4c45828e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">S.C.C. refused 384 N.R. 383<ital>n</ital></cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175968" w-seq-number="00014" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2000545513" w-pub-number="0005506" ID="I6e4c45858e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Visagie v. TVX Gold Inc.</ital></cite.query> (1998), 42 B.L.R. (2d) 53 (Ont. Ct. (Gen. Div.)), <case.history>affd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175968" w-seq-number="00015" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2000545513" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I6e4c45878e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">187 D.L.R. (4th) 193 (Ont. C.A.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8afc1018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175968" w-seq-number="00016" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1997409384" w-pub-number="0003591" w-pinpoint-page="230" ID="I6e4d2fd08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Soulos v. Korkontzilas</ital> (1997), 146 D.L.R. (4th) 214 at p. 230, [1997] 2 S.C.R. 217</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>See also <cite.query w-src-number="0492175968" w-seq-number="00017" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2009574073" w-pub-number="0003986" ID="I6e4d2fd38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Minera Aquiline Argentina SA v. IMA Exploration Inc.</ital>, [2007] 1 W.W.R. 43</cite.query> at paras. 245–246 (B.C.S.C.), <case.history>affd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175968" w-seq-number="00018" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2012444302" w-pub-number="0003986" ID="I6e4d2fd58e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">[2007] 10 W.W.R. 648 (B.C.C.A.)</cite.query>, leave to appeal to <cite.query w-src-number="0492175968" w-seq-number="00019" w-ref-type="ER" w-normalized-cite="384NRCA383n" w-pub-number="0005466" ID="I6e4d2fd78e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">S.C.C. refused 384 N.R. 383<ital>n</ital></cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175968" w-seq-number="00020" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2022565317" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I6e4d2fd98e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>CCS Corp. v. Secure Energy Services Inc.</ital> (2010), 190 A.C.W.S. (3d) 1277, 2010 ABQB 466</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8afc1028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175968" w-seq-number="00021" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1986268645" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I6e4e68508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>LAC Minerals Ltd. v. International Corona Resources Ltd.</ital> (1986), 25 D.L.R. (4th) 504, 53 O.R. (2d) 737 (H.C.J.)</cite.query>, <case.history>affd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175968" w-seq-number="00022" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1987290799" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I6e4e68538e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">44 D.L.R. (4th) 592, 62 O.R. (2d) 1 (C.A.)</cite.query>, <case.history>affd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175968" w-seq-number="00023" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1989312320" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I6e4e68568e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">61 D.L.R. (4th) 14, [1989] 2 S.C.R. 574, at p. 45</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>See also <cite.query w-src-number="0492175968" w-seq-number="00024" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2010357337" w-pub-number="0003986" ID="I6e4e68598e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Murphy Oil Co. v. Predator Corp.</ital>, [2007] 3 W.W.R. 255, 2006 ABQB 680</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175968" w-seq-number="00025" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2022565317" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I6e4e685c8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>CCS Corp. v. Secure Energy Services Inc.</ital> (2010), 190 A.C.W.S. (3d) 1277, 2010 ABQB 466</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8afc1038e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>4</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175968" w-seq-number="00026" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2022565317" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I6e4eb6708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>CCS Corp. v. Secure Energy Services Inc.</ital> (2010), 190 A.C.W.S. (3d) 1277, 2010 ABQB 466</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8afc1048e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>5</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175968" w-seq-number="00027" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039181989" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I6e4edd808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>XY, LLC v. Canadian Topsires Selection Inc.</ital>, 2016 CarswellBC 1648, 2016 BCSC 1095</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8afe8108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>6</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175968" w-seq-number="00028" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039181989" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I6e4f04908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>XY, LLC v. Canadian Topsires Selection Inc.</ital>, 2016 CarswellBC 1648, 2016 BCSC 1095</cite.query>, at paras. 3–5.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8afe8118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>7</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175968" w-seq-number="00029" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039181989" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I6e4f2ba08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>XY, LLC v. Canadian Topsires Selection Inc.</ital>, 2016 CarswellBC 1648, 2016 BCSC 1095</cite.query>, at paras. 25, and 32–33.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8afe8128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>8</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175968" w-seq-number="00030" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039181989" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I6e4f79c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>XY, LLC v. Canadian Topsires Selection Inc.</ital>, 2016 CarswellBC 1648, 2016 BCSC 1095</cite.query>, at paras. 37–38.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8afe8138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>9</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175968" w-seq-number="00031" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039181989" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I6e4fa0d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>XY, LLC v. Canadian Topsires Selection Inc.</ital>, 2016 CarswellBC 1648, 2016 BCSC 1095</cite.query>, at paras. 118–119, and 131.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8afe8148e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>10</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175968" w-seq-number="00032" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039181989" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I6e4fc7e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>XY, LLC v. Canadian Topsires Selection Inc.</ital>, 2016 CarswellBC 1648, 2016 BCSC 1095, at para. 221</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8afe8158e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>11</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175968" w-seq-number="00033" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039181989" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I6e4feef08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>XY, LLC v. Canadian Topsires Selection Inc.</ital>, 2016 CarswellBC 1648, 2016 BCSC 1095, at para. 222</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8afe8168e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>12</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175968" w-seq-number="00034" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039181989" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I6e5016008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>XY, LLC v. Canadian Topsires Selection Inc.</ital>, 2016 CarswellBC 1648, 2016 BCSC 1095</cite.query>, at paras. 225–227.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8b00f208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>13</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175968" w-seq-number="00035" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039181989" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I6e503d108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>XY, LLC v. Canadian Topsires Selection Inc.</ital>, 2016 CarswellBC 1648, 2016 BCSC 1095</cite.query>, at paras. 230–242.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8b00f218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>14</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175968" w-seq-number="00036" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035428008" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I6e5064208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Scott &amp; Associates Engineering Ltd. v. Finavera Renewables Inc.</ital>, 2015 CarswellAlta 182, 2015 ABCA 51</cite.query>, leave to appeal refused <cite.query w-src-number="0492175968" w-seq-number="00037" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037505168" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I6e5064238e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2015 CarswellAlta 2009</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id8b00f228e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>15</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175968" w-seq-number="00038" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035428008" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I6e50b2408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Scott &amp; Associates Engineering Ltd. v. Finavera Renewables Inc.</ital>, 2015 CarswellAlta 182, 2015 ABCA 51</cite.query>, leave to appeal refused <cite.query w-src-number="0492175968" w-seq-number="00039" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037505168" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I6e50b2438e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2015 CarswellAlta 2009, at paragraphs 1, 17, 27–28, 30, and 39–41</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 7:15<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
