<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 1:6<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I4d7849c0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>1.</label.designator><headtext>Confidential Business Information in Historical Context</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I4d790d10411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>I.</label.designator><headtext>Origins of Intellectual Property</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f59bec6ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>1:6.</label.designator><headtext>Information Age</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The large corporations of the Industrial Age created the need for communication over long distances, data storage and increased competition, which in turn fueled the Information Age. <eos/><bos/>In post-industrial society, information, more than labour, land or concrete inventions, has become the basis of wealth. <eos/><bos/>Information is a combination of equipment and techniques and the know-how of those who develop them. <eos/><bos/>New information is created at ever-increasing speeds as a result of new technologies such as microprocessing, fibre optics, lenses and digitization. <eos/><bos/>In 1956, white-collar workers, that is, those in technical, managerial and clerical positions, outnumbered blue-collar workers for the first time in modern history. <eos/><bos/>In 1982, more than 60% of American jobs were information-handling jobs, compared to only 13% manufacturing jobs. <eos/><bos/>In many cases, there is no longer any physical property to protect, and the significance of information often lies in the exploitation of an idea rather than physical access to it.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Icddfa8308e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Icddfa8308e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>G. Klueck, <begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>“The Coming Jurisprudence of the Information Age: Examinations of the Three Past Socio-Economic Ages Suggest the Future”<end.quote refid="QT_0001"/> (1984), 21 San Diego L. Rev. 1077 at p. 1079.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 1:6<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
