<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 4:42<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I5089a870411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>4.</label.designator><headtext>Confidential Business Information and the Employment Relationship</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I52517020411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>V.</label.designator><headtext>Fiduciary Duty</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I53a16fc0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>B.</label.designator><headtext>Remedies Table—Employment Relationship—Breach of Fiduciary Duty</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f65f556ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>4:42.</label.designator><headtext>Borrelli v. Chan</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><ital>Borrelli v. Chan</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 4302, 2018 ONSC 1429</headtext><eos/><eop/></head><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Award</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Damages assessed in the amount of $2,627,478,000</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Punitive damages of $5 million</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Summary of Facts</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>An action by the SFC Litigation Trust against Chan, the chief executive officer and chairman of the Board of Sino-Forest from 1994 to 2011, was allowed and damages were assessed in the amount of $2,627,478,000. <eos/><bos/>Sino-Forest suffered a catastrophic failure in 2011 following the publication of a negative analyst&apos;s report by Muddy Waters. <eos/><bos/>The Muddy Waters Report accused Sino-Forest of being a Ponzi scheme, rife with fraud, theft and undisclosed related-party transactions. <eos/><bos/>An Independent Committee of the Board was ultimately unable to disprove the principal Muddy Waters allegations. <eos/><bos/>It was unable to establish that Sino-Forest held good title to $2.99 billion of standing timber plantations in mainland China which were recorded as assets in Sino-Forest&apos;s audited financial statements. <eos/><bos/>It was unable to establish that Sino-Forest&apos;s counterparties in many standing timber and wood log trading transactions were arm&apos;s-length, partly because most of these counter parties disappeared or ceased to exist after publication of the Muddy Waters Report. <eos/><bos/>The Independent Committee uncovered evidence that Chan and other members of senior management were involved in the management and control of some of these counterparties. <eos/><bos/>Sino-Forest obtained a stay and restructuring orders under the <ital>Companies&apos; Creditors Arrangement Act</ital>. <eos/><bos/>By virtue of a plan of compromise approved by the Ontario Superior Court of Justice, the debtholders acquired the tangible assets of the company, which they later sold. <eos/><bos/>Sino-Forest&apos;s rights of action were assigned to the SFC Litigation Trust.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Sino-Forest was an integrated forest plantation operator and forest products company with assets predominantly in the People&apos;s Republic of China. <eos/><bos/>Its principal businesses included the ownership and management of forest plantations, the buying and selling of standing timber, wood logs and wood products and the complementary manufacturing of downstream wood products.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Chan had ultimate control over nearly all aspects of Sino-Forest&apos;s operations. <eos/><bos/>Chan&apos;s co-founder, Poon, by contrast, was described as “a figurehead.” <eos/><bos/>Operationally, Chan approved all plantation purchases and not only approved but signed all plantation sales contracts. <eos/><bos/>Similarly, Chan approved, and in many cases signed, all of Sino-Forest&apos;s wood log trading contracts.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>From 2005 onward, Sino-Forest utilized two models for its standing timber business in the PRC. One involved subsidiaries incorporated in the British Virgin Islands (“BVIs”) and the other involved subsidiaries incorporated in the PRC as wholly foreign owned enterprises (“WFOEs”).<eos/><bos/> Sino-Forest&apos;s BVI model was designed to circumvent restrictions on foreign companies carrying on business in the PRC. Foreign companies were not permitted to have PRC bank accounts, operate or sell timber plantations, or own land use rights in the PRC. Under the BVI model, Sino-Forest&apos;s BVI subsidiaries acquired standing timber from Suppliers. <eos/><bos/>The Suppliers were represented as third party aggregators who acquired the standing timber rights from other suppliers or from original timber owners such as village collectives. <eos/><bos/>The BVI subsidiaries (BVIs) did not acquire land use rights in the PRC. Instead, by means of standing timber purchase contracts, they acquired the rights to standing timber in the PRC. The BVIs did not sell standing timber directly to end-user customers. <eos/><bos/>Instead, the BVIs conducted the sale of standing timber through “authorized intermediaries” (“AIs”).<eos/><bos/> The AIs effectively served as the BVIs&apos; customers under the BVI model. <eos/><bos/>The BVIs did not directly pay the Suppliers or receive payments from the AIs. <eos/><bos/>Instead, the AIs were instructed by Sino-Forest&apos;s management to make “set-off payments.” <eos/><bos/>Under these arrangements, the AIs were supposed to make payments directly or indirectly to the Suppliers for amounts owed by the BVIs to those Suppliers. <eos/><bos/>As a result, no cash actually flowed through the BVI&apos;s or through Sino-Forest&apos;s bank accounts. <eos/><bos/>The AIs were also responsible for the payment of all taxes applicable to the sale transactions. <eos/><bos/>There were a number of negative features of the BVI Model. <eos/><bos/>Chief among them was that profits on the purchase and sale of standing timber plantations were “locked up” in the PRC. This was because the BVIs, not being able to have bank accounts or conduct active business in the PRC, could not monetize the value of their holdings in standing timber and transfer that value out of the PRC. They could only plough trading profits back into the acquisition of more standing timber.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Commencing in 2004, the PRC&apos;s Ministry of Commerce permitted foreign investors to invest in PRC-incorporated trading companies (WFOEs) and to participate in the commodity distribution industry, including the purchase of standing timber and land use rights throughout the PRC. Prior to this time, WFOEs were prohibited from engaging in the commodity distribution industry. <eos/><bos/>After the law changed to permit the use of foreign-owned PRC companies to own forestry assets, the WFOE model was “better” for Sino-Forest than the previously used BVI model. <eos/><bos/>Unlike Sino-Forest&apos;s BVIs, Sino-Forest&apos;s WFOEs could acquire plantation land use rights. <eos/><bos/>WFOEs were able to harvest the timber and sell both logs and standing timber directly to end customers. <eos/><bos/>Also, unlike BVIs, WFOEs could open PRC bank accounts, meaning that WFOEs could directly pay Suppliers and receive payments directly from customers. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, WFOEs did not need to utilize the set-off payments that were implemented under the BVI model. <eos/><bos/>Profits on WFOE enterprises were not “locked up” in the PRC. Although WFOEs did not need to use AIs, Sino-Forest&apos;s WFOEs continued to sell forestry assets to AIs using set-off arrangements rather than end-users, who would pay cash due to the longstanding relationships the AIs had with Sino-Forest. <eos/><bos/>After the law changed in 2004, Sino-Forest began looking for mechanisms to transfer assets held in the BVI model to the WFOE model. <eos/><bos/>This process was called “on-shoring.” <eos/><bos/>Between 2004 and 2011, Sino-Forest conducted four small “pilot test” on-shoring transactions, all of which took place in 2009. <eos/><bos/>No successful method was discovered to achieve “on-shoring” by June 2011.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Sino-Forest&apos;s financial statements reported exceptional growth from 2003 until the second quarter of 2011. <eos/><bos/>Between the 2003 and 2010 financial year ends, Sino-Forest&apos;s total reported assets increased by 1,268% and its total reported revenues increased by 624%. <eos/><bos/>The BVI standing timber model was, by far, the predominant contributor to the Sino-Forest Group&apos;s reported assets, revenue and profit.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Muddy Waters Report alleged that: (a) Sino-Forest did not hold the full amount of timber assets that it reported; (b) Sino-Forest overstated its revenue; and (c) Sino-Forest had engaged in undisclosed related-party transactions, including with Yuda Wood, Sino-Forest&apos;s largest supplier of standing timber between 2007 and 2010. <eos/><bos/>It was alleged that Yuda Wood was secretly controlled by Sino-Forest insiders.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The starting point for the Independent Committee (“IC”) investigation was to determine whether Sino-Forest owned the billions of dollars of BVI standing timber assets recorded in its audited financial statements. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, the IC asked to see the contracts underlying the BVI assets. <eos/><bos/>The purchase contracts stated that plantation rights certificates and villagers authorization were attached, which would have confirmed Sino-Forest&apos;s legal title to the standing timber. <eos/><bos/>However, the plantation rights certificates and villagers authorization were not attached to any of its BVI standing timber contracts and Sino-Forest did not have any of these documents. <eos/><bos/>The IC advisors sought to obtain new confirmations from the forestry bureaus. <eos/><bos/>However, new confirmations were only issued in four instances. <eos/><bos/>In those four instances, the new confirmations did not confirm ownership of the BVI standing timber assets but only recognized the contractual relationship between Sino-Forest and its Supplier. <eos/><bos/>Since Sino-Forest did not have any of the documentation necessary to establish title to the BVI standing timber or that its transactions with its BVI counterparties actually took place, the IC sought to set up meetings with Sino-Forest&apos;s BVI Suppliers and AIs to see if they had documentation to establish the validity of Sino-Forest&apos;s BVI standing timber assets. <eos/><bos/>All of the Suppliers and AIs who were asked, refused or were otherwise unable to produce any documentation of ownership or banking records indicating they had paid or received payment by way of the set offs directed by Sino-Forest. <eos/><bos/>The IC also discovered documentary evidence of close relationships between Sino-Forest and some of its BVI standing timber counterparties, including a company called Yuda Wood.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Audit Committee&apos;s primary concern was that Sino-Forest&apos;s management remained unable to provide satisfactory explanations of documents appearing to indicate that there were connections between Sino-Forest and certain of its AIs and Suppliers. <eos/><bos/>The Audit Committee did not have sufficient comfort that the financial statements could be presented fairly and accurately. <eos/><bos/>The Audit Committee, therefore, made a recommendation against release of the Q3 Results. <eos/><bos/>On November 15, 2011, Sino-Forest issued a press release stating that it was deferring the release of the Q3 Results for a 30 day period. <eos/><bos/>Sino-Forest&apos;s failure to file the Q3 Results and provide a copy of the Q3 Results to the noteholders constituted a default. <eos/><bos/>Sino-Forest issued a press release explaining that it was not going to be in a position to release the Q3 Results within the 30-day period set out in its November 15 press release. <eos/><bos/>Sino-Forest further announced in that, in the circumstances, there was no assurance that it would ever be able to release the Q3 Results, or, if able, when the release might occur. <eos/><bos/>Sino-Forest then failed to make a $9.775 million interest payment on the 2016 convertible notes that was due on December 15, 2011. <eos/><bos/>This failure constituted another event of default under the indentures. <eos/><bos/>Following further discussions with its external auditors, on January 10, 2012 Sino-Forest issued a press release cautioning that its <begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>“historic financial statements and related audit reports should not be relied upon.”<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0001"/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff&apos;s allegations of breach of fiduciary duty were that Chan had an undisclosed interest in many significant Sino-Forest transactions; that Chan preferred his own interest to the interest of Sino-Forest; and that Chan had undisclosed conflicts of interest that permeated his tenure as chairman and CEO. <eos/><bos/>Justice Perry observed that the first critical disputed issue involved whether Sino-Forest&apos;s counter-parties in the BVI standing timber transactions, WFOE standing timber transactions and wood log trading transactions were <ital>bona fide</ital> arm&apos;s length parties or whether they were secretly connected to and under the control of Chan or other members of Inside Management at Chan&apos;s direction. <eos/><bos/>The second critical disputed issue was whether the BVI and WFOE standing timber transactions which purported to produce an asset value in 2011 of $2.99 billion were real transactions for which valuable consideration was paid and received; resulted in BVI standing timber assets that could be located and were actually owned by Sino-Forest&apos;s subsidiaries and could be harvested or sold on the market for valuable consideration; and had a value anywhere near $2.99 billion.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Penny noted that as the CEO, a director and Chairman of the Board of Sino-Forest, Chan owed the Sino-Forest fiduciary duties. <eos/><bos/>Chan was charged with managing the assets of Sino-Forest honestly and in a manner consistent with the objects of the corporation. <eos/><bos/>Chan&apos;s fiduciary duties included an obligation: (a) to act in good faith and in the best interests of the corporation; (b) not to abuse his position for personal gain; and (c) to avoid conflicts of interest with the corporation. <eos/><bos/>Directors and officers must serve the corporation selflessly, honestly and loyally.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Penny observed that as CEO, director and Chairman, Chan owed fiduciary duties akin to those of a trustee because he exercised control and management over Sino-Forest&apos;s assets. <eos/><bos/>Corporate directors are not true trustees. <eos/><bos/>They are, however, in a closely analogous position. <eos/><bos/>The duties of loyalty and good faith that they owe to the corporation are akin to those imposed upon trustees. <eos/><bos/>The obligations of directors who are involved in the control and management of corporate assets are closely analogous to those of trustees in relation to trust property. <eos/><bos/>Directors and officers who manage or control property of the corporation have an obligation to ensure that property is used in furtherance of specified purposes of the company. <eos/><bos/>For this reason, a misapplication of corporate assets by a director can be akin to a breach of trust. <eos/><bos/>Chan owed fiduciary duties towards Sino-Forest akin to the obligations of a trustee because of the high degree of control and management that he exercised over Sino-Forest&apos;s assets. <eos/><bos/>Chan orchestrated all the transactions which ultimately led to Sino-Forest&apos;s collapse. <eos/><bos/>He gave instructions and authorization to the activities of other members of Inside Management. <eos/><bos/>Chan had ultimate control over nearly all aspects of Sino-Forest&apos;s operations and very little, if any, decision-making occurred without his knowledge and approval.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Penny concluded that Chan breached his fiduciary duties to the corporation. <eos/><bos/>He violated his duty to act in good faith with a view to the best interests of the corporation by pursuing his personal interests and those of his friends and associates. <eos/><bos/>He abused his position for personal gain by making personal profits from transactions that harmed the corporation and funneling funds to entities that he controlled or benefited from. <eos/><bos/>He violated his duty to avoid conflicts of interest by causing the payment of Sino-Forest funds into transactions with corporations that he secretly beneficially owned or controlled.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Penny observed that the Court may infer causation in the absence of evidence to the contrary. <eos/><bos/>The Court may make such inferences even if the plaintiff adduces little affirmative evidence and lacks positive or scientific proof of causation. <eos/><bos/>The Court may make an adverse inference against the defendant if the defendant fails to provide a credible explanation to rebut the evidence adduced by the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>This is not a reverse onus. <eos/><bos/>Instead, it is merely the application of a <begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>“robust and pragmatic approach to the...facts”<end.quote refid="QT_0002"/> and is consistent with the trial judge&apos;s fundamental role in weighing evidence. <eos/><bos/>Canadian courts have applied this basic evidentiary principle to fraud and breach of fiduciary duty. <eos/><bos/>Adverse inferences may be drawn against defendants as long as the plaintiff has made reasonable efforts to adduce evidence to link the defendant&apos;s conduct to the harm suffered and the defendant provides no credible explanation. <eos/><bos/>The court assessing damages will not demand exacting proof of the precise loss from fraud or breach of fiduciary duty, but instead draw an adverse inference against a defendant found to have been fraudulent or in breach of fiduciary duty unless that defendant leads evidence to disprove the amount or cause of the loss.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Penny noted that it is also a well-established legal principle that the Court is entitled to resolve evidentiary difficulties against the wrongdoer who created them. <eos/><bos/>Sino-Forest&apos;s collapse was triggered by the revelations in the Muddy Waters Report but was caused by the inability of the company to demonstrate that it owned BVI standing timber assets worth $2.9 billion; audits standing timber and wood log trading operations were <ital>bona fide</ital>, conducted with arm&apos;s-length counterparties at fair market value. <eos/><bos/>It could not do so because through Chan&apos;s fraud and breach of fiduciary duty, Sino-Forest did not own standing timber worth $2.9 billion and engaged in secret, related-party transactions. <eos/><bos/>Chan concealed the use of non-arm&apos;s-length counterparties and the diversion of funds to those counterparties in the form of the wood log skimming and deposit frauds. <eos/><bos/>Sino-Forest did not own BVI standing timber assets worth anything close to $2.9 billion. <eos/><bos/>Sino-Forest&apos;s BVI standing timber and wood log trading operations were not <ital>bona fide</ital> and were not conducted with arm&apos;s-length counterparties. <eos/><bos/>Chan directed a massive fraud, in breach of his fiduciary duties to the company, in which he caused Sino-Forest to misrepresent its assets and their value. <eos/><bos/>The causal link between Chan&apos;s misfeasance and the total collapse of Sino-Forest was established.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Reasons Given by Court for Award</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Penny observed that much like causation, the determination of quantum is also a matter of common sense. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff has an onus to prove the facts upon which damages are estimated but where the assessment is difficult because of the nature of the damage proved, the difficulty of assessment is no ground for refusing substantial damages, <begin.quote ID="QT_0003"/>“even to the point of resorting to guess work,”<end.quote refid="QT_0003"/> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175896" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1998462285" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I41276ac08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Martin v. Goldfarb</ital>, 1998 CarswellOnt 3319 (Ont. C.A.)</cite.query>, leave to appeal refused [1999] 1 S.C.R. x (S.C.C.).<eos/><bos/> The difficulty of determining quantum can never excuse the wrongdoer from paying damages. <eos/><bos/>It followed that determining quantum is a process of holistic assessment, not precise mathematical calculation. <eos/><bos/>While expert evidence is admissible and may be useful, assessment of damages is ultimately a task for the court and not for accountants or other mathematical and statistical experts.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Penny observed that the central complicating factor in the calculation of damages was that the BVI standing timber model was essentially a cashless model. <eos/><bos/>Due to the unique characteristics of foreign (BVI) companies operating in China and foreign currency controls, the BVI standing timber model was based on ploughing paper profits back into the purported acquisition of ever greater stands of timber in China. <eos/><bos/>Little or no money came into or went out of Sino-Forest in connection with trading in BVI standing timber itself. <eos/><bos/>When Sino-Forest bought a plantation from a Supplier, it sold another plantation to an AI. <eos/><bos/>Sino-Forest did not pay the Supplier for the new plantation. <eos/><bos/>Sino-Forest did not receive payment from the AI on the sale of the old plantation. <eos/><bos/>Rather, Sino-Forest directed AIs to pay Suppliers, not Sino-Forest. <eos/><bos/>Sino-Forest&apos;s asset base in BVI standing timber grew, but Sino-Forest received no cash flow on these transactions. <eos/><bos/>At one level, therefore, Justice Penny observed that one could argue that, upon the collapse of the BVI standing timber model, Sino-Forest suffered no loss. <eos/><bos/>It paid nothing for the asset so if the asset turned out not to exist, or to have no value, Sino-Forest suffered no damage. <eos/><bos/>However, this approach would ignore the effect of having carried the BVI standing timber assets on the books of the company valued at $2.99 billion. <eos/><bos/>From a financial perspective, the largest impact of representing this value of Sino-Forest&apos;s principal asset in its audited financial statements was that it enabled Sino-Forest to go to the capital markets and raise money. <eos/><bos/>The Sino-Forest business model required cash infusions for operating expenses precisely because the BVI standing timber model generated no cash revenues.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Whether or not the BVI standing timber assets existed and whether they had any value was a central disputed issue of fact. <eos/><bos/>It is not a matter for experts to decide. <eos/><bos/>Chan had provided no evidence that the former Sino-Forest BVI standing timber assets had been identified, located or had their ownership confirmed, much less monetized. <eos/><bos/>Justice Penny found as a fact that Sino-Forest did not own the BVI standing timber asset and that its value was nil. <eos/><bos/>The best indication of value is what an arm&apos;s-length purchaser is willing to pay. <eos/><bos/>The pre-CCAA attempt to sell the BVI standing timber assets produced nothing. <eos/><bos/>The Monitor&apos;s efforts to identify value while Sino-Forest was under court supervision also produced nothing. <eos/><bos/>EPHL, although highly motivated to realize the highest possible value, wrote the BVI standing timber assets down to nil.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Penny observed that this was a case where the principle of equitable damages applied. <eos/><bos/>Chan was a fiduciary. <eos/><bos/>He caused Sino-Forest to invest in Greenheart when he had an undisclosed interest. <eos/><bos/>This was a breach of his fiduciary duty owed to Sino-Forest. <eos/><bos/>Chan&apos;s role as CEO and Chairman was not as a trustee but it was “trust-like.” <eos/><bos/>Chan&apos;s fiduciary obligation as the senior officer and director of Sino-Forest placed upon him the obligation to deal with Sino-Forest&apos;s property, including funds available, for the benefit only of Sino-Forest. <eos/><bos/>Equitable compensation is determined by analogy to the principles of trust law. <eos/><bos/>Equity is concerned with restoration of the actual value of the thing lost through the breach of duty, in this case Sino-Forest&apos;s funds raised on the capital markets. <eos/><bos/>Equitable compensation is assessed at the date of trial, not, like common-law damages, at the date of the breach. <eos/><bos/>And, equity presumes the trust funds will be invested in the most profitable way or put to the most advantageous use.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Penny concluded that the failure to disclose Chan&apos;s interest was a breach of Chan&apos;s fiduciary duty. <eos/><bos/>Sino-Forest was entitled to be put in the position it would have been if the breach had not occurred, i.e., if the investment had not been made. <eos/><bos/>Sino-Forest was not required to bear the risk of market fluctuation between the date of acquisition and the date of sale. <eos/><bos/>The fact that the discovery of Chan&apos;s fraud had a negative effect on the market value of the Greenheart asset was not a market risk Sino-Forest had to bear. <eos/><bos/>Justice Penny concluded that Sino-Forest was, in the circumstances, not required to prove that the Greenheart investment of $202 million was not at fair market value at the time was made. <eos/><bos/>It was sufficient that Sino-Forest suffered a loss in fact, provided the realization was not improvident. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence that the sale of Greenheart to New Forest was an improvident realization in the circumstances.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Penny concluded that there was no evidence there were any external forces affecting value. <eos/><bos/>It was not the plaintiff&apos;s obligation to exclude every possible contributor to a decline in value. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff made his theory clear --- the collapse of Sino-Forest was the result of Chan&apos;s fraud. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff established there was a fraud and that over $2.7 billion in assets did not exist. <eos/><bos/>It was for the defendant to show that there were other factors contributing to the loss. <eos/><bos/>Chan failed to lead any evidence that any external factors contributed to Sino-Forest&apos;s losses.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Penny observed that the question of whether Chan could only be held liable for specific amounts resulting from losses due to specific frauds, or whether Chan could only be found liable for amounts specifically traceable to him as a result of his misfeasance or breach of fiduciary duty, are legal questions, not questions for the damages experts. <eos/><bos/>The defendant had not justified the transaction by transaction approach as the <ital>sine qua non</ital> of an appropriate loss calculation, in law or in damage calculation practice. <eos/><bos/>The loss suffered as a result of Chan&apos;s fraud was more than the sum of specific losses attributable to individual transactions or components of the fraud. <eos/><bos/>The BVI standing timber model was a cashless model. <eos/><bos/>Even if the BVI standing timber assets were misrepresented and had no value, they were not bought with cash. <eos/><bos/>No amount of “transaction by transaction” analysis would produce any loss.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Between 2007 and 2010, Sino-Forest raised in excess of USD$2.1 billion and CAD$800 million in Canada&apos;s debt and capital markets. <eos/><bos/>This money belonged to the corporation. <eos/><bos/>Justice Penny found that, but for Chan&apos;s deceit, Sino-Forest would never have undertaken obligations of this magnitude to lenders and shareholders or entrusted this money to him and Inside Management. <eos/><bos/>Chan, rather than directing Sino-Forest&apos;s spending on legitimate business operations, poured hundreds of millions of dollars into fictitious or over-valued lines of business where he engaged in undisclosed related-party transactions and funneled funds to entities that he secretly controlled. <eos/><bos/>The loss of these funds to Sino-Forest was directly related to Chan&apos;s fraud and breach of fiduciary duty. <eos/><bos/>The fact that Chan was able to conceal where a great deal of the money went after it was paid out to these non-arms&apos; length third parties could not defeat the plaintiff&apos;s claim. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, Chan was liable to Sino-Forest to return the property that went missing as a result of his fraud and breaches of fiduciary duty by making good the loss suffered by Sino-Forest. <eos/><bos/>Billions of dollars of forestry assets purportedly owned by Sino-Forest remained unaccounted for despite nearly six years of investigations by a number of sophisticated parties and experienced professionals. <eos/><bos/>Chan also failed to come forward with any evidence confirming the validity of Sino-Forest&apos;s title to 520,000 ha of standing timber held in the BVI model or any evidence that these assets had material value. <eos/><bos/>The evidence established that Sino-Forest raised net cash proceeds of approximately $2.588 billion. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff&apos;s expert reasonably assumed that Sino-Forest would have earned a return of approximately $477.853 million had it invested that cash, using Sino-Forest&apos;s issue costs and debt interest as a proxy for a minimum rate of return. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, but for the fraud perpetrated by Chan on Sino-Forest and Chan&apos;s breaches of fiduciary duty, these funds totalling $3.065 billion would have been available to Sino-Forest to invest in legitimate business operations. <eos/><bos/>EPHL recovered $438.5 million on its sale of Sino-Forest&apos;s assets. <eos/><bos/>As such, approximately $3,065,985,000 of Sino-Forest&apos;s monies were converted into assets ultimately worth only $438,509,000. <eos/><bos/>The appropriate measure of damage was the difference between the amount raised by Sino-Forest in the capital markets and the realized value of the assets which was $2,627,512,000.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Penny observed that Chan abused his unique position as a fiduciary to orchestrate an extremely large and complex fraud, resulting in the loss by Sino-Forest of billions of dollars. <eos/><bos/>An award of punitive damages was entirely appropriate. <eos/><bos/>Given the sums involved, any award of punitive damages could only be token in nature. <eos/><bos/>Nevertheless, in the circumstances, Justice Penny awarded punitive damages of $5 million.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></section.body></section><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 4:42<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
