<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 4:50<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I5089a870411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>4.</label.designator><headtext>Confidential Business Information and the Employment Relationship</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I52517020411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>V.</label.designator><headtext>Fiduciary Duty</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I53a16fc0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>B.</label.designator><headtext>Remedies Table—Employment Relationship—Breach of Fiduciary Duty</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f6864b6ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>4:50.</label.designator><headtext>Consolidated Compressor Co. v. Northwest Equipment Ltd.</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><ital>Consolidated Compressor Co. v. Northwest Equipment Ltd.</ital>, 2012 CarswellAlta 660, 2012 ABQB 222</headtext><eos/><eop/></head><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Award</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The employer was awarded damages in the amount of $40,595.93 against its general manager and against the corporate defendant</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Summary of Facts:</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The employer was a family owned company. <eos/><bos/>In 1999, its primary existing business was to provide construction contractors with diesel-powered portable compressors and abrasives equipment. <eos/><bos/>Lesley Smith was the President, handing financial and administrative affairs and Charles Smith, her father and the founder of the business, was the semi-retired Chairman of the Board. <eos/><bos/>The shares were owned by Ms. Smith, Mr. Smith and his wife. <eos/><bos/>Mr. Smith wished to retire completely, but revenue in the business was on a downward trend. <eos/><bos/>Mr. Smith hired V initially as an outside consultant to help the Smiths decide whether it would be best to sell the company or whether, with some changes, it could be a viable continuing entity. <eos/><bos/>V&apos;s first report to the employer&apos;s Board stated that lack of marketing was a problem and advised that he and Ms. Smith had agreed to hire B, who was V&apos;s nephew, as a full-time outside salesman. <eos/><bos/>The employer knew that the corporate defendant was a company that V used to conduct some miscellaneous business such as buying and selling used equipment. <eos/><bos/>The consulting fees for V&apos;s work were paid to the corporate defendant rather than to V directly. <eos/><bos/>At some point in December 1999, the employer decided to hire V as its general manager. <eos/><bos/>He was hired to bring in new product lines and to therefore raise sales. <eos/><bos/>His duties were to officially begin in January, 2000. <eos/><bos/>When Mr. Smith returned from Florida on April 25, 2000, he was alarmed to see from a review of the employer&apos;s first quarter financials that the company&apos;s cash position was deteriorating. <eos/><bos/>On May 23, 2000, the general manager met with Mr. Smith and Ms. Smith. <eos/><bos/>They discussed concerns, and did not reach any constructive resolution. <eos/><bos/>The next day, the general manager resigned. <eos/><bos/>Ms. Smith and Mr. Smith decided not to require the general manager to serve the two weeks&apos; notice he had given and asked him to leave immediately. <eos/><bos/>They then met with B and W, an employee who had been hired by the employer as a service technician at the instigation of the general manager, who said that the general manager spoke for all of them and that they were leaving. <eos/><bos/>The next day, B and Wood returned to the employer&apos;s office, gathered up the manuals associated with product lines that they had brought to the employer as employees and distributed new business cards in the name of the corporate defendant. <eos/><bos/>After the general manager&apos;s group left, the employer was unable to continue purchasing from some of its existing suppliers. <eos/><bos/>The corporate defendant was dealing with a number of the employer&apos;s customers in 2000 and 2001, and entered into a number of service agreements some of which were with pre-existing clients of the employer.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Reasons Given by Court for Award:</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The court concluded that the employer&apos;s general manager V had a fiduciary obligation to the employer arising from his position as a key employee. <eos/><bos/>The general manager was the controlling mind of the corporate defendant and the corporate defendant was the entity that benefitted from his breaches. <eos/><bos/>The corporate defendant was equally liable with the general manager for his breaches of fiduciary duty.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The employer had claimed damages for breach of employment and consulting agreements in the total amount of $102,666.28 against the general manager, B and W. The court observed that this claim appeared to be a claim for the reimbursement of salaries paid to them. <eos/><bos/>The court concluded that this claim could not succeed against the general manager because the employer did not claim that the general manager breached his contractual terms of employment, but that he breached his duty as a fiduciary, a claim in restitution. <eos/><bos/>While B and W could be said to have breached the non-solicitation provisions of their contracts of employment, the damages that resulted to the employer from these breaches arose from the loss of business from the employer&apos;s clients and the loss of corporate opportunities, not from wasted expenditures on salaries. <eos/><bos/>The employer established that damages representing foregone profit were payable by the general manager and the corporate defendant on the basis of disgorgement of profits arising from the general manager&apos;s breach of his fiduciary obligations.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></section.body></section><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 4:50<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
