<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 4:49<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I5089a870411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>4.</label.designator><headtext>Confidential Business Information and the Employment Relationship</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I52517020411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>V.</label.designator><headtext>Fiduciary Duty</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I53a16fc0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>B.</label.designator><headtext>Remedies Table—Employment Relationship—Breach of Fiduciary Duty</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f686486ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>4:49.</label.designator><headtext>Parsons Canada Ltd. v. Nathoo</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><ital>Parsons Canada Ltd. v. Nathoo</ital>, 2013 CarswellOnt 13866, 2013 ONSC 5975</headtext><eos/><eop/></head><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Award</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Plaintiff awarded judgment against the defendants for the following:</paratext><list><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>1.</label.designator></head><paratext>Damages in the amount of $1,938,860.42</paratext></para></list.item><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>2.</label.designator></head><paratext>Special damages in the amount of Canadian dollars equivalent to US$272,099.50</paratext></para></list.item><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>3.</label.designator></head><paratext>Punitive damages in the amount of $50,000</paratext></para></list.item></list><eos/><eop/></para><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Summary of Facts:</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff, Parsons alleged that its former employees, Nathoo and Jamal defrauded it $2,176,845.78 over the course of several years. <eos/><bos/>The defendants retained counsel, but did not deliver statements of defence and were noted in default. <eos/><bos/>Parsons manages private company programs and government programs. <eos/><bos/>The Province of Ontario retained Parsons to help administer a government program. <eos/><bos/>Parsons was responsible for implementing an accounting system to deal with financial transactions for more than 2,000 different facilities involved in the Program. <eos/><bos/>This involved maintaining multiple corporate bank accounts and thousands of daily transactions. <eos/><bos/>The defendants were accountants involved in administering the Program for the various corporate bank accounts. <eos/><bos/>Certain anomalies were discovered while reconciling the Program&apos;s accounting system with Parsons&apos; accounting system in late 2012. <eos/><bos/>Investigations revealed that 54 cheques and 5 bank drafts totaling $1,417,299.43 had been drawn on the BMO Account or the RBC Account and made payable to Nathoo or Jamal. <eos/><bos/>The investigation team confirmed 88 “flagged” transactions from Parsons&apos; corporate accounts by the defendants, totaling $1,861,196.27 over a seven year period from 2006 through 2012.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Reasons Given by Court for Award:</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The court accepted the findings of the Protiviti Report. <eos/><bos/>Protiviti identified 88 fraudulent withdrawals by the defendants over a seven year period totaling $1,861,196.27. <eos/><bos/>Protiviti identified an additional 65 “suspicious transactions” totaling $316,111.35 that took place between 2004 and 2012, but could not link these transactions directly to the defendants. <eos/><bos/>The court was satisfied that the defendants fraudulently withdrew a total of $1,960,191.36 from Parsons&apos; corporate accounts for their direct benefit. <eos/><bos/>This left $216,655.12 in unconfirmed suspicious transactions. <eos/><bos/>Parsons can identify that the unconfirmed amount was withdrawn from its corporate accounts for no apparent business reason, but cannot trace the amounts into accounts controlled by Nathoo or Jamal. <eos/><bos/>Parsons&apos; Audit Group concluded that the defendants took the unconfirmed amount as there is no other plausible explanation for the withdrawals. <eos/><bos/>It was not sufficient for Parsons to say that the defendants must have withdrawn the unconfirmed amount because Parsons could find no other explanation. <eos/><bos/>Parsons must link the defendants to the withdrawals in some meaningful way to satisfy its onus. <eos/><bos/>Therefore, Parsons could identify on a balance of probabilities that Nathoo or Jamal fraudulently withdrew $1,960,191.36 from Parsons&apos; corporate accounts for their personal benefit. <eos/><bos/>Parsons was entitled to judgment against the defendants in the amount of $1,960,191.36 for damages for conversion, fraud, and breach of fiduciary duty.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The defendants&apos; conduct justified an award of punitive damages. <eos/><bos/>For several years, the defendants for their direct benefit engaged in a scheme intentionally designed to defraud their employer and grossly abuse their positions of trust and authority. <eos/><bos/>Such conduct is unpalatable, reprehensible, and egregious. <eos/><bos/>The defendants committed almost 100 incidents of fraud over an extended period of time. <eos/><bos/>Their conduct was deserving of punishment on its own.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>An award of $50,000 is more rationally related to the objectives for which the punitive damages are awarded. <eos/><bos/>The expert reports conclude that Nathoo and Jamal committed the thefts to serve their gambling disorders. <eos/><bos/>Mr. Goyer describes the problem as <begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>“diagnostically better known as Pathological Gambling. <eos/><bos/>This is a medical condition in which a person can lose control over their gambling urges and can lead to a significant loss of money … the behavior has a compulsive quality akin to that as an addiction”<end.quote refid="QT_0001"/>. <eos/><bos/>Dr. Rootenberg describes the condition as “severe gambling disorder”.<eos/><bos/> Second, the defendants&apos; ongoing criminal proceedings impact the punitive damages award. <eos/><bos/>Nathoo and Jamal are each facing criminal charges of fraud over $5,000. <eos/><bos/>In all probability, the defendants will receive criminal punishments for the fraudulent acts. <eos/><bos/>It is fully expected that society will collectively denounce the abhorrent conduct and impose a punitive sentence. <eos/><bos/>Third, the amount of Parsons&apos; loss impacts the quantum of punitive damages.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Parsons was also awarded US$272,099.50 as special damages for the costs of a forensic investigation to determine Parsons&apos; loss as a result of the defendants&apos; fraudulent actions damages arising out of a forensic investigation undertaken to determine the damages suffered by it as a result of the defendants&apos; actions. <eos/><bos/>These special damages flow naturally from the established cause of action.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></section.body></section><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 4:49<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
