<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 4:6<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I5089a870411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>4.</label.designator><headtext>Confidential Business Information and the Employment Relationship</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I50976410411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>III.</label.designator><headtext>Confidentiality</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f6112f6ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>4:6.</label.designator><headtext>Information Meriting Protection—Following End of Employment Relationship</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The duty owed by an employee in relation to some kinds of information, following the conclusion of the employment relationship, is less stringent than that owed during the course of employment. <eos/><bos/>The English Court of Appeal made this clear in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1985030763" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I258bd9e18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Faccenda Chicken Ltd. v. Fowler</ital></cite.query>:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>(4) The implied term which imposes an obligation on the employee as to his conduct after the determination of the employment <ital>is more restricted in its scope</ital> than that which imposes a general duty of good faith.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0001"/></paratext></para><head parent="display.quote"><headtext>…..</headtext></head><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>The obligation does not extend, however, to cover all information which is given to or acquired by the employee while in his employment, and in particular may not cover information which is only ‘confidential’ in the sense that an unauthorised disclosure of such information to a third party <ital>while the employment subsisted</ital> would be a clear breach of the duty of good faith.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0002"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id38ce7708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><paratext>(Emphasis added.)<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Canadian courts have made frequent use of <ital>Faccenda Chicken Ltd. v. Fowler</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id38ce7718e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>] in which the trial court had divided information into three categories. <eos/><bos/>See for example <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2006796530" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I258e23d18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">ACS Public Sector Solutions Inc. v. Courthouse Technologies</cite.query> Ltd.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id38ce7728e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">3</footnote.reference>] which confirmed the usefulness of the <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1985030763" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I258e23d38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Faccenda</ital></cite.query> categories:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0003"/>The first was trivial information which would not be protected against use by a former employee. <eos/><bos/>The third was specific trade secrets which would be so protected. <eos/><bos/>The middle category was described, at p. 731 of the trial judgment, as follows:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext>Second, there is information which the servant must treat as confidential, either because he is expressly told it is confidential, or because from its character it obviously is so, but which once learned necessarily remains in the servant&apos;s head and becomes part of his own skill and knowledge applied in the course of his master&apos;s business. <eos/><bos/>So long as the employment continues, he cannot otherwise use or disclose such information without infidelity and therefore breach of contract. <eos/><bos/>But when he is no longer in the same service, the law allows him to use his full skill and knowledge for his own benefit in competition with his former master …<end.quote refid="QT_0003"/></paratext></para></display.quote></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0004"/>On the evidence before me, I conclude that is the situation we have here. <eos/><bos/>It has not been demonstrated that the defendants are doing anything other than using or planning to use their own skills and expertise as requested Kerr.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0004"/></paratext></para></display.quote><paratext>The courts have focused on a number of factors when determining whether a former employee should be prevented from using specific information. <eos/><bos/>However, the most successful route for employers to obtain protection is to demonstrate that the information is unique and not generally known within the employer&apos;s industry.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38d83b08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">4</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A party seeking to protect information must be reasonably specific in describing what is at risk and why it should be protected. <eos/><bos/>This point was highlighted in <ital>Future Shop v. Northwest-Atlantic (B.C.)</ital>, where the court concluded:[<footnote.reference refid="Id38d83b18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">5</footnote.reference>]</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0006"/>The plaintiff&apos;s material is far from specific about what confidential material Ms. Moseley has in her possession and how the disclosure of that material would benefit Best Buy and harm Future Shop. <eos/><bos/>One example is the plaintiff&apos;s assertion that Ms. Moseley knows their “highly confidential negotiating strategy”.<eos/><bos/> No particulars are disclosed and Ms. Moseley responds by saying she does not know of such a strategy.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0006"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0007"/>The burden lies on the applicant to provide details sufficient to support the finding they seek and to enable the court to craft, if appropriate, an injunction that goes no further than is reasonably necessary to protect the interest at risk. <eos/><bos/>A portion of the decision of Gill, J. in <ital>Ebco Industries v. Kaltech Manufacturing Ltd.</ital> [[1999] B.C.J. 2350], is particularly applicable to the assertion of a highly confidential negotiating strategy. <eos/><bos/>At para. 48 of her reasons, Gill, J. notes:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext>… It cannot be the case that merely because the relief sought is interim rather than permanent that a bare statement that there is a “unique” process sought is sufficient to support a conclusion that there is a fair question to be tried as to the existence of confidential information or trade secrets. <eos/><bos/>As was pointed out by counsel for the defendants, no where in the materials is there a specific description of any process or system such that the alleged confidentiality can be assessed. <eos/><bos/>At best there is reference to <begin.quote ID="QT_0005"/>“certain techniques such as modifying machines or retooling”<end.quote refid="QT_0005"/>. <eos/><bos/>Neither the collective agreement nor the employment contract referred to above can remedy this deficiency. <eos/><bos/>I therefore cannot accede to the plaintiff&apos;s argument that a fair question has been made out on this issue.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0007"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id38daac08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">6</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Similarly, in <ital>Rawlco Communications (Sask.) Ltd. v. Clements</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id38daac18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">7</footnote.reference>] the plaintiff did not succeed because it had only made vague allegations stating that the respondent was knowledgeable about a number of secret ideas the company was “planning and considering”, but the plaintiff did not provide <begin.quote ID="QT_0008"/>“any details, even in general terms, of what the secret ideas were alleged to be.”<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0008"/> The same result was reached in <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2001461243" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I259269918e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Life Investors Insurance Co. of America v. Tis Management</cite.query> Ltd.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id38daac28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">8</footnote.reference>] where the plaintiffs had provided “little if any credible evidence” to support their contentions. <eos/><bos/>On the other hand, where a party identifies specific projects, transactions or opportunities, they are more likely to succeed in protecting related business information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38daac38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">9</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>There can be no breach of confidentiality by an employee where the information has been widely disclosed, falls within the general knowledge available in the industry, is easily ascertainable on inquiry, or is readily available but for simple modifications.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38daac48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">10</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Often, the courts in these cases focus on whether reasonable steps were taken by the employer in the circumstances to maintain the secrecy of the information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38daac58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">11</footnote.reference>] The greater the effort made by an employer to protect information from disclosure, both within and outside the organization, the greater the likelihood the courts will consider the information to be confidential.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In the leading decision of the Ontario Court of Appeal, <ital>International Tools Ltd. v. Kollar</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id38daac68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">12</footnote.reference>] certain employees were provided limited access to an area of the employer&apos;s facility for specific purposes. <eos/><bos/>The area was completely secured, difficult to access, and marked by signs prohibiting entry. <eos/><bos/>The court, in preventing the recipients from making use of or disclosing the information in question, observed that:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0009"/>A high degree of secrecy was maintained in connection with the pin-making; it was done in a locked area to which the only access was through the office of a managerial employee and to the door of which only two keys were in existence; the presence of “No Admission” signs on the door, the masking of the glass partition to prevent observation from outside of what was going on inside, all served to reinforce the warning which the defendants had been given.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0009"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id38dd1d08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">13</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1985030763" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I2595c4f18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Faccenda Chicken</ital></cite.query>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id38dd1d18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">14</footnote.reference>] a former employee, Fowler, established a competitive business shortly after his departure from the plaintiff&apos;s business. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff, Faccenda Chicken, marketed fresh chickens from refrigerated vans that traveled particular routes. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff sought to restrain Fowler from using sales and pricing information related to the company&apos;s customers and business. <eos/><bos/>The court outlined a number of factors that should be considered by employers seeking to protect business information from disclosure, including restricting the circulation of information to a limited number of individuals, impressing on the recipient, through specific instructions and warnings, the confidentiality of the information, and maintaining an attitude towards the information that reinforces its confidentiality.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38dd1d28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">15</footnote.reference>] In the circumstances, the court concluded that a number of factors led to the clear conclusion that the information at issue did not have the necessary degree of confidentiality:</paratext><list><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(1)</label.designator></head><paratext>The information was necessarily acquired by all the defendants in order to perform their work.<eos/><bos/></paratext></para></list.item><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(2)</label.designator></head><paratext>The information was generally known among the staff, including those at quite a junior level.<eos/><bos/></paratext></para></list.item><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(3)</label.designator></head><paratext>There was no evidence that the plaintiff had ever given any express instructions that the information was to be treated as confidential.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38dd1d38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">16</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></list.item></list><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Safety First Contracting (1995) Ltd. v. Murphy</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id38df8e08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">17</footnote.reference>] Safety First was involved in the management of traffic diversion and safety during road redesign and construction activity. <eos/><bos/>Safety First had a near monopoly in the traffic control business for the St. John&apos;s metropolitan market from 2011 to 2016, at least with respect to traffic control for the more complicated construction sites. <eos/><bos/>This lawsuit arose from circumstances surrounding the end of that near monopoly, and the decision of Safety First&apos;s former operations manager, Murphy, to accept a near identical management position with the new competitor in the marketplace, Hi-Vis. <eos/><bos/>Murphy had been with Safety First for just 14 months at the time he tendered his resignation. <eos/><bos/>He accepted the new position with Hi-Vis less than three weeks after resigning. <eos/><bos/>In the St. John&apos;s metropolitan market, Safety First and Hi-Vis competed for the same customers.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38df8e18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">18</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Safety First sought damages against Murphy for breach of a confidentiality and non-competition agreement, breach of confidence, and wrongful conversion of trade secrets. <eos/><bos/>Safety First claimed that Murphy signed a confidentiality and non-competition agreement as part of his employment terms, and that he violated that agreement by accepting employment with Hi-Vis and by passing trade secrets over to Hi-Vis. <eos/><bos/>Alternatively, Safety First alleged that Murphy violated his common law obligations of confidentiality and non-competition.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38df8e28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">19</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Hi-Vis was incorporated on April 18, 2016 and began business activity on June 1, 2016. <eos/><bos/>Murphy resigned from Safety First on May 9, 2016, accepted the position as Hi-Vis general manager on May 26, 2016, and commenced work with Hi-Vis on June 1, 2016. <eos/><bos/>The trade secrets that Murphy was alleged to have copied from Safety First, and passed over to Hi-Vis, included practice manuals, customer lists, industry contact lists, employee pay scales, and employee contact information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38df8e38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">20</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge concluded that Safety First failed to prove the existence of an agreement, either written or oral, on confidentiality and non-competition. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, there was no breach of agreement and no entitlement to damages for breach.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38df8e48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">21</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Even without a written or oral agreement, there are confidentiality and non-competition obligations imposed by common law. <eos/><bos/>If an employee occupied a fiduciary position, then there is a continuing obligation post-employment to keep confidences, and not to actively solicit the customers of the former employer for a reasonable period. <eos/><bos/>If an employee occupied a non-fiduciary position, then there are lesser obligations, and these are balanced with the common law right of former employees to compete with their former employers. <eos/><bos/>However, the non-fiduciary employee still has an obligation not to copy and carry away confidential documentation for the use and benefit of a new employer.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38df8e58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">22</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge observed that there is no bright line distinguishing fiduciary and non-fiduciary employees. <eos/><bos/>Senior management, or senior officers with access to confidential corporate information and with independent decision-making authority, are more likely to be fiduciary employees. <eos/><bos/>The courts are hesitant to classify employees as fiduciaries unless the evidence is clear, because that classification carries more onerous restrictions post-employment. <eos/><bos/>The law favours freedom for individuals to pursue economic advantage through mobility in employment.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38df8e68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">23</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge observed that the specific duties of the operations manager included hiring employees, setting work schedules, dispatching employees to job sites, administering payroll, tracking equipment use for billing purposes, and ensuring clients&apos; need are satisfied. <eos/><bos/>The remuneration ($60,000 per annum) and responsibilities were more in line with an administrative position, as distinct from a senior management position. <eos/><bos/>Safety First functioned well for many years without an operations manager, and in that sense, Murphy was not a key employee. <eos/><bos/>In addition, Murphy had no significant decision making authority, did not handle funds, and was restricted in his access to corporate information. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge accepted the evidence of Murphy that he used his password solely for the purposes of accessing information relating to his job duties. <eos/><bos/>If he had unrestricted access to corporate information in sub-files, he was unaware of it. <eos/><bos/>Considering the limited decision-making authority, limited access to corporate information, and no handling of funds, Murphy was a non-fiduciary employee. <eos/><bos/>As a non-fiduciary employee, Murphy had fewer restrictions upon post-employment competition compared to fiduciary employees. <eos/><bos/>However, he still had a common law obligation not to copy and carry away confidential documentation for the benefit of a subsequent employer.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38e1ff08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">24</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge concluded that Murphy did not breach any obligation of confidentiality and non-competition. <eos/><bos/>Safety First failed to prove that Murphy appropriated any trade secrets or customer lists of Safety First, and failed to prove that Murphy was engaged in the enticement of Safety First customers. <eos/><bos/>In addition, Murphy was free to rely upon his memory of Safety First&apos;s customers, and contact those customers in the interest of generating new business for Hi-Vis. <eos/><bos/>This type of information, from memory and unaided by the employer&apos;s documentation, does not fall within the scope of confidential trade secrets. <eos/><bos/>In any event, the trial judge concluded that Murphy did not share that information from memory or otherwise.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38e1ff18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">25</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id38e1ff28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">26</footnote.reference>] the applicants alleged that Good, a former employee and director of the applicant EMW and a shareholder of the applicant Employee Co. had breached a Non-Disclosure Agreement with EMW [2016 Agreement] and a Non-Disclosure/Non-Competition/Non-Solicitation Agreement with EMW [2017 Agreement] through his employment by Confidence. <eos/><bos/>They also alleged that Good breached fiduciary obligations he owed to EMW resulting from his employment in a fiduciary capacity and to Employee Co. as a director. <eos/><bos/>The application for an interim injunction requiring that Good&apos;s employment with Confidence and any other corporate entity associated with FWS be terminated and restraining the continuation of the alleged breaches was dismissed.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38e1ff38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">27</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>EMW was in the business of providing maintenance, repair and construction services to clients in the agriculture and mining industries. <eos/><bos/>Good was, but for a period of seven months, employed by EMW from 2001 until he resigned October 26, 2017. <eos/><bos/>He began as a welder, advancing to senior crew leader in 2006 and Project Manager in 2008. <eos/><bos/>In 2011, It was alleged that Good was again promoted and became one of four department managers in the Ag Division. <eos/><bos/>Good disagreed and alleged that his title and formal position did not change and that he was a Project Manager until he left EMW. <eos/><bos/>Whatever his title, Good&apos;s responsibilities after 2008 related almost exclusively to Richardson, a major EMW client, generating 12.14% of Ag Division revenue in 2015 and 16.4% in 2016. <eos/><bos/>There was conflicting evidence as to Good&apos;s duties. <eos/><bos/>Good deposed that from 2008, he worked almost exclusively on Richardson fertilizer site expansions, which he described as small new capital builds. <eos/><bos/>He said there were 70 such projects, and in addition, two repair and maintenance calls and one grain facility upgrade for Richardson. <eos/><bos/>He described his duties as including business development; ensuring the department met safety standards and followed EMW procedures; corresponding with clients and customers; overseeing project invoicing, job costing and product status and scheduling; and performing estimate reviews. <eos/><bos/>Good deposed that his sole contact with Richardson was with the engineering group in Winnipeg. <eos/><bos/>Richardson maintenance work was managed by another EMW employee based in Regina. <eos/><bos/>He did not have an office at EMW, working from his home in Souris, Manitoba. <eos/><bos/>He claimed he was not invited to any department meetings where policy and decision-making took place and did not contribute to the development of strategy relating to sales, pricing, business development or other high-level policy issues.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38e1ff48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">28</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>EMW alleged that Good had broader responsibilities as one of four Ag Division managers. <eos/><bos/>An Ag Department Manager was described as being <begin.quote ID="QT_0010"/>“responsible for all activities of the respective department”<end.quote refid="QT_0010"/>, assigning project roles within the department, creating and implementing a marketing plan, and assisting in the coordination of project resources and in the hiring process. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence Good received that job description or carried out all those duties.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38e1ff58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">29</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>There was evidence that Good attended Ag Department Manager meetings until January 2017, when those meetings were replaced by one-on-one meetings with Morrison, who had become the Ag Division Manager. <eos/><bos/>There was also evidence Good had online access to EMW client accounts, pricing, suppliers and procedures relating to construction and maintenance and repair projects. <eos/><bos/>There was little evidence as to the extent to which he exercised that access. <eos/><bos/>Good also received weekly “batting orders” which showed contact information and schedules for EMW employees.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38e47008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">30</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Morrison and his wife were the sole shareholders of EMW until 2007. <eos/><bos/>In August 2007, they sold 15 key EMW employees 48% of EMW&apos;s common shares at a value of $1 per share. <eos/><bos/>Good, who was one of those key employees, acquired 3000 shares. <eos/><bos/>All the minority shareholders also became directors of EMW until October 2015.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38e47018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">31</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In 2016, the minority shareholders froze the value of their shares at $107.95 per share, to enable new key employees the opportunity to become minority shareholders in EMW at a nominal cost. <eos/><bos/>To carry out that transaction, Good and the other minority shareholders transferred their shares to Employee Co. Each received one common share in Employee Co. and was to receive preferred shares equal to the value of the shares they held in EMW. <eos/><bos/>On March 13, 2017, Good, all other EMW shareholders, Employee Co. and EMW entered into an EMW Unanimous Shareholders Agreement which contained the following provision relating to the 2017 Agreement: 20. <eos/><bos/>The Parties agree that all shareholders of [Employee Co.] as well as Ewen shall sign Non-Competition/Non-Disclosure/Non-Solicitation Agreements in a form as determined acceptable to the Board Directors of the Corporation. <eos/><bos/>They also entered into an Employee Co. Unanimous Shareholders Agreement. <eos/><bos/>That agreement provided that Good and the other minority shareholders would be the directors and specified the process for shareholders to terminate their participation in Employee Co. The 2017 Agreement contained broad non-disclosure, non-competition and non-solicitation obligations.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38e47028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">32</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>On October 6, 2017, Good sent a <begin.quote ID="QT_0012"/>“letter of resignation from EMW Industrial, and its subsidiary company or companies”<end.quote refid="QT_0012"/>, effective October 27, 2017. <eos/><bos/>His resignation letter referred to his shares in Employee Co., stating that he had “no clue on this stuff” and that he wanted to <begin.quote ID="QT_0011"/>“just to ‘rip off the band-aid’ and hopefully clear everything up as soon as possible, and move on”<end.quote refid="QT_0011"/>. <eos/><bos/>Good was negotiating with FWS. He received a written offer of employment October 13, 2017 and began work October 30, 2017 in the position of “Business Development”.<eos/><bos/> The services specified in the job description included participating in project development and the preparation of proposal documents, identifying and managing risks to FWS when searching for new markets, working with clients to develop project concepts and determining if projects are realistic and suited to FWS.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38e47038e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">33</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Richardson was an existing FWS client. <eos/><bos/>Good&apos;s evidence was that EMW&apos;s work for Richardson was smaller scale and was typically in the repair and maintenance sector. <eos/><bos/>That evidence did not appear to be consistent with his evidence that he worked on 70 small capital projects for Richardson while with EMW. <eos/><bos/>Good also said that he was not involved in any way with servicing Richardson&apos;s account for FWS, and that his only participation in a Richardson project since joining FWS was taking pictures on one project site. <eos/><bos/>He said he was involved in a project bid involving both FWS and EMW relating to a Cargill project. <eos/><bos/>He said he turned over or destroyed all EMW information when he left the company and had not shared any confidential or proprietary information. <eos/><bos/>He also denied any involvement in the solicitation of EMW employees, customers or suppliers.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38e47048e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">34</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>EMW presented a different picture of the competition between FWS and EMW. <eos/><bos/>Morrison described FWS as EMW&apos;s largest competitor in the grain and fertilizer industry. <eos/><bos/>He said that FWS was not particularly involved in maintenance and repair, a significant component of EMW&apos;s work where EMW believes it had a competitive advantage, but that FWS wished to expand in that area. <eos/><bos/>He alleged that Good could harm EMW, adversely affecting its competitive advantage and the value of shares in Employee Co., because of the knowledge and relationships he had from working at EMW. <eos/><bos/>Morrison deposed that Good had been involved in tenders on behalf of FWS where EMW was asked to bid. <eos/><bos/>He alleged that FWS and EMW frequently compete for work from Cargill, which was also a large EMW client. <eos/><bos/>He deposed that EMW does significant work other than maintenance and repair, including bidding on larger projects, and provided a list of such bids. <eos/><bos/>He deposed that FWS probably competed with EMW on all of those bids. <eos/><bos/>Morrison also deposed that Good was having a significant detrimental effect on the share value of Employee Co. by providing FWS with a competitive advantage, as he knows EMW&apos;s bidding process. <eos/><bos/>He said that the grain and fertilizer industry has a very secretive bidding process and that billing information is confidential. <eos/><bos/>There was, however, no evidence Employee Co. shares were valued or sold after Good joined FWS. Morrison also alleged the information in the batting orders had potential strategic significance.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38e47058e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">35</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The parties agreed that the strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case standard applied in relation to both the restrictive covenant and the fiduciary obligation. <eos/><bos/>That standard is a significant hurdle for the applicant. <eos/><bos/>In undertaking the preliminary review, the court must consider not only the applicants&apos; evidence, but the conflicting evidence of the respondents.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38e6e108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">36</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The applicants alleged that Good was employed in a fiduciary capacity. <eos/><bos/>A departing employee who was so employed is subject to different obligations than one who was not. <eos/><bos/>The court is concerned with the scope of the employee&apos;s powers, their ability to unilaterally exercise that power or discretion so as to affect the beneficiaries&apos; interests, and whether the beneficiary is peculiarly vulnerable or at the mercy of the fiduciary. <eos/><bos/>Matters such as level of responsibility, degree of contact with customers, and knowledge of customer and pricing information may be significant.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38e6e118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">37</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motions judge observed that the obligations owed by a fiduciary employee are limited, and their term and content --- as in relation to every fiduciary duty - turns on the facts. <eos/><bos/>Key employees who are not senior managers may be found to be fiduciaries. <eos/><bos/>A fiduciary may compete with their former employer, as long as they do not do so unfairly. <eos/><bos/>It is for that reason that they may be precluded from soliciting clients, but not from competing in general, and then only for a reasonable time after leaving their employment. <eos/><bos/>That temporal limit results reflects the purpose of the non-solicitation obligation.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38e6e128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">38</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Finally, the applicants submitted that Good was a director of Employee Co., and as such, continued to be subject to the fiduciary duties. <eos/><bos/>They say he breached that duty by taking employment with FWS and competing directly with EMW. <eos/><bos/>The respondents alleged that Good was not a director, as he resigned.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38e6e138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">39</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Turning to the application of the law to the facts, the motion judge dealt first with the allegation that Good had continuing fiduciary duties as a director of Employee Co., and was breaching those duties. <eos/><bos/>Good expressly stated that his resignation letter was intended to relate to <begin.quote ID="QT_0013"/>“all of his roles and capacities”<end.quote refid="QT_0013"/>. <eos/><bos/>The respondents did not claim they did not understand he wished to resign Further, there was no evidence the applicants continued to treat him as a director or that he has acted as such since his resignation. <eos/><bos/>In these circumstances, the applicants had not made out a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that they did not receive effective notice of Good&apos;s resignation, and accordingly, that he was still a director.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38e6e148e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">40</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Further, and even if there was a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that Good was a director of Employee Co., the motion judge would not exercise a discretion to grant an injunction on that ground. <eos/><bos/>The application for an equitable remedy should not turn on whether Good managed to extricate himself as a minority shareholder or director of Employee Co. At this stage, it should turn on the former employment relationship between EMW and Good. <eos/><bos/>That primary relationship should drive the analysis. <eos/><bos/>As such, the issue was whether there was strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that Good breached the 2016 Agreement, the 2017 Agreement or fiduciary obligations which arose from his employment in a fiduciary capacity by EMW. <eos/><bos/>The applicants had not made out a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that the non-competition and non-solicitation provisions of the 2017 Agreement were enforceable. <eos/><bos/>There was a strong argument they were unreasonably restrictive and aimed against competition generally. <eos/><bos/>EMW failed to make out a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case the 2016 Agreement continued in force.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38e6e158e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">41</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motion judge observed that there were substantial conflicts between the evidence of the applicants and the evidence of the respondents as to the scope of Good&apos;s powers when he was employed by EMW, his ability to unilaterally exercise that power or discretion so as to affect EMW&apos;s interests, and whether EMW was peculiarly vulnerable or at the mercy of Good as a result of his employment by EMW. <eos/><bos/>There was also conflicting evidence as to his duties with FWS, and the relationship between those duties and his work with EMW and the confidential information he obtained while employed by EMW.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38e95208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">42</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>There were certain matters that appeared to be clear. <eos/><bos/>Good worked almost exclusively with Richardson during his last eight years with EMW, in only two provinces, within the limits of his comfort zone. <eos/><bos/>He did not do large projects and had very little to do with the maintenance and repair business which was of particular importance to EMW and in relation to which EMW claimed a particular advantage and exposure to particular risks. <eos/><bos/>Although there was evidence he was involved in some bidding, there was limited evidence as to the timing and extent of that involvement. <eos/><bos/>Although Good had significant responsibilities for a very important client, it appeared that he did not participate in senior management functions such as determining the strategy relating to sales, pricing, business development or other high-level policy issues. <eos/><bos/>There was evidence Good had online access to a broad range of proprietary information. <eos/><bos/>However, there was no evidence that he used that access in relation to much of that information or that he took any information in electronic or written form when he left EMW. <eos/><bos/>The motion judge concluded that, taken as a whole, the evidence suggested Good was a middle manager focused almost exclusively on one aspect of the business of one client. <eos/><bos/>However, middle managers can be fiduciaries. <eos/><bos/>In the motion judge&apos;s view, there was a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that Good was a fiduciary. <eos/><bos/>He had major responsibilities, including serving as a key contact, for a very significant client, and had knowledge of some confidential matters such as pricing and supplier information. <eos/><bos/>There was sufficient evidence as to EMW&apos;s vulnerability. <eos/><bos/>The question, accordingly, was the nature and extent of his fiduciary obligations. <eos/><bos/>A fiduciary is not precluded from competing with the former employer. <eos/><bos/>He or she is precluded from unfairly competing, and in particular, from soliciting clients of the former employer for a limited time. <eos/><bos/>The scope and temporal limits of that prohibition depend on the facts. <eos/><bos/>In these circumstances, there was a sound argument that Good was not obliged to avoid soliciting all clients for all kinds of business. <eos/><bos/>The key issue was Richardson. <eos/><bos/>Good was not the only or the most senior EMW employee responsible for the relationship with Richardson. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence that transitioning his project management, marketing, relationship and other responsibilities with Richardson to another employee presented unusual difficulties or would have taken EMW much time. <eos/><bos/>The ability to effect that transition was relevant to EMW&apos;s vulnerability.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38e95218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">43</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The evidence as to the competition between FWS and EMW was also an important consideration. <eos/><bos/>While it appeared that the applicants overstated the extent of that competition, it appeared the respondents understated it. <eos/><bos/>There was evidence FWS and EMW were competitors in relation to a significant number of projects and that competition would increase. <eos/><bos/>Good could have been employed in a manner that engaged the concern with unfair competition, particularly in relation to Richardson.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38e95228e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">44</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>However, the evidence suggested that Good had done very little that constituted competition with EMW in relation to any client. <eos/><bos/>He played some role in two bids for Cargill business that involved both EMW and FWS. He had not provided services in relation to Richardson, other than taking photographs on one occasion. <eos/><bos/>There was no other evidence that Good&apos;s employment with FWS has impacted EMW&apos;s business or the value of Employee Co.[<footnote.reference refid="Id38e95238e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">45</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motion judge observed that it was also significant that the application was heard more than six months after Good joined FWS. There was a strong argument Good was no longer subject to an obligation to avoid soliciting EMW clients, at least other than Richardson, when the application was heard. <eos/><bos/>Additional time had now passed. <eos/><bos/>Further, the passage of time meant that confidential information that depends on its currency --- such as information about the allocation of specific staff in the batting orders, or information as to then current projects or bids that are now complete was no longer an issue.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38e95248e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">46</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motion judge was not satisfied there was a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that Good had used or shared confidential information so as to engage the concern with unfair competition by a fiduciary. <eos/><bos/>Nor was there a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that he had otherwise competed unfairly by soliciting EMW&apos;s clients. <eos/><bos/>The mere fact that FWS competes with EMW did not mean that Good could not work for FWS in any capacity. <eos/><bos/>The motion judge disagreed with the submission by EMW that employment by a competitor will inevitably result in sharing confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The question as to whether to draw that inference is a question of fact.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38e95258e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">47</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In the result, the applicants had not made out a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that Good has breached a fiduciary obligation to EMW or any other applicant. <eos/><bos/>Further, the motion judge was not satisfied that EMW would suffer irreparable harm, whether as a result of erosion of EMW&apos;s market share, the disclosure of confidential information, the erosion of the value of Employee Co. shares or otherwise, if an interim injunction was not granted.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38e95268e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">48</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Guzzo v. Randazzo</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id38ebc308e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">49</footnote.reference>] the formation of a new local of the Carpenters came into existence by virtue of the efforts of the former employees and members of Local 1110, in particular Randazzo, the former business manager of Local 1110, with the assistance of Carpenters members. <eos/><bos/>Randazzo was alleged to have been in the role of a fiduciary vis-à-vis LiUNA and consequently, given the circumstances of her departure and establishment of a new local, it was alleged she breached her fiduciary duty of loyalty and confidentiality.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38ebc318e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">50</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>All of the former Local 1110 employees had either cellular phones or laptops utilized by them for fulfilling their employment and for their personal needs. <eos/><bos/>They had received $500 towards the purchase of the laptops. <eos/><bos/>Randazzo believed that the laptop would be hers when she left the employ of Local 1110. <eos/><bos/>The cellphones would have contact numbers with various employees of the bargaining units. <eos/><bos/>It was not until November 14th, 2011 after LiUNA had commenced a motion seeking an injunction that the property was returned to Local 1110 through counsel. <eos/><bos/>It would appear that the defendants had on their computers materials relevant to both unions. <eos/><bos/>Randazzo was emphatic in her testimony that none of the information contained on any device was used during the subsequent campaign. <eos/><bos/>The reason for delay in surrendering the devices was that they were working nonstop on the campaign.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38ebc328e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">51</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge concluded that Randazzo was not a fiduciary and consequently was not liable for damages for breach of fiduciary duties. <eos/><bos/>She was liable for damages arising out of breach of basic employee duties.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38ebc338e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">52</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>An employee cannot capitalize or use confidential information of a former employer. <eos/><bos/>Confidential information can go far beyond a trade secret to encompass customer lists, company policies and information relating to customers. <eos/><bos/>If the information in the first instance is in the public domain, as would be the case with collective agreements and their expiry dates, it is difficult to advance the notion that the information was confidential at all. <eos/><bos/>Information retrieved from or in the public domain could become confidential if its collection or assembly was <begin.quote ID="QT_0014"/>“brought into being by the application of the skill and ingenuity of the human brain”<end.quote refid="QT_0014"/> or if the confider was able to gain advantage that he or she would not otherwise have had if he or she had to check only public sources.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38ebc348e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">53</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Confidential information is a contextual phenomenon. <eos/><bos/>It has to be considered in light of what a departing employee can take away from his employment, namely, the general skills and knowledge acquired. <eos/><bos/>Randazzo in her long-term employment would have knowledge of contact personnel in the various bargaining units. <eos/><bos/>Once that information is possessed legitimately, networking furnishes the names of the rest of the bargaining unit. <eos/><bos/>Randazzo and her colleagues did possess contact lists on their computers and cell phones, which they took with them and which were ultimately surrendered to counsel for LiUNA. <eos/><bos/>That possession, although not necessary given their collective ability to remember those to contact, did appear to be a <ital>prima facie</ital> possession of what has been traditionally confidential information. <eos/><bos/>In retrospect, the better idea would have been to leave all that equipment behind the day before their final resignations.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38ebc358e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">54</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The question of whether or not there was confidential information ultimately misused on the computers and cell phones was muddied somewhat by the fact that there was personal information on these devices as well. <eos/><bos/>In <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2007111380" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I25d5db308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Aon Consulting Inc. v. Watson Wyatt &amp; Co</ital>., 2005 CarswellOnt 3706 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, Swinton J. observed that an electronic copy of contacts and an address book contained hundreds of names, including personal friends and family members, as well as business contacts. <eos/><bos/>Referring to the three elements of breach of confidence referred to above from <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00007" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1968073413" w-pub-number="0005149" ID="I25d5db338e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>International Corona Resources Ltd</ital></cite.query>., Justice Swinton found that the blend of personal and business information eroded the necessary quality of confidence or that there was an unauthorized use of the information. <eos/><bos/>As in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00008" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2007111380" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I25d5db368e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Aon Consulting</ital></cite.query>, the plaintiffs were unable to specifically show how or if whatever was retained was misused. <eos/><bos/>The fact that the computers were for both personal and business use, that the individual purchased the computer with the assistance of a $500 grant from the union and could expect to eventually keep the computer, belied the concept of confidential storage. <eos/><bos/>If the employer knows that the employee will someday legitimately keep the computer irrespective of employment, how could it be asserted that whatever was there would be “confidential”?<eos/><bos/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id38ee3408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">55</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The fifth file found on the computers of Randazzo, Boyle, Taylor and LeBlanc entitled OFHCW, LiUNA Local 1110 Organizing Plan was the only file found to be an internal Local 1110 document. <eos/><bos/>Even at that, the campaigns listed would be based on “open periods” which are readily accessible in the public domain. <eos/><bos/>The only aspect that was truly internal was the reference to the costs proposals of the campaigns. <eos/><bos/>It was hard to believe that information could <ital>per se</ital> could be used against Local 1110 in a campaign.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38ee3418e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">56</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The creation of a business plan for the Carpenters using a jurisdiction report that Randazzo had previously prepared using known information was hardly a breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>Its creation appeared to be a matter of precedent usage. <eos/><bos/>The material retained lacks the aura of confidentiality and there was, aside from suspicion, lack of proof of misuse.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38ee3428e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">57</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>On appeal in <ital>Guzzo v. Randazzo</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id38ee3438e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">58</footnote.reference>] the Appellants submitted that the trial judge erred in not finding that Randazzo was a fiduciary and that she breached that fiduciary duty to Local 1110. <eos/><bos/>They also argued that the damages awarded to be paid by certain Respondents to the Appellants did not reflect the damages caused by their conduct.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38ee3448e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">59</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Appellants argued that the trial judge made a palpable and overriding error in failing to find Randazzo to be a fiduciary. <eos/><bos/>It is undisputed that there exists jurisprudence to support the general conclusion that officers of a union may hold a fiduciary position with respect to the union and its members. <eos/><bos/>To find a fiduciary relationship, what is generally required is evidence of a mutual understanding that one party has relinquished her own self-interest and agreed to act solely on behalf of the other party. <eos/><bos/>Fiduciary obligations tend to be imposed only where one party is, in reality, at the mercy of the other and places total reliance and dependent on the fiduciary. <eos/><bos/>As a result, whether a fiduciary obligation exists must be decided based on the particular circumstances of each case. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge considered that even the fact that an employee may be a key employee or the fact that the employer may be vulnerable are not absolutely determinative of the imposition of a fiduciary relationship and the obligations that flow from that designation. <eos/><bos/>Those are simply two factors among many to be considered. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge made several findings of fact, supported by the evidence, which served to characterize Randazzo&apos;s power and influence over the Appellants as being quite limited. <eos/><bos/>Given the provisional nature of Local 1110&apos;s charter, it could be amended, revoked and consolidated abruptly and without notice. <eos/><bos/>Although the Executive Board tended to agree with any recommendations made by Randazzo it was not obliged to do so. <eos/><bos/>Randazzo had no cheque-signing authority. <eos/><bos/>Although she had employees reporting to her, she could not employ or dismiss employees, set employment policies or rates of pay, or establish budgets without approval of the Executive Board. <eos/><bos/>Randazzo was not directly responsible to the local union membership. <eos/><bos/>In addition, although Randazzo could appoint stewards and was in charge of field representatives, she was not the only contact for Local 1110 bargaining unit members, given the presence of many stewards, service representatives, and organizers. <eos/><bos/>Although Randazzo was knowledgeable as to the provisions of the relevant collective agreements, it was observed that these were public documents. <eos/><bos/>Although she may have been knowledgeable with respect to labour law practices, including the conduct of grievances, such knowledge was neither unique nor proprietary to Local 1110. <eos/><bos/>In contrast, Mancinelli had broad powers concerning Local 1110, and he exercised those powers without much restraint. <eos/><bos/>Mancinelli was the person in control of Local 1110. <eos/><bos/>When the events occurred, Randazzo was its newly-demoted “Acting” Business Manager.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38ee3458e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">60</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Divisional Court did not accept that the fact that the trial judge&apos;s references to the Uniform Constitution of the LIUNA District Council rendered his conclusion that Randazzo was not a fiduciary one that could not be sustained on appeal. <eos/><bos/>In coming to the conclusion that he did the trial judge relied on the powers and roles that the key players actually played in the running of Local 1110, not on how those powers or roles were set out in any particular document. <eos/><bos/>Furthermore, the Divisional Court did not agree that the trial judge reached his conclusion that Randazzo was not a fiduciary purely on the basis that there was someone senior to her or she had a reporting obligation. <eos/><bos/>Rather, the trial judge made findings of fact as to Randazzo&apos;s powers in context and within the particular organization in which such powers could be exercised. <eos/><bos/>The facts as found by the trial judge, amply supported his conclusion that Local 1110 was not at the mercy of, reliant on, or dependent on Randazzo.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38ee3468e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">61</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>As the trial judge noted, what is confidential information is a determination to be made in the context of the circumstances. <eos/><bos/>It must be considered in light of what items a departing employee rightfully may be able to take away from employment which include general skills and knowledge acquired on the job. <eos/><bos/>Although the trial judge found that it would have been preferable for the Defendants to leave all equipment and documents behind when they left, mere possession of these items is not a breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge found that the Appellants were unable to specifically prove what information had been either used or misused, or how. The trial judge also found that Randazzo&apos;s creation of a business plan for the Carpenters, using a report that she had prepared previously for Local 1110 as a guide and using information that was publicly available and not confidential, was only an incident of “precedent usage” and not a breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>In general, the trial judge found that the material said to have been retained by the Defendants lacked any “aura of confidentiality” and was generally available to the public. <eos/><bos/>He made this finding after examining the material in detail and absent a palpable and overriding error, his findings were entitled to deference. <eos/><bos/>The Divisional Court concluded that the findings made were available to the trial judge on the evidence before him.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38f0a508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">62</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Consbec Inc. v. Walker</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id38f0a518e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">63</footnote.reference>] the trial judge dismissed the majority of Consbec&apos;s claims holding that Peter was not Consbec&apos;s fiduciary and had not breached his common-law duties as an employee. <eos/><bos/>However, the judge held that Peter had failed to give Consbec reasonable notice before terminating his employment and awarded Consbec damages in that regard. <eos/><bos/>In its appeal, Consbec contended that the trial judge committed a number of errors in dismissing Consbec&apos;s claim against Peter for breach of fiduciary duty. <eos/><bos/>In the alternative, Consbec argued that the judge erred in finding that Peter had not breached his common-law duties of confidentiality, good faith, and fidelity he owed as an employee.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38f0a528e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">64</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge rejected Consbec&apos;s claim that Peter took Consbec&apos;s Excel spreadsheet, took or destroyed Consbec&apos;s client (contact) list, and wiped an office computer clean. <eos/><bos/>The Court of Appeal concluded that Consbec sought to have the appellate Court retry the case and make findings of fact that differed from the trial judge&apos;s findings. <eos/><bos/>For example, Consbec challenged the judge&apos;s finding that Consbec failed to prove Peter took the Excel spreadsheet and used it to compete. <eos/><bos/>In making that finding the judge referred not only to Peter&apos;s denial but also to Consbec&apos;s failure to present any direct evidence that Peter took the spreadsheet or expert evidence to support its allegation that someone took the spreadsheet and wiped a computer clean. <eos/><bos/>In addition, the judge found that Consbec failed to prove even the existence of the contact list it alleged Peter took. <eos/><bos/>In effect, the trial judge found that all that Peter took with him when he left Consbec were the general skills and knowledge he had acquired while working for that company. <eos/><bos/>That is something he was entitled to do.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38f0a538e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">65</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Donaldson Travel Inc. v. Murphy</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id38f0a548e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">66</footnote.reference>] the Statement of Claim alleged that the defendants, both before and after Murphy terminated her employment with Donaldson, actively solicited customers of Donaldson; Van Der Hayden and Goliger&apos;s knew or ought to have known that by soliciting customers of Donaldson, Murphy was in breach of the employment agreement and that she was misappropriating confidential information of Donaldson; the defendants Van Der Heyden and Goliger&apos;s, or either of them, induced Murphy to breach the employment agreement and participated in her misappropriation of confidential information such that those acts constituted wrongful interference with contractual relations. <eos/><bos/>It was not pleaded that Murphy was a fiduciary employee of Donaldson. <eos/><bos/>Although not pleaded in the Statement of Claim, except in the prayer for relief, an additional basis was advanced by the plaintiff in submissions, namely that Murphy was under an obligation at common law, that is, apart from the employment agreement, not to misappropriate confidential information of Donaldson and that she did so. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff, in the prayer for relief, claimed that Van Der Heyden and Goliger&apos;s participated in the misappropriation of confidential information and were therefore liable. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff Donaldson and the corporate defendant Goliger&apos;s each carried on business as travel agencies. <eos/><bos/>The defendant Van Der Heyden was the President and director of Goliger&apos;s. <eos/><bos/>The defendant Murphy had been employed by Donaldson as a travel agent from June 2007 to February 3, 2012 when she resigned from that employment. <eos/><bos/>On February 6, 2012, Murphy commenced employment as a travel agent with Goliger&apos;s.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38f0a558e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">67</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The defendants conceded that there is a common-law obligation for an employee to maintain confidence. <eos/><bos/>In this case, there was also a confidentiality provision in Donaldson&apos;s policy manual.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38f31608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">68</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In the judge&apos;s view, Murphy, by disclosing to Van Der Heyden the annual work volume that she was capable of, based upon her experience with Donaldson, was not disclosing information of Donaldson that had a “quality of confidence”.<eos/><bos/> The same could be said about the names of clients, which could be readily ascertained from public sources.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38f31618e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">69</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>On her examination for discovery Donaldson acknowledged that her position that Murphy disclosed confidential information was just based on Murphy&apos;s words to Lochead that she shared that information with Van Der Heyden. <eos/><bos/>When asked whether the information that she was claiming was confidential was in “physical form on paper” she responded that she didn&apos;t know. <eos/><bos/>Donaldson presented no evidence that Murphy shared confidential information with Goliger&apos;s by means of the delivery of electronic or paper documentation. <eos/><bos/>Donaldson relied solely on the information related by Lochead as to what Murphy told her was discussed in her interview with Van Der Heyden. <eos/><bos/>The judge concluded that even if Lochead&apos;s evidence was to be preferred over the more specific evidence of Murphy and Van Der Heyden as to what was discussed in their interview, the information that Lochead said that Murphy related to her did not have the “quality of confidence” to support a claim for breach of confidence.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38f31628e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">70</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Since the evidence did not support a finding of breach of confidence or misuse of confidential information on the part of Murphy, it followed that there could be no such finding as against Goliger&apos;s and Van Der Heyden. <eos/><bos/>Donaldson advanced no independent claim against Goliger&apos;s and Van Der Heyden for breach of confidence but rather claimed that they participated in Murphy&apos;s alleged misappropriation of confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The judge concluded that there was no genuine issue requiring a trial with respect to Donaldson&apos;s claim against the defendants for misappropriation of confidential information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id38f31638e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">71</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Id38ce7708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00009" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1985030763" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I25ee45308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Faccenda Chicken Ltd. v. Fowler</ital>, [1986] 1 All E.R. 617 (C.A.), at p. 625</cite.query>, <case.history>affg</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00010" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1983032242" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I25ee45328e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">[1985] 1 All E.R. 724 (Ch. D.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38ce7718e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00011" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1985030763" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I25ee93508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Faccenda Chicken Ltd. v. Fowler</ital>, [1986] 1 All E.R. 617 (C.A.)</cite.query>, <case.history>affg</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00012" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1983032242" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I25ee93528e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">[1985] 1 All E.R. 724 (Ch. D.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38ce7728e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00013" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2006796530" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I25eeba608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>ACS Public Sector Solutions Inc. v. Courthouse Technologies Ltd.</ital> (2005), 140 A.C.W.S. (3d) 736 (B.C.S.C.)</cite.query> at paras. 38-39 of the <case.history>judgment, affd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00014" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2007831032" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I25eeba628e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">262 D.L.R. (4th) 512 (C.A.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38d83b08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>4</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00015" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1948026647" w-pub-number="0004707" ID="I25ef7db08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>R.L. Crain Ltd. v. Ashton</ital>, [1949] 2 D.L.R. 481, [1949] O.R. 303 (H.C.)</cite.query>, <case.history>affd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00016" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1949034206" w-pub-number="0004707" ID="I25ef7db38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">[1950] 1 D.L.R. 601, [1950] O.R. 62 (C.A.)</cite.query>; See also <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00017" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1918039825" w-pub-number="0004707" ID="I25ef7db68e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Canada Bonded Attorney and Legal Directory Ltd. v. Leonard-Parmiter Ltd.</ital> (1918), 42 D.L.R. 342, 42 O.L.R. 141 (S.C.A.D.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00018" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1950038703" w-pub-number="0004707" ID="I25ef7db98e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Reliable Toy Co. v. Collins</ital>, [1950] 4 D.L.R. 499, [1950] O.R. 360 (H.C.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00019" w-ref-type="PM" w-serial-number="1972097334" w-pub-number="0003986" ID="I25ef7dbc8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Guyer Oil Co. v. Fulton</ital>, [1973] 1 W.W.R. 97, 35 C.P.R. (2d) at p. 146 (Sask. Q.B.)</cite.query>, <case.history>affd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00020" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1977148510" w-pub-number="0005652" w-pinpoint-page="171" ID="I25ef7dbf8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">35 C.P.R. (2d) at p. 171, 16 N.R. 468 (Sask. C.A.)</cite.query>, <case.history>affd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00021" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1977148510" w-pub-number="0005156" ID="I25ef7dc28e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">[1977] 2 S.C.R. 791, [1977] 4 W.W.R. 112</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00022" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1974145203" w-pub-number="0005155" w-pinpoint-page="827" ID="I25ef7dc58e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Consolidated Textiles Ltd. v. Central Dynamics Ltd.</ital>, [1974] 2 F.C. 814 at p. 827, 18 C.P.R. (2d) 1 (T.D.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00023" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1977023899" w-pub-number="0003986" w-pinpoint-page="24" ID="I25ef7dc88e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Bendix Home Systems Ltd. v. Clayton</ital>, [1977] 5 W.W.R. 10 at p. 24, 33 C.P.R. (2d) 230 (B.C.S.C.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00024" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1977151608" w-pub-number="0005652" ID="I25ef7dcb8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cradle Pictures (Canada) Ltd. v. Penner</ital> (1977), 34 C.P.R. (2d) 34 (Ont. H.C.J.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38d83b18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>5</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>Future Shop v. Northwest-Atlantic (B.C.)</ital> (2000), 2 C.P.C. (5th) 358 (B.C.S.C.) at paras. 55-56.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38daac08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>6</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>Future Shop v. Northwest-Atlantic (B.C.)</ital> (2000), 2 C.P.C. (5th) 358 (B.C.S.C.) at paras. 55-56.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38daac18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>7</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00025" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2001344563" w-pub-number="0005463" ID="I25f104508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Rawlco Communications (Sask.) Ltd. v. Clements</ital> (2001), 204 Sask. R. 272 (Q.B.)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/><ital>ATI Technologies Inc. v. Henry</ital> (2000), 5 C.C.E.L. (3d) 101 (Ont. S.C.J.) confirms that an employer will be expected to demonstrate that a former employee has actually breached a duty of non-disclosure.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38daac28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>8</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00026" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2001461243" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I25f12b608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Life Investors Insurance Co. of America v. Tis Management Ltd.</ital> (2001), 109 A.C.W.S. (3d) 647 (B.C.S.C.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38daac38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>9</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>See <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00027" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2001031113" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I25f1c7a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>FCI Fisker Cargo Inc. v. ABX Logistics Corp.</ital> (2001), 102 A.C.W.S. (3d) 597 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at para. 14; and <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00028" w-ref-type="ER" w-normalized-cite="275NBR2CA6" w-pub-number="0005158" ID="I25f1c7a28e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Kent Building Supplies, a division of J.D. Irving Ltd. v. Magasin du Ridge Ltée</ital> (2004), 275 N.B.R. (2d) 6 (Q.B.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38daac48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>10</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>See, for example, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00029" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1983176309" w-pub-number="0005505" w-pinpoint-page="526" ID="I25f1eeb08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Berkey Photo (Canada) Ltd. v. Ohlig</ital> (1983), 43 O.R. (2d) 518 at p. 526, 2</cite.query> C.C.E.L. 113 (H.C.J.).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38daac58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>11</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>As was mentioned in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00030" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1985030763" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I25f23cd08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Faccenda Chicken Ltd. v. Fowler</ital>, [1986] 1 All E.R. 617 (C.A.)</cite.query>, <case.history>affg</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00031" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1983032242" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I25f23cd28e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">[1985] 1 All E.R. 724 (Ch. D.)</cite.query>, the court will place emphasis on how the information was treated by the employer. <eos/><bos/>See also <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00032" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1968073413" w-pub-number="0005149" w-pinpoint-page="389" ID="I25f23cd48e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>International Tools Ltd. v. Kollar</ital> (1968), 67 D.L.R. (2d) 386 at p. 389, [1968] 1 O.R. 669 (C.A.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00033" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1976147414" w-pub-number="0005652" w-pinpoint-page="275" ID="I25f23cd78e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Amer-Can Development Corp. v. Tele Time Saver Inc.</ital> (1976), 29 C.P.R. (2d) 272 at pp. 275-6, 1</cite.query> C.P.C. 230 (Ont. H.C.J.).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38daac68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>12</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00034" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1968073413" w-pub-number="0005149" ID="I25f263e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>International Tools Ltd. v. Kollar</ital> (1968), 67 D.L.R. (2d) 386, [1968] 1 O.R. 669 (C.A.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38dd1d08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>13</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00035" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1968073413" w-pub-number="0005149" w-pinpoint-page="389" ID="I25f28af28e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>International Tools Ltd. v. Kollar</ital> (1968), 67 D.L.R. (2d) 386, at p. 389, [1968] 1 O.R. 669 (C.A.)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>In addition, the defendants were told when they started work that the “bundling process” was secret.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38dd1d18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>14</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00036" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1985030763" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I25f2d9108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Faccenda Chicken Ltd. v. Fowler</ital>, [1986] 1 All E.R. 617 (C.A.)</cite.query>, <case.history>affg</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00037" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1983032242" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I25f2d9128e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">[1985] 1 All E.R. 724 (Ch. D.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38dd1d28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>15</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00038" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1985030763" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I260a31a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Faccenda Chicken Ltd. v. Fowler</ital>, [1986] 1 All E.R. 617 (C.A.), at pp. 626-9</cite.query>, <case.history>affg</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00039" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1983032242" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I260a31a28e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">[1985] 1 All E.R. 724 (Ch. D.)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>See also <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00040" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1989314665" w-pub-number="0004655" w-pinpoint-page="69" ID="I260a31a48e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Reed Stenhouse Ltd. v. Foster</ital> (1989), 98 A.R. 49, 69</cite.query> Alta. L.R. (2d) 80 (Q.B.); <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00041" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1939037192" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I260a31a68e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>E. Worsley and Co. v. Cooper</ital>, [1939] 1 All E.R. 290 (Ch.), at p. 307</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38dd1d38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>16</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00042" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1985030763" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I260b6a208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Faccenda Chicken Ltd. v. Fowler</ital>, [1986] 1 All E.R. 617 (C.A.)</cite.query>, <case.history>affg</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00043" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1983032242" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I260b6a228e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">[1985] 1 All E.R. 724 (Ch. D.)</cite.query>, has been cited with approval in a number of Canadian cases: see, for example, <ital>Cline v. Don Watt and Assoc. Communications Inc.</ital> (1986), 15 C.C.E.L. 181 (Ont. Dist. Ct.); <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00044" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1986268016" w-pub-number="0005653" ID="I260b6a258e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Coin-A-Matic (Pacific) Ltd. v. Saibil</ital></cite.query> (1986), 13 C.C.E.L. 59, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00045" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1986268016" w-pub-number="0005653" ID="I260b6a268e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">12 C.P.R. (3d) 33 (B.C.S.C.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38df8e08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>17</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00046" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047624473" w-pub-number="0008073" ID="I260bb8408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Safety First Contracting (1995) Ltd. v. Murphy</ital>, 2019 CarswellNfld 62, 2019 NLSC 47 (Nfld. and Lab. S.C.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38df8e18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>18</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00047" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047624473" w-pub-number="0008073" ID="I260bdf518e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Safety First Contracting (1995) Ltd. v. Murphy</ital>, 2019 CarswellNfld 62, 2019 NLSC 47 (Nfld. and Lab. S.C.)</cite.query>, at para. 1.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38df8e28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>19</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00048" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047624473" w-pub-number="0008073" ID="I260c06618e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Safety First Contracting (1995) Ltd. v. Murphy</ital>, 2019 CarswellNfld 62, 2019 NLSC 47 (Nfld. and Lab. S.C.)</cite.query>, at para. 2.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38df8e38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>20</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00049" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047624473" w-pub-number="0008073" ID="I260c2d718e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Safety First Contracting (1995) Ltd. v. Murphy</ital>, 2019 CarswellNfld 62, 2019 NLSC 47 (Nfld. and Lab. S.C.)</cite.query>, at para. 3.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38df8e48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>21</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00050" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047624473" w-pub-number="0008073" ID="I260c54818e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Safety First Contracting (1995) Ltd. v. Murphy</ital>, 2019 CarswellNfld 62, 2019 NLSC 47 (Nfld. and Lab. S.C.)</cite.query>, at paras. 13 and 36.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38df8e58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>22</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00051" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047624473" w-pub-number="0008073" ID="I260c7b918e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Safety First Contracting (1995) Ltd. v. Murphy</ital>, 2019 CarswellNfld 62, 2019 NLSC 47 (Nfld. and Lab. S.C.)</cite.query>, at para. 37.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38df8e68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>23</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00052" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047624473" w-pub-number="0008073" ID="I260ca2a18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Safety First Contracting (1995) Ltd. v. Murphy</ital>, 2019 CarswellNfld 62, 2019 NLSC 47 (Nfld. and Lab. S.C.)</cite.query>, at para. 38.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38e1ff08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>24</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00053" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047624473" w-pub-number="0008073" ID="I260cc9b18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Safety First Contracting (1995) Ltd. v. Murphy</ital>, 2019 CarswellNfld 62, 2019 NLSC 47 (Nfld. and Lab. S.C.)</cite.query>, at paras. 39-41.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38e1ff18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>25</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00054" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047624473" w-pub-number="0008073" ID="I260d17d18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Safety First Contracting (1995) Ltd. v. Murphy</ital>, 2019 CarswellNfld 62, 2019 NLSC 47 (Nfld. and Lab. S.C.)</cite.query>, at paras. 42 and 46.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38e1ff28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>26</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00055" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I260d17d38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38e1ff38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>27</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00056" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I260d3ee08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47</cite.query>, at paras. 2-3.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38e1ff48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>28</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00057" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I260d8d008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47</cite.query>, at paras. 4-8.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38e1ff58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>29</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00058" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I260d8d038e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47, at para. 9</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38e47008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>30</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00059" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I260db4108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47, at para. 10</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38e47018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>31</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00060" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I260ddb208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47, at para. 11</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38e47028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>32</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00061" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I260e02308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47</cite.query>, at paras. 12-14.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38e47038e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>33</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00062" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I260e29408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47</cite.query>, at paras. 16-18.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38e47048e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>34</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00063" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I260e50508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47</cite.query>, at paras. 19-20.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38e47058e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>35</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00064" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I260e9e708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47</cite.query>, at paras. 21-22.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38e6e108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>36</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00065" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I260ec5808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47</cite.query>, at paras. 27-28.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38e6e118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>37</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00066" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I260eec908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47</cite.query>, at paras. 33-35.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38e6e128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>38</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00067" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I260f13a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47</cite.query>, at paras. 36-37.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38e6e138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>39</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00068" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I260f3ab08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47, at para. 40</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38e6e148e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>40</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00069" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I260f61c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47</cite.query>, at paras. 41-42.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38e6e158e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>41</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00070" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I260fafe08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47</cite.query>, at paras. 43-44, and 47-48.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38e95208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>42</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00071" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I260fd6f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47, at para. 56</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38e95218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>43</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00072" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I261025108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47</cite.query>, at paras. 57-61.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38e95228e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>44</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00073" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I261073308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47, at para. 62</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38e95238e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>45</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00074" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I26109a408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47, at para. 63</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38e95248e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>46</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00075" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I2610c1508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47, at para. 64</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38e95258e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>47</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00076" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I26110f708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47, at para. 66</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38e95268e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>48</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00077" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640572" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I261136808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>EMW Industrial Ltd. v. Good</ital>, 2019 CarswellSask 96, 2019 SKQB 47, at para. 67</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38ebc308e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>49</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00078" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037776888" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I26115d908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Guzzo v. Randazzo</ital>, 2015 CarswellOnt 18762, 2015 ONSC 6936</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00079" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038708043" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I26115d938e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 5965, 2016 ONSC 2588</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38ebc318e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>50</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00080" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037776888" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2611abb08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Guzzo v. Randazzo</ital>, 2015 CarswellOnt 18762, 2015 ONSC 6936</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00081" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038708043" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2611abb38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 5965, 2016 ONSC 2588</cite.query>, at paras. 1, 3, and 6.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38ebc328e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>51</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00082" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037776888" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2611f9d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Guzzo v. Randazzo</ital>, 2015 CarswellOnt 18762, 2015 ONSC 6936</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00083" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038708043" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I261220e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 5965, 2016 ONSC 2588</cite.query>, at paras. 74, 82, and 84.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38ebc338e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>52</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00084" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037776888" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I261247f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Guzzo v. Randazzo</ital>, 2015 CarswellOnt 18762, 2015 ONSC 6936</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00085" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038708043" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I261247f38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 5965, 2016 ONSC 2588, at para. 236</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38ebc348e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>53</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00086" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037776888" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I261296108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Guzzo v. Randazzo</ital>, 2015 CarswellOnt 18762, 2015 ONSC 6936</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00087" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038708043" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2612bd218e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 5965, 2016 ONSC 2588</cite.query>, at paras. 189, and 191.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38ebc358e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>54</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00088" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037776888" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I26130b408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Guzzo v. Randazzo</ital>, 2015 CarswellOnt 18762, 2015 ONSC 6936</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00089" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038708043" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I26130b438e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 5965, 2016 ONSC 2588</cite.query>, at paras. 192-194.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38ee3408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>55</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00090" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037776888" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I261359608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Guzzo v. Randazzo</ital>, 2015 CarswellOnt 18762, 2015 ONSC 6936</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00091" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038708043" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I261359638e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 5965, 2016 ONSC 2588</cite.query>, at paras. 196-197.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38ee3418e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>56</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00092" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037776888" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2613a7808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Guzzo v. Randazzo</ital>, 2015 CarswellOnt 18762, 2015 ONSC 6936</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00093" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038708043" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2613a7838e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 5965, 2016 ONSC 2588, at para. 198</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38ee3428e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>57</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00094" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2037776888" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2613ce908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Guzzo v. Randazzo</ital>, 2015 CarswellOnt 18762, 2015 ONSC 6936</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00095" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038708043" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2613ce938e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 5965, 2016 ONSC 2588, at para. 199</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38ee3438e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>58</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00096" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041971433" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I26141cb08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Guzzo v. Randazzo</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 9950, 2017 ONSC 1845 (Ont. Div. Ct.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38ee3448e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>59</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00097" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041971433" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I26146ad08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Guzzo v. Randazzo</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 9950, 2017 ONSC 1845 (Ont. Div. Ct.)</cite.query>, at paras. 1 and 5.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38ee3458e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>60</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00098" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041971433" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2614b8f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Guzzo v. Randazzo</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 9950, 2017 ONSC 1845 (Ont. Div. Ct.)</cite.query>, at paras. 61-62, and 65-73.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38ee3468e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>61</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00099" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041971433" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2614e0008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Guzzo v. Randazzo</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 9950, 2017 ONSC 1845 (Ont. Div. Ct.)</cite.query>, at paras. 77-78.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38f0a508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>62</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00100" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041971433" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I26152e208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Guzzo v. Randazzo</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 9950, 2017 ONSC 1845 (Ont. Div. Ct.)</cite.query>, at paras. 81-83.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38f0a518e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>63</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00101" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038457254" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I261555308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Consbec Inc. v. Walker</ital>, 2016 CarswellBC 642, 2016 BCCA 114</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38f0a528e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>64</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00102" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038457254" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I2615a3508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Consbec Inc. v. Walker</ital>, 2016 CarswellBC 642, 2016 BCCA 114</cite.query>, at paras. 4-5.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38f0a538e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>65</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00103" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038457254" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I2615f1708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Consbec Inc. v. Walker</ital>, 2016 CarswellBC 642, 2016 BCCA 114</cite.query>, at paras. 18, 43, 45, and 47.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38f0a548e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>66</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00104" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039399963" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I26163f908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Donaldson Travel Inc. v. Murphy</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 11537, 2016 ONSC 740</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00105" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038438235" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I26163f938e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 3473, 2016 ONSC 1396</cite.query>, <case.history>affirmed</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00106" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039669154" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I26163f968e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 13571, 2016 ONCA 649</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38f0a558e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>67</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00107" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039399963" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2616b4c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Donaldson Travel Inc. v. Murphy</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 11537, 2016 ONSC 740</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00108" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038438235" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2616b4c38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 3473, 2016 ONSC 1396</cite.query>, <case.history>affirmed</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00109" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039669154" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2616b4c68e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 13571, 2016 ONCA 649</cite.query>, at paras. 1, 3-4, 9-10, and 15.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38f31608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>68</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00110" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039399963" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I261729f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Donaldson Travel Inc. v. Murphy</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 11537, 2016 ONSC 740</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00111" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038438235" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I261729f38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 3473, 2016 ONSC 1396</cite.query>, <case.history>affirmed</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00112" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039669154" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I261729f68e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 13571, 2016 ONCA 649, at para. 40</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38f31618e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>69</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00113" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039399963" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I261778108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Donaldson Travel Inc. v. Murphy</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 11537, 2016 ONSC 740</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00114" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038438235" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I261778138e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 3473, 2016 ONSC 1396</cite.query>, <case.history>affirmed</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00115" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039669154" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I261778168e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 13571, 2016 ONCA 649, at para. 52</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38f31628e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>70</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00116" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039399963" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2617ed408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Donaldson Travel Inc. v. Murphy</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 11537, 2016 ONSC 740</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00117" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038438235" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2617ed438e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 3473, 2016 ONSC 1396</cite.query>, <case.history>affirmed</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00118" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039669154" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I2617ed468e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 13571, 2016 ONCA 649</cite.query>, at paras. 53-54.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id38f31638e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>71</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00119" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039399963" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I261862708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Donaldson Travel Inc. v. Murphy</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 11537, 2016 ONSC 740</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00120" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038438235" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I261862738e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 3473, 2016 ONSC 1396</cite.query>, <case.history>affirmed</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175860" w-seq-number="00121" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2039669154" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I261862768e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2016 CarswellOnt 13571, 2016 ONCA 649</cite.query>, at paras. 55-56.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 4:6<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
