<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 4:43<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I5089a870411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>4.</label.designator><headtext>Confidential Business Information and the Employment Relationship</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I52517020411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>V.</label.designator><headtext>Fiduciary Duty</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I53a16fc0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>B.</label.designator><headtext>Remedies Table—Employment Relationship—Breach of Fiduciary Duty</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f65f586ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>4:43.</label.designator><headtext>York University v. Markicevic</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><ital>York University v. Markicevic</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 8794, 2016 ONSC 3718 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List]), additional reasons 2016 CarswellOnt 16475, 2016 ONSC 6561 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</headtext><eos/><eop/></head><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Award</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Judgment was granted against the defendants for damages as follows: Judgment against Markicevic, Brown and the “A-Tech defendants” for damages in the amount of $357,383.50 in respect of the A-Tech scheme, on a joint and several basis; Judgment against Markicevic and the A-Tech defendants for damages in the amount of $17,600 in respect of the two Aleeyah invoices, on joint and several basis; Judgment against Markicevic for damages in the amount of $515,461 in respect of the CAC scheme; Judgment against Markicevic for damages in the amount of $23,000 in respect of the residence improvements at 211 Osprey and 124 Woodville; Judgment against Brown for damages in the amount of $46,262 in respect of Pcard purchases for non-York purposes and $14,979 in respect of the two Rona purchases; and Judgment against Markicevic for a portion of Navigant&apos;s fees reasonably referable to the CAC, A-Tech and Residence Improvement schemes, in the amount of $200,000. <eos/><bos/>Brown and the A-Tech defendants were jointly and severally liable for $75,000 of the $200,000, for fees reasonably referable to the A-Tech scheme.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The court further granted the following declaratory relief: a declaration that the Severance Agreement (including the Release) was rescinded and Markicevic must repay to York the severance paid to him under the Severance Agreement; a declaration that the transfer of Markicevic&apos;s interest in 124 Woodville to Mima was void as a fraudulent conveyance; declaration that the transfer of Markicevic&apos;s interest in 211 Osprey to Fleming was void as a fraudulent conveyance; a declaration that York had a constructive trust over 124 Woodville in respect of: (i) $122,000, the amount paid by York for Ritacca&apos;s work on that property; and (ii) $13,000, the amount paid by York for its employees&apos; work on that property; and a declaration that York had a constructive trust over 211 Osprey in respect of $10,000, the amount paid by York for its employees&apos; work on that property.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Summary of Facts:</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Between 2007 and 2009, Markicevic devised a scheme to falsely invoice York for work that was not actually done at the university. <eos/><bos/>York alleged that he implemented this scheme through his subordinates Brown and McCann. <eos/><bos/>From August 23, 2007 until June 29, 2009, a total of 30 invoices were issued to York in the name of A-Tech Construction &amp; Design Inc. in the aggregate amount of $357,383.50 plus HST. The description of the work on each invoice was provided Mr. Markicevic. <eos/><bos/>Many of the invoices were for “emergency repairs” or related to safety matters. <eos/><bos/>Markicevic and/or Brown approved payment of the invoices. <eos/><bos/>Brown signed 21 of the invoices in his name alone, consistent with the special signing authority that Markicevic had given Mr. Brown for contractor invoices. <eos/><bos/>Markicevic co-signed eight of the invoices. <eos/><bos/>None of the work covered by those invoices was ever performed at York. <eos/><bos/>York paid $357,383.50 plus HST for the false A-Tech invoices and $17,600 plus HST for the false Aleeyah invoices.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Markicevic created a scheme to charge York inflated costs for drain repair work required in its Keele Campus Student Services Parking Garage. <eos/><bos/>York alleged that the difference between the actual cost of the repair work and the amount charged to York was kicked back to Markicevic in various ways, including cash payments and work done on his residence in Vaughan. <eos/><bos/>Markicevic implemented the CAC scheme through his subordinate Ierullo. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge found that Markicevic orchestrated the CAC scheme. <eos/><bos/>Ierullo acted as the liaison in dealing with Ritacca and receiving the kickback funds. <eos/><bos/>The fair market cost of replacing the 52 drains would have been $175,000. <eos/><bos/>The overpayment for the drain project was $515,461.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Markicevic used York tradespeople to do work at his houses during regular working hours, at York&apos;s expense. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge found that Correia, Figueiredo and McCann did the work they described at Markicevic&apos;s houses during regular work hours. <eos/><bos/>They were paid for their time by York and not by Markicevic. <eos/><bos/>York paid $10,000 for the work done at 112 Osprey and $13,000 for the work done at 124 Woodville. <eos/><bos/>Given that these funds went directly towards the improvement of 112 Osprey and 124 Woodville, and in light of the trial judge&apos;s finding that Markicevic&apos;s use of York tradespeople was a breach of his fiduciary duty, York was entitled to a declaration that it had a constructive trust in those properties to the extent of those expenditures.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Over his three years at York, Brown charged $200,000 to his Pcard. <eos/><bos/>York identified $46,262 of Brown&apos;s purchases for which York received no value. <eos/><bos/>Those included purchases for flooring, home furnishings, marble and tiles, and miscellaneous holiday and weekend purchases. <eos/><bos/>There were no work orders or labour charges associated with those purchases, the materials were not entered into York&apos;s inventory tracking system, and the materials were not observed on York&apos;s campuses. <eos/><bos/>In addition to his own Pcard, Brown used Pcards belonging to two of his subordinates</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><head style="l" parent="section.body"><bop/><bos/><headtext><bold>Reasons Given by Court for Award:</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Court found that Markicevic and Brown engaged in the fraudulent activities and, in so doing, breached their fiduciary duties as senior employees of York. <eos/><bos/>From 2007 to 2010, Markicevic was the Assistant Vice-President CSBO, occupying the most senior position in the department. <eos/><bos/>Brown was the Director of Maintenance and reported directly to Markicevic.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Markicevic and Brown conceded that they were fiduciaries of York. <eos/><bos/>As fiduciaries, they had a duty to act only in the best interests of York. <eos/><bos/>There was no question that: (i) by participating in the A-Tech scheme, Markicevic and Brown breached their fiduciary duty to act only in York&apos;s best interest; (ii) by participating in the CAC scheme, Markicevic breached his fiduciary duty to act only in York&apos;s best interest; (iii) by having York employees work on his personal residences at York&apos;s expense, Markicevic breached his fiduciary duty to act only in York&apos;s best interest; and (iv) by using Pcards for non-York purposes, Brown breached his fiduciary duty to act only in York&apos;s best interest.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>York sought to rescind the severance agreement that it entered into with Markicevic. <eos/><bos/>Pursuant to the Severance Agreement, York terminated Markicevic without cause and paid him 36 months&apos; gross salary ($696,166).<eos/><bos/> As a fiduciary, Markicevic had a positive obligation to disclose the full extent of his fraudulent activity before he entered into the Severance Agreement. <eos/><bos/>He did quite the opposite. <eos/><bos/>He failed to disclose these activities and actively denied that he had done anything improper. <eos/><bos/>This intentional and material non-disclosure itself entitled York to set aside the Severance Agreement.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Over the period from 2007 to 2010, Markicevic held a senior and trusted position at York. <eos/><bos/>He abused that trust for his own personal gain. <eos/><bos/>He masterminded two fraudulent schemes, which he implemented through his subordinates. <eos/><bos/>He used York employees to improve his personal residences, at York&apos;s expense. <eos/><bos/>He transferred those residences to Mima and Ms. Fleming to put those assets beyond York&apos;s reach. <eos/><bos/>He then accepted a severance payment of three years&apos; salary without disclosing any of his fraudulent activities.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Brown was also a senior and trusted York employee. <eos/><bos/>He also abused his position of trust. <eos/><bos/>He knowingly participated in a scheme to defraud York. <eos/><bos/>He facilitated the attendance of York employees to work on Markicevic&apos;s residences. <eos/><bos/>He used his Pcard for non-York purposes.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></section.body></section><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 4:43<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
