<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 5:7<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I540dc620411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>5.</label.designator><headtext>Claims for Breach of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I540ded30411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>I.</label.designator><headtext>Civil Actions</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I5458b1d0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>B.</label.designator><headtext>Breach of Confidence</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f6ad566ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>5:7.</label.designator><headtext>Relationships Covered by an Action for Breach of Confidence</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Relationships of confidence upon which legal action may be based generally fall into three categories:</paratext><list><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(1)</label.designator></head><paratext>relationships where a contract exists between the parties;</paratext></para></list.item><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(2)</label.designator></head><paratext>relationships which are not purely “contractual” but which contain elements of trust; and</paratext></para></list.item><list.item><para><head parent="para"><label.designator>(3)</label.designator></head><paratext>relationships where personal contact or dealing impose an obligation of trust and confidence.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6ba59a08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></list.item></list><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The confidential relationships in the first category have been examined in sections <cite.query w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="NA" w-normalized-cite="ELLTHORBURNBIs5:3" w-pub-number="0236187" ID="Id6ba59a18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">5:3</cite.query> and  <cite.query w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="NA" w-normalized-cite="ELLTHORBURNBIs5:5" w-pub-number="0236187" ID="Id6ba59a28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">5:5</cite.query> regarding express and implied contractual obligations. <eos/><bos/>Where a contractual provision exists, the provisions in the contract regarding the maintenance of confidence normally govern.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>An action for breach of confidence may also be evoked in the absence of a contract.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6ba59a38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>] The “reasonable man” test is used to determine whether an obligation of confidence will be implied in relationships which are not purely contractual. <eos/><bos/>The party seeking relief must also establish that the information is of some importance as <begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>“equity ought not to be invoked to protect trivial tittle-tattle, however confidential”<end.quote refid="QT_0001"/>.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6ba80b08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">3</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A third party may also owe a duty of confidence where he or she received information from another party who improperly imparted it.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6ba80b18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">4</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>An action for breach of confidence is based on the duty to act in good faith.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6ba80b28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">5</footnote.reference>] The law depends on <begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>“the broad principle of equity that he who has received information in confidence shall not take unfair advantage of it”<end.quote refid="QT_0002"/>.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6ba80b38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">6</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175918" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1989312320" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I45b1fbf18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">LAC Minerals Ltd. v. International Corona Resources</cite.query> Ltd.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id6ba80b48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">7</footnote.reference>] the court considered the effect of custom in determining the level of obligation a confidee owes to the confidor. <eos/><bos/>The court held that in the mining industry, there was a practice that parties involved in serious negotiations would not harm the other&apos;s business by divulging information acquired through those negotiations. <eos/><bos/>The disclosure of confidential information was also considered “customary” in the <cite.query w-src-number="0492175918" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1989312320" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I45b1fbf58e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>LAC</ital></cite.query> case. <eos/><bos/>This assisted the plaintiff in establishing that, although the information had been disseminated, the plaintiff had taken all necessary steps to maintain its secrecy.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6ba80b58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">8</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The central issue on the appeal in <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175918" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2040732478" w-pub-number="0005506" ID="I45b4bb118e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Nissen v. Durham Regional Police Services</cite.query> Board</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id6ba80b68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">9</footnote.reference>] was: what are the required elements for a claim for damages against the police for breach of a promise of confidentiality made to a citizen reporting criminal wrongdoing? <eos/><bos/>Stack was awarded damages against the Police for what was pleaded as breach of informer privilege. <eos/><bos/>Stack went to the Police to tell them that she had learned that the teenaged son of her neighbours had broken into another neighbour&apos;s house and stolen some guns. <eos/><bos/>Stack asserted that she had asked the Police and been promised by them that her identity and the fact that she had reported the theft of the guns would be treated as confidential. <eos/><bos/>Unbeknownst to Stack, the Police videotaped her interview. <eos/><bos/>Her neighbours&apos; sons were charged and a recording of Stack&apos;s interview was included in the disclosure provided in the criminal proceedings. <eos/><bos/>Stack was subsequently subjected to threatening and harassing conduct by the parents of the accused. <eos/><bos/>Stack and her family were so distressed by this conduct that they sold their home and moved to another community. <eos/><bos/>As a result of these events, Stack had been diagnosed as having post-traumatic stress disorder.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6ba80b78e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">10</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge found as a fact that the Officer had promised Stack anonymity and confidentiality. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge found that the police owed a common law duty not to disclose the identity of an informer, and that even if the duty was not absolute, reasonable care had not been taken in the circumstances. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge rejected the claim for damages arising from the sale of the Whitby home and purchase of the new home, as no expert evidence was called as to loss of value. <eos/><bos/>He also rejected a claim for <ital>Charter</ital> damages, and the claims Stack and her husband had asserted for lost income or lost opportunity. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge did, however, award Stack general damages for emotional and psychological injury. <eos/><bos/>That claim was supported by her own evidence, that of her family and friends, and that of Dr. Silver, who had diagnosed her with post-traumatic stress disorder, an opinion that was not contradicted by the expert retained by the Police. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge found that the psychological injury Stack had suffered rose above the level of ordinary upset or anxiety, and was therefore compensable at law. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge found that the failure of the Police to act after they learned of the neighbour&apos;s harassing behaviour, other than the one brief telephone conversation, was an aggravating factor. <eos/><bos/>He rejected the claim for punitive damages and fixed the general damages in the amount of $345,000. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge also awarded <ital>Family Law Act</ital>, damages for loss of guidance, care and companionship, in the amount of $65,000 to the husband, and $25,000 to each child.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6baa7c08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">11</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Court of Appeal was not referred to any case in which damages for breach of informer privilege had been awarded. <eos/><bos/>However, in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175918" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1983169041" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I45b6b6e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Bisaillon c. Keable</ital> (1983), 2 D.L.R. (4th) 193, [1983] 2 S.C.R. 60, 4</cite.query> Admin. L.R. 205, 37 C.R. (3d) 289, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175918" w-seq-number="00007" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1983169041" w-pub-number="0005466" ID="I45b6b6e38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">51 N.R. 81, 7 C.C.C. (3d) 385, 1983 CarswellQue 384, 1983 CarswellQue 28, 10 W.C.B. 359, [1983] A.C.S. No. 65, [1983] S.C.J. No. 65 (S.C.C.)</cite.query>, Beetz J. stated that although there was no precedent on the point, he would have no difficulty in finding that an action for damages for such a breach would lie. <eos/><bos/>The Police do not dispute that proposition. <eos/><bos/>However, the Police did argue that the trial judge erred by finding that a plaintiff only need prove that the police made a promise of confidentiality in exchange for information in order to establish the privilege. <eos/><bos/>They submitted that the elements for a civil claim for damages for breach of a promise of confidentiality by the police will not lie without proof of two other elements, namely, (1) that the information provided must be difficult or impossible to obtain; and (2) that the informer must be likely to suffer harm or danger if his or her identity is disclosed.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6baa7c18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">12</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Sharpe disagreed with the Police submission that the trial judge erred with respect to the necessary elements for the claim, concluding that should be decided as a civil claim for damages for breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>The fundamental point was that, on the findings of the trial judge, the Officer made a promise of confidentiality and anonymity to Stack in exchange for the information she provided. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge found that the promise was breached and Stack suffered damages as a result. <eos/><bos/>Those findings brought the case squarely within the long-recognized cause of action for breach of confidence, and Stack was accordingly entitled to recover on that basis. <eos/><bos/>While other considerations may come into play in a criminal case where the prosecution is resisting disclosure of the identity of a confidential informer to an accused, this was a civil case between the police and an individual who was promised confidentiality. <eos/><bos/>That promise gave rise to a common law and equitable right entitling Stack to have her identity kept confidential. <eos/><bos/>Her right was not contingent upon other ways the Police may have had to get the information she provided, or on what the Police thought about the danger she faced. <eos/><bos/>Difficulty in obtaining the information and fear of harm to the witness may well be the rationales underlying the doctrine of informer privilege in criminal law, but Justice Sharpe was not persuaded that they are necessary elements to sustain the privilege, even in a criminal case. <eos/><bos/>There is no reason to qualify the right to sue for breach of confidence by adding additional elements necessary to establish a civil claim for damages. <eos/><bos/>To do so would put the citizen interacting with the police in an impossible situation. <eos/><bos/>Stack had no way of determining whether the Police could obtain from another source the information she was offering. <eos/><bos/>Nor did she have any way of gauging what the Police considered to be the risk of harm she faced should her identity be disclosed. <eos/><bos/>She explained her fear of harm to the Officer and that fear ultimately proved to be well-founded. <eos/><bos/>She was entitled to rely on the Officer&apos;s promise of confidentiality in exchange for her cooperation in giving him the information she had.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6baa7c28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">13</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Sharpe also did not accept the submission that because the Police did not follow their own Directive for confidential informers, Stack&apos;s civil claim for damages was defeated. <eos/><bos/>While the Officer may have thought that Stack was not a confidential informer within the meaning of the Directive, Justice Sharpe failed to see how that could affect her right to claim for breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>Her claim rested upon the promise of confidentiality that the Officer made, and the exchange of information that followed as a result. <eos/><bos/>She had no way of determining whether she fit within the terms of the Directive, and it would be obviously unfair to deny her claim on the basis of a Directive that had never been explained or brought to her attention.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6baa7c38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">14</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Id6ba59a08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>W.R. McComas, M.R. Davison and D.M. Gonski, <ital>Protection of Trade Secrets: A General Guide</ital> (Sydney: Butterworths, 1981), p. 29 as <ital>per</ital> Roxburgh J.&apos;s decision in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175918" w-seq-number="00008" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1959018301" w-pub-number="0004831" ID="I45ba60608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Terrapin Ltd. v. Builders&apos; Supply Co. (Hayes) Ltd.</ital>, [1960] R.P.C. 128 (C.A.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ba59a38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>Margaret, </ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175918" w-seq-number="00009" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1964015422" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I45ba87708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Duchess of Argyll v. Duke of Argyll</ital>, [1965] 1 All E.R. 611 (Ch.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175918" w-seq-number="00010" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1849049683" w-pub-number="0005801" ID="I45ba87728e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Prince Albert v. Strange</ital> (1849), 1 H. &amp; Tw. 1, 47 E.R. 1302 (Ch.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ba80b08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175918" w-seq-number="00011" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1968018312" w-pub-number="0004831" ID="I45be09e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Coco v. A.N. Clark (Engineers) Ltd.</ital>, [1969] R.P.C. 41 (Ch.), at p. 50</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ba80b18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>4</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>La Forest J. in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175918" w-seq-number="00012" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1989312320" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I45be30f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>LAC Minerals Ltd. v. International Corona Resources Ltd.</ital> (1989), 1989 CarswellOnt 126, 61 D.L.R. (4th) 14, at p. 36, [1989] 2 S.C.R. 574</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ba80b28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>5</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175918" w-seq-number="00013" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1968017805" w-pub-number="0003898" ID="I45be58008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Fraser v. Evans</ital>, [1969] 1 Q.B. 349 (C.A.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ba80b38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>6</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175918" w-seq-number="00014" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1967018556" w-pub-number="0004891" ID="I45be7f108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seager v. Copydex Ltd.</ital>, [1967] 1 W.L.R. 923 (C.A.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ba80b48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>7</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175918" w-seq-number="00015" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1989312320" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I45be7f128e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>LAC Minerals Ltd. v. International Corona Resources Ltd.</ital> (1989), 61 D.L.R. (4th) 14, [1989] 2 S.C.R. 574</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ba80b58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>8</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The “custom or usage” principle set out in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175918" w-seq-number="00016" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1967017988" w-pub-number="0004891" ID="I45c50ec08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cunliffe-Owen v. Teather &amp; Greenwood</ital>, [1967] 1 W.L.R. 1421 (Ch.)</cite.query> was applied by the Supreme Court of Canada in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175918" w-seq-number="00017" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1989312320" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I45c50ec28e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>LAC Minerals Ltd. v. International Corona Resources Ltd.</ital> (1989), 61 D.L.R. (4th) 14, [1989] 2 S.C.R. 574</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>See also <cite.query w-src-number="0492175918" w-seq-number="00018" w-ref-type="ER" w-normalized-cite="1912 29RPCUK639" w-pub-number="0004831" ID="I45c50ec58e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Liquid Veneer Co. v. Scott</ital>, [1912] 29 R.P.C. 639 (Ch.)</cite.query>, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175918" w-seq-number="00019" w-ref-type="ER" w-serial-number="1989312320" w-pub-number="0005156" w-pinpoint-page="644" ID="I45c50ec78e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">at p. 644</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ba80b68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>9</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175918" w-seq-number="00020" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040732478" w-pub-number="0005506" ID="I45c55ce08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Nissen v. Durham Regional Police Services Board</ital> (2017), 134 O.R. (3d) 81, 2017 CarswellOnt 114, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 426, 2017 ONCA 10 (Ont. C.A.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ba80b78e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>10</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175918" w-seq-number="00021" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040732478" w-pub-number="0005506" ID="I45c583f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Nissen v. Durham Regional Police Services Board</ital> (2017), 134 O.R. (3d) 81, 2017 CarswellOnt 114, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 426, 2017 ONCA 10 (Ont. C.A.)</cite.query>, at paras. 1–2.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6baa7c08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>11</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175918" w-seq-number="00022" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040732478" w-pub-number="0005506" ID="I45c5ab008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Nissen v. Durham Regional Police Services Board</ital> (2017), 134 O.R. (3d) 81, 2017 CarswellOnt 114, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 426, 2017 ONCA 10 (Ont. C.A.)</cite.query>, at paras. 16, 19, and 21–22.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6baa7c18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>12</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175918" w-seq-number="00023" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040732478" w-pub-number="0005506" ID="I45c5f9208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Nissen v. Durham Regional Police Services Board</ital> (2017), 134 O.R. (3d) 81, 2017 CarswellOnt 114, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 426, 2017 ONCA 10 (Ont. C.A.)</cite.query>, at paras. 26–27.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6baa7c28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>13</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175918" w-seq-number="00024" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040732478" w-pub-number="0005506" ID="I45c620308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Nissen v. Durham Regional Police Services Board</ital> (2017), 134 O.R. (3d) 81, 2017 CarswellOnt 114, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 426, 2017 ONCA 10 (Ont. C.A.)</cite.query>, at paras. 31–34.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6baa7c38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>14</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175918" w-seq-number="00025" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2040732478" w-pub-number="0005506" ID="I45c647408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Nissen v. Durham Regional Police Services Board</ital> (2017), 134 O.R. (3d) 81, 2017 CarswellOnt 114, 274 A.C.W.S. (3d) 426, 2017 ONCA 10 (Ont. C.A.)</cite.query>, at para. 36.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 5:7<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
