<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information Appendix A<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I5a3a4780411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><headtext>Appendices</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><appendix ID="I5a3a4781411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f770bc6ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Appendix</label.name><label.designator>A.</label.designator><headtext>Precedents</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title><appendix.body><head style="l" parent="appendix.body"><bop/><bos/><label.name><bold>§ </bold></label.name><label.designator><bold>A:1.</bold></label.designator><headtext><bold>Introduction</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The purpose of this appendix is to provide sample court documents and agreements related to the law of confidential business information. <eos/><bos/>As with all precedents, the user will need to adapt the documents and agreements so that they meet the needs of the relevant fact situation. <eos/><bos/>Sample pleadings should only be used as a guideline, and every pleading must be drafted on the basis of the circumstances involved. <eos/><bos/>It is equally important that standard form confidentiality, non-competition and non-solicitation agreements be revised to reflect the specific conditions of the particular relationship.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Another issue that must be addressed is the fact that this area of the law is constantly changing. <eos/><bos/>This will require users of these precedents to be diligent in keeping up with the developments in these substantive areas of the law.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A third issue to keep in mind when using the precedents is the need to modify them to take into account the relevant legal jurisdiction. <eos/><bos/>For the most part, the precedents can be used across Canada. <eos/><bos/>However, special attention should be paid when dealing with Quebec law, as most of the written precedents are based on common law principles. <eos/><bos/>In addition, it should be noted that the pleadings were prepared according to the format required by the Ontario <ital>Rules of Civil Procedure</ital>, R.R.O. 1990, Reg. 194.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In summary, it will, of necessity, be up to the individual user to determine both the suitability of a specific precedent and the degree to which modifications are necessary. <eos/><bos/>The looseleaf format of this book will allow for continual revision of the existing precedents and the addition of new ones as legal principles and business needs evolve.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><head style="l" parent="appendix.body"><bop/><bos/><label.name><bold>§ </bold></label.name><label.designator><bold>A:2.</bold></label.designator><headtext><bold>Sample Confidentiality Clause</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><form ID="I5cc4ea00411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><form.body><form.unit ID="Id9f5d5908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Id9f5d5918e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(1)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Employee acknowledges that during <instruction><ital>[his/her]</ital></instruction> employment <instruction><ital>[he/she]</ital></instruction> will inevitably acquire substantial knowledge, experience and expertise in aspects of the Company&apos;s business or businesses now or hereafter conducted and that the Company will be relying on such knowledge, experience and expertise in its operation of such business or businesses.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9f5d5928e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(2)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Employee further acknowledges and agrees that as a result of the nature of <instruction><ital>[his/her]</ital></instruction> position and its inherent opportunities, the Employee will have access to and will be entrusted with specific detailed confidential information concerning the business or businesses now or hereafter conducted by the Company, including but not limited to information relating to <instruction><ital>[business opportunities, services provided, pricing policies, financial information, research and development information, marketing schemes, sales and distribution information]</ital></instruction>, and customer information, and that the disclosure of any such information to the competitors of the Company or any other third party would be detrimental to the best interests of the Company and would cause irreparable harm to the Company&apos;s interests.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9f5d5938e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(3)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Employee also acknowledges that the right to maintain such information in confidence constitutes a proprietary right that the Company is entitled to protect.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9f5d5948e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(4)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Employee accordingly covenants and agrees with the Company that <instruction><ital>[he/she]</ital></instruction> will not, during <instruction><ital>[his/her]</ital></instruction> employment or at any time thereafter, disclose any such confidential information to any third party, except as required in the ordinary course of <instruction><ital>[his/her]</ital></instruction> employment with the Company, nor shall <instruction><ital>[he/she]</ital></instruction> use such confidential information for any purpose other than to further the interests of the Company.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9f75c308e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(5)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Employee agrees that upon the termination of this agreement, for any reason whatsoever, the Employee will immediately return all Company business documents, lists, files, materials, equipment and property, including all copies of such information and property in such Employee&apos;s possession, to the Company.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit></form.body></form><head style="l" parent="appendix.body"><bop/><bos/><label.name><bold>§ </bold></label.name><label.designator><bold>A:3.</bold></label.designator><headtext><bold>Sample Non-Solicitation Clause</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><form ID="I5cc51110411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><form.body><form.unit ID="Id9f846908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Id9f846918e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(1)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Employee further agrees that for a period of <instruction><ital>[twelve (12) months]</ital></instruction> following the termination of <instruction><ital>[his/her]</ital></instruction> employment hereunder, regardless of the manner of such termination, <instruction><ital>[he/she]</ital></instruction> will not directly or indirectly solicit business from any client or potential client of the Company which was served or solicited by the Company within the <instruction><ital>[thirty-six (36) months]</ital></instruction> immediately preceding the termination.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9f846928e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(2)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Employee further agrees that for a period of <instruction><ital>[twelve (12) months]</ital></instruction> following the termination of <instruction><ital>[his/her]</ital></instruction> employment, regardless of how that termination should occur, <instruction><ital>[he/she]</ital></instruction> will not directly or indirectly hire or take away or cause to be hired or taken away any employee of the Company or, following the termination of the employment, any employee who was in the employ of the Company during the <instruction><ital>[six (6) months]</ital></instruction> preceding termination.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit></form.body></form><head style="l" parent="appendix.body"><bop/><bos/><label.name><bold>§ </bold></label.name><label.designator><bold>A:4.</bold></label.designator><headtext><bold>Sample Non-Competition Clause</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><form ID="I5cc55f30411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><form.body><form.unit ID="Id9fab7908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Id9fab7918e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(1)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Employee covenants and agrees that <instruction><ital>[he/she]</ital></instruction> will not, during the duration of <instruction><ital>[his/her]</ital></instruction> employment and for a period of <instruction><ital>[twelve (12) months]</ital></instruction> thereafter, whether as principal, as agent or as an Employee of, or in partnership or association with any person, firm or corporation or in any manner whatsoever, directly or indirectly carry on, be engaged in, advise, own shares in (other than solely as a holder of not more than 1% of the issued and outstanding voting shares of any public corporation), lend money to, guarantee the debts or obligations of or permit <instruction><ital>[his/her]</ital></instruction> name to be used or employed by any person, firm or corporation engaged in, concerned with or interested in <instruction><ital>[describe the nature of the business]</ital></instruction> anywhere within the <instruction><ital>[defined geographical area]</ital></instruction>.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fab7928e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(2)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Employee acknowledges and confirms that the scope of this covenant is in all respects and particularly in respect of area, time and subject-matter, no more than is reasonable to protect the Company.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fab7938e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(3)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Employee agrees to devote <instruction><ital>[his/her]</ital></instruction> full effort to the Company&apos;s business, and in recognition of the demands of <instruction><ital>[his/her]</ital></instruction> employment, agrees to forego any outside employment or business relationships, whether amounting to an actual conflict of interest or not.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit></form.body></form><head style="l" parent="appendix.body"><bop/><bos/><label.name><bold>§ </bold></label.name><label.designator><bold>A:5.</bold></label.designator><headtext><bold>Sample Letter Agreement</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><form ID="I5cc58640411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><form.body><form.caption><tbl ID="I5a4b3771411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><table><bos/><tgroup cols="2" align="left"><colspec colnum="1" colname="1"/><colspec align="right" colnum="2" colname="2"/><tbody><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2"><instruction><ital>[Return address]</ital></instruction></entry></row><row><entry colname="1"> </entry><entry colname="2"/></row><row><entry colname="1"><instruction><ital>[Date]</ital></instruction></entry><entry colname="2"/></row><row><entry colname="1"> </entry><entry colname="2"/></row><row><entry colname="1">PRIVATE &amp; CONFIDENTIAL</entry><entry colname="2"/></row><row><entry colname="1"> </entry><entry colname="2"/></row><row><entry colname="1">Attention:</entry><entry colname="2"/></row><row><entry colname="1"> </entry><entry colname="2"/></row><row><entry colname="1">Dear<leaveout><fill.in><textrule weight="0.5pt" position="baseline" length=" 5em "/></fill.in></leaveout>:</entry><entry colname="2"/></row><row><entry colname="1"> </entry><entry colname="2"/></row><row><entry colname="1"><underscore>Re: Confidentiality Agreement</underscore></entry><entry colname="2"/></row></tbody></tgroup><eos/></table><eop/></tbl></form.caption><form.para><bop/><form.text><bos/>ABC Limited (“ABC”) is interested in retaining XYZ Consulting Inc. (“XYZ”) as a consultant for the purpose of providing advice relating to a proposed acquisition transaction involving DEF Enterprises. <eos/><bos/>Specifically, XYZ will provide advice with respect to <instruction><ital>[business integration issues]</ital></instruction> that may arise in connection with the proposed transaction. <eos/><bos/>In that regard, XYZ agrees to make available to ABC the knowledge and expertise gained by XYZ on other engagements where its advice has been sought, subject to obtaining the appropriate consents if necessary.<eos/></form.text><eop/></form.para><form.para><bop/><form.text><bos/>Accordingly, ABC will make available to XYZ confidential information, in oral, written or electronic form, related to the business and operations of DEF Enterprises, ABC and their respective subsidiaries and affiliates (the “Confidential Information”).<eos/><bos/> The Confidential Information does not include information which, at the time of disclosure thereafter, is generally available to and known by the public or independently developed by XYZ (other than as a result of a breach of this agreement by XYZ).<eos/></form.text><eop/></form.para><form.para><bop/><form.text><bos/>Except as otherwise specifically provided herein, in consideration of ABC making the Confidential Information available to it and for other consideration, XYZ agrees on its behalf and agrees on behalf of its directors, officers, employees, agent, advisors and other representatives:<eos/></form.text><eop/></form.para><form.unit ID="Id9fc3e308e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Id9fc3e318e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>1.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>not to use or allow the use of, for any purpose, any portion of the Confidential Information, notes, summaries or other material prepared by XYZ and derived from its inspection or evaluation of the Confidential Information (the “Notes”), except in connection with the performance of its engagement as a consultant by ABC;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fc3e328e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>2.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>not to disclose or allow disclosure to others of any portion of the Confidential Information or the Notes, except to those of its officers and employees who are advised of the confidential nature of the Confidential Information and agree in writing to be bound by the terms of this agreement, and only for the purpose described in clause 1 above;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fc3e338e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>3.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>not to discuss the engagement of XYZ or any of the Confidential Information with any party other than ABC;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fc3e348e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>4.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>not to make copies of or otherwise reproduce the Confidential Information or any part thereof, or remove any of the Confidential Information from the place where it is made available, except as permitted by ABC;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fc3e358e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>5.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>to deliver to ABC, immediately upon request, the Confidential Information and any Notes, without retaining any copies or extracts therefrom; and<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fc3e368e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>6.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>to be bound by the terms of the Confidentiality Agreement signed by ABC relating to a proposed transaction involving DEF Enterprises, a copy of which has been provided to and reviewed by XYZ.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit><form.para><bop/><form.text><bos/>In the event that XYZ is required by law to disclose any portion of the Confidential Information or the Notes, XYZ shall provide ABC with prompt written notice of such requirement so that ABC may seek an appropriate court order which would have the effect of relieving XYZ of this requirement to disclose.<eos/></form.text><eop/></form.para><form.para><bop/><form.text><bos/>ABC shall be entitled to equitable relief, including an injunction and specific performance, in the event of any breach of the provisions of this agreement, in addition to any other remedies available to ABC at law.<eos/></form.text><eop/></form.para><form.para><bop/><form.text><bos/>This agreement constitutes the entire agreement between the parties pertaining to the subject-matter of this agreement. <eos/><bos/>No amendment or waiver of this agreement shall be binding unless executed in writing by the party to be bound thereby. <eos/><bos/>This agreement shall be binding on the successors of the parties hereto.<eos/></form.text><eop/></form.para><form.para><bop/><form.text><bos/>This agreement shall be governed by and construed in accordance with the laws of the <instruction><ital>[Province of Ontario]</ital></instruction> and the laws of Canada applicable therein, and the parties attorn exclusively to the jurisdiction of the laws of the <instruction><ital>[Province of Ontario]</ital></instruction>.<eos/></form.text><eop/></form.para><form.signature.block><bop/><tbl ID="Idd00c9d0898a11ea95a1b70c6ff9646c"><table><bos/><tgroup cols="2" align="left"><colspec colnum="1" colname="1"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="2"/><tbody><row><entry colname="1">Yours very truly,</entry><entry colname="2"/></row><row><entry colname="1"> </entry><entry colname="2"/></row><row><entry colname="1"> </entry><entry colname="2"/></row><row><entry colname="1">By: <leader><leaderchar>_</leaderchar></leader></entry><entry colname="2"/></row><row><entry colname="1"> </entry><entry colname="2"/></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2"><bold>Acknowledged and accepted this</bold></entry></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2"><instruction><ital>[insert date]</ital></instruction></entry></row><row><entry colname="1"> </entry><entry colname="2"/></row><row><entry colname="1"> </entry><entry colname="2"/></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2"><bold>By:</bold> <leaveout><fill.in><textrule weight="0.5pt" position="baseline" length="  11em "/></fill.in></leaveout></entry></row></tbody></tgroup><eos/></table></tbl><eop/></form.signature.block></form.body></form><head style="l" parent="appendix.body"><bop/><bos/><label.name><bold>§ </bold></label.name><label.designator><bold>A:6.</bold></label.designator><headtext><bold>Sample Statements of Claim</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><form ID="I5cc64990411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><form.body><form.caption><form.line style="r"><bop/><bos/>Court File No. 97-CQ-XXXXXXXXXX<eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/><bold><csc>Superior Court of Justice</csc></bold><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="l"><bop/><bos/>BETWEEN:<eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/><bold><csc>Tolley Protection Services Limited</csc></bold><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="r"><bop/><bos/>Plaintiff<eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/>—and—<eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/><bold><csc>Durand Security Services Ltd.</csc></bold>,<eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/><bold><csc>David Durand</csc></bold>,<eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/><bold><csc>Kate Kendry</csc>, and</bold><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/><bold><csc>Michael Cohen</csc></bold><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="r"><bop/><bos/>Defendants<eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/><bold><csc>Statement of Claim</csc></bold><eos/><eop/></form.line></form.caption><form.line style="l"><bop/><bos/><csc>To the defendant(s)</csc>:<eos/><eop/></form.line><form.para><bop/><form.text><bos/><csc>A legal proceeding has been commenced against you</csc> by the plaintiff(s).<eos/></form.text><eop/></form.para><form.para><bop/><form.text><bos/>The claim made against you is set out in the following pages.<eos/></form.text><eop/></form.para><form.para><bop/><form.text><bos/><csc>If you wish to defend this proceeding</csc>, you or an Ontario lawyer acting for you must prepare a statement of defence in Form 18A prescribed by the Rules of Civil Procedure, serve it on the plaintiff&apos;s lawyer, or, where the plaintiff does not have a lawyer, serve it on the plaintiff, and file it, with proof of service, in this court office, <csc>within twenty days</csc> after this statement of claim is served on you, if you are served in Ontario.<eos/></form.text><eop/></form.para><form.para><bop/><form.text><bos/>If you are served in another province or territory of Canada or in the United States of America, the period for serving and filing your statement of defence is forty days. <eos/><bos/>If you are served outside Canada and the United States of America, the period is sixty days.<eos/></form.text><eop/></form.para><form.para><bop/><form.text><bos/>Instead of serving and filing a statement of defence, you may serve and file a notice of intent to defend in Form 18B prescribed by the Rules of Civil Procedure. <eos/><bos/>This will entitle you to ten more days within which to serve and file your statement of defence.<eos/></form.text><eop/></form.para><form.para><bop/><form.text><bos/><csc>If you fail to defend this proceeding, judgment may be given against you in your absence and without further notice to you</csc>.<eos/></form.text><eop/></form.para><form.para><bop/><form.text><bos/>If you wish to defend this proceeding but are unable to pay legal fees, legal aid may be available to you by contacting a Legal Aid Office.<eos/></form.text><eop/></form.para><tbl ID="I5a568210411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><table><bos/><tgroup cols="2" align="left"><colspec colnum="1" colname="1"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="2"/><tbody><row><entry colname="1">Date: <leaveout><fill.in><textrule weight="0.5pt" position="baseline" length="  11em "/></fill.in></leaveout></entry><entry colname="2">Issued by: <leaveout><fill.in><textrule weight="0.5pt" position="baseline" length="  11em "/></fill.in></leaveout></entry></row><row><entry colname="1"> </entry><entry colname="2"/></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2">Address of Court Office:</entry></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2">145 Queen Street West</entry></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2">Toronto, Ontario</entry></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2">M5H 2N9</entry></row></tbody></tgroup><eos/></table><eop/></tbl><tbl ID="Idd0f6fd0898a11ea95a1b70c6ff9646c"><bop/><table><bos/><tgroup cols="2" align="left"><colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="6*"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="30*"/><tbody><row><entry colname="1">TO:</entry><entry colname="2"><bold>Durand Security Services Ltd.</bold></entry></row><row><entry colname="1"> </entry><entry colname="2"/></row><row><entry colname="1">AND TO:</entry><entry colname="2"><bold>David Durand</bold></entry></row><row><entry colname="1"> </entry><entry colname="2"/></row><row><entry colname="1">AND TO:</entry><entry colname="2"><bold>Kate Kendry</bold></entry></row><row><entry colname="1"> </entry><entry colname="2"/></row><row><entry colname="1">AND TO:</entry><entry colname="2"><bold>Michael Cohen</bold></entry></row></tbody></tgroup><eos/></table><eop/></tbl><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/><bold><underscore>CLAIM</underscore></bold><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.unit ID="Id9fd01808e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Id9fd01818e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator><bold>1</bold>.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/><bold><csc>The plaintiff claims</csc></bold>:<eos/></form.text></form.para><form.unit ID="Id9fd01828e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.unit ID="Id9fd01838e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(a)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>damages in the amount of $1,000,000.00 for breach of contract, inducing breach of contract, and for breach of confidence, fidelity, and/or fiduciary duties;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd01848e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(b)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>in the alternative, an accounting of the profits made by the defendants in breach of their fiduciary duties and/or duties of fidelity and confidence;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd01858e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(c)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>punitive damages in the amount of $100,000;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd01868e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(d)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>an interim, interlocutory and permanent injunction restraining the defendants personally or by their agents, employees, servants and assigns from:<eos/></form.text></form.para><form.unit ID="Id9fd01878e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.unit ID="Id9fd01888e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(i)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>soliciting or dealing with the clients or employees of the plaintiff Tolley Protection Services Limited;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd01898e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(ii)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>trading upon or diminishing the goodwill of the plaintiff;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd018a8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(iii)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>doing or participating in any act which breaches the Non-Competition and Confidentiality Agreement entered into by the defendant David Durand in favour of the plaintiff;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd018b8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(iv)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>disclosing to third parties or making any unauthorized use of the plaintiff&apos;s Confidential Information and any documents related to the Confidential Information;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd018c8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(v)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>copying or allowing inspection of the Confidential Information and any documents related to the Confidential Information, except with the consent of the plaintiff or pursuant to an order of this Honourable Court; and<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd018d8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(vi)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>doing or participating in any act which breaches the fiduciary duties owed by the defendants to the plaintiff;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit></form.unit></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd28908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(e)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>an interim, interlocutory and permanent injunction requiring the defendants to deliver up to the plaintiff any documents which are the property of the plaintiff which contain any of the Confidential Information, and any copies thereof that have been made;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd28918e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(f)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>pre-judgment and post-judgment interest pursuant to the provisions of the <ital>Courts of Justice Act</ital>, R.S.O. 1990, c. C.43, as amended;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd28928e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(g)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>the costs of this action assessed on a solicitor and client scale; and<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd28938e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(h)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>such further and other relief as to this Honourable Court may seem just.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit></form.unit></form.unit><eop/></form.unit><form.line style="l"><bop/><bos/><underscore>The Parties</underscore><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.unit ID="Id9fd28948e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Id9fd28958e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>2.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The plaintiff, Tolley Protection Services Limited (“Tolley”), is a company incorporated pursuant to the laws of the Province of Ontario and carries on business providing security guard, protection, and investigation services.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd28968e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>3.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The defendant, Michael Cohen (“Cohen”), resides in the City of Toronto in the Province of Ontario. <eos/><bos/>Cohen is the President and a Director of Durand Security Services Ltd.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd28978e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>4.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The defendant, Kate Kendry (“Kendry”), resides in the City of Scarbor ough in the Province of Ontario. <eos/><bos/>Kendry is the Vice-President and a Director of Durand Security Services Ltd.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd28988e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>5.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The defendant, David Durand (“Durand”), is an individual well known in the security guard industry, the Chief Executive Officer and founder of Durand Security Services Ltd.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd28998e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>6.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The defendant, Durand Security Services Ltd. (“Durand Security”), is a company incorporated on November 19, 1996, pursuant to the laws of the Province of Ontario. <eos/><bos/>Durand Security carries on the business of providing security guard services from its head office in Toronto, Ontario. <eos/><bos/>The controlling minds and agents of Durand Security are the personal defendants.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit><form.line style="l"><bop/><bos/><underscore>Employment at Tolley</underscore><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.unit ID="Id9fd289a8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Id9fd289b8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>7.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>From September 26, 1978, until his resignation, Cohen was an employee of Tolley and of its predecessor companies, and worked out of the head office in Toronto, Ontario. <eos/><bos/>At the time of his resignation from Tolley, he held the position of Senior Vice President and was earning an annual salary of $125,000.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd289c8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>8.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>From October 14, 1987, until her resignation, Kendry was an employee of Tolley and of its predecessor companies, and worked out of the head office in Toronto, Ontario. <eos/><bos/>At the time of her resignation from Tolley, she held the position of Senior Manager and was earning an annual salary of $65,500.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd289d8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>9.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>From the inception of Tolley&apos;s predecessor companies until his resignation, Durand was an employee of Tolley and of its predecessor companies. <eos/><bos/>He also worked out of the head office in Toronto, Ontario, and at all times during his employment held a position in senior management. <eos/><bos/>At the time of his resignation from Tolley, he held the position of Chairman and was earning an annual salary of $145,000.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit><form.line style="l"><bop/><bos/><underscore>Access to Confidential Information</underscore><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.unit ID="Id9fd289e8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Id9fd289f8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>10.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>While employed by Tolley, the personal defendants each had access to confidential information belonging to Tolley. <eos/><bos/>Such information included but was not limited to Tolley&apos;s price structures, pay rates, bill rates, renewal dates of contracts, client needs and service requirements, client lists, and the name of the contact person for each client (“the Confidential Information”).<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd28a08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>11.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Tolley states that the Confidential Information was treated by Tolley as confidential, that the personal defendants knew or ought to have known the Confidential Information was confidential, and that the personal defendants knew or ought to have known that any improper use of the Confidential Information would seriously damage or impair Tolley.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd28a18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>12.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Tolley states that it was an implied term of the contract of employment between Kendry and Tolley that the Confidential Information would remain confidential, that it would be used only for the purposes of Tolley, and that she would not disclose to third persons or use for her own benefit, or for the benefit of any third person, any of the Confidential Information.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd28a28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>13.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Tolley further states that it was an express term of the contract of employment between Durand and Tolley and between Cohen and Tolley that the Confidential Information would remain confidential, that it would be used only for the purposes of Tolley, and that they would not disclose to third persons or use for their own benefit, or for the benefit of any third person, any of the Confidential Information.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd28a38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>14.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Tolley states that the personal defendants each stood in a fiduciary position with respect to Tolley as a result of the following:<eos/></form.text></form.para><form.unit ID="Id9fd28a48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.unit ID="Id9fd28a58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(a)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>each enjoyed top management status with Tolley;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd28a68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(b)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>each spent considerable time in the top management of Tolley;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd28a78e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(c)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>each was an employee key to Tolley&apos;s operation;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd28a88e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(d)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>each had access to the Confidential Information;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd28a98e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(e)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Tolley was vulnerable to the misappropriation and abuse of the Confidential Information; and<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd28aa8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(f)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Tolley was vulnerable to the trading upon its goodwill.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit></form.unit></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd28ab8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>15.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Therefore, the personal defendants were and are in a fiduciary relationship to Tolley and were each under an obligation not to divert Tolley&apos;s maturing or existing business opportunities to themselves or to any third party.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd4fa08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>16.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The plaintiff further states that it was an implied term of Tolley&apos;s contract of employment with each of the personal defendants that each of the personal defendants would act towards Tolley with honesty, good faith and fidelity.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit><form.line style="l"><bop/><bos/><underscore>Sale of Goodwill and Non-Competition Agreement</underscore><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.unit ID="Id9fd4fa18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Id9fd4fa28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>17.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The predecessor of Tolley was established in 1976 by Durand and others. <eos/><bos/>This business became incorporated as Tolley Protection Services Limited in 1982. <eos/><bos/>As viewed by the Industry, Durand is synonymous with Tolley.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd4fa38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>18.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Prior to October 1, 1996, the business of Tolley was controlled by the personal defendants, and the majority of shares in Tolley were owned indirectly by the personal defendants&apos; holding company (“the Durand holding company”).<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd4fa48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>19.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>On or about October 1, 1996, through a series of amalgamations involving the Durand holding company and a share sale agreement, Durand, Cohen, and Kendry sold their controlling interest in Tolley to 50425 Ontario Ltd. (“the Acquisition”).<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd4fa58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>20.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>As part of the Acquisition, 50425 Ontario Ltd. and Tolley agreed to continue to employ the personal defendants in Tolley. <eos/><bos/>Durand retained his position as Chairman. <eos/><bos/>Cohen retained his position as Senior Vice President. <eos/><bos/>Kendry retained her position as Senior Manager.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd4fa68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>21.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>At the time of the Acquisition, Durand entered into a Non-Competition and Confidentiality Agreement with 50425 Ontario Ltd. whereby he agreed not to compete in any manner, directly or indirectly, with Tolley for a period of the longer of 3 years from the Acquisition or 2 years from the date Durand&apos;s employment with Tolley ended. <eos/><bos/>In this agreement, Durand also agreed not to solicit any of Tolley&apos;s employees for the same period.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd4fa78e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>22.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>An essential element of the Acquisition was the sale of the goodwill in Tolley to the new shareholders. <eos/><bos/>This included the goodwill built up in the name “Durand”.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd4fa88e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>23.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>50425 Ontario Ltd. amalgamated with Tolley on or about October 8, 1996. <eos/><bos/>All of 50425 Ontario Ltd.&apos;s assets, rights and privileges, including employment contracts and non-competition agreements, became those of Tolley.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit><form.line style="l"><bop/><bos/><underscore>Resignations</underscore><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.unit ID="Id9fd4fa98e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Id9fd4faa8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>24.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Cohen resigned from Tolley on November 14, 1996.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd4fab8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>25.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Durand resigned from Tolley on November 16, 1996, effective November 21, 1996.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd4fac8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>26.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Kendry resigned from Tolley on November 14, 1996.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd4fad8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>27.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Immediately upon their resignation, Durand, Kendry and Cohen incorporated Durand Security Services Ltd.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit><form.line style="l"><bop/><bos/><underscore>Solicitation of Clients</underscore><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.unit ID="Id9fd4fae8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Id9fd4faf8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>28.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Immediately upon its incorporation, and through the personal defendants, Durand Security began directly soliciting customers of Tolley. <eos/><bos/>At the date of issue of this pleading, Tolley is aware of direct solicitation by Durand Security of 8 of Tolley&apos;s current major clients:<eos/></form.text></form.para><form.unit ID="Id9fd4fb08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.unit ID="Id9fd4fb18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(a)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Rocket Express;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd4fb28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(b)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>West Oak Trust;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd4fb38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(c)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>the <ital>Oakville Chronicle</ital>;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd4fb48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(d)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Haddow Realty;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd4fb58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(e)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Halton Television;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd4fb68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(f)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>the Drummond Centre;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd4fb78e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(g)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>the Michael Broadcasting Corporation; and<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd4fb88e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(h)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Canadian Schools.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit></form.unit></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd76b08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>29.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The direct solicitation by the defendants has resulted in Rocket Express and Haddow Realty moving their business to Durand Security. <eos/><bos/>The direct solicitation and usurping of corporate contracts, accomplished through the misappropriation and abuse of the Confidential Information, is in breach of the personal defendants&apos; contractual and fiduciary obligations, of the personal defendants&apos; employment contracts with Tolley, and of the duty of confidence owed by the personal defendants to Tolley. <eos/><bos/>Further, such direct solicitation is in breach of the Non-Competition Agreement entered into by Durand.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd76b18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>30.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The plaintiff states that Durand Security, at the time of such solicitations of Tolley&apos;s clients, knew that such solicitations were a breach of the personal defendants&apos; fiduciary obligations owed to Tolley, a breach of the personal defendants&apos; contracts of employment with Tolley, and a breach of Durand&apos;s Non-Competition Agreement. <eos/><bos/>Durand owes a fiduciary duty and duty of confidence as a result of transmitted fiduciary responsibility and has breached such duties through its solicitation of Tolley&apos;s clients.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit><form.line style="l"><bop/><bos/><underscore>Solicitation of Employees</underscore><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.unit ID="Id9fd76b28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Id9fd76b38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>31.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Tolley states that the defendants have solicited employees of Tolley to resign their employment at Tolley and to commence employment with Durand Security. <eos/><bos/>Tolley further states that at least two employees of Tolley, Thomas Seaver and Lawrence Bird, have been induced to resign their employment with Tolley and to commence employment with Durand Security.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd76b48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>32.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Tolley states that Durand Security, at the time of such solicitations of Tolley&apos;s employees, knew that such solicitations were a breach of the personal defendants&apos; fiduciary obligations owed to Tolley, a breach of the personal defendants&apos; contracts of employment with Tolley, and a breach of Durand&apos;s Non-Competition Agreement. <eos/><bos/>Durand Security owes a fiduciary duty and duty of confidence as a result of transmitted fiduciary responsibility and has breached such duties through its solicitation of Tolley&apos;s employees.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit><form.line style="l"><bop/><bos/><underscore>Breach of Fiduciary Duties and Trading Upon Tolley&apos;s Goodwill</underscore><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.unit ID="Id9fd76b58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Id9fd76b68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>33.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The defendants, after having sold the goodwill in the Durand holding company and in Tolley, including the use of the name “Durand”, to Tolley&apos;s new shareholders, have entered into direct competition with Tolley and are using the name “Durand” to carry on business and attract clients. <eos/><bos/>Such acts are a direct frontal assault on the business of Tolley and constitute trading upon the goodwill of Tolley.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd76b78e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>34.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>As a result of the defendants misappropriating and abusing Tolley&apos;s good-will and Confidential Information, Durand Security has been and will be put into a better position than it would have been had Tolley&apos;s goodwill and Confidential Information not been so misappropriated and abused.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit><form.line style="l"><bop/><bos/><underscore>Breach of Duty of Fidelity, Good Faith and Honesty</underscore><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.unit ID="Id9fd76b88e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Id9fd76b98e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>35.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>In any event, the personal defendants owed a duty of fidelity, good faith and honesty to their former employer Tolley. <eos/><bos/>The defendants breached this duty by making unauthorized use of Tolley&apos;s Confidential Information, which was acquired during the personal defendants&apos; employment with Tolley, to solicit Tolley&apos;s clients, to solicit Tolley&apos;s employees, and to further injure Tolley.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit><form.line style="l"><bop/><bos/><underscore>Damages</underscore><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.unit ID="Id9fd76ba8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Id9fd76bb8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>36.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>As a result of the foregoing, the plaintiff, Tolley, has suffered damages, the particulars of which are as follows:<eos/></form.text></form.para><form.unit ID="Id9fd76bc8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.unit ID="Id9fd76bd8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(a)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Tolley has suffered and will continue to suffer a loss of goodwill;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd76be8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(b)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Tolley has lost corporate opportunities that have been usurped by the defendants;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd76bf8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(c)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Tolley has suffered loss of profits and reputation; and<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd76c08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(d)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Tolley has lost employees that have been solicited by the defendants and induced to leave Tolley&apos;s employ.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit></form.unit></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd76c18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>37.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The plaintiff states that the conduct of the defendants was undertaken by the defendants consciously and in full knowledge that such conduct was improper, in breach of fiduciary duties owed, and likely to injure Tolley. <eos/><bos/>The defendants are therefore liable for punitive damages.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd76c28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>38.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Further, by reason of the matters aforesaid, the plaintiff has suffered and will continue to suffer irreparable harm by the conduct of the defendants, and has been put to considerable trouble, inconvenience and expense.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd76c38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>39.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The plaintiff further states that by reason of the defendants&apos; activities as set out above, Tolley has suffered and will continue to suffer loss and damage, and the defendants have and will, unless restrained by this Honourable Court, continue to make profits therefrom.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd76c48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>40.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The plaintiff further states that the consequences of the acts described above cannot be entirely satisfied in law by the awarding of damages. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff claims an injunction to restrain the acts of the defendants as described above.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fd76c58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>41.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The plaintiff proposes that the trial of this action take place in Toronto.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit><form.signature.block><bop/><tbl ID="Idd2ff020898a11ea95a1b70c6ff9646c"><table><bos/><tgroup cols="2" align="left"><colspec colnum="1" colname="1"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="2"/><tbody><row><entry colname="1">Date: <leaveout><fill.in><textrule weight="0.5pt" position="baseline" length="  11em "/></fill.in></leaveout></entry><entry colname="2"><leaveout><fill.in><textrule weight="0.5pt" position="baseline" length="  11em "/></fill.in></leaveout></entry></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2">Counsel for the Plaintiff</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" namest="1" nameend="2" align="center"><leaveout><fill.in><textrule weight="0.5pt" position="baseline" length="  11em "/></fill.in></leaveout></entry></row></tbody></tgroup><eos/></table></tbl><eop/></form.signature.block><form.line style="r"><bop/><bos/>Court File No. 96-32504<eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/><bold><csc>Superior Court of Justice</csc></bold><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="l"><bop/><bos/><bold>BETWEEN:</bold><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/><bold><csc>John Doe</csc>, <csc>Mary Pryor</csc> and <csc>Samuel Smith</csc></bold><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="r"><bop/><bos/>Plaintiffs<eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/><bold>—and—</bold><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/><bold><csc>Elmars Copper Inc.</csc></bold><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="r"><bop/><bos/>Defendant<eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/><bold><csc>Statement of Claim</csc></bold><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="l"><bop/><bos/><bold><csc>To the defendant(s)</csc>:</bold><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.para><bop/><form.text><bos/><bold>A <csc>legal proceeding has been commenced against you</csc></bold> by the plaintiffs. <eos/><bos/>The claim made against you is set out in the following pages.<eos/></form.text><eop/></form.para><form.para><bop/><form.text><bos/><bold><csc>If you wish to defend this proceeding</csc></bold>, you or an Ontario lawyer acting for you must prepare a statement of defence in Form 18A prescribed by the Rules of Civil Procedure, serve it on the plaintiffs&apos; lawyer, or, where the plaintiffs do not have a lawyer, serve it on the plaintiffs, and file it, with proof of service, in this court office, <ital><csc>within twenty days</csc></ital> after this statement of claim is served on you, if you are served in Ontario.<eos/></form.text><eop/></form.para><form.para><bop/><form.text><bos/>If you are served in another province or territory of Canada or in the United States of America, the period for serving and filing your statement of defence is forty days. <eos/><bos/>If you are served outside Canada and the United States of America, the period is sixty days.<eos/></form.text><eop/></form.para><form.para><bop/><form.text><bos/>Instead of serving and filing a statement of defence, you may serve and file a notice of intent to defend in Form 18B prescribed by the Rules of Civil Procedure. <eos/><bos/>This will entitle you to ten more days within which to serve and file your statement of defence.<eos/></form.text><eop/></form.para><form.para><bop/><form.text><bos/><bold><csc>If you fail to defend this proceeding, judgment may be given against you in your absence and without further notice to you</csc></bold>.<eos/></form.text><eop/></form.para><form.para><bop/><form.text><bos/>If you wish to defend this proceeding but are unable to pay legal fees, legal aid may be available to you by contacting a Legal Aid Office.<eos/></form.text><eop/></form.para><form.signature.block><bop/><tbl ID="Idd38a2b0898a11ea95a1b70c6ff9646c"><table><bos/><tgroup cols="3" align="left"><colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="13*"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="6*"/><colspec colnum="3" colname="3" colwidth="14*"/><tbody><row><entry colname="1">Date <leaveout><fill.in><textrule weight="0.5pt" position="baseline" length="  11em "/></fill.in></leaveout></entry><entry colname="2" namest="2" nameend="3">Issued by: <leaveout><fill.in><textrule weight="0.5pt" position="baseline" length="  11em "/></fill.in></leaveout></entry></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2"/><entry colname="3">Local registrar</entry></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2">Address of</entry><entry colname="3"/></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2">court office:</entry><entry colname="3">Ontario Court (General Division)</entry></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2"/><entry colname="3">361 University Avenue</entry></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2"/><entry colname="3">Toronto, Ontario</entry></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2"/><entry colname="3">M5G 1T3</entry></row></tbody></tgroup><eos/></table></tbl><eop/></form.signature.block><tbl ID="Idd3f8080898a11ea95a1b70c6ff9646c"><bop/><table><bos/><tgroup cols="2" align="left"><colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="3*"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="33*"/><tbody><row><entry colname="1">TO:</entry><entry colname="2"><csc>Elmars Copper Inc.</csc></entry></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2">c/o <csc>James McDermott</csc></entry></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2">Barrister &amp; Solicitor</entry></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2">55 Kensington Street</entry></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2">Toronto, Ontario</entry></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2">M4M 3X2</entry></row><row><entry colname="1"> </entry><entry colname="2"/></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2">James McDermott</entry></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2">Tel: 593-8600</entry></row><row><entry colname="1"> </entry><entry colname="2"/></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2">Solicitor for the Defendant</entry></row></tbody></tgroup><eos/></table><eop/></tbl><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/><bold>CLAIM</bold><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.unit ID="Id9fefd508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Id9fefd518e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>1.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The plaintiffs claim is for:<eos/></form.text></form.para><form.unit ID="Id9fefd528e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.unit ID="Id9fefd538e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(a)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>An interim, interlocutory and permanent injunction restraining the defendant from directly or indirectly disclosing confidential information belonging to the plaintiffs;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fefd548e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(b)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>A declaration that the defendant holds the property in trust for the plaintiffs as a result of the breach of fiduciary duty and misuse of confidential information on the part of the defendant;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fefd558e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(c)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Damages for breaches of fiduciary duty and damages for misuse of confidential information in the amount of $1,000,000;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fefd568e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(d)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Punitive damages for the deliberate breach of trust and fiduciary duty;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fefd578e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(e)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Pre-judgment interest in accordance with the <ital>Courts of Justice Act</ital>;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fefd588e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(f)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Delivery up by the defendant of all materials and documents in the possession of the defendant which contain any of the confidential information used to acquire the property in question;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fefd598e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(g)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Goods and Services Tax;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fefd5a8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(h)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Costs; and<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fefd5b8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(i)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Such further and other relief as to this Honourable Court may seem just.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit></form.unit></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fefd5c8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>2.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The plaintiffs operate a business under the name Down South.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fefd5d8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>3.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The defendant is a mining company incorporated pursuant to the laws of Canada.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fefd5e8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>4.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Prior to January, 1996, the plaintiffs had developed confidential information regarding the commercial exploitation of a new mine in Labrador. <eos/><bos/>This information constitutes confidential information. <eos/><bos/>Confidentiality was maintained through the use of confidentiality agreements with those employees of the plaintiffs who had access to the information, and through a decision to withhold this information from all third parties.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fefd5f8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>5.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>In January, 1996, the plaintiffs were introduced to the defendant. <eos/><bos/>The purpose of the meeting was to determine whether the defendant wished to pursue the joint acquisition with the plaintiffs. <eos/><bos/>The defendant had not as yet pursued any interest in the Labrador mine.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fefd608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>6.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>At the January meeting, the defendant expressed a keen interest in the Labrador mine and signed a Confidentiality Agreement dated February 1, 1996, with the plaintiffs.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fefd618e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>7.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Confidentiality Agreement provides as follows:<eos/></form.text></form.para><display.quote><para><bos/><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>In order to allow you to evaluate the possible joint venture to acquire the Labrador mine we will deliver to you, upon your execution of this agreement, certain information about the Labrador mine. <eos/><bos/>All information about the mine which is imparted by us either before or after the date of this Agreement, and regardless of the manner in which it is furnished, is considered “Confidential Information”.<eos/><bos/> Confidential Information does not include, however, information which is or becomes generally available to the public other than as a result of a disclosure by you.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0001"/></paratext></para><para><bos/><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>You agree not to use the Confidential Information for any purpose other than in connection with the consummation of the proposed acquisition in a manner which we have approved.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0002"/></paratext></para><para><bos/><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0003"/>If you determine that you do not wish to proceed with the proposed acquisition, you will promptly deliver to us all of the Confidential Information, including all copies, reproductions, summaries or extracts thereof in your possession or in the possession of any of your representatives.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0003"/></paratext></para></display.quote></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fefd628e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>8.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The only purpose for providing confidential information to the defendant was to permit it to determine whether it wished to enter into a joint venture with the plaintiffs.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9fefd638e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>9.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>After signing the Confidentiality Agreement, the defendant was provided with numerous drawings, mining reports, financial information and technical data. <eos/><bos/><instruction><ital>[Details of the nature of the confidential information should be inserted.]</ital></instruction><eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9ff24608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>10.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>All of the material provided was confidential, and none of the information provided was previously known to the defendant.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9ff24618e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>11.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The confidential information regarding the Labrador mine demonstrated to the defendant the viability of the project.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9ff24628e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>12.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The defendant expressed to the plaintiffs its satisfaction with the information provided and its interest in pursuing a joint venture based on the confidential information provided by the plaintiffs.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9ff24638e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>13.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>As a result, a number of further meetings took place between the plaintiffs and the defendant to discuss the details of the acquisition of the Labrador mine. <eos/><bos/>At these meetings, the geological potential for the Labrador mine was discussed in detail. <eos/><bos/>Marketing plans were reviewed, and the mining facility was visited.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9ff24648e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>14.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>After signing the Confidentiality Agreement, and during the course of the follow-up meetings, the plaintiffs reposed trust and confidence in the defendant because the defendant had assured the plaintiffs that it would work with the plaintiffs towards the joint acquisition of the Labrador mine.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9ff24658e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>15.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>By agreement dated April 1, 1996, the plaintiffs and the defendant agreed to jointly acquire the Labrador mine.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9ff24668e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>16.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>By May 31, 1996, the plaintiffs had given the defendant absolute discretion and had placed itself in a position of vulnerability with regard to the acquisition of the Labrador mine. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs did so in the belief that their confidential information would only be used by the defendant to pursue the joint venture.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9ff24678e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>17.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Therefore, the plaintiffs regularly offered their help in completing the due diligence. <eos/><bos/>The defendant declined the plaintiffs&apos; offer of assistance but continually assured the plaintiffs that the due diligence had been completed and the sale would be finalized shortly thereafter.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9ff24688e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>18.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>With such assurances and in view of the joint venture, the plaintiffs did not interfere with the efforts of the defendant.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9ff24698e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>19.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>By letter dated July 22, 1996, without any warning, the defendant wrote to the plaintiffs advising that the defendant was terminating the Joint Venture Agreement on the grounds that the Labrador mine would not accept the offer presented by the plaintiffs. <eos/><bos/>Thereafter the defendant, without the knowledge or consent of the plaintiffs, proceeded to acquire the Labrador mine on its own behalf.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9ff246a8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>20.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The plaintiffs plead that the fiduciary obligations owed by the defendant to the plaintiffs did not end with the termination of the Joint Venture Agreement and did not, in any event, permit the defendant to proceed to seek to acquire the Labrador mine for itself to the exclusion of the plaintiffs.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9ff246b8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>21.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Furthermore, the defendant continued to be obligated to the plaintiffs for the confidential information it had acquired from the plaintiffs. <eos/><bos/>Pursuant to the Confidentiality Agreement, all confidential information was required to be returned to the plaintiffs, which the defendant failed to do.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9ff246c8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>22.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The plaintiffs plead that the defendant wrongfully used the confidential information imparted by them as a springboard to further its progress towards the acquisition of the Labrador mine on its own behalf to the exclusion of the plaintiffs.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9ff246d8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>23.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>On July 31, 1996, the defendant purchased the Labrador mine on its own behalf for a purchase price of $25,000,000.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9ff246e8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>24.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The plaintiffs wrote to the defendant by letter dated August 12, 1996, demanding their share of the defendant&apos;s interest in the Labrador mine. <eos/><bos/>The defendant has refused to recognize any such interest.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9ff246f8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>25.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>As a result, the plaintiffs claim ownership of the Labrador mine.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9ff24708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>26.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The defendant deliberately breached its trust and fiduciary duty to the plaintiffs.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Id9ff24718e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>27.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>As a result of the deliberate breaches outlined above, the plaintiffs plead that they are entitled to punitive damages in the amount of $500,000.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit><form.para><bop/><form.text><bos/>The plaintiffs propose that this action be tried in the City of <leaveout><fill.in><textrule weight="0.5pt" position="baseline" length=" 5em "/></fill.in></leaveout><eos/></form.text><eop/></form.para><form.signature.block><bop/><tbl ID="Idd568af0898a11ea95a1b70c6ff9646c"><table><bos/><tgroup cols="2" align="left"><colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="22*"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="14*"/><tbody><row><entry colname="1"><bold><csc>Date of Issue</csc></bold>: <leaveout><fill.in><textrule weight="0.5pt" position="baseline" length="  11em "/></fill.in></leaveout></entry><entry colname="2"/></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2"><bold><csc>John Q. Smith</csc></bold></entry></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2">Barrister &amp; Solicitor</entry></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2">10 Jacob Street West</entry></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2">Suite 102</entry></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2">Toronto, Ontario</entry></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2">M5R 1Z1</entry></row><row><entry colname="1"> </entry><entry colname="2"/></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2"><bold>John Q. Smith</bold></entry></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2"><bold>Tel: 869-1234</bold></entry></row><row><entry colname="1"> </entry><entry colname="2"/></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2"><bold>Solicitor for the Plaintiffs</bold></entry></row></tbody></tgroup><eos/></table></tbl><eop/></form.signature.block></form.body></form><head style="l" parent="appendix.body"><bop/><bos/><label.name><bold>§ </bold></label.name><label.designator><bold>A:7.</bold></label.designator><headtext><bold>Sample Statements of Defence</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><form ID="I5cc6e5d0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><form.body><form.caption><form.line style="r"><bop/><bos/>Court File No. 97-CQ-XXXXX<eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/><bold><csc>Superior Court of Justice</csc></bold><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/>BETWEEN:<eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/><bold><csc>Tolley Protection Services Limited</csc></bold><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="r"><bop/><bos/>Plaintiff<eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/>—and—<eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/><bold><csc>Durand Security Services Ltd.</csc></bold>,<eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/><bold><csc>David Durand</csc></bold>,<eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/><bold><csc>Kate Kendry</csc>, and</bold><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/><bold><csc>Michael Cohen</csc></bold><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="r"><bop/><bos/>Defendants<eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/><bold><csc>Statement of Defence and Counterclaim</csc></bold><eos/><eop/></form.line></form.caption><form.unit ID="Ida0120308e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Ida0120318e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>1.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Defendants admit the allegations contained in paragraphs 2, 3, 4, 7, 8, 9, 20, 21 and 25 of the Statement of Claim.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0120328e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>2.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Defendants deny the allegations contained in paragraphs 1, 5, 6, 10 to 19, 22, 24, 26 to 40 of the Statement of Claim.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0120338e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>3.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Defendants have no knowledge of the allegations contained in paragraph 23 of the Statement of Claim.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0120348e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>4.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>On or about the 12th day of September, 1996, the Defendant, David Durand (hereinafter referred to as “Durand”) entered into an Agreement of Purchase and Sale (hereinafter referred to as “the Agreement”) together with Terry Leonard, Rob Oborn, Doug Larson, and Bob Rice as Vendors, 2820 Ontario Inc. as Purchaser, and 2051 Ontario Limited as a third party.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0120358e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>5.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Defendants state and the fact is that Kate Kendry (hereinafter referred to as “Kendry”) and Michael Cohen (hereinafter referred to as “Cohen”) were not parties to the Agreement and were not bound by the provisions thereof.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0120368e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>6.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Defendants state that 2051 Ontario Limited was a holding company whose sole purpose was to hold shares. <eos/><bos/>At no time did 2051 Ontario Limited actively carry on business.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0120378e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>7.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The transaction contemplated by the Agreement closed on or about the 1st day of October, 1996, and was at all times a sale of shares in Tolley Protection Services Limited (hereinafter referred to as “Tolley”).<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0120388e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>8.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The name “Durand” was not part of the transaction, was not referred to in the Agreement, and was not assigned on closing. <eos/><bos/>Prior to the closing of the transaction on October 1, 1996, Tolley was controlled by Durand together with Leonard, Oborn, Larson and Rice.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0120398e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>9.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>At no time did Kendry or Cohen have a controlling interest in Tolley.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida01203a8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>10.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Defendant Durand admits that he entered into an Employment Agreement and Non-Competition Agreement both dated the 1st day of October, 1996, as did Leonard, Oborn, Larson and Rice.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida01203b8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>11.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Defendant Kendry entered into an Employment Agreement with the Plaintiff Tolley on the 1st day of October, 1996, which provided as follows:<eos/></form.text></form.para><form.unit ID="Ida01203c8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.unit ID="Ida01203d8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(a)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>employment as senior manager of Tolley;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida01203e8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(b)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>six months&apos; notice in writing or payment in lieu thereof in the event that Tolley should terminate her employment without cause;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida01203f8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(c)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>that at all times hereafter Kendry will hold all information which has been or may be furnished to her in the course of her employment with Tolley confidential.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit></form.unit></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0120408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>12.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Defendant Kendry did not enter into a Non-Competition Agreement.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0120418e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>13.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Defendant Cohen was not required to enter into and did not enter into an Employment Agreement or a Non-Competition and Confidentiality Agreement.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0120428e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>14.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>On or about the 14th day of November, 1996, Kendry was summarily dismissed without cause.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0120438e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>15.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Defendant Kendry was paid six months&apos; severance pay in accordance with the term of her Employment Agreement.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0120448e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>16.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>On or about the 16th day of November, 1996, the Defendant Cohen gave notice that he could no longer continue with the Plaintiff after the summary dismissal of Kendry.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0120458e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>17.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Defendant Cohen&apos;s final day of work was November 24, 1996.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0120468e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>18.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Defendant Cohen did not receive and was not given severance pay.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0120478e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>19.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Defendant Kendry is 43 years of age and was employed by Tolley since she graduated from university in 1987. <eos/><bos/>Her only experience and background is in the security guard business.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0120488e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>20.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Defendant Cohen is 46 years of age and was employed by Tolley since his graduation from graduate school in 1978. <eos/><bos/>His only experience and background is in the security guard business.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0120498e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>21.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Defendants Kendry and Cohen incorporated Durand Security Services Ltd. on the 19th day of November, 1996. <eos/><bos/>The business of Durand Security Services Ltd. is restricted to the security guard business.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0147408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>22.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Plaintiff is a large corporation which employs more than 1,500 employees and has offices in Toronto, Mississauga, Oakville, Calgary, Vancouver and Peterborough.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0147418e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>23.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Defendant Durand specifically denies that he is the controlling mind or agent of Durand Security Services Ltd.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0147428e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>24.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Defendant Durand is retired from the security guard business and has had no involvement with the business carried on by Durand Security Services Ltd.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0147438e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>25.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Defendant Durand specifically denies that he has solicited customers from the Plaintiff.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0147448e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>26.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>At all times the Defendant Durand has complied with the terms of his Non-Competition and Confidentiality agreement.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0147458e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>27.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Defendants put the Plaintiff to the burden of proof that Durand has solicited Tolley&apos;s clients.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0147468e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>28.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Defendants Kendry and Cohen admit that they have sent letters of introduction to the businesses listed in paragraph 28 of the Statement of Claim, but state that this was part of their overall general competition in the marketplace.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0147478e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>29.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Defendants Kendry and Cohen admit that Rocket Express and Haddow Realty are current clients of Durand Security Services Ltd. but that Rocket Express and Haddow Realty terminated their relationships with Tolley and took bids from other companies before retaining Durand Security Services Ltd.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0147488e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>30.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Defendants Kendry and Cohen specifically deny that Tolley has any proprietary right to the customers referred to in paragraph 28 and specifically deny usurping corporate contracts.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0147498e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>31.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Defendants Kendry and Cohen deny that they have any fiduciary obligations to the Plaintiff or, in the alternative, that they are in breach of any such obligations.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida01474a8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>32.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Defendants deny that they have solicited employees of Tolley or that they have induced employees to resign and put the Plaintiff to the burden of proof thereof.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida01474b8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>33.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Defendants deny the Plaintiff&apos;s allegations that the Defendants have misappropriated, improperly used or disclosed confidential information and put the Plaintiff to the burden of proof thereof. <eos/><bos/>The Defendants put the Plaintiff to the burden of proof to establish that pay rates, price structures, wage rates, bill rates and client needs/requirements are confidential or that the Defendants have used such alleged confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The Defendants state that pay rates, price structures, wage rates, bill rates and client needs/requirements are within the general knowledge of any person involved in the business of providing security guards.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida01474c8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>34.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Defendants Kendry and Cohen are attempting to earn their livelihood in the marketplace. <eos/><bos/>The Defendants Kendry and Cohen state that they are using general knowledge, skills and experience which they have developed through their years of experience in the security guard business. <eos/><bos/>The Defendants Kendry and Cohen state that they are entitled to compete with the Plaintiff.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida01474d8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>35.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Defendants deny that the Plaintiff has suffered damages and put the Plaintiff to the strict burden of proof thereof. <eos/><bos/>The Defendants further deny that the Plaintiff has suffered irreparable harm and put the Plaintiff to the strict burden of proof thereof. <eos/><bos/>In the event that the Plaintiff has suffered any damages as a result of the actions of the Defendants, which is specifically denied, the Defendants state that the proper remedy is damages, if any, and not an injunction.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida01474e8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>36.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Defendants submit that the Plaintiff&apos;s claim be dismissed with costs on a solicitor and client basis.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit><form.signature.block><bop/><tbl ID="I5a8bc2e0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><table><bos/><tgroup cols="3" align="left"><colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="4*"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="14*"/><colspec colnum="3" colname="3" colwidth="18*"/><tbody><row><entry colname="1" namest="1" nameend="2">DATE: <leaveout><fill.in><textrule weight="0.5pt" position="baseline" length=" 5em "/></fill.in></leaveout></entry><entry colname="3"><bold><csc>Counsel for the Defendants</csc></bold></entry></row><row><entry colname="1"> </entry><entry colname="2"/><entry colname="3"/></row><row><entry colname="1">To:</entry><entry colname="2"><bold><csc>Counsel for the Plaintiff</csc></bold></entry><entry colname="3"/></row><row><entry colname="1"> </entry><entry colname="2"/><entry colname="3"/></row><row><entry colname="1" namest="1" nameend="3"><leaveout><fill.in><textrule weight="0.5pt" position="baseline" length="  11em "/></fill.in></leaveout></entry></row></tbody></tgroup><eos/></table></tbl><eop/></form.signature.block><form.line style="r"><bop/><bos/>Court File No. 96-32504<eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/><bold><csc>Superior Court of Justice</csc></bold><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="l"><bop/><bos/><bold>BETWEEN:</bold><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/><bold><csc>John Doe</csc>, <csc>Mary Pryor</csc> and <csc>Samuel Smith</csc></bold><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="r"><bop/><bos/>Plaintiffs<eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/>—<bold>and</bold>—<eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/><bold><csc>Elmars Copper Inc.</csc></bold><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="r"><bop/><bos/>Defendant<eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/><bold><csc>Statement of Defence</csc></bold><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.unit ID="Ida01474f8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Ida0147508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>1.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The defendant, Elmars Copper Inc., admits paragraphs <instruction><ital>[insert]</ital></instruction> of the Statement of Claim.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida016e508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>2.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The defendant denies paragraphs <instruction><ital>[insert]</ital></instruction> of the Statement of Claim and puts the plaintiffs to the strict proof thereof.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida016e518e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>3.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The defendant has no knowledge of paragraphs <instruction><ital>[insert]</ital></instruction> of the Statement of Claim.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit><form.line style="l"><bop/><bos/><underscore>Background</underscore><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.unit ID="Ida016e528e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Ida016e538e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>4.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>On January 20, 1996, the plaintiffs indicated to the defendant that they wished to enter into a contract with the defendant in respect of the purchase of a mine in Labrador.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida016e548e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>5.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The plaintiffs represented to the defendant that they had the exclusive right to negotiate the acquisition of the Labrador mine. <eos/><bos/>This representation was the sole reason the defendant expressed an interest in pursuing discussions with the plaintiffs and the possibility of entering into a potential contractual relationship with them.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida016e558e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>6.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The defendant was led by the plaintiffs to believe that the plaintiffs had the exclusive right to negotiate a financially beneficial purchase of the Labrador mine quickly and easily.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit><form.line style="l"><bop/><bos/><underscore>The Terms of the Confidentiality Agreement</underscore><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.unit ID="Ida016e568e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Ida016e578e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>7.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The defendant agreed to execute a Confidentiality Agreement on or about January 31, 1996. <eos/><bos/>The Confidentiality Agreement provided that the defendant would agree to keep confidential certain “Confidential Information” relating to the Labrador mine. <eos/><bos/>However, the Agreement did not cover “information which is or becomes generally available to the public other than as a disclosure by <instruction><ital>[the defendant]</ital></instruction>”.<eos/><bos/> The Confidentiality Agreement also provided that, “upon our request, you will promptly deliver to us all of the Confidential Information”.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida016e588e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>8.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>But for the fact that the plaintiffs specifically represented that they owned confidential information pertaining to the Labrador mine, the defendant would not have entered into the Confidentiality Agreement.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit><form.line style="l"><bop/><bos/><underscore>The Information Provided by the Plaintiffs</underscore><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.unit ID="Ida016e598e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Ida016e5a8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>9.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The material provided consisted largely of promotional information that was intended to create an interest in the Labrador mine. <eos/><bos/>The information, however, was of little or no value in determining whether the mine was economically feasible. <eos/><bos/>Furthermore, some of the information provided by the plaintiffs to the defendant had previously been widely circulated to others in the industry by the plaintiffs.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida016e5b8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>10.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Despite the fact that the plaintiffs did not in fact possess any confidential information which was of use to the defendant, the defendant became interested in pursuing the acquisition of the Labrador mine because of the plaintiffs&apos; representation that they had an exclusive right to negotiate the acquisition of the mine.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida016e5c8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>11.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Accordingly, the defendant sent its own experts to do an assessment of the site.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit><form.line style="l"><bop/><bos/><underscore>The Joint Venture Agreement</underscore><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.unit ID="Ida016e5d8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Ida016e5e8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>12.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>As a result of the site investigations and research conducted by the defendant, a Joint Venture Agreement was executed, setting out the terms by which the parties would combine their efforts to attempt to purchase the Labrador mine.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit><form.line style="l"><bop/><bos/><underscore>Efforts to Acquire the Labrador Mine Pursuant to the Terms of the Joint Venture Agreement</underscore><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.unit ID="Ida016e5f8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Ida016e608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>13.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The defendant subsequently determined that the plaintiffs had no exclusive right to negotiate a sale and, as such, the letter Agreement was terminated.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit><form.line style="l"><bop/><bos/><underscore>Termination of the Joint Venture Agreement</underscore><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.unit ID="Ida016e618e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Ida016e628e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>14.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>By letter dated July 22, 1996, the defendant advised the plaintiffs that it was terminating the Joint Venture Agreement. <eos/><bos/>As a gesture of goodwill, the defendant issued a cheque to the plaintiffs to compensate them for any efforts made on the defendant&apos;s behalf.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida016e638e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>15.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The plaintiffs accepted the cheque and did not respond to the Termination Letter. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs did not indicate that they wished to continue to be involved either alone or with the defendant in the acquisition of the Labrador mine or that the defendant ought to be precluded from submitting a bid on its own.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida016e648e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>16.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>By their silence and their conduct, the plaintiffs accepted the termination of the contractual relationship with the defendant.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit><form.line style="l"><bop/><bos/><underscore>No Confidential Information Given to the Defendant by the Plaintiffs</underscore><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.unit ID="Ida016e658e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Ida016e668e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>17.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The defendant denies that it ever received confidential or proprietary information from the plaintiffs. <eos/><bos/>Most of the information provided by the plaintiffs to the defendant was already known to others in the industry or became publicly available without the assistance of the plaintiffs.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida016e678e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>18.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>In any event, at the time the Termination Letter was delivered by the defendant to the plaintiffs, the defendant offered to return all material that the plaintiffs had provided to the defendant after the execution of the Confidentiality Agreement. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs expressed no interest in the return of that information.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit><form.line style="l"><bop/><bos/><underscore>The Defendant&apos;s Acquisition of the Labrador Mine</underscore><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.unit ID="Ida0195608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Ida0195618e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>19.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>On July 20, 1996, the defendant submitted a bid to acquire the Labrador mine at a public auction. <eos/><bos/>On July 31, 1996, the defendant was informed that its bid had been accepted.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0195628e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>20.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>By letter dated October 15, 1996, the plaintiffs first informed the defendant that they claimed an interest in the Labrador mine. <eos/><bos/>This letter was the first communication of any type from the plaintiffs to the defendant since the Termination Letter of July 22, 1996. <eos/><bos/>As such, the plaintiffs should be estopped from now asserting this or any claim pursuant to the Joint Venture Agreement.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit><form.line style="l"><bop/><bos/><underscore>No Fiduciary Relationship</underscore><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.unit ID="Ida0195638e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Ida0195648e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>21.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The defendant states that the relationship between itself and the plaintiffs was at all times contractual only and never amounted to a fiduciary relationship between the parties. <eos/><bos/>The defendant fulfilled its contractual obligations pursuant to the Joint Venture Agreement and at all times acted in good faith. <eos/><bos/>The contractual relationship was properly terminated by virtue of the Termination Letter, and no further legal or equitable rights existed thereafter between the parties.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit><form.line style="l"><bop/><bos/><underscore>Breach of Confidence</underscore><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.unit ID="Ida0195658e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Ida0195668e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>22.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>In formulating its bid, the defendant did not use any of the information provided to it by the plaintiffs. <eos/><bos/>In submitting its bid pursuant to the auction process, the defendant used only information that it had independently researched and acquired. <eos/><bos/>As such, the defendant did not get a “head start” over other bidders in the auction process.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit><form.line style="l"><bop/><bos/><underscore>Estoppel</underscore><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.unit ID="Ida0195678e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Ida0195688e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>23.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The plaintiffs are now estopped from pursuing their claim because they accepted the termination of the Joint Venture Agreement and the right of the defendant to pursue the acquisition on its own behalf.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit><form.line style="l"><bop/><bos/><underscore>No Damages</underscore><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.unit ID="Ida0195698e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Ida01956a8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>24.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The defendant denies that the plaintiffs have suffered any loss or damage.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida01956b8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>25.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The defendant states that there is no legal basis for a claim for punitive, exemplary or aggravated damages.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida01956c8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>26.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The defendant asks that this action be dismissed with costs assessed as between solicitor and client.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit><form.signature.block><bop/><tbl ID="Idd8c8f10898a11ea95a1b70c6ff9646c"><table><bos/><tgroup cols="2" align="left"><colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="22*"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="14*"/><tbody><row><entry colname="1"><bold><csc>Date of Issue</csc>:</bold> <leaveout><fill.in><textrule weight="0.5pt" position="baseline" length="  11em "/></fill.in></leaveout></entry><entry colname="2"/></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2"><bold><csc>James McDermott</csc></bold></entry></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2">Barrister &amp; Solicitor</entry></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2">55 Kensington Street</entry></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2">Toronto, Ontario</entry></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2">M4M 3X2</entry></row><row><entry colname="1"> </entry><entry colname="2"/></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2"><bold>James McDermott</bold></entry></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2"><bold>Tel: 593-8600</bold></entry></row><row><entry colname="1"> </entry><entry colname="2"/></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2"><bold>Solicitor for the Defendant</bold></entry></row></tbody></tgroup><eos/></table></tbl><eop/></form.signature.block><tbl ID="Idd90d4d0898a11ea95a1b70c6ff9646c"><bop/><table><bos/><tgroup cols="2" align="left"><colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="2*"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="34*"/><tbody><row><entry colname="1"><bold>TO</bold>:</entry><entry colname="2"><bold><csc>John Q. Smith</csc></bold></entry></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2">Barrister &amp; Solicitor</entry></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2">10 Jacob Street West</entry></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2">Suite 102</entry></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2">Toronto, Ontario</entry></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2">M5R 1Z1</entry></row><row><entry colname="1"> </entry><entry colname="2"/></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2">John Q. Smith</entry></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2">Tel: 869-1234</entry></row><row><entry colname="1"> </entry><entry colname="2"/></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2"><bold>Solicitor for the Plaintiffs</bold></entry></row></tbody></tgroup><eos/></table><eop/></tbl></form.body></form><head style="l" parent="appendix.body"><bop/><bos/><label.name><bold>§ </bold></label.name><label.designator><bold>A:8.</bold></label.designator><headtext><bold>Sample Notice of Motion</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><form ID="I5cc733f0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><form.body><form.caption><form.line style="r"><bop/><bos/>Court File No. 97-CQ-XXXXX<eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/><bold><csc>Superior Court of Justice</csc></bold><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/>BETWEEN:<eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/><bold>ABC <csc>Products Limited</csc></bold><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="r"><bop/><bos/>Plaintiff<eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/>—and—<eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/><bold><csc>John Green</csc>, <csc>Jane White</csc>, <csc>Richard Brown</csc>, and XYZ <csc>enterprises Limited</csc></bold><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="r"><bop/><bos/>Defendants<eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/><bold><csc>Notice of Motion</csc></bold><eos/><eop/></form.line></form.caption><form.para><bop/><form.text><bos/><bold><csc>The Plaintiff</csc></bold> wilt make a motion to a Judge on Thursday the 4th day of September, 1997 at 10:00 a.m. or as soon after that time as the motion can be heard, at Osgoode Hall, 130 Queen Street West, Toronto, Ontario.<eos/></form.text><eop/></form.para><form.para><bop/><form.text><bos/><bold><csc>The motion is for an order for</csc>:</bold><eos/></form.text><eop/></form.para><form.unit ID="Ida02f4f08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Ida02f4f18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>1.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>An interim and interlocutory injunction restraining the Defendants, anyone employed by them, their agents, representatives, or anyone acting on their behalf from:<eos/></form.text></form.para><form.unit ID="Ida02f4f28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.unit ID="Ida02f4f38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(i)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>inducing any of the Plaintiff&apos;s customers or employees to breach their contracts with the Plaintiff;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida02f4f48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(ii)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>communicating with the Plaintiff&apos;s customers or employees in an attempt in any way to disrupt the Plaintiff&apos;s business and operations or to entice any of the Plaintiff&apos;s customers or employees to discontinue dealing with the Plaintiff;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida02f4f58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(iii)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>soliciting the Plaintiff&apos;s existing or potential customers; and<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida02f4f68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(iv)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>soliciting the business of the companies listed in Schedule “A” attached hereto, which are certain of the Plaintiff&apos;s existing and potential customers;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit></form.unit></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida02f4f78e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>2.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>An interim and interlocutory injuction restraining the Defendant, John Green (“Green”), from doing any act which breaches the fiduciary duties or the duty of confidence that he owes to the Plaintiff as a result of his former employment status with the Plaintiff;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida02f4f88e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>3.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>An order requiring the Defendants, their employees, agents or persons acting on their behalf, to deliver up to the Plaintiff all information, documents, materials or things of any description in their possession or control, which are the property of the Plaintiff, or which contain confidential information or trade secrets relating to the Plaintiff&apos;s business or the business of the Plaintiff&apos;s customers;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida031c008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>4.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>An order requiring the Defendants to preserve all documents or evidence relating to the matters at issue herein;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida031c018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>5.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The costs of this motion on a solicitor and client basis; and<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida031c028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>6.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Such further and other relief as this Honourable Court deems to be just.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit><form.para><bop/><form.text><bos/><bold><csc>The grounds for the motion are</csc>:</bold><eos/></form.text><eop/></form.para><form.unit ID="Ida031c038e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Ida031c048e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>1.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Plaintiff is in the business of manufacturing and selling numerous types of polyethylene products.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida031c058e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>2.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Green was employed by the Plaintiff as a salesperson, from April 1983 to August 25, 1997, to sell the Plaintiff&apos;s polyethylene products.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida031c068e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>3.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Green had complete access to the Plaintiff&apos;s confidential information, including confidential customer lists, purchase orders, invoices, customer histories, confidential credit reports, independent market research, information regarding the Plaintiff&apos;s products and suppliers, costing sheets and price lists.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida031c078e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>4.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Green, during the course of his employment with the Plaintiff:<eos/></form.text></form.para><form.unit ID="Ida031c088e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.unit ID="Ida031c098e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(i)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>was competing directly with the Plaintiff by attempting to sell polyethylene products to the Plaintiff&apos;s existing and potential customers, including existing customers for which Green was responsible during his tenure with the Plaintiff;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida031c0a8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(ii)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>sold, on his own account, polyethylene products to at least two of the Plaintiff&apos;s customers;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida031c0b8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(iii)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>was negotiating with the Plaintiff&apos;s competitors and suppliers in order to purchase polyethylene products for resale to the Plaintiff&apos;s existing and potential customers; and<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida031c0c8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(iv)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>delivered a list of the Plaintiff&apos;s existing and potential customers to a third party.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit></form.unit></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida031c0d8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>5.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Green breached his obligation of fidelity and good faith, the terms of his employment contract, his duty of confidence, and the fiduciary duties that he owes to the Plaintiff, by rendering services to the Plaintiff&apos;s customers while still in the employ of the Plaintiff.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida031c0e8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>6.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Defendants are acting in unison to market themselves to present and potential customers of the Plaintiff based on the experience and reputation of the Plaintiff.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida031c0f8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>7.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>In the circumstances, the Plaintiff has a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida031c108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>8.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>No prejudice will result to the Defendants which cannot be compensated for in costs.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida031c118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>9.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Rules 40 and 45 of the <ital>Rules of Civil Procedure</ital>.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida031c128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>10.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Section 101 of the <ital>Courts of Justice Act</ital>.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida031c138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>11.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Such further and other grounds as counsel may advise.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit><form.para><bop/><form.text><bos/><bold><csc>The following documentary evidence will be used at the hearing of the motion</csc>:</bold><eos/></form.text><eop/></form.para><form.unit ID="Ida031c148e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Ida031c158e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(a)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>the Affidavit of Randolph Tingey sworn on August 27, 1997 and the Exhibits thereto; and<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida031c168e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(b)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>such further and other materials as counsel may advise and this Honourable Court permit.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit><form.line style="l"><bop/><bos/>Date: August 27, 1997<eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/><bold><csc>Solicitors for the Plaintiff</csc></bold><eos/><eop/></form.line><tbl ID="I5aa5b380411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><table><bos/><tgroup cols="2" align="left"><colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="6*"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="30*"/><tbody><row><entry colname="1"><bold>TO</bold>:</entry><entry colname="2"><bold><csc>John Green</csc></bold></entry></row><row><entry colname="1"> </entry><entry colname="2"/></row><row><entry colname="1"><bold>AND TO</bold>:</entry><entry colname="2"><bold><csc>Jane White</csc></bold></entry></row><row><entry colname="1"> </entry><entry colname="2"/></row><row><entry colname="1"><bold>AND TO</bold>:</entry><entry colname="2"><bold><csc>Richard Brown</csc></bold></entry></row><row><entry colname="1"> </entry><entry colname="2"/></row><row><entry colname="1"><bold>AND TO</bold>:</entry><entry colname="2"><bold>XYZ <csc>Distributors Inc.</csc></bold></entry></row><row><entry colname="1"> </entry><entry colname="2"/></row><row><entry colname="1"><bold>AND TO</bold>:</entry><entry colname="2"><bold>XYZ <csc>enterprises Ltd.</csc></bold></entry></row></tbody></tgroup><eos/></table><eop/></tbl></form.body></form><head style="l" parent="appendix.body"><bop/><bos/><label.name><bold>§ </bold></label.name><label.designator><bold>A:9.</bold></label.designator><headtext><bold>Sample Affidavit</bold></headtext><eos/><eop/></head><form ID="I5cc7a920411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><form.body><form.caption><form.line style="r"><bop/><bos/>Court File No. 97-CQ-XXXXX<eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/><bold><csc>Superior Court of Justice</csc></bold><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/>BETWEEN:<eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/><bold>ABC <csc>Products Limited</csc></bold><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="r"><bop/><bos/>Plaintiff<eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/>—and—<eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/><bold><csc>John Green</csc>, <csc>Jane White</csc>, <csc>Richard Brown</csc>, and XYZ <csc>Enterprises Limited</csc></bold><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="r"><bop/><bos/>Defendants<eos/><eop/></form.line><form.line style="c"><bop/><bos/><bold><csc>Affidavit of Randolph Tingey</csc></bold><eos/><eop/></form.line></form.caption><form.para><bop/><form.text><bos/>I, Randolph Tingey, of the City of Toronto, in the Municipality of Metropolitan Toronto, MAKE OATH AND SAY:<eos/></form.text><eop/></form.para><form.unit ID="Ida04f0c08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Ida04f0c18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>1.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>I am the Vice-President of the plaintiff, and thus have, unless otherwise stated, personal knowledge of the matters herein deposed to.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit><form.line style="l"><bop/><bos/><underscore><bold>The Business and Products of ABC Products Limited</bold></underscore><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.unit ID="Ida04f0c28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Ida04f0c38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>2.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The plaintiff, ABC Products Limited (“ABC”), is and has been since 1963, in the business of manufacturing and selling numerous types of polyethylene products, including polyethylene sheeting (“Poly Sheeting”), polyethylene tubing (“Poly Tubing”), polyethylene bags (“Poly Bags”), and polyethylene stretch film (“Stretch Film”).<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida04f0c48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>3.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Poly Sheeting has numerous different applications, but is primarily used as a protective covering in the construction industry. <eos/><bos/>Certain types of Poly. <eos/><bos/>Sheeting have more specialized uses. <eos/><bos/>For example, ABC designs, manufactures and distributes treated Poly Sheeting which is used in greenhouses (“Greenhouse Poly”).<eos/><bos/> Greenhouse Poly is designed to protect plants and produce from the harmful effects of sunlight.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida04f0c58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>4.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Stretch Film is a durable and versatile polyethylene wrap designed to hold, stabilize and protect products during shipping and handling. <eos/><bos/>Attached to my affidavit as Exhibit “A” is a copy of ABC&apos;s Stretch Film brochure which demonstrates Stretch Film in use and outlines its unique product features.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida04f0c68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>5.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>At present, ABC is negotiating with Matthews Chemical, one of the largest manufacturers of Stretch Film in Canada and the United States, for a large supply of Stretch Film. <eos/><bos/>ABC has the opportunity to sell Stretch Film to existing high volume purchasers of ABC&apos;s other polyethylene products and to new customers. <eos/><bos/>Our customers are currently purchasing significant quantities of Stretch Film from other sources and it is our hope to sell Stretch Film to these customers.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida04f0c78e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>6.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The polyethylene industry in general, and Stretch Film in particular, is highly competitive in nature and extremely price sensitive. <eos/><bos/>The prices for raw materials in the industry fluctuate dramatically within short periods of time. <eos/><bos/>In order to remain competitive, it is critical for ABC to keep information regarding its customers, product components, costing and pricing strictly confidential. <eos/><bos/>ABC&apos;s internal confidential documents, including customer lists, customer histories, credit reports, independent market research information, purchase orders, invoices, costing sheets, price lists, business practice data and other materials (“ABC&apos;s Confidential Information”) are key to its ongoing marketing success.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida04f0c88e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>7.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Familiarity with, or possession of, ABC&apos;s Confidential Information would be invaluable to any of ABC&apos;s competitors. <eos/><bos/>This is particularly so in light of the fact that ABC obtains most contracts for the supply of its products through competitive pricing and by ensuring that it has a thorough understanding of customer needs and intended end-uses.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit><form.line style="l"><bop/><bos/><underscore><bold>ABC&apos;s Employment of the Defendant, John Green (“Green”)</bold></underscore><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.unit ID="Ida0517d08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Ida0517d18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>8.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>ABC hired Green as a Salesperson in April 1983, over 14 years ago. <eos/><bos/>Green has been employed on a full-time basis throughout the period of his employment. <eos/><bos/>Since September 1988, Green was one of the salespeople responsible for the sale of ABC&apos;s polyethylene products, including Poly Sheeting, Poly Tubing, Poly Bags and Stretch Film. <eos/><bos/>In his capacity as a Salesperson, Green was to maintain and solidify ABC&apos;s existing customer relationships, to expand such relationships by promoting and introducing ABC&apos;s products, and to develop new business and leads on ABC&apos;s behalf.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0517d28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>9.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>As a result of his long-standing position with ABC, Green developed a close and ongoing relationship with numerous customers, as well as a familiarity with many other long-term ABC customers. <eos/><bos/>In fact, with respect to approximately 29 ABC customers, Green became ABC&apos;s contact person and had the responsibility for ascertaining and meeting the business needs of those customers.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0517d38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>10.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Throughout his employment, Green was able to access ABC&apos;s Confidential Information. <eos/><bos/>In particular, Green was given and had the use of confidential customer lists, purchase orders, invoices, customer histories, confidential credit reports, independent market research, information regarding ABC&apos;s products and suppliers, costing sheets and price lists in both documentary and computer format.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit><form.line style="l"><bop/><bos/><underscore><bold>ABC&apos;s Termination of Green&apos;s Employment</bold></underscore><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.unit ID="Ida0517d48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Ida0517d58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>11.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Green&apos;s employment with ABC was terminated for cause on May 14, 1997. <eos/><bos/>At the time of termination, Green&apos;s remuneration package consisted of an annual base salary of $48,000period;000, commissions of $43,300.00 (for a total annual salary of $91,300.00), plus full company benefits and a company vehicle (for both business and personal use), including the full payment of all gas, repairs and car insurance. <eos/><bos/>The decision to terminate Green&apos;s employment was based upon a number of factors:<eos/></form.text></form.para><form.unit ID="Ida0517d68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.unit ID="Ida0517d78e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(i)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Green&apos;s performance level had decreased to an unacceptably low level, to the point that his sales for ABC were less than his salary;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0517d88e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(ii)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>As a result of my suspicions in relation to Green&apos;s performance, I conducted a thorough review of Green&apos;s daily 1996 and 1997 Sales Activity Reports (“the Sales Activity Reports”).<eos/><bos/> The Sales Activity Reports are a complete daily record of the sales appointments and telephone calls made by Green on ABC&apos;s behalf. <eos/><bos/>After completing my review, it became apparent to me that Green&apos;s hours had become consistently more sporadic during the course of 1996, and that he had, by February 1997, largely abandoned his job responsibilities.<eos/></form.text></form.para><form.para><form.text><bos/>Attached to my affidavit as Exhibit “C” are true copies of the Sales Activity Reports which demonstrate Green&apos;s complete lack of performance.<eos/></form.text></form.para><form.para><form.text><bos/>On the basis of Green&apos;s 1996 and 1997 Sales Activity Reports, I also prepared a summary which provides a daily estimate of the time spent by Green working on ABC&apos;s behalf. <eos/><bos/>On average, I estimate that Green spent less than 4 hours per day performing work for ABC throughout 1996. <eos/><bos/>In addition, on average, I estimate that from mid-January until May 14, 1997, Green spent approximately 1 hour or less per day performing work for ABC.<eos/></form.text></form.para><form.para><form.text><bos/>Attached to my affidavit as Exhibit “D” is a copy of my Summary of Green&apos;s Sales Activity Reports;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0517d98e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(iii)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>ABC learned that Green had conducted personal business during his regular working hours; and<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0517da8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(iv)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Green failed to submit his Sales Activity Reports on a timely basis despite two verbal and two written requests to do so.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit></form.unit></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0517db8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>12.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>By letter dated May 14, 1997, delivered to Green at a meeting conducted on May 14, 1997 (“the Meeting”), Green&apos;s employment with ABC was formally terminated. <eos/><bos/>In the letter dated May 14, 1997, ABC set forth the grounds upon which it relied in support of the termination of Green&apos;s employment for “just cause”.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit><form.line style="l"><bop/><bos/><underscore><bold>Direct Competition by Green During His Employment with ABC</bold></underscore><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.unit ID="Ida0517dc8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Ida0517dd8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>13.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Following Green&apos;s departure, I was able to review his files. <eos/><bos/>During that review, I located a number of documents which clearly demonstrate that Green, during the course of his employment with ABC:<eos/></form.text></form.para><form.unit ID="Ida0517de8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.unit ID="Ida0517df8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(i)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>had been competing directly with ABC and selling Poly Sheeting (specifically, Greenhouse Poly) and Stretch Film to ABC&apos;s existing and potential customers, including customers for which Green was responsible in his position with ABC;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0517e08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(ii)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>had been negotiating with ABC&apos;s competitors and suppliers, and was even purchasing Greenhouse Poly and Stretch Film for resale to ABC&apos;s existing and potential customers; and<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0517e18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(iii)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>delivered a list of ABC&apos;s existing and potential customers to a third party.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit></form.unit></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0517e28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>14.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>After Green&apos;s departure, I was also able to obtain and examine his ABC desk calendar (“the Desk Calendar”), files and business cards. <eos/><bos/>The Desk Calendar is a record of some of Green&apos;s daily appointments on ABC&apos;s behalf. <eos/><bos/>The Business Cards represent the accounts and leads that Green dealt with on ABC&apos;s behalf. <eos/><bos/>Attached to my affidavit as Exhibit “F” is a true copy of the Desk Calendar.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit><form.line style="l"><bop/><bos/><underscore><bold>Supporting Documentation Indicating Direct Competition by Green</bold></underscore><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.unit ID="Ida0517e38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Ida0517e48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>15.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>In my review of Green&apos;s files, I located a number of documents which demonstrate that Green delivered a list of ABC&apos;s existing and potential customers to Jane White as potential business leads for the sale of Stretch Film.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0517e58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>16.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Specifically, on March 12, 1997, Green faxed a 4-page list of companies (“the List”) to Jane White. <eos/><bos/>The List contains 73 companies (“the Companies”).<eos/><bos/> On the cover page to the March 12, 1997 facsimile, Green makes reference to an introductory letter which he will revise and return with the new pricing sheet. <eos/><bos/>Attached to my affidavit as Exhibit “G” are true copies of the fax cover sheet dated March 12, 1997, and the List.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0517e68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>17.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Twenty-one of the Companies on the List are current ABC customers. <eos/><bos/>Attached to my affidavit as Exhibit “H” are copies of 21 ABC invoices which show that the Companies in question are existing ABC customers.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida053ee08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>18.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>In addition, to ABC&apos;s knowledge, gained from the Sales Activity Reports, Green contacted, on ABC&apos;s behalf, another 12 of the Companies on the List which, while not current ABC customers, are businesses that ought to have been pursued exclusively for ABC&apos;s benefit.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida053ee18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>19.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Part of Green&apos;s job was to pursue, on ABC&apos;s behalf, each and every company on the List as potential purchasers, from ABC, of polyethylene products.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida053ee28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>20.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>In documents retrieved from Green&apos;s company vehicle, I also located a letter to Richard Brown (“Brown”) from Green dated April 17, 1997, which refers to a letter to be printed “for the list of customers already provided”.<eos/><bos/> The April 17, 1997 letter also makes reference to a “new pricing sheet” and four potential “very interested” customers. <eos/><bos/>Attached to my affidavit as Exhibit “M” is a true copy of the letter dated April 17, 1997.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida053ee38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>21.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Another letter from Green to Brown, on “XYZ Enterprises Ltd.” letter-head, dated April 24, 1997, encloses a “new pricing sheet” and a “new address sheet for the form letters”.<eos/><bos/> The pricing sheet, on “XYZ” letterhead, is titled “Customer Pricing Sheet” for “XYZ Stretch Wrap”.<eos/><bos/> The new address sheet for the form letters, also on XYZ letterhead, describes the Stretch Wrap product and outlines its features. <eos/><bos/>Attached to my affidavit as Exhibit “N” is a true copy of the letter dated April 24, 1997, and the enclosures.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida053ee48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>22.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>During my review of the documents retrieved from Green&apos;s ABC files, I also found a number of documents which demonstrate that Green was purchasing Stretch Film from one of our competitors, Rocket Wrap Inc.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida053ee58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>23.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>It is significant that ABC does not purchase any product from Rocket Wrap Inc. Further, Green&apos;s job duties do not relate in any way to product purchasing, nor is he authorized to purchase on ABC&apos;s behalf.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida053ee68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>24.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>On May 3, 1997, David Connell, on Rocket Wrap Inc. letterhead, sent a fax to Green, confirming an upcoming meeting with Green and indicated that he had provided a quotation to Kirk Industries (one of the Companies on the List) and referred to Kirk&apos;s potential interest in Stretch Film. <eos/><bos/>Attached to my affidavit as Exhibit “O” is a true copy of the fax dated May 3, 1997.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida053ee78e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>25.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>With the letter from Connell, I located numerous product brochures relating to Stretch Film, Rocket Wrap Inc. Attached to one of the product brochures are letters on XYZ letterhead, to 7 of the Companies on the List, which promote the Rocket Wrap Inc. Stretch Film. <eos/><bos/>The letters are dated May 11, 1997, and are signed by “John Green”.<eos/><bos/> Attached to my affidavit as Exhibit “Q” are true copies of the product brochures and the letters dated May 11, 1997.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida053ee88e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>26.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Also located were two business cards, one for XYZ Distributors Inc. in the name of Jane White (describing the business as “Polyethylene Packaging Products”) and another for XYZ Enterprises in the name of Richard Brown. <eos/><bos/>Attached to my affidavit as Exhibit “R” are true copies of the business cards.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida053ee98e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>27.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>I also found numerous pricing sheets for Rocket Wrap Inc., including 6 sheets of “Suggested Resale Prices” and 3 “Distributor Cost Sheets”.<eos/><bos/> In addition, I found further “Customer Pricing Sheets” for Rocket Wrap Stretch Film dated February 17, 1997, with the name “Buzz Distributors Inc.” on the top of the pricing sheet. <eos/><bos/>Attached to my affidavit as Exhibit “S” are true copies of the “Suggested Resale Prices” sheets and the “Distributor Cost Sheets”.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida053eea8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>28.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>I also located a series of correspondence directly between Green, on behalf of “XYZ Distributing”, and David Connell of Rocket Wrap, as follows:<eos/></form.text></form.para><form.unit ID="Ida053eeb8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.unit ID="Ida053eec8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(i)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>On January 22, 1997, David Connell, on Rocket Wrap letterhead, sent a fax to Green providing him with information relating to Rocket Wrap&apos;s products, including price sheets, suggested resale prices, price quotes, duty, freight prepaid and minimum quantity. <eos/><bos/>Attached to my affidavit as Exhibit “T” is a true copy of the fax dated January 22, 1997;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida053eed8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(ii)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>On January 28, 1997, XYZ sent a courier to Rocket Wrap providing them with product samples. <eos/><bos/>Attached to my affidavit as Exhibit “U” are true copies of the Shipping Receipt and Declaration of Contents dated January 28, 1997;<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida053eee8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(iii)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>On January 29, 1997, Green faxed a memorandum to Rocket Wrap requesting information with respect to the ability of Stretch Wrap to withstand blast freezer temperatures. <eos/><bos/>In response, Connell sent a fax back to Green on January 30, 1997. <eos/><bos/>In his fax, Connell asked Green, “Have you decided how your skids are to be delivered?” <eos/><bos/>Attached to my affidavit as Exhibit “V” is a true copy of the faxes dated January 29 and 30, 1997; and<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida053eef8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>(iv)</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>On February 7, 1997, Connell sent a fax to Green, on Rocket Wrap letterhead, providing information relating to minimum orders and the timing of delivery. <eos/><bos/>Attached to my affidavit as Exhibit “X” is a true copy of the fax dated February 7, 1997.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit></form.unit></form.unit><eop/></form.unit><form.line style="l"><bop/><bos/><underscore><bold>Green&apos;s Further Efforts to Obtain Polyethylene Products from ABC&apos;s Competitors and Suppliers</bold></underscore><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.unit ID="Ida053ef08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Ida053ef18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>29.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>During my file review, I found a number of documents which appear to indicate that Green was attempting to purchase polyethylene products, including Greenhouse Poly and Stretch Film, from ABC&apos;s competitors and suppliers.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida053ef28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>30.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>On the back of some notes (“the Notes”) made by Green regarding one of ABC&apos;s customers, Green had written the names and contact persons of two of ABC&apos;s competitors, Young Plastics (“Young”) and Rice Packaging (“Rice”).<eos/><bos/> Attached to my affidavit as Exhibit “Y” is a true copy of Green&apos;s notes.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida053ef38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>31.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Attached to the Notes was a draft letter, in the name of Jane White of XYZ Distributors Inc., which indicates an intention to contact companies in relation to distributing clear stretch film. <eos/><bos/>In addition, the letter states, “We are suppliers to the Polyethylene user market of various Poly film products.” <eos/><bos/>At the bottom of the draft letter are the addresses of our competitors, Young and Rice. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, I believe that Green had and has every intention to purchase further polyethylene products from ABC&apos;s competitors and to compete with the defendants, lane White and Richard Brown.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida053ef48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>32.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>On March 17, 1997, Green made an entry in the Desk Calendar of Young&apos;s address. <eos/><bos/>After becoming aware of the Desk Calendar entry, I contacted Bill Walsh (“Walsh”), Young&apos;s Sales Manager, in order to inquire as to whether Green had ever contacted Walsh to purchase product from Young. <eos/><bos/>I am advised by Walsh and verily believe that Green did contact him with respect to the potential purchase of Stretch Wrap from Young by Green.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0565f08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>33.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>I have also contacted Carmen Policy (“Policy”), Rice&apos;s Division Manager, in order to inquire as to whether Green had ever contacted Rice to purchase product. <eos/><bos/>Rice is a supplier, to ABC, of Greenhouse Poly. <eos/><bos/>I am informed by Policy and verily believe that Green has contacted Rice on several occasions with respect to the potential purchase of Greenhouse Poly from Rice.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit><form.line style="l"><bop/><bos/><underscore><bold>Sale of Goodwrappers Stretch Film to an ABC Customer by Green</bold></underscore><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.unit ID="Ida0565f18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Ida0565f28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>34.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>On March 23, 1997, Richard Brown, from XYZ Enterprises, sent a fax to Green enclosing a purchase order (“the Hearst Purchase Order”) and price confirmation (both also dated March 23, 1997) from Garrison Hearst of Hearst Supply Co. Ltd. (“Hearst”).<eos/><bos/> Attached to my affidavit as Exhibit “Z” is a true copy of the fax, purchase order and price confirmation sheet each dated March 23, 1997.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0565f38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>35.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The Hearst Purchase Order is addressed to XYZ Distributors for the supply of 24 cases of 3-inch Rocket Wrap Stretch Wrap. <eos/><bos/>The Hearst Purchase Order also states “Artwork sent via John Green”.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0565f48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>36.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Hearst is one of ABC&apos;s customers. <eos/><bos/>Hearst is also one of the Companies on the List. <eos/><bos/>As part of his employment duties, Green was specifically responsible for developing Hearst&apos;s business for ABC. <eos/><bos/>In that regard, Green visited and telephoned Hearst on ABC&apos;s behalf on numerous occasions. <eos/><bos/>There are references to such contacts and visits in the Desk Calendar and the Sales Activity Reports on each of the following days: January 9, February 19, March 3, 10, April 18, 22 and 28, 1997. <eos/><bos/>Included within Exhibit “H” is a copy of an ABC invoice to Hearst for the supply of product during 1996 which demonstrates that Hearst was one of ABC&apos;s customers.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0565f58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>37.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>On May 2, 1997, Green sent a fax to Connell at Rocket Wrap marked “RE: HEARST BLOCK ORDER”.<eos/><bos/> Enclosed with the fax was a letter from Green to Connell requesting various information relating to pricing and a further order of product by Green. <eos/><bos/>In addition, Green enclosed the “FINISHED ARTWORK FOR ‘HEARST BLOCK’ ORDER”.<eos/><bos/> Attached to my affidavit as Exhibit “AA” is a copy of the fax and enclosures sent by Green dated May 2, 1997.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit><form.line style="l"><bop/><bos/><underscore><bold>Attempted Sale of Greenhouse Poly to an ABC Customer by Green</bold></underscore><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.unit ID="Ida0565f68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Ida0565f78e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>38.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>On March 17, 1997, Green sent faxes (one enclosing a quote for the purchase of Greenhouse Poly) to Mary Lemieux of Provo Construction on behalf of ABC. <eos/><bos/>Attached to my affidavit as Exhibit “EE” is a true copy of the quote dated March 17, 1997.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0565f88e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>39.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Provo Construction is one of ABC&apos;s customers. <eos/><bos/>As part of his employment duties, Green was specifically responsible for developing Provo as a customer for ABC. <eos/><bos/>In that regard, Green visited and telephoned Provo on ABC&apos;s behalf on numerous occasions. <eos/><bos/>Specifically, there are purchase orders, invoices, telephone calls, and references to contacts and visits in the Desk Calendar and the Sales Activity Reports for each of the following days: December 11, 1996, January 15, February 26, March 6, 7, 13, 14 and 17, 1997.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0565f98e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>40.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>In fact, from 1994 to 1996 Green, on ABC&apos;s behalf, sold Greenhouse Poly to Provo Construction. <eos/><bos/>The name of the Salesperson on the relevant invoices is clearly indicated as being Green. <eos/><bos/>Attached to my affidavit as Exhibit “FF” are copies of ABC invoices to Provo for the supply of product.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><form.unit ID="Ida0565fa8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>41.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>Green, knowing the price that would likely be quoted to Provo by ABC, prepared a formal quotation to be submitted to Provo on behalf of XYZ. Attached to my affidavit as Exhibit “HH” is a copy of the formal quotation, on XYZ Services Limited letterhead.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit><form.line style="l"><bop/><bos/><underscore><bold>Irreparable Harm to ABC</bold></underscore><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.unit ID="Ida0565fb8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Ida0565fc8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>42.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>The conduct described above amounts to an extreme breach of Green&apos;s obligations to act in good faith and fidelity towards ABC. <eos/><bos/>In addition, Green&apos;s conduct amounts to a breach of the terms of his employment contract with ABC, his fiduciary duties and his duty of confidence.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit><form.line style="l"><bop/><bos/><underscore><bold>Undertaking as to Damages</bold></underscore><eos/><eop/></form.line><form.unit ID="Ida0565fd8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><bop/><form.unit ID="Ida0565fe8e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><form.para><form.head><bos/><label.designator>43.</label.designator><eos/></form.head><form.text><bos/>As the Vice-President of ABC, I hereby undertake on behalf of ABC to pay any damages should it be determined that an injunction was improperly granted in this action.<eos/></form.text></form.para></form.unit><eop/></form.unit><form.signature.block><bop/><tbl ID="I5abf07e0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><table><bos/><tgroup cols="3" align="left"><colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="18*"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="1*"/><colspec colnum="3" colname="3" colwidth="15*"/><tbody><row><entry colname="1"><csc>Sworn before me</csc></entry><entry colname="2">)</entry><entry colname="3"/></row><row><entry colname="1">at the City of Toronto</entry><entry colname="2">)</entry><entry colname="3"/></row><row><entry colname="1">in the Municipality</entry><entry colname="2">)</entry><entry colname="3"/></row><row><entry colname="1">of Metropolitan Toronto</entry><entry colname="2">)</entry><entry colname="3"/></row><row><entry colname="1">on <leaveout><fill.in><textrule weight="0.5pt" position="baseline" length=" 5em "/></fill.in></leaveout>, 1997.</entry><entry colname="2">)</entry><entry colname="3"><leader><leaderchar>_</leaderchar></leader></entry></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2">)</entry><entry colname="3"><csc>Randolph Tingey</csc></entry></row><row><entry colname="1"> </entry><entry colname="2"/><entry colname="3"/></row><row><entry colname="1"><leader><leaderchar>_</leaderchar></leader></entry><entry colname="2">)</entry><entry colname="3"/></row><row><entry colname="1">A Commissioner for Taking Affidavits, etc.</entry><entry colname="2">)</entry><entry colname="3"/></row></tbody></tgroup><eos/></table></tbl><eop/></form.signature.block></form.body></form></appendix.body></appendix><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI APP A<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
