<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information ยง 5:2<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I540dc620411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>5.</label.designator><headtext>Claims for Breach of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I540ded30411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>I.</label.designator><headtext>Civil Actions</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I54178a20411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>A.</label.designator><headtext>Breach of Contract</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f686666ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>ยง </label.name><label.designator>5:2.</label.designator><headtext>Introduction</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Most of the cases dealing with breach of express or implied contractual obligations regarding the use of confidential business information arise in the employment context. <eos/><bos/>With the increasing importance of knowledge as a source of power and wealth, the information acquired by employees and management personnel and the restrictions on their ability to disseminate that information have become increasingly important. <eos/><bos/>The courts will enforce any express or implied obligations of a contracting party provided the clause in question is reasonable and lawful. <eos/><bos/>The courts have dealt with two types of clauses protecting confidential business information: non-competition clauses restricting the mobility of employees and thus their use of acquired business knowledge, and clauses relating specifically to the protection of the information.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></section.body></section><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI ยง 5:2<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
