<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 3:9<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I4ed25b80411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>3.</label.designator><headtext>Defining Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I4eeaec90411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>II.</label.designator><headtext>Information Capable of Protection</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I4eecc150411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>A.</label.designator><headtext>The “Confidential” Nature of the Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f5ea286ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>3:9.</label.designator><headtext>When Disclosure Is a Breach of Confidence—Reasonable person test</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The courts have generally applied the standard of a reasonable person, set forth in the leading case of <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175840" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1968018312" w-pub-number="0004831" ID="I1c5b8e618e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Coco v. A.N. Clark (Engineers)</cite.query> Ltd.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id246abd08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>] to determine whether or not a party disclosing information should have been aware that the information was confidential.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id246abd18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>] If the person should realize that the information was to be maintained in privacy, then there will be an implied obligation to maintain it in confidence.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id246d2e08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">3</footnote.reference>] In various Canadian cases, the courts have applied the test of the reasonable person to determine whether, in the circumstances, the person in question should have known the information was confidential based upon its “obvious character”.<eos/><bos/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id246d2e18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">4</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Generally, when a lawyer receives confidential information from a person in a non solicitor-client relationship, the communication is not considered to be confidential information when there was a clear understanding that it would not be used by the solicitor against the third party who divulged the information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id246d2e28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">5</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In addition, the courts will hold third parties liable where those parties receive confidential information with the knowledge that it was communicated in breach of confidence or where they subsequently acquire notice of that fact even if they were innocent at the time of acquisition. <eos/><bos/>In that regard, use of such information must be confined to the original purpose for which the information was provided.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id246f9f08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">6</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In an English case of some notoriety, <ital>Thomas Marshall (Exporters) Ltd. v. Guinle</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id246f9f18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">7</footnote.reference>] Megarry V.C. added a subjective element to the inquiry. <eos/><bos/>His Lordship held that so long as the owner of information reasonably believes that the information is not already in the public domain, the information should arguably merit protection. <eos/><bos/>He stated that this should be the case <begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>“even where some or all of his rivals already have the information”<end.quote refid="QT_0001"/>. <eos/><bos/>While this principle should not be overextended, <ital>i.e.</ital>, to information widely available, there will be proper circumstances where information should remain protected despite the fact that competitors have developed or obtained similar information independently. <eos/><bos/>For example, in an economy where technological advances occur at a rapid pace, it is inevitable that, at times, competitors will properly be developing information simultaneously.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>More recent case law has continued to rely on the test of the “reasonable” and “honourable” person.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id24721008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">8</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A claim for damages by the plaintiff arising from the alleged misuse of confidential business information by the defendants was dismissed in <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175840" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2034750957" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I1c5ffb318e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Seaway Marine Services Ltd. v. Weiwaikum General Partner</cite.query> Ltd.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id24721018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">9</footnote.reference>] The case concerned the ownership and operation of a marine fuel barge docked at a marina. <eos/><bos/>The fuel barge and associated equipment was owned by Esso for several years. <eos/><bos/>Esso decided to divest itself of all marine fuel dock operations on the British Columbia coast. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff was notified of Esso&apos;s intention to not renew their dealership agreement. <eos/><bos/>Shortly thereafter, the plaintiff expressed an interest to Esso in buying the fuel barge and associated equipment from Esso, and assuming Esso&apos;s lease. <eos/><bos/>The Weiwaikum board assumed management of certain marina-related assets, including the Esso lease which was soon coming to an end. <eos/><bos/>The Weiwaikum board sent letters requesting various items of information related to the lease to Esso and to the plaintiff concerning the lease and the marine fuel operation. <eos/><bos/>It received representations from the plaintiff in support of the plaintiff&apos;s plan to purchase the fuel barge and assume the lease. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff&apos;s reply to Weiwaikum enclosed a “Letter of Intent” indicating that the plaintiff was in the midst of negotiations with Esso to purchase the fuel barge and with Devco to assume Esso&apos;s leasehold. <eos/><bos/>Weiwaikum ultimately decided that the Limited Partnership would purchase the fuel barge from Esso.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id24721028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">10</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff alleged that the defendants breached confidence in relation to the information the plaintiff communicated, including reports on the condition and value of the fuel barge; the plaintiff&apos;s financial statements; and an outline of the plaintiff&apos;s operational plan for the marine fuel business. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge observed that equity is “quick to protect confidences” and sets a “relatively low threshold” on the type of information capable of providing the foundation for a breach of confidence claim. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge had no difficulty in concluding that the information as to the barge condition and value, the information in the financial statements, and the aspects of the “operational plan” was confidential information and accepted on that basis by Weiwaikum. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff&apos;s documents were manifestly confidential. <eos/><bos/>The information in them would have been known to very few outside of the plaintiff, was acquired by the expenditure of the plaintiff&apos;s money or its effort, and could not be easily acquired or duplicated by others. <eos/><bos/>The defendants received the information from business letters exchanged during the course of commercial negotiations. <eos/><bos/>The reasonable person standing in the shoes of the defendants would have realized on reasonable grounds that the information was being given by the plaintiff in confidence, and the equitable duty of confidence was therefore imposed.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id24748108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">11</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In the course of the exchange of letters, Weiwaikum stated that it was in the process of reviewing the various options available to it relating to the fuel facility. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff argued that it was objectively reasonable for its representatives to think that the word “options” related to lease options in relation to the plaintiff and that the option of the defendants choosing to run the business was not “reasonably in prospect”.<eos/><bos/> The trial judge did not accept that the language in the letter should be read down so as to include only options that would involve the plaintiff&apos;s ongoing participation in the marine fuel business. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff must be taken to have known that one of Weiwaikum&apos;s options would be to negotiate to buy the barge. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge observed that what the plaintiff knew, or a reasonable person in the plaintiff&apos;s position must be taken to have known, was important only insofar as it informed what Weiwaikum, as the recipient of the information, knew or must be taken to have known when it came into receipt of the confidential information. <eos/><bos/>There was no reason for Weiwaikum to be fixed with the knowledge that the plaintiff was sending the confidential barge information on the basis that Weiwaikum would only use it to consider business options that involved the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>Weiwaikum was entitled to use the confidential barge information it received from Seaway to consider its various options, including the option of a Band entity purchasing the fuel barge and running the business without the plaintiff&apos;s involvement.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id24748118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">12</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge was also inclined to find that the use of the financial statements for purposes other than determining whether the plaintiff was a viable tenant was unauthorized, absent other considerations. <eos/><bos/>However, the plaintiff replied to the defendant&apos;s letter of request by stating that it was more than capable of assuming the financial commitments of the current lease, and that it was willing to forward the financial statements if necessary and it is demonstrated that this is a standard requirement of all lessees or assignees. <eos/><bos/>The response from Weiwaikum spoke of confirming the financial status of the plaintiff and stated that requiring the financial statements of prospective lessees or assignees is common practice. <eos/><bos/>This response, and the language used by the plaintiff in its letter enclosing the financial statements would lead a reasonable recipient of the financial statements to the conclusion that they were to be used for the purpose of deciding whether the plaintiff would be a viable tenant and not otherwise.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id24748128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">13</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge reached the same conclusion with regard to the confidential aspects of the “operational plan.” <eos/><bos/>The Weiwaikum request was specific: <begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>“In order for the Landlord to consider your request for a ten year lease, we will need to receive a business plan from you outlining your plans for the use and operation of the Fuel Facility.”<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0002"/> The plaintiff&apos;s response was that no business plan was needed as the plan was to sell fuel for ten years plus any optional years. <eos/><bos/>Weiwaikum replied that if the plaintiff was interested in a new lease, Weiwaikum required a business plan as part of its due diligence. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff then sent the one-page “operational plan” alongside a reiteration of its position that it was seeking an assignment of the existing lease rather than a new lease. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge concluded that this exchange of correspondence would lead a reasonable recipient of the confidential aspects of the plaintiff&apos;s “operational plan” to conclude that the permitted use was in connection with deciding whether the plaintiff would be a viable tenant and not otherwise.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id24748138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">14</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge&apos;s conclusion that the defendants were entitled to use the plaintiff&apos;s barge information when considering all of the various options for the fuel dock narrowed the issue to whether the defendants made use of the financial statements or confidential aspects of the “operational plan” for purposes other than assessing the viability of the plaintiff as a tenant. <eos/><bos/>Briefing notes prepared for a meeting with Chief Pollard included a reference to information from figures extracted from the plaintiff&apos;s 2005 income statement and reflected use of the financial statements for an unauthorized purpose. <eos/><bos/>The use of the information in the financial statements as part of a briefing note for a meeting to consider whether the Limited Partnership should take over the marine fuel dock was not a permitted use of this confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The question whether the information was actually factored in to the decision to purchase and run the fuel barge was another matter. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge considered it unlikely that there was substantive discussion at this brief meeting on the question of whether the Limited Partnership should take over the fuel dock business, and highly unlikely that any use was made during this meeting of the plaintiff&apos;s 2005 financial figures.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id2476f208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">15</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff argued that the timing of a meeting by the Weiwaikum board and Chief Pollard with Esso representatives, occurring just a few days after Weiwaikum received confidential information from the plaintiff, together with the exclusion of the plaintiff from the meeting, was powerful evidence in support of its case. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge concluded that this meeting was scheduled at the instance of Esso. <eos/><bos/>Esso had the date in mind before the plaintiff&apos;s letter was written. <eos/><bos/>There was nothing on Esso&apos;s agenda that called for the plaintiff&apos;s attendance. <eos/><bos/>It was fair to characterize Esso&apos;s agenda as that of a tenant meeting with its landlord in advance of the expiry of its lease. <eos/><bos/>There certainly was some discussion during the meeting of the terms on which Esso might deal with Weiwaikum, but there was no support for the notion that Weiwaikum or Chief Pollard made use of Seaway&apos;s financial statements or “operational plan”.<eos/><bos/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id2476f218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">16</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff alleged that during the period from the date that Weiwaikum received the plaintiff&apos;s confidential information until the date of purchase of the fuel barge from Esso, Weiwaikum and the Band used the confidential information to assess the risk in deciding to take over the fuel dock. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge concluded that there was no evidence that pointed to the conclusion that the defendants likely made use of the financial statements or confidential aspects of the operational plan in coming to their decisions to buy the barge and run the marine fuel business.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id2476f228e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">17</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The only misuse of confidential information demonstrated was very limited, namely, the inclusion of data from the 2005 financial statements in the Weiwaikum briefing note. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence that the very limited misuse of the confidential information played any part in the decision taken to acquire the fuel barge and operate the marine fuel business. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff was in no different position than it would have been in had the misuse not occurred. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff failed to prove damages on a <begin.quote ID="QT_0003"/>“common sense view of causation.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0003"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id2476f238e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">18</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff was not entitled to compensatory damages for the defendants&apos; misuse of confidential information despite the submission that this result was foreclosed by the necessary imposition on the defendants of a <begin.quote ID="QT_0006"/>“special disability in the field of competition”<end.quote refid="QT_0006"/>. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge understood the plaintiff&apos;s argument to be that this “special disability” was imposed regardless of the nature and extent of the misuse of confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge observed that the difficulty with this argument was that it lost sight of the relationship between the concept of “special disability” and the concept of using information as a “spring-board” to get an “unfair start”; stating:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0007"/>It is not every misuse of confidential information, regardless of how limited or trifling, that triggers the application of the “special disability.” <eos/><bos/>In the case at bar the defendants did not make use of the information as a <begin.quote ID="QT_0005"/>“spring-board for activities detrimental to the person who made the confidential communication”<end.quote refid="QT_0005"/> so there is no question of obtaining an unfair start and no basis for finding that the defendants were specially disabled from acquiring the marine fuel business in these particular circumstances.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0007"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0008"/>In <cite.query w-src-number="0492175840" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017324749" w-pub-number="0006457" ID="I1c694a008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Aram Systems Ltd. v. NovAtel Inc.</ital>, 2008 ABQB 441 (Alta. Q.B.)</cite.query>, <case.history>aff&apos;d</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175840" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2019530368" w-pub-number="0006455" ID="I1c694a028e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2009 ABCA 262 (Alta. C.A.)</cite.query>, MacLeod J. wrote, at para. 105, that regardless of how the breach of confidence obligation is characterized, <begin.quote ID="QT_0004"/>“the Court&apos;s concern is with enforcing the reasonable expectations of the parties in the particular commercial context.”<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0004"/> From this narrow perspective, it cannot be seriously contended that it would have been within the expectation of Seaway or the defendants that the mere receipt or trifling misuse of the confidential information would result in the defendants being cleared from the field of competition for the marine fuel business.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0008"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0009"/>Moreover, there is a broader perspective to consider. <eos/><bos/>While there is no question of the importance of the policy of the law that confidences are to be respected, to impose the competitive disability on the defendants advocated for by Seaway in the absence of a finding that the defendants made use of the information as a “spring-board” would be inconsistent with the strong public interest in the maintenance of commercial competition spoken of by Smith J.A. in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175840" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2005997312" w-pub-number="0006458" ID="I1c69e6408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Expert Travel Financial Security (E.T.F.S.) Inc. v. BMS Harris &amp; Dixon Insurance Brokers Ltd.</ital>, 2005 BCCA 5 (B.C. C.A.)</cite.query> at para. 79. <eos/><bos/>The proper balance between the policy of the law that encourages competition and the policy of the law that protects commercial confidences would be upset by finding that the defendants were uniquely disabled from acquiring the fuel barge business in circumstances where the confidential information played no role in its acquisition.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0009"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id247bd408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">19</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge observed that the result should not differ between a case where information is in fact “nothing very special” and a case where information may have value but is treated by the recipient as if it was “nothing very special”.<eos/><bos/> The trial judge concluded that the plaintiff&apos;s claim failed because the limited misuse of the confidential information by Weiwaikum made no difference to the plaintiff&apos;s position. <eos/><bos/>The breach of confidence was not sufficiently serious that the Court should invoke its equitable discretion to award damages.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id247bd418e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">20</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Id246abd08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175840" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1968018312" w-pub-number="0004831" ID="I1c6a82808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Coco v. A.N. Clark (Engineers) Ltd.</ital>, [1969] R.P.C. 41 (Ch.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id246abd18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175840" w-seq-number="00007" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1967018767" w-pub-number="0004831" ID="I1c6e04f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Terrapin Ltd. v. Builder&apos;s Supply Co. (Hayes) Ltd.</ital>, [1967] R.P.C. 375 (Ch.), at p. 388</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>See also <cite.query w-src-number="0492175840" w-seq-number="00008" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2005997312" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I1c6e04f28e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Expert Travel Financial Security (E.T.F.S.) Inc. v. BMS Harris &amp; Dixon Insurance Brokers Ltd.</ital> (2005), 249 D.L.R. (4th) 367 (B.C.C.A.)</cite.query>, where the court used the “honourable man” test.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id246d2e08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175840" w-seq-number="00009" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2025839806" w-pub-number="0007659" ID="I1c6e53108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Wyn Re Network LP v. Vanden Broek</ital>, 2011 ONSC 4730 (Comm. List)</cite.query>, <case.history>affirmed</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175840" w-seq-number="00010" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028315378" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I1c6e53128e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2012 CarswellOnt 9315, 2012 ONSC 3336</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id246d2e18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>4</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>See, for example, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175840" w-seq-number="00011" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1989320546" w-pub-number="0005653" ID="I1c70c4108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ken Graham Consumer Products Ltd. v. Sunbeam Corp. (Canada) Ltd.</ital> (1989), 25 C.P.R. (3d) 52 (Ont. H.C.J.), at pp. 76-7</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175840" w-seq-number="00012" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1973141883" w-pub-number="0005652" ID="I1c70c4128e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Eaton Fund Distributors v. Poulin</ital> (1973), 12 C.P.R. (2d) 35 (Ont. H.C.J.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175840" w-seq-number="00013" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1931031426" w-pub-number="0004831" ID="I1c70c4148e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>United Indigo Chemical Co. v. Robinson</ital> (1931), 49 R.P.C. 178 (Ch.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id246d2e28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>5</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175840" w-seq-number="00014" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2025839806" w-pub-number="0007659" ID="I1c7112308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Wyn Re Network LP v. Vanden Broek</ital>, 2011 ONSC 4730 (Comm. List)</cite.query>, <case.history>affirmed</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175840" w-seq-number="00015" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028315378" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I1c7112328e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2012 CarswellOnt 9315, 2012 ONSC 3336</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id246f9f08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>6</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175840" w-seq-number="00016" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1999428661" w-pub-number="0003591" w-pinpoint-page="587" ID="I1c7160508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cadbury Schweppes Inc. v. FBI Foods Ltd.</ital> (1999), 167 D.L.R. (4th) 577 at pp. 587-8, [1999] 1 S.C.R. 142</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175840" w-seq-number="00017" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2025385581" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I1c7160538e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ali Arc Industries LP v. S &amp; V Manufacturing Ltd.</ital>, 2011 CarswellMan 228, 2011 MBQB 95</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id246f9f18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>7</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175840" w-seq-number="00018" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1978025276" w-pub-number="0004891" ID="I1c788c408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Thomas Marshall (Exporters) Ltd. v. Guinle</ital>, [1978] 3 W.L.R. 116 (Ch.), at p. 136</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id24721008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>8</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>See, for example, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175840" w-seq-number="00019" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2005997312" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I1c7901708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Expert Travel Financial Security (E.T.F.S.) Inc. v. BMS Harris &amp; Dixon Insurance Brokers Ltd.</ital> (2005), 249 D.L.R. (4th) 367 (B.C.C.A.)</cite.query>, at paras. 45-48; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175840" w-seq-number="00020" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2009574073" w-pub-number="0003986" ID="I1c7901728e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Minera Aquiline Argentina SA v. IMA Exploration Inc.</ital>, [2007] 1 W.W.R. 43</cite.query> at paras. 150-151 (B.C.S.C.), <case.history>affd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175840" w-seq-number="00021" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2012444302" w-pub-number="0003986" ID="I1c7901748e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">[2007] 10 W.W.R. 648 (B.C.C.A.)</cite.query>, leave to appeal to <cite.query w-src-number="0492175840" w-seq-number="00022" w-ref-type="ER" w-normalized-cite="384NRCA383n" w-pub-number="0005466" ID="I1c7901768e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">S.C.C. refused 384 N.R. 383<ital>n</ital></cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175840" w-seq-number="00023" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2025385581" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I1c7901788e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ali Arc Industries LP v. S &amp; V Manufacturing Ltd.</ital>, 2011 CarswellMan 228, 2011 MBQB 95</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id24721018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>9</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175840" w-seq-number="00024" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034750957" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I1c7976a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seaway Marine Services Ltd. v. Weiwaikum General Partner Ltd.</ital>, 2014 CarswellBC 3311, 2014 BCSC 2102</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id24721028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>10</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175840" w-seq-number="00025" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034750957" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I1c799db08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seaway Marine Services Ltd. v. Weiwaikum General Partner Ltd.</ital>, 2014 CarswellBC 3311, 2014 BCSC 2102</cite.query>, at paras. 2-4, 6, and 16.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id24748108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>11</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175840" w-seq-number="00026" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034750957" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I1c79c4c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seaway Marine Services Ltd. v. Weiwaikum General Partner Ltd.</ital>, 2014 CarswellBC 3311, 2014 BCSC 2102</cite.query>, at paras. 13, and 28-29.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id24748118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>12</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175840" w-seq-number="00027" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034750957" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I1c79ebd08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seaway Marine Services Ltd. v. Weiwaikum General Partner Ltd.</ital>, 2014 CarswellBC 3311, 2014 BCSC 2102</cite.query>, at paras. 31, 33, 37, and 40-41.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id24748128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>13</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175840" w-seq-number="00028" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034750957" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I1c7a39f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seaway Marine Services Ltd. v. Weiwaikum General Partner Ltd.</ital>, 2014 CarswellBC 3311, 2014 BCSC 2102</cite.query>, at paras. 44-45.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id24748138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>14</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175840" w-seq-number="00029" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034750957" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I1c7a61008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seaway Marine Services Ltd. v. Weiwaikum General Partner Ltd.</ital>, 2014 CarswellBC 3311, 2014 BCSC 2102</cite.query>, at paras. 46-47.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2476f208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>15</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175840" w-seq-number="00030" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034750957" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I1c7a88108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seaway Marine Services Ltd. v. Weiwaikum General Partner Ltd.</ital>, 2014 CarswellBC 3311, 2014 BCSC 2102</cite.query>, at paras. 49-53.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2476f218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>16</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175840" w-seq-number="00031" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034750957" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I1c7ad6308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seaway Marine Services Ltd. v. Weiwaikum General Partner Ltd.</ital>, 2014 CarswellBC 3311, 2014 BCSC 2102</cite.query>, at paras. 55, 58, and 61-62.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2476f228e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>17</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175840" w-seq-number="00032" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034750957" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I1c7afd408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seaway Marine Services Ltd. v. Weiwaikum General Partner Ltd.</ital>, 2014 CarswellBC 3311, 2014 BCSC 2102</cite.query>, at paras. 64-65.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id2476f238e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>18</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175840" w-seq-number="00033" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034750957" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I1c7b24508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seaway Marine Services Ltd. v. Weiwaikum General Partner Ltd.</ital>, 2014 CarswellBC 3311, 2014 BCSC 2102</cite.query>, at paras. 85-86.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id247bd408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>19</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175840" w-seq-number="00034" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034750957" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I1c7b72708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seaway Marine Services Ltd. v. Weiwaikum General Partner Ltd.</ital>, 2014 CarswellBC 3311, 2014 BCSC 2102</cite.query>, at paras. 87-91.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id247bd418e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>20</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175840" w-seq-number="00035" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034750957" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I1c7b99808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seaway Marine Services Ltd. v. Weiwaikum General Partner Ltd.</ital>, 2014 CarswellBC 3311, 2014 BCSC 2102, at para. 93</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 3:9<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
