<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 4:35<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I5089a870411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>4.</label.designator><headtext>Confidential Business Information and the Employment Relationship</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I52517020411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>V.</label.designator><headtext>Fiduciary Duty</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I5251be40411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>A.</label.designator><headtext>Analysis</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f65f406ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>4:35.</label.designator><headtext>Québec Law—Restrictive Covenants</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The provisions of the C.C.Q. set forth a number of conditions that must be met in order for a non-competition covenant to be legally valid and thus enforceable. <eos/><bos/>Art. 2089 reads as follows:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>2089. <eos/><bos/>The parties may stipulate in writing and in express terms that, even after the termination of the contract, the employee may neither compete with his employer nor participate in any capacity whatsoever in an enterprise which would then compete with him.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0001"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>Such a stipulation shall be limited, however, as to time, place and type of employment, to whatever is necessary for the protection of the legitimate interests of the employer.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0002"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0003"/>The burden of proof that the stipulation is valid is on the employer.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0003"/></paratext></para></display.quote><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Restrictive covenants must be in writing, but do not necessarily have to be in the same document as a contract of employment. <eos/><bos/>Such covenants must be drafted in terms clear enough for a reasonable person to easily understand their scope and substance.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>It should be noted that, if the contract is related to work performed in the Province of Québec, the written documents must be drafted in French, unless the use of the English language is specifically requested by the employee. <eos/><bos/>A clause indicating that request should be added to all employment-related agreements drafted in English in order to alleviate any problem that could arise later on.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>As is the case in the Common Law jurisdictions, restrictive covenants must be limited in both their geographical and temporal aspects. <eos/><bos/>The scope of the covenant must not unduly prevent the employee from earning a living for a period longer than what is necessary to protect the employer from immediate competition. <eos/><bos/>The clause must also indicate the types of employment the employee will be restricted from undertaking. <eos/><bos/>As to the time, place and type of employment limits that will be acceptable, each situation is fact specific.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id54ebbb08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Even though art. 2089 C.C.Q. does not create a distinction between regular employees and those that have a higher fiduciary duty towards the employer, the courts will take into account a former employee&apos;s position within the company. <eos/><bos/>A review of the case law clearly shows that more severe restrictive covenants will be tolerated by the courts where an employee held an important position within the organization.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Article 2089 C.C.Q. does not currently distinguish between non-competition and non-solicitation covenants. <eos/><bos/>Even though the principle developed in <ital>Lyons v. Multari</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id54ebbb18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>] is not currently enunciated in any decision rendered in the Province of Québec, a similar development should be expected.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>When a restrictive covenant forms part of a contract prepared in connection with a business sale, the courts will accept more restrictive terms as valid, especially when the clause is directed towards ensuring that key employees do not impinge on the value of the enterprise sold.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id54ebbb28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">3</footnote.reference>] It must also be noted that, in the context of the sale of a business, it was formerly argued that a restrictive covenant would not survive. <eos/><bos/>However, since 1994, that argument can no longer succeed in light of the drafting of art. 2097 C.C.Q., which reads as follows:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0004"/>2097. <eos/><bos/>A contract of employment is not terminated by alienation of the enterprise or any change in its legal structure by way of amalgamation or otherwise.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0004"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0005"/>The contract is binding on the successor of the employer.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0005"/></paratext></para></display.quote><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Id54ebbb08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175889" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1998467414" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I403988508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>TRM Copy Centers (Canada) Ltd. v. Copiscope Inc.</ital> (1998), 85 A.C.W.S. (3d) 170, REJB 1998-09660 (Que. C.A.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175889" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2002058291" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I403988538e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Bergeron v. Dubuc</ital> (2002), 112 A.C.W.S. (3d) 1054, J.E. 2002-352 (Que. C.A.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175889" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2022158989" w-pub-number="0006462" ID="I403988568e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Emballages Alpha inc. v. Plastilec Inc.</ital> (2010), 83 C.P.R. (4th) 455, 2010 QCCS 2124</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id54ebbb18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175889" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2000551350" w-pub-number="0005506" ID="I4039d6708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Lyons v. Multari</ital> (2000), 50 O.R. (3d) 526, 136 O.A.C. 281 (C.A.)</cite.query>, leave to appeal to the <cite.query w-src-number="0492175889" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="ER" w-normalized-cite="150OACCA197n" w-pub-number="0005460" ID="I4039d6738e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">S.C.C. refused 150 O.A.C. 197<ital>n</ital>, 171 N.R. 195<ital>n</ital></cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id54ebbb28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175889" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2024581191" w-pub-number="0005481" ID="I4039fd808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Corovessis v. 6656285 Canada inc.</ital>, 2011 CarswellQue 1151, 2011 QCCS 476</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 4:35<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
