<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 6:2<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I55e174b0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>6.</label.designator><headtext>Defences to Claims for Breach of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I55e4f720411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>II.</label.designator><headtext>Nature of the Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f6d4706ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>6:2.</label.designator><headtext>Information Not Confidential</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A defendant will be successful in refuting a claim for breach of confidential business information if he or she can establish that the information was not confidential. <eos/><bos/>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1983031647" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I51b676118e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Fraser v. Thames Television</cite.query> Ltd.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id77da9a08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>]the court held that, in order to be protected as confidential, information must be <begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>“clearly identifiable, original, of potential commercial attractiveness and capable of reaching fruition”<end.quote refid="QT_0001"/>. <eos/><bos/>Further, in order for information to be protected by the courts, the plaintiff must have impressed upon the defendant the confidentiality of the information such that there existed an obligation to keep the information confidential.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id77da9a18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Information which is public knowledge will not be considered confidential business information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id77da9a28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">3</footnote.reference>] For example, in <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1985263355" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I51b787818e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Promotivate International Inc. v. Toronto Star Newspapers</cite.query> Ltd.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id77da9a38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">4</footnote.reference>] the plaintiff agreed to set up a consecutively numbered lottery for the defendant, whereby six numbers would be printed in each issue of Starweek magazine, and awards issued when between three and six numbers drawn matched those printed. <eos/><bos/>After Promotivate&apos;s proposal, the defendant ran a similar lottery, at which point the plaintiff claimed breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>The claim for breach of confidence was dismissed on the grounds that the concept presented by the plaintiff to the defendant was already well known and thus, could not be considered confidential business information.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2042570374" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I51b95c418e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Hamilton v. F&amp;M Management</cite.query> Ltd</ital>.,[<footnote.reference refid="Id77da9a48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">5</footnote.reference>] the essence of the plaintiffs&apos; claim was that the defendants induced them to enter into a corporate services agreement and a non-disclosure agreement in order to obtain their confidential information and use it to develop, patent, and successfully market VECTTOR. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff Hamilton was an entrepreneur in the remediation industry. <eos/><bos/>He was the principal of Enviro-Klean which produced a thermal desorption machine called the KM-4. <eos/><bos/>F&amp;M was a management firm that offered corporate advisory services to the waste management and remediation sectors. <eos/><bos/>Calaeris was incorporated to build, develop, and sell a thermal desorption machine called VECTTOR. <eos/><bos/>Bogzaran was a director of both F&amp;M and Calaeris. <eos/><bos/>His brother Ramin was a director of Calaeris but not of F&amp;M. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs retained F&amp;M and entered into the agreements for that purpose.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id77da9a58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">6</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Prior to 2011, Hamilton had known Bogzaran for some time. <eos/><bos/>Bogzaran became aware that Hamilton was considering selling his company and introduced him to his brother. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs entered into the Agreements pursuant to which F&amp;M was to assist in the sale of Enviro-Klean. <eos/><bos/>In exchange for a fee, F&amp;M would prepare a company profile based on confidential and other information received from the plaintiffs, identify potential buyers, and assist in the purchase process. <eos/><bos/>Under the non-disclosure agreement, F&amp;M did not require any rights in or licence to use confidential information received from the plaintiffs. <eos/><bos/>It could only use that information for the purposes set out in these Agreements. <eos/><bos/>The Agreements did not in any way restrict F&amp;M or its principals from contracting with other thermal desorption companies, producers, or inventors to provide them with services similar to those in the Agreements or otherwise from engaging in any activities related to thermal desorption technology.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id77da9a68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">7</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Hoffman, who knew Bogzaran and had worked with him previously on a different thermal desorption process, developed VECTTOR. <eos/><bos/>He deposed that he did so without the involvement of Bogzaran and that he received no information relating to this work from any of F&amp;M, either of the Bogzaran brothers, or Banack, who was also a principal of Calaeris. <eos/><bos/>Hoffman applied for a U.S. patent for VECTTOR on January 25, 2013, and for an international patent on January 24, 2014. <eos/><bos/>Hamilton applied for Canadian and U.S. patents for the KM-4 on June 7, 2013.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id77dd0b08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">8</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In April 2014, the International Patent Office issued a non-binding opinion indicating that the Hoffman process was patentable. <eos/><bos/>On December 15, 2015, the U.S. Patent Office issued a non-final rejection of Hamilton&apos;s patent application on the basis that it was too similar to an existing patent. <eos/><bos/>The similarity was not to the Hoffman process, but to another thermal desorption process.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id77dd0b18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">9</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>During his examination for discovery, Hamilton stated that the defendants used information that he had provided to them to help with the development of VECTTOR. <eos/><bos/>However, despite being asked repeatedly to specify what that information was, he was evasive and unable to do so.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id77dd0b28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">10</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In preparation for the litigation, the defendants commissioned an expert report from Sadler, a chemical engineer with experience and expertise in thermal desorption, incineration, air pollution control, and waste water treatment. <eos/><bos/>He was provided with all of the material Hamilton had provided to F&amp;M under the Agreements, as well as additional information provided by Hamilton to F&amp;M and a CD containing videos of the KM-4. <eos/><bos/>In his report, Sadler reviewed the patent applications filed in support of the KM-4 and VECTTOR, identifying in detail the similarities and differences between them, as well as novel features of each. <eos/><bos/>He concluded that the Hoffman process was significantly different from the Hamilton process. <eos/><bos/>The similarities between the two processes were not unique and had been employed on other processes. <eos/><bos/>Sadler did not compare the KM-4 and VECTTOR machines in operation, because there was no KM-4 in operation that he could have observed.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id77dd0b38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">11</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The defendants did not dispute that some of the information communicated by the plaintiffs to the defendants concerning the KM-4 was confidential. <eos/><bos/>The Chambers judge observed that the question was whether there was any evidence that the defendants misused that information. <eos/><bos/>Hoffman denied receiving any such information. <eos/><bos/>The Chambers judge observed that while Sadler opined that some of the material delivered by the plaintiffs to F&amp;M could be considered confidential and could be used to develop a process similar to that used in the KM-4, that Hoffman&apos;s process did not use those aspects of Hamilton&apos;s process. <eos/><bos/>He also stated that the similarities between the two processes were not unique to them, but were also seen elsewhere in the thermal desorption industry. <eos/><bos/>The Chambers judge concluded that the plaintiffs had not shown that it was more likely than not that F&amp;M breached confidence by misusing information it received from the plaintiffs and disclosing it to Calaeris and/or Hoffman.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id77dd0b48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">12</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Kamloops-Cariboo Regional Immigrants Society v. Herman</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id77dd0b58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">13</footnote.reference>] the trial judge concluded that the tort of breach of confidentiality had not been made out and the action was dismissed. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff Society was a not-for-profit society and registered charity that assisted immigrants, visible minorities and first generation Canadians in becoming full and equal members of Canadian society. <eos/><bos/>The defendant Herman was the former executive director of the Society. <eos/><bos/>Herman was terminated as executive director in July 2009. <eos/><bos/>Despite the improvement at the Society office after Herman assumed the role of executive director there continued to be some employee conflict. <eos/><bos/>At the AGM in October 2008, changes to the Board occurred. <eos/><bos/>Igwe ascended to President of the Society. <eos/><bos/>Almost immediately, the new members of the Board began to express concern and critique Herman&apos;s abilities as executive director. <eos/><bos/>The relationship between Herman and Igwe began to deteriorate. <eos/><bos/>On April 20, 2009, Herman sent an email to the Board advising that she was going on medical leave for at least one month due to the “hostile environment” created by the board president. <eos/><bos/>On April 27, 2009, the Board held a special board meeting to discuss the plans for Herman&apos;s return and the need to discuss their concerns with her. <eos/><bos/>They also discussed whether they could legally fire Herman over her performance. <eos/><bos/>Several people came forward with concerns about the Society and this group became known as the “Committee”.<eos/><bos/> The members of the Committee included Herman. <eos/><bos/>While still on medical leave, Herman emailed about a possible meeting of the Committee. <eos/><bos/>In her email she expressed the hope that new members could be recruited to the Society in order to have enough votes to re-elect the Board. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiffs characterized this action by Herman as illustrative of her improper efforts to overthrow the Board. <eos/><bos/>On June 22, 2009, a letter with twelve signatories including Herman was sent to Igwe advising that they were requisitioning the Board to convene a general meeting of the Society within 14 days of receipt of the letter, pursuant to s. 58(2) of the <ital>Society Act</ital>. <eos/><bos/>The stated purpose of the requested meeting was to elect a new Board due to the <begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>“membership no longer having confidence in the present Board of Directors”<end.quote refid="QT_0002"/>. <eos/><bos/>According to Igwe, the Board was outraged by this letter and considered it a blatant attempt at a <ital>coup d&apos;etat</ital> by Herman and her supporters. <eos/><bos/>Igwe replied by email on the Board&apos;s behalf stating that Herman was not authorized to call a meeting and that the Board declined to call the general meeting. <eos/><bos/>On June 25, 2009, a letter was sent to the Board on behalf of Herman and seven other employees which alleged that <begin.quote ID="QT_0003"/>“a number of employees have been subjected to harassment”<end.quote refid="QT_0003"/> as defined by the <ital>Human Rights Act</ital>, by Short, Interim Executive Director and Igwe, Board President. <eos/><bos/>Although details were not provided, the harassment alleged in the June 25, 2009 letter included <begin.quote ID="QT_0004"/>“sexual, gender, and ethnic origin harassment”<end.quote refid="QT_0004"/>. <eos/><bos/>In Igwe&apos;s view, the letter was more evidence of Herman&apos;s attempt to tarnish his reputation. <eos/><bos/>On July 7, 2009, Herman received a letter from Igwe terminating her employment for cause. <eos/><bos/>The grounds for Herman&apos;s termination included insubordination; failure to uphold the Society&apos;s Constitution and by-laws; improper hiring practices; unfair remuneration practices; administrative incompetence; and incomplete financial reporting to the Board. <eos/><bos/>The harassment report concluded that Igwe engaged in personal harassment towards Herman.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id77dd0b68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">14</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Herman had signed a Confidentiality Statement in which she agreed to hold in confidence all matters that came to her attention in the line of duty at the Society, including: (a) Information gathered from clients; (b) Information about clients; (c) Matters regarding colleagues (personal and work-related); (d) Agency administration information—such as Board discussions, staff discussion and financial information. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiffs alleged Herman breached her duty when she disclosed the following information: (a) providing and sharing internal information with her Committee about alleged harassment against Igwe and Short, and allowing that information to be disseminated in the June 25, 2009 harassment letter; (b) allowing the publication and sharing of internal information with the Committee about a “toxic, hostile environment” at the Society in the July 31, 2009 article, attempts to file human rights complaints, remove the Board and suggesting in the newspaper on September 29, 2009 that the board was terrorizing employees, telling them they will be canned if you do not do what the Board tells you to do.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id77df7c08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">15</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Plaintiffs alleged that Herman was privy to information that she expressly contracted to keep confidential. <eos/><bos/>This information was part of the internal processes of the Board, including internal efforts to resolve employee disputes and allegations of misconduct. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiffs submitted that Herman provided this information to the Committee that she established, and in turn used it to overthrow the Board. <eos/><bos/>However, the trial judge was of the view that it was questionable whether the information specified by the Plaintiffs was indeed confidential and/or communicated in confidence. <eos/><bos/>In terms of the harassment letter, this letter was an attempt by the employees to express their subjective experience of harassment in the workplace to the Board through an internal mechanism provided for under the Society&apos;s Personal Policy Manual. <eos/><bos/>The harassment procedure stated that an employee <begin.quote ID="QT_0005"/>“who wishes to initiate a formal complaint may submit a complaint in writing within 30 days of the alleged occurrence directly to a 3 member grievance team.”<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0005"/> The fact that the letter was written in a collective manner and submitted directly to the Board did not disentitle. <eos/><bos/>Herman from utilizing the harassment procedure and it did not place her in breach of her confidentiality agreement.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id77df7c18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">16</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Moreover, this was not the type of “confidential information” conceived of under this cause of action. <eos/><bos/>Herman disclosed her own personal perception of harassment to employees of the Society, who in turn discussed their experience of harassment with her. <eos/><bos/>They then attempted to use an internal mechanism to communicate their complaint to the Board in order to resolve the issue. <eos/><bos/>In this context, the information shared and provided related to their personal experiences, and was not information for which the Society retained a proprietary right. <eos/><bos/>This information belonged to the employees, and was not communicated in confidence by the Society itself.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id77df7c28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">17</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In terms of the information allegedly discussed by Herman with the Committee, the Plaintiffs had not specifically identified what information they claimed a proprietary right to other than the allegations of harassment between staff and Igwe and Short. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge observed that the case law required that the exact information under which the Plaintiffs claim a proprietary right and the related circumstances must be specifically identified. <eos/><bos/>Beyond the contents of the harassment letter, the Plaintiffs had not sufficiently identified what confidential information Herman has disseminated to their detriment.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id77e45e08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">18</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In terms of the newspaper articles, the comments relating to a “toxic work environment” came from Brown and Oswell, not Herman. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence that these individuals were told of the toxic work environment from Herman, as opposed to other employees within the Society. <eos/><bos/>The unsatisfactory work environment was discussed widely amongst staff, and Herman received approximately ten phone calls during her leave of absence attesting to conflict in the workplace. <eos/><bos/>A similar situation existed with respect to discussions regarding human rights complaints.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id77e45e18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">19</footnote.reference>] Herman&apos;s comment that staff had been terrorized and told that they would be “canned” if they did not do what the board told them to do was stated at the end of September, 2009. <eos/><bos/>This was in reference to comments Cruz made to staff at the May 20, 2009 staff meeting while Herman was on medical leave. <eos/><bos/>Herman was officially fired on July 7, 2009. <eos/><bos/>Herman did not obtain the information in a confidential manner, and thus had not breached any confidentiality provisions.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id77e6cf08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">20</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>If a plaintiff is able to establish that information is confidential and thus of commercial value, the onus shifts to the defendant to show that the information ceased to be secret on the authorization of the plaintiff and thus the plaintiff has suffered no damages.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id77e6cf18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">21</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2026505357" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I51d410318e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Intellibox Concept Inc. v. Intermec Technologies Canada</cite.query> Ltd.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id77e6cf28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">22</footnote.reference>] the plaintiff Intellibox alleged that the defendants breached obligations of confidence owed to the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>The defendants contended that the plaintiff was one of a number of unsuccessful bidders on a potential project to utilize radio frequency identification (RFID) technology in association with recyclable plastic containers (RPCs).<eos/><bos/> Justice Penny concluded that there were no genuine issues requiring a trial and granted summary judgment dismissing this action against all defendants.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id77e6cf38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">23</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Georgia-Pacific manufactured and distributed tissue, packaging, paper, pulp and building products. <eos/><bos/>It used corrugated boxes to ship its own products and sold those boxes to customers for their own use. <eos/><bos/>In 1999, Georgia-Pacific considered introducing RPCs, which offered benefits over one time use corrugated boxes. <eos/><bos/>Georgia-Pacific chose IPL as its principal RPC supplier. <eos/><bos/>Between 2000 and 2009, Georgia-Pacific purchased 10,000,000 RPCs from IPL. <eos/><bos/>In Georgia-Pacific&apos;s business, controlling and tracking the presence of those RPCs was an important element of inventory control. <eos/><bos/>One potential method to do this was through newly emerging RFID technology. <eos/><bos/>One of the obvious applications of RFID technology was to track containers or products through the supply chain. <eos/><bos/>The Intermec defendants were leading RFID innovators. <eos/><bos/>In the late 1990s, Intermec sold its products in Canada both directly (straight to end-use customers) and indirectly (through a network of authorized resellers who, in turn, sold to end-use customers).<eos/><bos/> Before Intellibox existed and before it applied to become an Intermec reseller in 1999, Intermec already had a number of authorized RFID resellers in North America. <eos/><bos/>Intermec had developed container tracking RFID applications before Intellibox existed. <eos/><bos/>In 1998, Richter drafted an RFID educational primer for Intermec resellers. <eos/><bos/>This paper contained a five-page section entitled “RFID and the Supply Chain” which described in detail the potential applications of RFID technology to supply chain logistics. <eos/><bos/>Intermec&apos;s RFID primer was provided to Intellibox in January 2000.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id77e6cf48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">24</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In 1999, Deschenes was a consultant working at Gogh E-Solutions Inc. During this period, he began to investigate the use of RFID technology as a means to track goods through the supply chain. <eos/><bos/>Deschenes claimed to have developed the “Intellibox concept,” a business model by which RFID tags would be affixed to shipping containers, with data being read and written at various points along the containers&apos; journey through the supply chain. <eos/><bos/>In October 1999 Deschene established Intellibox Concept Inc. to carry on with this initiative.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id77e6cf58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">25</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In April 1999 Deschenes was introduced to IPL. <eos/><bos/>IPL was seeking out, for one of its customers, technology which could be used to track RPCs throughout the supply chain. <eos/><bos/>IPL did not initially disclose to Deschenes the identity of this customer, which turned out to be Georgia-Pacific. <eos/><bos/>In June 1999, Deschenes was investigating a number of companies who were developing RFID technology. <eos/><bos/>At this time, Deschenes approached Intermec to determine whether Intermec&apos;s RFID technology would be suitable for the proposed application of attaching RFID tags to RPCs. In July 1999 Deschenes obtained an RFID demonstration kit from Intermec. <eos/><bos/>Deschenes used this kit to demonstrate the capabilities of Intermec&apos;s RFID technology to representatives of IPL. <eos/><bos/>In September 1999, Deschenes entered into an agreement, on behalf of Gogh, with IPL under which IPL was required to purchase any RFID tags exclusively from Gogh. <eos/><bos/>This agreement was later assigned to Deschenes and then to the plaintiff Intellibox. <eos/><bos/>In any event, a new agreement containing the same terms was entered into between Intellibox and IPL on February 17, 2000, for the period January 1, 2000 January 1, 2002.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id77e6cf68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">26</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In October, 1999 IPL arranged for Deschenes to make a presentation about RFID technology to representatives of Georgia-Pacific. <eos/><bos/>Georgia-Pacific was aware that there was some relationship between Intellibox and IPL. <eos/><bos/>By the end of that year, an arrangement was made whereby Georgia-Pacific was permitted to deal directly with Deschenes/Intellibox concerning any purchase of RFID tags.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id77e6cf78e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">27</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>On January 31, 2000, Georgia-Pacific invited proposals from 9 of the 15 identified vendors of RFID technology, by way of a request for quotation. <eos/><bos/>In the RFQ, Georgia-Pacific requested a quotation for a RFID tracking system for RPCs for a project that could require 8 to 10 million RFID tags over 3 to 5 years. <eos/><bos/>It indicated that Georgia-Pacific was looking to select a system integrator or group of suppliers to allow it to build a system to track multiple items across a complex supply chain. <eos/><bos/>Georgia-Pacific identified a list of “musts and wants” which were to be used, respectively, as mandatory requirements and to rank quotations received from vendors. <eos/><bos/>Intellibox was one of seven RFID vendors that responded to the RFQ. Three of the seven respondents, namely Alpha Software, Savi Technology and Intellibox, all proposed the same Intermec RFID tag for use in the project.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id77e94008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">28</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Georgia-Pacific could not make its purchase decision based only upon the written responses to the RFQ and so invited Intellibox, Alpha Software, Savi Technology and Samsys Technologies to meet in Atlanta. <eos/><bos/>Georgia-Pacific&apos;s objective was to allow each of the invited respondents to explain their proposals and to enable Georgia-Pacific to learn more about the various RFID options that were available. <eos/><bos/>All four of the potential suppliers attended the meeting. <eos/><bos/>Alpha Technology, in fact, invited an Intermec representative to attend this meeting to assist in its presentation to Georgia-Pacific. <eos/><bos/>Intellibox attended the meeting alone.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id77e94018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">29</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Following receipt of the RFQ responses, Georgia-Pacific began to test RFID functionality and to confirm its requirements for a system that would track RPCs in the supply chain. <eos/><bos/>Savi Technology volunteered to assist in the testing process and brought with it engineers from Intermec to support the testing. <eos/><bos/>Georgia-Pacific procured 350 RPCs from IPL and bought a similar number of RFID tags directly from Intermec in order to conduct these tests. <eos/><bos/>The RFID tags used for testing were the same as the tags proposed to be used by each of Savi, Alpha and Intellibox in their responses to the RFQ.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id77e94028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">30</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Georgia-Pacific&apos;s testing confirmed that to ensure tracking reliability in field conditions, the RFID tags would have to be encapsulated in some form of plastic container in order to survive periodic washing. <eos/><bos/>Such tags were not available on the market and none of the respondents to the RFQ had proposed an encapsulated tag. <eos/><bos/>Georgia-Pacific, therefore, began to consider the possibility of engaging Intermec to make customized tags to suit its particular requirements.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id77e94038e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">31</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Deschenes heard about Georgia-Pacific&apos;s communications directly with Intermec and requested a meeting on April 17, 2000 with Georgia-Pacific. <eos/><bos/>Deschenes advised that he wanted the opportunity to requote his price and to discuss data collection options and other ways that Intellibox could add further value to RFID technology that would benefit Georgia-Pacific. <eos/><bos/>Three days later, Intellibox delivered a further response to the RFQ. In submitting this second response, Deschenes acknowledged that he understood that Georgia-Pacific <begin.quote ID="QT_0006"/>“will have to make a decision concerning which vendor will be getting the contract.”<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0006"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id77e94048e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">32</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In early May 2000, Georgia-Pacific decided that none of the responses to its RFQ had resulted in satisfactory proposals. <eos/><bos/>Georgia-Pacific decided to ask Intermec to develop, manufacture and deliver a custom, encapsulated RFID tag. <eos/><bos/>Georgia-Pacific wrote to the potential RFID vendors, including Intellibox, to advise them that Georgia-Pacific had concluded that no existing RFID product satisfied its needs and that it had contracted with an existing tag manufacturer to develop a custom tag. <eos/><bos/>Ultimately, on June 1, 2000, Georgia-Pacific and Intermec entered into a purchase agreement for the purchase of custom RFID tags.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id77e94058e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">33</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>On July 1, 2001, Georgia-Pacific entered into an agreement with IPL to purchase a large quantity of RPCs for the pilot project. <eos/><bos/>This agreement required IPL to affix RFID tags, purchased by Georgia-Pacific from Intermec, to the RPCs manufactured by IPL. <eos/><bos/>The project was unsuccessful. <eos/><bos/>Georgia-Pacific never employed the RFID tags on RPCs in its commercial operations.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id77e94068e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">34</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Deschenes maintained that the identity of Intellibox&apos;s possible customer, Georgia-Pacific, was confidential vis-à-vis Intermec. <eos/><bos/>Intellibox argued that, prior to disclosing to Intermec the identity of Intellibox&apos;s potential customer, Intellibox insisted on entering into a proprietary information agreement, which was prepared by Intermec in February 2000. <eos/><bos/>The PIA defined proprietary information as information that either party specifically and expressly identified as proprietary. <eos/><bos/>Intellibox never designated any information as being proprietary under the PIA. <eos/><bos/>Intermec, however, specifically designated information regarding its RFID tags as confidential and proprietary to it. <eos/><bos/>Further, section 4 of the PIA excluded certain types of information from being considered confidential or proprietary: a) information already known to the receiving party; b) information that is already publicly available or in the public domain; c) information rightfully furnished to the receiving party by any third party; and, d) information subsequently developed by the receiving party independently.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id77ebb108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">35</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In Justice Penny&apos;s view, Intellibox&apos;s failure to designate any information provided in connection with the Georgia-Pacific RFQ as confidential under the PIA was fatal to its argument concerning Intermec&apos;s breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>However, even in the absence of this point, Intellibox had not made out a case for breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>First and foremost, Intellibox failed to establish that it provided Intermec with any confidential information. <eos/><bos/>Deschenes was unable to articulate, what Intellibox&apos;s alleged business model specifically consisted of and what about it was confidential. <eos/><bos/>Deschenes admitted that Intellibox added nothing to the RFID hardware he proposed to sell to Georgia-Pacific and that he had not yet developed any software for use in tracking the RPCs.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id77ebb118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">36</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The “business model” Intellibox was pursuing appeared to have been well known in the industry. <eos/><bos/>For example, in September 1998, Samsys Technologies publicly announced the sale of RFIDs for a pilot project which involved installing RFID tags on reusable plastic tote shipping containers to track their movements within the supply chain. <eos/><bos/>Deschenes&apos; attempted descriptions of his business model were essentially no different from the list of “musts and wants” provided in Georgia-Pacific&apos;s RFQ or, for that matter, the contents of Richler&apos;s RFID/supply chain article.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id77ebb128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">37</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Intermec was a leading RFID innovator in its own right and, at the time it first encountered Deschenes, already had a portfolio of 160 RFID patents. <eos/><bos/>Before Intellibox existed, Intermec already had a number of authorized RFID resellers in North America. <eos/><bos/>Intermec was also developing container tracking RFID applications before it ever met Deschenes. <eos/><bos/>Richter, a senior Intermec employee, drafted an RFID educational primer for Intermec resellers in 1998 which contained a five-page section entitled ‘RFID and the supply chain.’ <eos/><bos/>This primer described in detail the potential applications of RFID technology to supply chain logistics. <eos/><bos/>Potential RFID capabilities and applications were, in fact, well known within the supply chain industry in the late 1990s. <eos/><bos/>Indeed, Deschenes admitted on discovery that RFID technology <begin.quote ID="QT_0007"/>“was probably talked [about] a lot in the market”<end.quote refid="QT_0007"/> in the late 1990s and admitted in cross-examination that Intermec would have been aware of the potential for RFID applications in supply chain tracking when Richter authored his 1998 paper.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id77ebb138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">38</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Not only was Intermec already aware of and developing supply chain tracking capabilities in RFID technology before Intellibox existed, Intermec had already helped another customer actually implement them. <eos/><bos/>Before it ever met or knew of Deschenes, it had developed a unique RFID tag for a company called CHEP, a competitor of Georgia-Pacific, for use in connection with CHEP&apos;s own RPCs. It was in fact the Green Tag that Deschenes and Intermec&apos;s other resellers used as the basis for their quotations to Georgia-Pacific in response to Georgia-Pacific&apos;s RFQ.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id77ebb148e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">39</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Accordingly, information regarding the potential use of RFID tags for tracking containers, RPCs or otherwise, through supply chain could not be confidential as it was already known to Intermec, and known widely throughout the industry. <eos/><bos/>Further, the identity of Georgia-Pacific as a potential customer of Intellibox could not be confidential since Georgia-Pacific was an existing Intermec customer and other Intermec resellers besides Intellibox were bidding on the same Georgia-Pacific RFQ. Georgia-Pacific&apos;s needs could not be confidential because they were contained in Georgia-Pacific&apos;s RFQ which was widely distributed to a number of possible suppliers, including at least three Intermec resellers. <eos/><bos/>Likewise, Intermec&apos;s pricing of its products could not possibly be confidential since that pricing was known to Intermec and was provided to other resellers quoting on the Georgia-Pacific RFQ. Further, Intermec was asked by Georgia-Pacific to develop a custom tag as its existing products were determined inadequate for Georgia-Pacific&apos;s needs. <eos/><bos/>This required additional research and development and new, unique pricing for the custom product. <eos/><bos/>A trial was not required to resolve the allegations of breach of confidence against Intermec. <eos/><bos/>There was no genuine issue requiring a trial.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id77ebb158e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">40</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Deschenes claimed that he kept the identity of Intermec, the supplier of his proposed RFID, secret from Georgia-Pacific. <eos/><bos/>Intellibox submitted its proposal to Georgia-Pacific, which was marked “Confidential.” <eos/><bos/>The proposal, Intellibox argued, included specific details as to the RFID tags and hardware that Intellibox proposed to supply and details as to the software Intellibox proposed to develop. <eos/><bos/>Intellibox, on this basis, argued that Georgia-Pacific utilized the information in respect of the Intermec RFID products provided by Intellibox in its proposal in order to solicit a direct quote from Intermec in respect of the same product and to purchase some of those products in order to conduct testing of the RFID tags. <eos/><bos/>This interaction, as alleged by Intellibox, ultimately led to Georgia-Pacific and Intermec&apos;s agreement for the purchase of new custom RFID tags. <eos/><bos/>On this basis, Intellibox argued that Georgia-Pacific misused information delivered to it by Intellibox in confidence.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id77ebb168e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">41</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Penny concluded that Intellibox had not shown there was a genuine issue requiring a trial with respect to the allegations against Georgia-Pacific. <eos/><bos/>Intellibox was unable to demonstrate that any confidential information was, in fact, conveyed. <eos/><bos/>Apart from a very high level description of the Intellibox “business model” and bald statements that “everything” was confidential, Intellibox had not identified any particular sets of information as confidential and had adduced no evidence that would explain the basis upon which it could be said that such information was confidential. <eos/><bos/>The use of RFID technology to track containers in the supply chain was known throughout the industry. <eos/><bos/>The identity of Intermec as a leading supplier of RFID products for applications such as those Georgia-Pacific was looking for was well known to Georgia-Pacific before Intellibox existed. <eos/><bos/>Georgia-Pacific was in fact already a customer of Intermec&apos;s. <eos/><bos/>In any event, Intermec&apos;s identity as a leading manufacturer of RFID technology became apparent from sources other than Intellibox during the RFQ process.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id77ee2208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">42</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Id77da9a08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1983031647" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I51f442608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Fraser v. Thames Television Ltd.</ital>, [1983] 2 All ER. 101 (Q.B.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id77da9a18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1974148438" w-pub-number="0005652" w-pinpoint-page="199" ID="I51f469708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Molnar Lithographic Supplies Ltd. v. Sikatory</ital> (1974), 14 C.P.R. (2d) 197 at p. 199 (Ont. C.A.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id77da9a28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>Saltman Engineering Co. v. Campbell Engineering Co.</ital>, [1963] 3 All E.R. 413<ital>n</ital> (C.A.).<eos/><bos/> See also <cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00007" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1968018312" w-pub-number="0004831" ID="I51f4b7908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Coco v. A.N. Clark (Engineers) Ltd.</ital>, [1969] R.P.C. 41 at p. 4 (Ch.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id77da9a38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>4</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00008" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1985263355" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I51f4dea08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Promotivate International Inc. v. Toronto Star Newspapers Ltd.</ital> (1985), 23 D.L.R. (4th) 196, 53 O.R. (2d) 9 (H.C.J.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id77da9a48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>5</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00009" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042570374" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I51f4dea38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Hamilton v. F&amp;M Management Ltd</ital>., 2017 CarswellBC 2449, 2017 BCSC 1606</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id77da9a58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>6</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00010" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042570374" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I51f52cc08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Hamilton v. F&amp;M Management Ltd</ital>., 2017 CarswellBC 2449, 2017 BCSC 1606</cite.query>, at paras. 3–6.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id77da9a68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>7</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00011" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042570374" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I51f553d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Hamilton v. F&amp;M Management Ltd</ital>., 2017 CarswellBC 2449, 2017 BCSC 1606</cite.query>, at paras. 15–16.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id77dd0b08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>8</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00012" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042570374" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I51f57ae08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Hamilton v. F&amp;M Management Ltd</ital>., 2017 CarswellBC 2449, 2017 BCSC 1606</cite.query>, at paras. 20–21.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id77dd0b18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>9</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00013" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042570374" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I51f5a1f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Hamilton v. F&amp;M Management Ltd</ital>., 2017 CarswellBC 2449, 2017 BCSC 1606, at para. 22</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id77dd0b28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>10</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00014" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042570374" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I51f5c9008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Hamilton v. F&amp;M Management Ltd</ital>., 2017 CarswellBC 2449, 2017 BCSC 1606, at para. 24</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id77dd0b38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>11</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00015" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042570374" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I51f5f0108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Hamilton v. F&amp;M Management Ltd</ital>., 2017 CarswellBC 2449, 2017 BCSC 1606</cite.query>, at paras. 25, and 28–29.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id77dd0b48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>12</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00016" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042570374" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I51f617208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Hamilton v. F&amp;M Management Ltd</ital>., 2017 CarswellBC 2449, 2017 BCSC 1606</cite.query>, at paras. 35–38.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id77dd0b58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>13</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00017" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036372174" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I51f63e308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Kamloops-Cariboo Regional Immigrants Society v. Herman</ital>, 2015 CarswellBC 1437, 2015 BCSC 886</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id77dd0b68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>14</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00018" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036372174" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I51f665408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Kamloops-Cariboo Regional Immigrants Society v. Herman</ital>, 2015 CarswellBC 1437, 2015 BCSC 886</cite.query>, at paras. 4, 6, 9, 16–17, 19, 21, 24, 27, 29, 30, 32–34, 37–38, and 42.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id77df7c08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>15</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00019" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036372174" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I51f6b3608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Kamloops-Cariboo Regional Immigrants Society v. Herman</ital>, 2015 CarswellBC 1437, 2015 BCSC 886</cite.query>, at paras. 110–111.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id77df7c18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>16</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00020" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036372174" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I51f6da708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Kamloops-Cariboo Regional Immigrants Society v. Herman</ital>, 2015 CarswellBC 1437, 2015 BCSC 886</cite.query>, at paras. 116–117.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id77df7c28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>17</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00021" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036372174" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I51f701808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Kamloops-Cariboo Regional Immigrants Society v. Herman</ital>, 2015 CarswellBC 1437, 2015 BCSC 886, at para. 118</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id77e45e08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>18</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00022" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036372174" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I51f728908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Kamloops-Cariboo Regional Immigrants Society v. Herman</ital>, 2015 CarswellBC 1437, 2015 BCSC 886, at para. 119</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id77e45e18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>19</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00023" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036372174" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I51f74fa08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Kamloops-Cariboo Regional Immigrants Society v. Herman</ital>, 2015 CarswellBC 1437, 2015 BCSC 886, at para. 121</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id77e6cf08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>20</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00024" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036372174" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I51f776b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Kamloops-Cariboo Regional Immigrants Society v. Herman</ital>, 2015 CarswellBC 1437, 2015 BCSC 886, at para. 122</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id77e6cf18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>21</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00025" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1985263355" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I51f999908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Promotivate International Inc. v. Toronto Star Newspapers Ltd.</ital> (1985), 23 D.L.R. (4th) 196, 53 O.R. (2d) 9 (H.C.J.), at pp. 198–9</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id77e6cf28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>22</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00026" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026505357" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I51f9e7b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Intellibox Concept Inc. v. Intermec Technologies Canada Ltd.</ital>, 2011 CarswellOnt 12099, 2011 ONSC 4264</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id77e6cf38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>23</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00027" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026505357" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I51fa0ec08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Intellibox Concept Inc. v. Intermec Technologies Canada Ltd.</ital>, 2011 CarswellOnt 12099, 2011 ONSC 4264</cite.query>, at paras. 1–3.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id77e6cf48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>24</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00028" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026505357" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I51fa35d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Intellibox Concept Inc. v. Intermec Technologies Canada Ltd.</ital>, 2011 CarswellOnt 12099, 2011 ONSC 4264</cite.query>, at paras. 4–5.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id77e6cf58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>25</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00029" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026505357" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I51fa5ce08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Intellibox Concept Inc. v. Intermec Technologies Canada Ltd.</ital>, 2011 CarswellOnt 12099, 2011 ONSC 4264, at para. 6</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id77e6cf68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>26</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00030" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026505357" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I51faab008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Intellibox Concept Inc. v. Intermec Technologies Canada Ltd.</ital>, 2011 CarswellOnt 12099, 2011 ONSC 4264</cite.query>, at paras. 7–8.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id77e6cf78e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>27</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00031" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026505357" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I51fad2108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Intellibox Concept Inc. v. Intermec Technologies Canada Ltd.</ital>, 2011 CarswellOnt 12099, 2011 ONSC 4264, at para. 11</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id77e94008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>28</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00032" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026505357" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I51faf9208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Intellibox Concept Inc. v. Intermec Technologies Canada Ltd.</ital>, 2011 CarswellOnt 12099, 2011 ONSC 4264</cite.query>, at paras. 20–21.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id77e94018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>29</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00033" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026505357" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I51fb20308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Intellibox Concept Inc. v. Intermec Technologies Canada Ltd.</ital>, 2011 CarswellOnt 12099, 2011 ONSC 4264, at para. 22</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id77e94028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>30</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00034" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026505357" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I51fb47408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Intellibox Concept Inc. v. Intermec Technologies Canada Ltd.</ital>, 2011 CarswellOnt 12099, 2011 ONSC 4264, at para. 23</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id77e94038e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>31</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00035" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026505357" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I51fb6e508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Intellibox Concept Inc. v. Intermec Technologies Canada Ltd.</ital>, 2011 CarswellOnt 12099, 2011 ONSC 4264, at para. 24</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id77e94048e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>32</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00036" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026505357" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I51fb95608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Intellibox Concept Inc. v. Intermec Technologies Canada Ltd.</ital>, 2011 CarswellOnt 12099, 2011 ONSC 4264, at para. 25</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id77e94058e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>33</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00037" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026505357" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I51fbbc708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Intellibox Concept Inc. v. Intermec Technologies Canada Ltd.</ital>, 2011 CarswellOnt 12099, 2011 ONSC 4264, at para. 26</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id77e94068e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>34</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00038" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026505357" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I51fbe3808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Intellibox Concept Inc. v. Intermec Technologies Canada Ltd.</ital>, 2011 CarswellOnt 12099, 2011 ONSC 4264</cite.query>, at paras. 27–28.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id77ebb108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>35</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00039" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026505357" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I51fc0a908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Intellibox Concept Inc. v. Intermec Technologies Canada Ltd.</ital>, 2011 CarswellOnt 12099, 2011 ONSC 4264</cite.query>, at paras. 54–56.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id77ebb118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>36</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00040" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026505357" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I51fc31a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Intellibox Concept Inc. v. Intermec Technologies Canada Ltd.</ital>, 2011 CarswellOnt 12099, 2011 ONSC 4264</cite.query>, at paras. 61–62.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id77ebb128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>37</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00041" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026505357" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I51fc58b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Intellibox Concept Inc. v. Intermec Technologies Canada Ltd.</ital>, 2011 CarswellOnt 12099, 2011 ONSC 4264, at para. 63</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id77ebb138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>38</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00042" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026505357" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I51fc7fc08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Intellibox Concept Inc. v. Intermec Technologies Canada Ltd.</ital>, 2011 CarswellOnt 12099, 2011 ONSC 4264, at para. 64</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id77ebb148e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>39</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00043" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026505357" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I51fca6d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Intellibox Concept Inc. v. Intermec Technologies Canada Ltd.</ital>, 2011 CarswellOnt 12099, 2011 ONSC 4264, at para. 65</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id77ebb158e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>40</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00044" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026505357" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I51fccde08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Intellibox Concept Inc. v. Intermec Technologies Canada Ltd.</ital>, 2011 CarswellOnt 12099, 2011 ONSC 4264</cite.query>, at paras. 66–67.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id77ebb168e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>41</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00045" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026505357" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I51fd1c008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Intellibox Concept Inc. v. Intermec Technologies Canada Ltd.</ital>, 2011 CarswellOnt 12099, 2011 ONSC 4264</cite.query>, at paras. 68–71.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id77ee2208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>42</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175937" w-seq-number="00046" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026505357" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I51fd43108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Intellibox Concept Inc. v. Intermec Technologies Canada Ltd.</ital>, 2011 CarswellOnt 12099, 2011 ONSC 4264</cite.query>, at paras. 72 and 79.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 6:2<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
