<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 5:13<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I540dc620411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>5.</label.designator><headtext>Claims for Breach of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I540ded30411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>I.</label.designator><headtext>Civil Actions</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I548cba20411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>C.</label.designator><headtext>Breach of Fiduciary Duty</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f6ad686ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>5:13.</label.designator><headtext>Types of Fiduciary Duties Owed—Employee</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>An employee owes a fiduciary duty to the employer where the employee has a sufficient degree of control over the employer&apos;s enterprise to place the employer in a vulnerable position vis-à-vis the employee.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6ed9ea08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id6ed9ea18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>] the trial judge concluded that the director-employee did not owe fiduciary obligations to any of the plaintiffs. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs also alleged that Vinall&apos;s misuse of their confidential and proprietary information constituted a breach of his fiduciary duty. <eos/><bos/>However, because the judge concluded that Vinall did not owe fiduciary obligations to the plaintiffs, the judge did not consider the breach of confidentiality claims within that frame of reference.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6edc5b08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">3</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Sateri organization was an international conglomerate consisting of several corporations. <eos/><bos/>One of its chief undertakings was the production of dissolving wood pulp, including a specialty acetate grade. <eos/><bos/>The defendant Vinall was a mechanical and electrical engineer. <eos/><bos/>He accumulated many years of experience in and extensive knowledge about the global pulp and paper industry, including the manufacture of dissolving pulp and the conversion of a conventional mill to a dissolving pulp facility.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6edc5b18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">4</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge observed that the nub of the plaintiffs&apos; complaint was that Vinall&apos;s knowledge about the Thurso Mill as a possible conversion candidate came to him as a fiduciary and was recommended by him to Sateri in that capacity and in breach of the duties of his office, he assisted a third party, Fortress, to acquire that opportunity. <eos/><bos/>In so doing, the plaintiffs alleged that Vinall placed himself in an impermissible conflict between his personal interest and the fiduciary obligations he owed to them.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6edc5b28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">5</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge observed that the corporate opportunity doctrine is a simple label for a complex construct. <eos/><bos/>The gravamen of the wrong and the fundamental basis of liability under the corporate opportunity rubric is that the fiduciary has permitted self-interest for profit to collide with the heightened duties owed by virtue of his or her fiduciary stature. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge also commented upon the parameters of the doctrine, stating:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>In <cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2010223186" w-pub-number="0006459" ID="I487a43b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Pan Pacific Recycling Inc. v. So</ital>, 2006 BCSC 1337</cite.query>, Sigurdson J. commented that the terminology used in Canaero of a “maturing business opportunity” that the corporation is “actively pursuing”, and the phrase, “ripening business opportunity” used in subsequent cases, are probably misleading insofar as they suggest that fiduciaries are only forbidden from taking opportunities that the corporation is willing and able to pursue. <eos/><bos/>The doctrine has a much wider grasp. <eos/><bos/>Sigurdson J. concluded that for liability to attach, the corporation does not have to establish that but for the fiduciary breach it would have pursued the opportunity and would have made the profit in question. <eos/><bos/>The rigour of the principle referred to by Sigurdson J. was affirmed by the Court of Appeal in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2012444287" w-pub-number="0006458" ID="I487a43b28e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Canadian Metals Exploration Ltd. v. Wiese</ital>, 2007 BCCA 318[Canadian Metals]</cite.query>, which held, at para. 19, that a fiduciary may not make personal use of an opportunity even where the corporation is unable to take it up or has declined to pursue it: see also, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2012388816" w-pub-number="0006489" ID="I487a43b48e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>3464920 Canada Inc. v. Strother</ital>, 2007 SCC 24</cite.query>.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0001"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id6edc5b38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">6</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><paratext>The trial judge noted that the extent to which the business opportunity must have “matured” is unsettled.<eos/><bos/></paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>In a case that Mr. Vinall relies on, <ital>Donor Gateway Inc. v. Passero</ital>, 2007 CarswellOnt 724at para. 14 (Ont S.C.J.), the court held that the business opportunity had to be a “prize ready for immediate grasping”.<eos/><bos/> However, in <ital>Blue Line Hockey Acquisition Co. v. Orca Bay Hockey Ltd. Partnership</ital>, 2009 BCCA 34at para. 61, the Court of Appeal, without deciding the issue, postulated:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext>If and when the point is ever argued, then, a Canadian court might well take the view that the appropriation of an opportunity “belonging to” a corporation by a director or former director merit equitable intervention even where the opportunity is not a “mature” one.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0002"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id6edc5b48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">7</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Vinall had been aware of the suitability of the Thurso Mill as a potential conversion mill long before he joined Sateri. <eos/><bos/>In performing his work assignment at Sateri, he learned that Fraser Papers was under creditor protection, a fact that was within the public domain. <eos/><bos/>Vinall regarded Fraser Papers&apos; financial descent as a significant plus in terms of the attractiveness of acquiring the Thurso Mill and was one the reasons he recommended the Thurso Mill to Sateri. the chief strategic decision-maker, were those he expressed at the October 8 Meeting. <eos/><bos/>Vinall was instructed to attend that meeting at the last minute, and not as a decision-maker, but as someone with stock technical knowledge of mills in Canada. <eos/><bos/>During the October 8 Meeting, little more than introductory remarks had been made about the Thurso Mill before Tanoto, the chief strategic decision-maker, halted the discussion by expressing his unqualified and unchallenged rejection of it. <eos/><bos/>It was also significant to the judge that there was an absence of evidence to indicate that Tanoto underwent a change of mind on the matter after the October 8 Meeting or that the plaintiffs subsequently adopted a different stance. <eos/><bos/>The very notion of the Thurso Mill as a candidate for conversion by Sateri was preliminary and superficial. <eos/><bos/>It was essentially over before it began and did not even rise to the threshold of being the subject matter of a considered discussion.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6edc5b58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">8</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The evidence about whether the plaintiffs had reached a decision concerning the Thurso Mill was not inconclusive. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge found that with Tanoto&apos;s unequivocal decree of rejection of the Thurso Mill at the outset, it was not even raised as a possible prospect before the board at the Second October Meeting, the subsequent board meeting in December 2009, or ever.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6edecc08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">9</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiffs&apos; primary contention was that there was a per se fiduciary relationship between Vinall and Sateri Singapore and Sateri International Co. flowing from his appointment as a director of each. <eos/><bos/>The second ground asserted was that, quite apart from his status as a director, Vinall derived his fiduciary obligations from his role as a senior officer and a member of high-level management in the Sateri enterprise. <eos/><bos/>They submitted that Vinall qualified as a fiduciary under the top management and key employee tests.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6edecc18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">10</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiffs argued that Vinall breached all such fiduciary duties through his secret relationship with Fortress by: a) entering that relationship with the aim of setting up a business that would compete with them; b) assisting Fortress in establishing a competing business while he was still employed by them; c) profiting from the Thurso Mill opportunity that came to his attention by virtue of his position with them; d) using their resources, confidential information and work product in pursuing the Thurso Mill opportunity and providing the same to Fortress; and e) withholding material facts from them regarding both his involvement with Fortress and the nature of the opportunity that he and Fortress were pursuing.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6edecc28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">11</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Vinall was not appointed a director of Sateri Singapore and Sateri International Co. until he signed consents to act as such effective December 26, 2009. <eos/><bos/>At that time, he had been working at Sateri for close to one year. <eos/><bos/>He was never appointed a director of his employer, Sateri Shanghai.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6edecc38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">12</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Several of the specific allegations of breach of fiduciary duty against Vinall pertained to his alleged misconduct that occurred before his first directorship, for example, planting the seeds to appropriate the Thurso Mill opportunity and to secretly compete with his employer. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs conceded that Vinall&apos;s appointments as director did not have any retrospective effect and did not impose fiduciary obligations in the pre-directorship period. <eos/><bos/>With respect to that period (and afterward), the plaintiffs relied on the key employee test and the <ital>Frame</ital> analysis to establish Vinall&apos;s elevated stature of a fiduciary.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6edecc48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">13</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge considered it logical to begin by determining whether Vinall owed fiduciary duties to any of the plaintiffs before he entered into a <ital>per se</ital> fiduciary relationship with Sateri International Co. and Sateri Singapore as a result of being appointed a director.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6edecc58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">14</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Vinall had acquired extensive experience in and knowledge of the operation of conventional and dissolving pulp mills and of the conversion of the former to the latter long before he was hired by Sateri Shanghai. <eos/><bos/>He was recruited by Sateri because of the breadth of his credentials in those areas.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6edecc68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">15</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Vinall&apos;s position in the organization did not unfold in the manner that he and Sateri executive management had envisaged. <eos/><bos/>The effort required to stabilize and improve the running of the Bahia Mill was considerably more challenging and time-consuming than had been forecast. <eos/><bos/>Vinall had little choice but to continue to concentrate on the day-to-day mill operations long after the initial six month period had elapsed, and even throughout the tenure of his employment. <eos/><bos/>Once the Vinall family relocated to Singapore, Vinall maintained his routine of working roughly three weeks of the month at the Bahia Mill and returning to his family base approximately every fourth week. <eos/><bos/>Substantially all of the business he engaged in while at the Singapore head office pertained to operational issues of the Bahia Mill. There were less than a small handful of exceptions to this. <eos/><bos/>One of them was the short-lived assignment he received in early October 2009 to provide input and collaborate with Li to identify potential mill candidates for conversion.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6ee13d08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">16</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>There was little cogent evidence about the nature of Vinall&apos;s authority over his managers. <eos/><bos/>Despite the fact that they reported directly to him, he was not allowed to make any staff changes in respect of them unless he first obtained approval from head office. <eos/><bos/>He was likewise not entitled to independently hire or terminate other senior employees at the Bahia Mill, or an employee who worked across jurisdictions. <eos/><bos/>The ambit of his authority with respect to the hiring and firing of lower-level staff was also constrained. <eos/><bos/>He was only permitted to fill vacancies at the Bahia Mill in respect of jobs that ranged from entry-level to mid-management, although not for all departments. <eos/><bos/>Even then, he was without authority to increase the overall employee headcount; that decision was reserved for head office management. <eos/><bos/>All decisions pertaining to the salaries and wages of the employees at the Bahia Mill and the plantation were set and controlled by human resources in Shanghai or Singapore, and not by Vinall. <eos/><bos/>He had no involvement in hiring senior staff or management level employees to fill positions at head office or outside the Bahia Mill and plantation.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6ee13d18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">17</footnote.reference>] Vinall&apos;s authority relative to financial matters pertaining to the Bahia Mill and the plantation was also circumscribed. <eos/><bos/>The financial side of the Brazilian operations were managed centrally in Singapore and, the designated financial employee on the ground at the Bahia Mill did not answer or report to Vinall. <eos/><bos/>The monetary ceiling imposed upon Vinall&apos;s entitlement to incur capital expenditures was relatively modest.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6ee13d28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">18</footnote.reference>] Vinall did not collaborate in the making of any higher level financial and economic decisions, for example, how to hedge against marketplace risk relative to any of the plaintiffs or Sateri&apos;s businesses. <eos/><bos/>He did not play a role of any importance in the budgetary process in respect of any of the plaintiffs.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6ee13d38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">19</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge concluded that it had not been shown that Vinall had broad access to financial and strategic confidential information of the nature and import that, if disclosed, left any of the plaintiffs susceptible to material harm or had the potential of significantly impairing their competitive advantage.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6ee13d48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">20</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Vinall&apos;s participation in the identification of mill candidates for conversion to dissolving pulp did not stand as an exception. <eos/><bos/>He was not part of management&apos;s pre-discussions as to whether and why a mill conversion might be a prudent growth mode for the organization. <eos/><bos/>The strategic decision to explore that option as a possibility had already been made by those ranking above Vinall at the executive management level before he became aware of the matter and received instructions to carry out his small part. <eos/><bos/>Vinall&apos;s assignment was simply to compile a list of recommended mill targets in collaboration with others and, on short notice, make a presentation at an early stage of the budgeting process. <eos/><bos/>The assignment was not unique to Vinall. <eos/><bos/>Li, Shaohua and Van Lee had each received similar instructions.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6ee13d58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">21</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Overall, the evidence revealed very little about how any of the plaintiffs might be vulnerable, even in theory, to the exercise of power or discretion granted to Vinall. <eos/><bos/>The Sateri organization followed a classically top-down management model, with a multi-layer hierarchy of management and authority over its various business interests. <eos/><bos/>Although Vinall ran the Bahia Mill, he was not a member of the plaintiffs&apos; upper management empowered to make decisions of consequence with regard to that business operation or any other. <eos/><bos/>Although he was given the impressive title of “President of Upstream” and later “President Specialty Cellulose”, Vinall was not an actual corporate officer of any plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>The restrictions imposed upon his discretion, power, and authority were very much by design and his actions were significantly overseen by the superior ranks of executive management for the purpose and in a manner that effectively safeguarded the plaintiffs&apos; interests and the valuable Bahia Mill. Though Vinall was expected to assume a significantly more enhanced management role once the Bahia Mill was running satisfactorily, that eventuality did not come about. <eos/><bos/>Instead, and despite his impressive title, Vinall&apos;s power and authority remained narrow and highly controlled and his discretion significantly fettered and constrained. <eos/><bos/>Had he been conferred with the extensive and high-level profit and loss power and authority for the upstream operation he had been recruited to do, he may well have owed fiduciary obligations to the plaintiffs, but he had not been.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6ee13d68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">22</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>An examination of the nature and scope of the power, authority and discretion delegated to Vinall and his responsibilities with respect to the Bahia Mill, the planation and, more crucially, relative to the plaintiffs showed that Vinall was not imbued with the distinguishing hallmarks of the fiduciary dynamic before he was appointed as a director. <eos/><bos/>He was not vested with the autonomy to exercise his limited delegated power, authority or discretion in a manner that could genuinely direct, affect or alter the legal, economic or vital practical interests of any of the plaintiffs or steer the management of their affairs. <eos/><bos/>He did not undertake to act in an utterly selfless manner so as to elevate him to the stature of a fiduciary. <eos/><bos/>Vinall&apos;s controlled and constrained authority did not leave the plaintiffs in a position of vulnerability.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6ee13d78e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">23</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Vinall&apos;s conduct was not above reproach. <eos/><bos/>He violated provisions of the Sateri Employment Contract and Declaration and breached his implied contractual duties of fidelity, good faith and loyalty. <eos/><bos/>It was incumbent on the Court to avoid the trap of reading equity backwards by reasoning that, on account of that misconduct, Vinall owed fiduciary duties to the plaintiffs.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6ee3ae08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">24</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>It was alleged that Vinall&apos;s responsibilities and those of other senior management cut “across multiple companies” in the Sateri “Group”.<eos/><bos/> The trial judge did not accept this evidence as remotely accurate. <eos/><bos/>Nevertheless, the plaintiffs asserted that based on this assertion, the language of the Sateri Employment Contract that linked most of Vinall&apos;s contractual obligations to the wider “Group”, and pursuant to the common employer doctrine, Vinall&apos;s fiduciary obligations were owed to all members of the “Sateri International Group”.<eos/><bos/> In support of their assertion, the plaintiffs relied on the following statement by Stacey Ball in the 1999 edition of Canadian Employment Law, adopted by the Ontario Court of Appeal in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2001348816" w-pub-number="0005506" ID="I4896f3708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Downtown Eatery (1993) Ltd. v. Ontario</ital> (2001), 54 O.R. (3d) 161 at para. 1</cite.query>, leave to appeal refused, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2002057095" w-pub-number="0006741" ID="I4896f3728e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">[2001] S.C.C.A. No. 397</cite.query>:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0003"/>The courts now recognize that, for purposes of determining the contractual and fiduciary obligations which are owed by employers and employees, an individual can have more than one employer. <eos/><bos/>The courts now regard the employment relationship as more than a matter of form and technical corporate structure. <eos/><bos/>Consequently, the present law states that an individual may be employed by a number of different companies at the same time.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0003"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0004"/>In the 2013 update of Mr. Ball&apos;s text, Canadian Employment Law, loose-leaf (Toronto: Canada Law Book, 2013-) at § 13.30.3(5), he writes:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext>Fiduciary obligations referred to in Canaero have been found to be owed not merely to the employee&apos;s immediate employer, but also to related companies of a corporate employer. <eos/><bos/>Consequently, just as the courts will go behind the corporate veil and find an employee to be employed by a “group enterprise”, fiduciary obligations can be owed to a “corporate group”.<eos/><bos/> This approach is sound in that, since corporate groups can owe employees common law obligations, there is nothing in policy or principle against a fiduciary employee owing obligations which extend beyond the technical employer in appropriate cases.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0004"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id6ee3ae18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">25</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge was skeptical of the <ital>quid pro quo</ital> reasoning that says simply because related corporate entities can owe duties to an employee of one of their affiliated companies, the employee may, in return, owe fiduciary duties to the corporate group as a whole. <eos/><bos/>The trial judge observed that it would be a most exceptional, even rare, case that would justify finding that an employee owed a fiduciary duty to an affiliated company of the actual employer, solely on the basis of the interrelation between those companies, and where there is an absence of factors that support a fiduciary relationship with the affiliate in the first place. <eos/><bos/>If the employee does not exercise a robust level of unilateral power, authority and discretion over the affiliate&apos;s vital interests and affairs and the affiliate is not vulnerable to the employee, it does not seem equitable to impose a fiduciary duty on that employee as regards the affiliate. <eos/><bos/>In doing so, the so-called fiduciary employee, who is unable to meaningfully participate in the management of the affiliate or influence its affairs, is held to a stringent standard of conduct without being granted any of the powers normally associated with such a burden. <eos/><bos/>The affiliated company thus reaps the benefit of being owed a fiduciary duty without ever assuming the risk of making itself vulnerable to the exercise of the discretion, power and authority of the employee in question. <eos/><bos/>This kind of logic would also allow for a backdoor to create a fiduciary duty where one would not otherwise exist.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6ee3ae28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">26</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Moreover, and in any event, in order for the doctrine to apply, the employee must first owe fiduciary duties to his or her immediate employer. <eos/><bos/>Only where that threshold exists, would the principle apply in appropriate cases to lift the corporate veil of the other corporations of the corporate group so as to extend the fiduciary employee&apos;s fiduciary obligations beyond the “technical employer” to the wider corporate group. <eos/><bos/>That threshold connection had not been proven in this case.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6ee3ae38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">27</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Vinall was aware that the Sateri Employment Contract stated he could be appointed a director of any company that fell within the broadly defined Sateri “Group” of companies, and that he was required to accept the appointment. <eos/><bos/>He therefore gave it little thought and assumed that he was being appointed as a mere matter of corporate convenience and expediency. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence to indicate that Mr. Vinall was advised about the appointments in advance or after they were made, or was told what they entailed. <eos/><bos/>He was not provided with any of the documents referred to in the consents. <eos/><bos/>Vinall did not attend an official board meeting of any of the plaintiffs or any Sateri company of which he was made a director. <eos/><bos/>He was not kept informed as to whether any such meetings had been convened, and was not supplied with an agenda or meeting minutes.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6ee3ae48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">28</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiffs asserted that the law of fiduciary duty does not recognize a nominal, passive or dummy director. <eos/><bos/>Their contention was that, as a matter of law, all directors owe fiduciary duties to their respective corporations.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6ee61f08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">29</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge concluded that Vinall was not a fiduciary in relation to the plaintiffs and did not owe them fiduciary duties, under the key employee test. <eos/><bos/>It was to be emphasized that his responsibilities and the nature and ambit of his power, autonomy and discretion did not change after he was appointed a director of Sateri International Co. and Sateri Singapore or the non-plaintiff companies.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6ee61f18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">30</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Vinall&apos;s <ital>per se</ital> fiduciary relationship with Sateri International Co. and Sateri Singapore borne out of his directorships of those corporations did not carry the essential characteristics inherent in a fiduciary relationship. <eos/><bos/>The fact that Vinall had little choice under the provisions of the Sateri Employment Contract but to accept those appointments lent support to the finding that he did not enjoy the rank of a true fiduciary. <eos/><bos/>So too did the fact that his job description and work assignments could be determined by his superiors at any time, and that he could be seconded to any of the companies within the “Group” at the pleasure of management. <eos/><bos/>This was an exceptional case of the kind envisaged by Sopinka J. in <ital>Lac Minerals</ital> where the presumption that Vinall&apos;s status as a director imposed fiduciary obligations upon him, had been rebutted by cogent evidence. <eos/><bos/>Vinall&apos;s stature as a director of Sateri International Co. and Sateri Singapore simply did not suffice. <eos/><bos/>In the material timeline Vinall was not in a fiduciary relationship with, and owed no fiduciary obligations to, any of the plaintiffs.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6ee61f28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">31</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Breach of confidence is a <ital>sui generis</ital> hybrid claim with roots in the common law and in equity. <eos/><bos/>The three-part test for the claim of breach of confidence provides that 1. the information must have a necessary quality of confidence about it; 2. the circumstances under which the information was imparted must give rise to an obligation of confidence; and, 3. the defendant must have made unauthorized use of the information. <eos/><bos/>In <ital>Lac Minerals</ital>, Justice Sopinka endorsed two general categories of confidential information: information that is confidential because it has not been made public; and information that may have been assembled from publicly available materials, but amounts to a confidential work product because its assembly required the application of some independent thought process. <eos/><bos/>The judge also observed that there is also authority for the proposition that information generally known within a particular industry may not qualify as confidential: <cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1984192374" w-pub-number="0006690" ID="I48a090608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Monarch Messenger Services Ltd. v. Houlding</ital>, [1984] A.J. No. 1018, 56 A.R. 147 (Alta. Q.B.)</cite.query>, at para. 18; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00007" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1985195536" w-pub-number="0006574" ID="I48a090638e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Lake Mechanical Systems Corp. v. Crandell Mechanical Systems Inc.</ital>, [1985] B.C.W.L.D. 2373, [1985] B.C.W.L.D. 2422 (B.C. S.C.)</cite.query> [<cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00008" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1985195536" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48a090668e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">1985 CarswellBC 453 (B.C. S.C.)</cite.query>].[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6ee61f38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">32</footnote.reference>] The threshold for establishing confidentiality is a low one. <eos/><bos/>However, the law recognizes a continuum of specialness with respect to confidentiality, and that the placement of such information on that continuum may affect the remedy awarded for a breach.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6ee61f48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">33</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiffs&apos; paramount contention in their claims for breach of confidence was that Vinall misused their confidential information in the wrongful pursuit of the Thurso Mill opportunity and in aid of his wrongful competition with them while still employed, for the benefit of himself and Fortress. <eos/><bos/>The specific components of the plaintiffs&apos; claims for breach of confidence were that during Vinall&apos;s employment, he converted and misappropriated the confidential and proprietary information learned and otherwise obtained during his employment with Sateri International; disclosed, used, removed and published to others confidential and proprietary information, without the consent or license of Sateri International; and negotiated new employment terms with Fortress.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6ee61f58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">34</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Most of the plaintiffs&apos; documents alleged to contain their confidential information were marked as <begin.quote ID="QT_0005"/>“confidential and intended solely for the use and information of the addressee”<end.quote refid="QT_0005"/>. <eos/><bos/>However, the designation of confidentiality was merely a page template that was automatically applied to every document that was created for the plaintiffs, irrespective of content. <eos/><bos/>Consequently, the appearance of that standard warning was not probative of whether the information contained in the imprinted documents was confidential under the applicable jurisprudence or pursuant to the Employment Contract or the Declaration.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6ee61f68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">35</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The particulars provided by the plaintiffs divided the alleged breaches into two main classifications. <eos/><bos/>They distinguished confidential and proprietary information said to be misused by Vinall from information alleged to have been wrongfully converted by all of the defendants into a Fortress presentation. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs asserted that the category one documents contained confidential and proprietary information about their business plans, including the plan for expansion of their cellulose business and consideration of the opportunity to acquire the Thurso Mill. Vinall was said to have copied these documents from his work laptop to a USB stick. <eos/><bos/>The four documents were: 1. The list prepared by Shaohua of the closed mill candidates with the accompanying map of North America showing the respective locations and proximity to seaports of the mills, both bearing Van Lee&apos;s highlighting. <eos/><bos/>The only evidence as to the sources of the information he used to compose the list were Shaohua&apos;s notations on the document crediting RISI and Hawkins Wright. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence to suggest that any information in the list was not within the public domain. <eos/><bos/>It was conceded that preparation of the map of North America would have taken only a few minutes and that the information could be obtained by using Google; 2. An email exchange attaching the chart showing three potential Canadian mill candidates and a map of Canada pinpointing their locations; 3. The minutes of the October 8 Meeting; and 4. The same map of North America referred to in item 1, but with a different heading, which was circulated for purposes of the Second October Meeting, together with the agenda of that meeting.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6ee89008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">36</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Assuming that the information contained in the category one documents qualified as confidential, the judge concluded that the argument nonetheless faltered on the sheer absence of cogent evidence that Vinall improperly disclosed or otherwise misused such information. <eos/><bos/>That was a full answer to the claims asserted on all grounds with respect to the information alleged to be confidential in the category one documents.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6ee89018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">37</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The evidence surrounding the plaintiffs&apos; claims concerning the confidentiality of the contents of the category two documents was nearly as underwhelming. <eos/><bos/>In carrying out her examination of the documents in the shared folder, Li found two multi-page Fortress presentations that she concluded contained Sateri&apos;s internal information. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs&apos; response to Li&apos;s findings was of interest. <eos/><bos/>Evidently, they were too pre-occupied by Sateri International Co.&apos;s public offering to address the misuse of their confidential information thought to be discovered by Li in a timely way. <eos/><bos/>It was not until several months afterwards that a general issue regarding Vinall&apos;s alleged misuse of confidential information was raised by the plaintiffs. <eos/><bos/>The judge observed that it is difficult to reconcile the plaintiffs&apos; uncontroverted evidence that the Sateri organization was highly protective of Sateri&apos;s internal and confidential information, with their prolonged inaction to Li&apos;s apparent discovery of misuse. <eos/><bos/>Although by no means conclusive, the plaintiffs&apos; casual reaction, especially in those crucial early months, was not an entirely neutral factor in the analysis. <eos/><bos/>It suggested that they were not overly concerned about the defendants&apos; disclosure or use of the information in question.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6ee89028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">38</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The contents of the category two documents that the plaintiffs asserted embodied their confidential and/or proprietary information included: 1. A table listing several mills and their respective capacities for dissolving pulp on a page titled, Current and Planned Dissolving Pulp Capacity; 2. A vertical bar chart showing the proportionate market share of synthetic fiber, cellulose fiber and natural fiber respectively from 2002 to 2008; 3. A bar graph expressing world cotton production over a period of time and a two-line linear graph comparing the cotton yield worldwide with the cotton yield for China; 4. A bullet point statement and a formula expressing the yield potential of wood-based fiber as compared to cotton-based fiber; and 5. A projection and correlation reflecting a prediction of the future demand for rayon in different parts of the world.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6ee89038e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">39</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Vinall reproduced the Fortress Table from an appendix to an internal report that Li had prepared for Sateri. <eos/><bos/>The appendix was not made available outside of the Sateri organization and its group of corporate affiliates. <eos/><bos/>Vinall did not deny that he received the internal report, with the appendix, in confidence.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6ee89048e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">40</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The judge found implausible Li&apos;s assertion that the information contained in the appendix was based entirely on Sateri&apos;s internal records. <eos/><bos/>The probabilities of the situation showed that the appendix contained a mix of a substantial amount of publicly accessible data that Li had not altered, as well as a small bit of information that was uniquely hers and was confidential to the plaintiffs. <eos/><bos/>The information within that latter category consisted chiefly of the references to the Tiger Forestry &amp; Paper and Sateri Rudong mills and, to a much lesser extent, to the dissolving pulp capacities of a few of the mills. <eos/><bos/>The totality of such confidential information carried a low grade of specialness. <eos/><bos/>The Fortress Table was one of 47 pages of the PowerPoint presented to the Quebec government. <eos/><bos/>During the course of that presentation, they did not discuss the content of the slides item-by-item. <eos/><bos/>The judge considered it unlikely that they would have highlighted or placed any emphasis on the few marginally special features of the Fortress Table that were confidential to the plaintiffs, or that the representatives of the Quebec government in attendance even noticed that information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6ee89058e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">41</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The judge&apos;s rejection of the plaintiffs&apos; allegations that the Thurso Mill was a taken opportunity and that Vinall was a fiduciary effectively dispelled the legitimacy of any assertion that the plaintiffs suffered a form of detriment stemming from the misuse of the bits of confidential information in the Fortress Table. <eos/><bos/>Any suggestion that the plaintiffs&apos; detriment took the form of their professed loss of a share of the dissolving pulp market in China occasioned by the Thurso Mill competing in that market, was similarly groundless. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs had not shown that they sustained any detriment, whether financial or of another kind, as a result of the misuse of the confidential information in the Fortress Table. <eos/><bos/>The absence of a demonstrated detriment was fatal to this aspect of their claim sounding in breach of confidence.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6ee89068e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">42</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Fortress Market Share Chart consisted of seven vertical bars that expressed the market share of three different kinds of fiber: synthetic, cellulosic and natural. <eos/><bos/>A separate colour was ascribed to each fiber so that each individual bar was made up of three colours to denote the proportionate market share of the three fibers. <eos/><bos/>The Fortress Market Share Chart was the same as a market share chart that appeared in a Sateri document prepared by Li. <eos/><bos/>Li had created her chart from information in her database that had been compiled by CIRFS, a fiber society in Europe. <eos/><bos/>That information was publicly available. <eos/><bos/>Yet, Li had not credited any external source on her chart. <eos/><bos/>The Fortress Market Share Chart cited the USDA (2009) as its source. <eos/><bos/>According to Li, the USDA would only be a partial but not a complete source for the information because that agency does not compile information on the global production of rayon. <eos/><bos/>That said, she went on to acknowledge that data about the world rayon supply expressed in market shares was publicly available. <eos/><bos/>Li further agreed that information about the worldwide market share of the three fibers in question was readily available in the public domain from sources other than the fiber society she relied upon or the USDA. <eos/><bos/>Whether, and to what extent, if any, Li brought to bear her own thought-process or unique treatment or assembly of the public information she used to create the plaintiffs&apos; market share chart was, at best, murky. <eos/><bos/>In the end, Li&apos;s primary assertion seemed to be no better than she “thought” she had at least chosen the tri-colour scheme of the bars. <eos/><bos/>Even assuming that Li did take a moment to choose the colour scheme of the bars in the chart she prepared, the straightforward act of using an Excel computer program to select those colours did not require that she exercise an independent thought process of the kind contemplated in <ital>Lac Minerals</ital> so as to imbue her composition with the requisite threshold of confidence. <eos/><bos/>Re-colouring bars that are accessible in the public domain had no substantive effect, and was in the nature of an inconsequential aesthetic tweaking. <eos/><bos/>The judge concluded that it would upend the governing principles and confuse the underlying policy rationale in this area of law were the Court to accept that the threshold of confidentiality lay that low. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs&apos; market share chart did not contain confidential information within the meaning of the breach of confidence authorities or pursuant to the provisions of Vinall&apos;s Sateri Employment Contract or the Declaration. <eos/><bos/>It followed that the Fortress Market Share Chart did not contain the plaintiffs&apos; confidential information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6eeb0108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">43</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Fortress Cotton Production Graph and Fortress Cotton Yield Graph were virtually identical to graphs that appeared in a pre-existing Sateri document titled, Upside Risks, prepared by Li. <eos/><bos/>The USDA was shown as the source on the face of both the Sateri and Fortress documents. <eos/><bos/>The preponderance of the evidence was that Vinall created the two Fortress graphs simply by cutting and pasting the graphs from the Upside Risks document prepared by Li. <eos/><bos/>Both of the USDA documents were accessible on the Internet. <eos/><bos/>There were two differences between the USDA cotton production graph and the one prepared by Li, namely the colour coding and the years used to bookend the vertical bars. <eos/><bos/>There were also differences in the colours, timeline and a few of the plot points used in the USDA graph reflecting the cotton yields, as compared to Li&apos;s graph capturing those yields. <eos/><bos/>The difference in years was readily explainable by the fact that the USDA version had been obtained from the Internet at a later point in time. <eos/><bos/>That the plaintiffs&apos; graphs were not identical to the two USDA graphs, did not necessarily mean that the plaintiffs&apos; graphs were not among the extensive publicly available materials on the USDA website, and relied upon by Li, at the time she prepared them. <eos/><bos/>The judge was left to speculate on whether, and to what extent, if any, Li may have applied her own brain power or signature treatment or assembly of the USDA data that she downloaded and used in preparing the plaintiffs&apos; cotton production and cotton yield graphs. <eos/><bos/>The judge concluded that the evidence did not establish that those graphs contained the plaintiffs&apos; confidential information by any standard. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, the Fortress Cotton Production Graph and the Fortress Cotton Yield Graph do not contain the plaintiffs&apos; confidential or proprietary information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6eeb0118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">44</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Fortress Yield Information was comprised of a statement and a formula. <eos/><bos/>Sateri&apos;s pre-existing Upside Risks document contained an identical statement and a practically identical formula. <eos/><bos/>The formula in the Sateri document reflected the wood-fibre output of the Bahia Mill as compared to a cotton-based yield; the formula in the Fortress Yield Information expressed the output of the Thurso Mill. Neither document credited an external source for the statement or the formula. <eos/><bos/>Vinall agreed that he had basically typed out the Fortress Yield Information from a Sateri document he had on hand. <eos/><bos/>He then changed the spelling of “fiber” to “fibre” and lowered the MAI factor from 35 to 25 to account for the difference in the expected yield from maple-based fiber (the Thurso Mill) as opposed to eucalyptus (the Bahia Mill).<eos/><bos/> Those changes then altered the final outcome number. <eos/><bos/>Li acknowledged that the MAI in the equation would vary depending on the wood variety and the geography of the wood source, and that such a variation would result in a different yield outcome. <eos/><bos/>According to Li, the statement and formula represented her uniquely conceived work product. <eos/><bos/>She maintained that no aspect of it was publicly available. <eos/><bos/>Vinall was adamant that the formula used in the Fortress Yield Information, as well as the formula appearing in the plaintiffs&apos; document, reflected an accepted industry-wide calculation regularly used to contrast the wood yield of fiber to the cotton fiber yield. <eos/><bos/>He persuasively maintained that he had used the formula many times in the past, and that there was nothing special about the concept it conveyed. <eos/><bos/>The judge concluded that it was more probable than not that the formula used by Li was widely known and applied broadly in the industry to calculate the difference in fiber yields, subject simply to variations in the inputting of the MAI factor and the consequential change to the yield outcome. <eos/><bos/>Still, her statement was an elegant articulation of information demonstrated by application of the formula that she composed using her thought process and was not publicly accessible. <eos/><bos/>The judge concluded that the statement, but not the formula, in the Fortress Yield Information was confidential to the plaintiffs. <eos/><bos/>In terms of specialness, the statement fell at the lowest end of the continuum.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6eeb0128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">45</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>There was, however no evidence to support a finding that the plaintiffs experienced a detriment of any kind on account of the defendants&apos; misuse of the confidential statement contained in the Fortress Yield Information. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, the plaintiffs&apos; claim for breach of confidence failed. <eos/><bos/>As in the case of the Fortress Table, Vinall&apos;s misuse of the confidential statement was in violation of his contractual obligations.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6eeb0138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">46</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiffs alleged that perhaps the most valuable information conveyed by Vinall to Fortress was his own conclusion that the Thurso Mill was an appropriate candidate for conversion. <eos/><bos/>They alleged that, because he made that determination in the course of and as a result of his employment, it was confidential to the plaintiffs. <eos/><bos/>The judge agreed that Vinall&apos;s assessment of the suitability of the Thurso Mill for Sateri was confidential to the plaintiffs; so too was his disclosure that Sateri had passed on it as a conversion prospect. <eos/><bos/>The judge found it implausible that Wasilenkoff would have been prepared to move on the Thurso Mill assets merely on Vinall&apos;s say so during the October 2009 Call. <eos/><bos/>The judge found an absence of detriment stemming from Vinall&apos;s disclosure. <eos/><bos/>Although a breach of confidence claim could not be made out, Vinall&apos;s disclosure of this confidential information was made in violation of his contractual obligations.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6eeb0148e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">47</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A finding of an employee as “key” does not necessarily mean the employee was in a fiduciary capacity to the company.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6eed7208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">48</footnote.reference>] In <ital>Zoic Studios BC Inc. v. Gannon</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id6eed7218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">49</footnote.reference>] the employer was a computer visual effects studio which specialized in feature films, television shows, commercials, video games, advertising and online content. <eos/><bos/>Zoic LA chose willing employees to relocate to Vancouver to set up the office. <eos/><bos/>Two senior employees were chosen including the defendant. <eos/><bos/>In 2008, the employee was elevated to executive creative director. <eos/><bos/>She also held the role of visual effects supervisor. <eos/><bos/>The employee reported directly to Zoic LA.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge concluded that substantively there is little difference between the categorical and principled approach to determining whether an employee is a fiduciary, stating:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0006"/>… It appears the ability of the employee to control the legal or economic interests of the employer is an important function of the fiduciary in both approaches.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0006"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0007"/>In any case, under either approach I cannot find that Ms. Gannon stood in a fiduciary position to Zoic BC. Admittedly, this is a case that comes very close to the line. <eos/><bos/>Had Ms. Gannon had any additional authority I would have concluded that she was in a fiduciary position. <eos/><bos/>As it stands, however, in my view, Ms. Gannon did not rise to that level.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0007"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0008"/>It is not disputed that Ms. Gannon had never occupied the position of an officer or director of Zoic BC. Equally, it is also not disputed that Ms. Gannon was the “top employee” in Zoic BC. This fact alone, however, is not enough to engender a fiduciary relationship between Ms. Gannon and Zoic BC.<end.quote refid="QT_0008"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id6eed7228e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">50</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Under either approach, the trial judge could not find that the employee stood in a fiduciary position to the employer. <eos/><bos/>The fact that she was the “top employee” in Zoic BC was not enough to establish a fiduciary relationship between the employee and the employer. <eos/><bos/>The evidence did not support a finding that the employee had the ability to affect her employer&apos;s legal or economic interests, an element that is necessary for both the principled and the categorical approaches to determination of fiduciary status:[<footnote.reference refid="Id6eed7238e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">51</footnote.reference>]</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0009"/>In summary, I find that while Ms. Gannon was the top employee in Vancouver, her control and authority of the company was significantly limited by Zoic LA. She had the authority to hire and dismiss, but this was limited to transitional hires. <eos/><bos/>She did not have any sort of authority that could affect the financial or legal interests of Zoic BC. She could not spend more than $1,000 without approval, she could not unilaterally change daily rates charged to clients. <eos/><bos/>She could not contractually bind Zoic BC. Her position did not put Zoic BC in a vulnerable position.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0009"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id6eed7248e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">52</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0010"/>The trial judge also observed that the structure of the employer must be viewed in relation to Zoic LA. The employer was a wholly owned subsidiary. <eos/><bos/>It would be artificial to view the structure of the employer on its own, without regard to the guiding influence and oversight of Zoic LA. While the employee may have been the “top employee”, she still answered to the management of Zoic LA. The management of Zoic LA was the top management of both Zoic studios. <eos/><bos/>The control and authority of Zoic BC lay with them. <eos/><bos/>The employee did not have the authority to sign contracts for Zoic BC to provide visual effects to clients. <eos/><bos/>If she did not have the authority to bind Zoic BC to provide the one and only service it was designed to provide, it is difficult to see how she could have guided the interests of Zoic BC in any significant way. <eos/><bos/>While the defendant was the top employee in Vancouver, her control and authority of the company was significantly limited by Zoic LA. She had the authority to hire and dismiss, but this was limited to transitional hires. <eos/><bos/>She did not have any sort of authority that could affect the financial or legal interests of Zoic BC. She could not spend more than $1,000 without approval, she could not unilaterally change daily rates charged to clients. <eos/><bos/>She could not contractually bind Zoic BC. Her position did not put Zoic BC in a vulnerable position.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0010"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id6eed7258e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">53</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>On appeal, the main thrust of the appellant&apos;s position was that the Trial Judge focused almost entirely on whether the employee had the legal authority to bind Zoic BC, and/or whether her authority at Zoic BC was unfettered and that the Trial Judge failed to consider whether the employee exercised discretionary power to affect Zoic BC&apos;s practical interests.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6eed7268e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">54</footnote.reference>] In dismissing the ground of appeal relating to breach of fiduciary duty, Justice Chiasson observed that the trial judge examined very thoroughly the authority of the employee, was alive to the law of fiduciary duty and that she considered the effect of the employee&apos;s authority on the interests of Zoic BC. The trial judge made no error of law. <eos/><bos/>Her findings of fact were supported by the evidence.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6eefe308e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">55</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Court of Appeal allowed the appeal to the extent only of remitting the matter to the trial judge with the direction that she consider whether an equitable accounting should be ordered arising out of the personal respondents&apos; breach of their duty of fidelity and loyalty by competing with the appellant.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6eefe318e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">56</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In these circumstances, the employee is precluded from making improper use of confidential trade secrets and from soliciting directly or indirectly the customers of his or her former employer.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6eefe328e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">57</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A key employee is one who generally is responsible for guiding the business affairs of the employer, is involved in the decision-making process or is someone having access to confidential information that if disclosed could impair competitive advantage that the employer enjoys. <eos/><bos/>In <ital>Laplante v. Hennessy-Craibe</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id6eefe338e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">58</footnote.reference>] the plaintiff had operated the business of Pascalina&apos;s since 1992. <eos/><bos/>The defendant, a student at Pascalina&apos;s between 1993 and 1995, became a teacher&apos;s aide at Pascalina&apos;s in 1996 and an instructor in 1998. <eos/><bos/>Her duties as an instructor included choreography, choosing and purchasing costumes, as well as choosing hair styles and make-up for recitals and competitions. <eos/><bos/>In 2008 the defendant entered into an employment agreement with Pascalina&apos;s for employment to teach dancing. <eos/><bos/>There was no restrictive covenant in the employment agreement. <eos/><bos/>In 2011 the defendant set up her own dance school business, competing with the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>The court concluded that the defendant&apos;s responsibility for the plaintiff&apos;s business did not come close to the necessary elements required for a key employee as outlined by Richardson J.A. in <ital>Imperial Sheet Metal Ltd. v. Landry</ital>:[<footnote.reference refid="Id6eefe348e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">59</footnote.reference>]</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0011"/>74. <eos/><bos/>Richardson J.A. In Imperial Sheet Metal suggested the following non-exhaustive code of necessary elements as to what are the constituent elements for a key employee to attract the fiduciary obligation suggested here by the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>A “key” employee is: (1) an integral and indispensable component of the management team that is responsible for guiding the business affairs of the employer; (2) necessarily involved in the decision-making process; and (3), therefore, has broad access to confidential information that if disclosed would significantly impair the competitive advantages that the former employer enjoyed. <eos/><bos/>These employees fall within the categories: “top management”, “senior management” or “key management”.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0011"/></paratext></para></display.quote><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The fact that several students and instructors followed her to her new business did not in and of itself constitute proof of the plaintiff&apos;s claim that the defendant was a key employee. <eos/><bos/>The defendant returned or destroyed all registration forms and any and all other property of Pascalina&apos;s that she had in her possession.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6eefe358e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">60</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Planit Search Inc. v. Mann</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id6eefe368e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">61</footnote.reference>] the fact that Soucy, a “Senior Account Manager” for the plaintiff who did not have persons reporting to him, may have been privy the plaintiff&apos;s databases which might have contained some confidential information regarding candidates or clients to perform his work, did not by itself, mean that Soucy was a fiduciary of the plaintiff.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff was a placement agency which specialized in IT personnel with expertise in enterprise resource planning software. <eos/><bos/>Soucy was a commissioned recruiting contractor. <eos/><bos/>His duties were to post available positions, identify and contact potential employee, set up interviews with possible candidates and place selected candidates in the available positions. <eos/><bos/>In between periods of employment with the plaintiff, Soucy worked as a recruitment contractor for competitors of the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>Soucy now worked for a competitor.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6ef25408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">62</footnote.reference>] During the 14 years during which the plaintiff had operated, it created a database of about 80,000 IT candidates, being persons with IT expertise mostly in the ERP area. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff also created a database which included approximately 12,000 clients who used IT personnel with the required IT skills. <eos/><bos/>Some of the candidates and clients in the databases had never been involved in any business arrangement with the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>The candidates in the database were better described as candidates and potential future candidates. <eos/><bos/>Likewise, the clients in the database were better described as clients and potential clients. <eos/><bos/>The databases were available to the plaintiff&apos;s employees to help them generate business for the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>After his departure from the plaintiff, Soucy contacted some potential candidates including some which the plaintiff alleged were “its candidates” from the databases and IBM, which the plaintiff alleged was “its client” from the databases, for the purpose of placing employees in the IT area. <eos/><bos/>However, the court concluded that it was not known whether those persons or company were in the plaintiff&apos;s databases or what information there was about them. <eos/><bos/>It was not known if they were actual candidates and clients of the plaintiff or potential candidates or clients. <eos/><bos/>It was not known whether the information regarding them was publicly available or known to competitors in the industry. <eos/><bos/>It was not known whether they had a contract with the plaintiff and, if so, on what terms.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6ef25418e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">63</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The court concluded that there was no evidence that Soucy was in a position to make any managerial or corporate decisions on behalf of the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>He had no discretion to make such decisions on behalf of the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>Given his previous comings and goings at the plaintiff, it was hard to imagine that the plaintiff would consider him a key or high level employee or provide Soucy with any discretionary authority for serious matters. <eos/><bos/>There were no other hallmarks of a fiduciary relationship. <eos/><bos/>There was not an “above-average level of trust” in or responsibility given to Soucy.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6ef25428e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">64</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>For the purposes of a motion for an interlocutory injunction, the court in <ital>GDI Solutions Inc. v. Walker</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id6ef25438e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">65</footnote.reference>] did not need to consider whether there was a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that the other named defendants were fiduciaries of GDL, as there was a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that Walker was a fiduciary of GDL and the other named defendants were impressed with fiduciary duties by joining Walker at Hudson in a competing business. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff GDL discovered that the defendant Walker, the individual from whom it purchased the GDL business, had, with several of his former subordinates and employees at GDL, joined a newly established direct competitor that was actively soliciting GDL clients. <eos/><bos/>Walker had started the information technology business in 2003. <eos/><bos/>GDL purchased the business, including its goodwill, technology, and book of business, from Walker in early 2010. <eos/><bos/>As a condition of the purchase, Walker became general manager of GDL, and expressly covenanted not to compete with GDL, solicit or accept business from its clients, solicit or employ its employees, or misuse its confidential information during his employment and for a period thereafter. <eos/><bos/>In June 2011, Walker was introduced to Evershed and Jankovic, a former employee of GDL. Evershed was planning to expand his IT business to Ottawa. <eos/><bos/>He incorporated Hudson on October 24, 2011. <eos/><bos/>Jankovic helped to set up Hudson. <eos/><bos/>In November of 2011, Walker and Mears both left GDL. Walker advised GDL that he was going to do consulting work and Mears advised that he was going to work for his father, an IT consultant. <eos/><bos/>Both joined Hudson. <eos/><bos/>Hudson then began to offer a CPR-like service for data recovery. <eos/><bos/>There were only two companies other than GDL and Hudson offering such a service. <eos/><bos/>Other employees also joined Hudson.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6ef25448e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">66</footnote.reference>] There was no evidence that any of the defendants other than Walker had an employment agreement or a non-compete/non-solicitation agreement with the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>Fiduciary obligations attach to employees who depart with fiduciaries to work with competitive businesses. <eos/><bos/>Were it otherwise, the fiduciary would be permitted to do indirectly what he or she cannot do directly. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff met the tests, that there was a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case made out, that misappropriation of GDL&apos;s data and use of confidential information gave rise to the probability of irreparable harm and that the balance of convenience favoured the plaintiff in this regard.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6ef25458e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">67</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Fiduciary relationships are often used as grounds for an action for breach of confidential business information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id6ef25468e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">68</footnote.reference>] However, unlike any of the other grounds for an action for breach of confidential information, only equitable remedies are available for breach of fiduciary duty.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Id6ed9ea08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00009" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1973144068" w-pub-number="0005150" ID="I48d275d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Canadian Aero Service Ltd. v. O&apos;Malley</ital> (1973), 40 D.L.R. (3d) 371, [1974] 1 S.C.R. 592</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00010" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1984185977" w-pub-number="0005505" ID="I48d275d38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesta Manufacturing Ltd. v. Babey</ital> (1984), 48 O.R. (2d) 94, 29</cite.query> B.L.R. 36 (H.C.J.); <cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00011" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1987290159" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I48d275d58e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Dialadex Communications Inc. v. Crammond</ital> (1987), 34 D.L.R. (4th) 392, 57 O.R. (2d) 746 (H.C.J.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00012" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1977148370" w-pub-number="0005150" ID="I48d275d88e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgar T. Alberts Ltd. v. Mountjoy</ital> (1977), 79 D.L.R. (3d) 108, 16 O.R. (2d) 682 (H.C.J.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00013" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1986267377" w-pub-number="0005653" ID="I48d275db8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Abrams v. Ross Wemp Motors Ltd.</ital> (1986), 12 C.P.R. (3d) 87 (Ont. H.C.J.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00014" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1986186861" w-pub-number="0005653" ID="I48d275de8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Profast (London) Ltd. v. Wright</ital></cite.query> (1986), 14 C.P.C. (2d) 284, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00015" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1986186861" w-pub-number="0005653" ID="I48d275df8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">14 C.P.R. (3d) 118 (Ont. H.C.J.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ed9ea18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00016" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d2eb008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6edc5b08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00017" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d312108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491, at para. 461</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6edc5b18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>4</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00018" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d339208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491</cite.query>, at paras. 3 and 6.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6edc5b28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>5</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00019" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d360308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491, at para. 317</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6edc5b38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>6</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00020" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d387408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491</cite.query>, at paras. 326–327.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6edc5b48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>7</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00021" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d3ae508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491, at para. 328</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6edc5b58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>8</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00022" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d3d5608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491</cite.query>, at paras. 329, and 333–334.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6edecc08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>9</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00023" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d3fc708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491, at para. 336</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6edecc18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>10</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00024" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d423808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491</cite.query>, at paras. 365–369.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6edecc28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>11</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00025" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d44a908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491, at para. 373</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6edecc38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>12</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00026" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d471a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491, at para. 379</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6edecc48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>13</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00027" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d498b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491, at para. 380</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6edecc58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>14</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00028" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d4bfc08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491, at para. 381</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6edecc68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>15</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00029" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d4e6d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491</cite.query>, at paras. 382–383.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ee13d08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>16</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00030" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d50de08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491</cite.query>, at paras. 385–386.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ee13d18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>17</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00031" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d55c008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491</cite.query>, at paras. 393–394.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ee13d28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>18</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00032" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d583108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491</cite.query>, at paras. 396–399.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ee13d38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>19</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00033" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d5aa208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491</cite.query>, at paras. 400–402.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ee13d48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>20</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00034" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d5d1308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491</cite.query>, at paras. 405–406.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ee13d58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>21</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00035" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d5f8408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491, at para. 407</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ee13d68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>22</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00036" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d61f508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491</cite.query>, at paras. 413–414.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ee13d78e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>23</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00037" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d646608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491, at para. 415</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ee3ae08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>24</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00038" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d66d708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491, at para. 416</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ee3ae18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>25</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00039" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d694808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491</cite.query>, at paras. 417–419.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ee3ae28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>26</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00040" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d6bb908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491</cite.query>, at paras. 427–428.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ee3ae38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>27</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00041" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d6e2a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491, at para. 430</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ee3ae48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>28</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00042" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d709b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491</cite.query>, at paras. 434–436.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ee61f08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>29</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00043" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d730c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491, at para. 437</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ee61f18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>30</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00044" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d757d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491, at para. 452</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ee61f28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>31</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00045" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d77ee08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491</cite.query>, at paras. 453–454.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ee61f38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>32</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00046" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d7a5f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491</cite.query>, at paras. 462–466.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ee61f48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>33</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00047" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d7cd008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491, at para. 467</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ee61f58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>34</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00048" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d81b208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491</cite.query>, at paras. 484–485.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ee61f68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>35</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00049" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d842308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491, at para. 486</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ee89008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>36</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00050" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d869408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491</cite.query>, at paras. 488–489.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ee89018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>37</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00051" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d890508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491, at para. 499</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ee89028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>38</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00052" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d8b7608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491</cite.query>, at paras. 500–504.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ee89038e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>39</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00053" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d8de708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491, at para. 508</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ee89048e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>40</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00054" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d8de738e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491, at para. 509</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ee89058e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>41</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00055" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d92c908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491</cite.query>, at paras. 512–513.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ee89068e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>42</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00056" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d953a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491</cite.query>, at paras. 514–515.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6eeb0108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>43</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00057" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d97ab08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491</cite.query>, at paras. 518–525.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6eeb0118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>44</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00058" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d9a1c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491</cite.query>, at paras. 526, 531, and 533.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6eeb0128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>45</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00059" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d9c8d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491</cite.query>, at paras. 534, 538–541, and 544–545.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6eeb0138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>46</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00060" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48d9efe08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491, at para. 547</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6eeb0148e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>47</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00061" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2041322458" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48da16f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sateri (Shanghai) Management Ltd. v. Vinall</ital>, 2017 CarswellBC 786, 2017 BCSC 491</cite.query>, at paras. 559–560.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6eed7208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>48</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00062" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028621307" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48da65108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Zoic Studios BC Inc. v. Gannon</ital>, 2012 CarswellBC 2792, 2012 BCSC 1322 (B.C. S.C.)</cite.query>, at para. 98.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6eed7218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>49</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00063" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028621307" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48da8c208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Zoic Studios BC Inc. v. Gannon</ital>, 2012 CarswellBC 2792, 2012 BCSC 1322 (B.C. S.C.)</cite.query>, at paras. 3–9.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6eed7228e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>50</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00064" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028621307" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48dab3308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Zoic Studios BC Inc. v. Gannon</ital>, 2012 CarswellBC 2792, 2012 BCSC 1322 (B.C. S.C.)</cite.query>, at paras. 112–114.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6eed7238e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>51</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00065" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028621307" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48dada408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Zoic Studios BC Inc. v. Gannon</ital>, 2012 CarswellBC 2792, 2012 BCSC 1322 (B.C. S.C.)</cite.query>, at paras. 133–135 and 149–150.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6eed7248e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>52</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00066" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028621307" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48db28608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Zoic Studios BC Inc. v. Gannon</ital>, 2012 CarswellBC 2792, 2012 BCSC 1322 (B.C. S.C.)</cite.query>, at para. 181.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6eed7258e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>53</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00067" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028621307" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48db4f708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Zoic Studios BC Inc. v. Gannon</ital>, 2012 CarswellBC 2792, 2012 BCSC 1322 (B.C. S.C.)</cite.query>, at para. 115.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6eed7268e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>54</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00068" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036767826" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48db76808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Zoic Studios B.C. Inc. v. Gannon</ital>, 2015 CarswellBC 2077, 2015 BCCA 334, at para. 61</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6eefe308e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>55</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00069" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028621307" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48db9d908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Zoic Studios BC Inc. v. Gannon</ital>, 2012 CarswellBC 2792, 2012 BCSC 1322 (B.C. S.C.)</cite.query>, at para. 62.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6eefe318e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>56</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00070" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028621307" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I48dbc4a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Zoic Studios BC Inc. v. Gannon</ital>, 2012 CarswellBC 2792, 2012 BCSC 1322 (B.C. S.C.)</cite.query>, at para. 91.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6eefe328e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>57</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00071" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1973144068" w-pub-number="0005150" ID="I48dc60e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Canadian Aero Service Ltd. v. O&apos;Malley</ital> (1973), 40 D.L.R. (3d) 371, [1974] 1 S.C.R. 592</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00072" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1985030763" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I48dc60e38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Faccenda Chicken Ltd. v. Fowler</ital>, [1986] 1 All E.R. 617 (C.A.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00073" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1984185977" w-pub-number="0005505" ID="I48dc60e58e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesta Manufacturing Ltd. v. Babey</ital> (1984), 48 O.R. (2d) 94, 29</cite.query> B.L.R. 36 (H.C.J.); <cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00074" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1977148370" w-pub-number="0005150" ID="I48dc60e78e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgar T. Alberts Ltd. v. Mountjoy</ital> (1977), 79 D.L.R. (3d) 108, 16 O.R. (2d) 682 (H.C.J.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00075" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1986186861" w-pub-number="0005653" ID="I48dc60eb8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Profast (London) Ltd. v. Wright</ital></cite.query> (1986), 14 C.P.C. (2d) 284, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00076" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1986186861" w-pub-number="0005653" ID="I48dc60ec8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">14 C.P.R. (3d) 118 (Ont. H.C.J.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00077" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1986268597" w-pub-number="0003986" ID="I48dc60ee8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Hudson&apos;s Bay Co. v. McClocklin</ital>, [1986] 5 W.W.R. 29, 42 Man. R. (2d) 283 (Q.B.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6eefe338e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>58</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00078" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026261395" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I48dcd6108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Laplante v. Hennessy-Craibe</ital>, 2011 CarswellOnt 10270, 2011 ONSC 5601</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6eefe348e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>59</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00079" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2012535541" w-pub-number="0005474" ID="I48dcfd208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Imperial Sheet Metal Ltd. v. Landry</ital>, 2007 CarswellNB 298, 2007 NBCA 51</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6eefe358e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>60</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00080" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026261395" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I48dd24308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Laplante v. Hennessy-Craibe</ital>, 2011 CarswellOnt 10270, 2011 ONSC 5601</cite.query>, at paras. 2–3, 5, 18, 21, 23, 28.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6eefe368e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>61</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00081" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2031914048" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I48dd24338e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Planit Search Inc. v. Mann</ital>, 2013 CarswellOnt 15233, 2013 ONSC 6847</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ef25408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>62</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00082" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2031914048" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I48dd72508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Planit Search Inc. v. Mann</ital>, 2013 CarswellOnt 15233, 2013 ONSC 6847</cite.query>, at paras. 2–3, 7 and 35.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ef25418e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>63</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00083" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2031914048" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I48dd99608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Planit Search Inc. v. Mann</ital>, 2013 CarswellOnt 15233, 2013 ONSC 6847</cite.query>, at paras. 10–11, 14–15 and 22–23.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ef25428e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>64</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00084" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2031914048" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I48ddc0708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Planit Search Inc. v. Mann</ital>, 2013 CarswellOnt 15233, 2013 ONSC 6847</cite.query>, at paras. 32–34.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ef25438e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>65</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00085" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028418359" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I48dde7808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>GDI Solutions Inc. v. Walker</ital>, 2012 CarswellOnt 9889, 2012 ONSC 4378</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ef25448e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>66</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00086" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028418359" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I48de0e908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>GDI Solutions Inc. v. Walker</ital>, 2012 CarswellOnt 9889, 2012 ONSC 4378</cite.query>, at paras. 1, 6 and 12–14.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ef25458e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>67</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00087" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2028418359" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I48de35a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>GDI Solutions Inc. v. Walker</ital>, 2012 CarswellOnt 9889, 2012 ONSC 4378</cite.query>, at paras. 81–82, 93 and 96.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id6ef25468e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>68</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00088" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1986187661" w-pub-number="0005653" ID="I48e0f4c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Gemologists International Inc. v. Gem Scan International Inc.</ital> (1986), 9 C.P.R. (3d) 255 (Ont. H.C.J.), at p. 258</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175924" w-seq-number="00089" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1979092475" w-pub-number="0005150" w-pinpoint-page="706" ID="I48e0f4c28e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Schauenburg Industries Ltd. v. Borowski</ital> (1979), 101 D.L.R. (3d) 701 at p. 706, 25 O.R. (2d) 737 (H.C.J.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 5:13<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
