<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 8:20<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I59ba4210411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>8.</label.designator><headtext>Practical Advice for Protecting Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I59fa7f60411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>III.</label.designator><headtext>Employment Duties and Written Contracts</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I5a022080411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>B.</label.designator><headtext>Restrictive Covenants</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f749dc6ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>8:20.</label.designator><headtext>Generally</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The most common method used by employers to protect their confidential information is the restrictive covenant. <eos/><bos/>Such covenants can take various forms and generally seek to restrain, within a specified geographical area and for a certain time, an employee&apos;s post-employment activities. <eos/><bos/>While we will not repeat the legal principles outlined in the last chapter, it is useful to briefly review some principles which will help to improve the chances of enforceability of restrictive covenants.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In general, any restraint with respect to confidential information should be as specific as possible. <eos/><bos/>While a broad description will obviously form the foundation of such covenants, effort should be made to ensure that specific information of importance to the business is highlighted in all agreements and discussions with the employee. <eos/><bos/>The danger in attempting to define the confidential information covered by the agreement is the possibility of leaving out something of importance. <eos/><bos/>It is therefore wise to maintain a balance which restricts the use of confidential information generally, but also states that such information will include, but not be limited to, certain specific information as defined. <eos/><bos/>Finally, the circumstances under which a restrictive covenant is signed should be recorded by memorandum or notes whenever possible.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A number of contract law doctrines can be utilized by employees in an effort to avoid post-employment restrictions. <eos/><bos/>These doctrines focus primarily on the relative bargaining power of the parties. <eos/><bos/>Most covenants will be drafted and imposed by the employer. <eos/><bos/>As a result, the burden of establishing the reasonableness of the covenant will be placed upon the employer. <eos/><bos/>Further, the legal maxim <ital>contra proferentum</ital> applies, and the courts will construe any ambiguity or dispute against the drafter of the covenant.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In the case law, it has been consistently recognized that a restrictive covenant must be of a limited and reasonable duration.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id9b634808e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>] The courts have made it clear that a covenant which prevents competition altogether is more likely to be struck down than a restraint which only prohibits the solicitation of specific clients of the former employer. <eos/><bos/>While a broader covenant may still be enforceable, where possible, covenants should be tailored to the circumstances in order to improve the likelihood of enforcement. <eos/><bos/>For example, in a situation where customers will come to rely on a certain employee, perhaps to the virtual exclusion of the business and others, the employer may want to go so far as to list specific customers in the covenant.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>What will be considered reasonable with regard to restraints placed on a former employee&apos;s competitive activities will depend upon the facts of the individual case. <eos/><bos/>The employee&apos;s position is particularly important. <eos/><bos/>A reasonable duration will usually be the length of time necessary for the employer to develop an employee to fill the position that was vacated. <eos/><bos/>More specifically, the employer must be allowed to solidify its interest in corporate opportunities and customer connections. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, historical information which demonstrates the time required to fill a position and solidify the employer&apos;s interests should be maintained in company records.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The case law has also limited restrictive covenants to a reasonable geographical area.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id9b634818e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>] Where an employer&apos;s business is established over a specific area or territory, covenants should focus on that same area or territory. <eos/><bos/>Even then, the courts will alter this basic premise where it can be established that such a restraint is unreasonable in the circumstances. <eos/><bos/>For example, in a large urban area with many competitors, it may be necessary to limit the non-competition clause to solicitation of the customers and contacts of the business.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id9b634828e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">3</footnote.reference>] Also, the courts will not prevent a former employee from competing for clients who are not serious potential customers of the employer. <eos/><bos/>Thus a non-competition clause may need to be restricted to the areas in which the employee was personally connected or involved during the course of his or her employment.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id9b634838e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">4</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Some employers will include an injunctive relief clause by which the recipient acknowledges that the disclosing party would suffer irreparable harm as a result of any breach of confidentiality and that, as a result, the disclosing party should be entitled to a court order restraining the recipient from breaching the provisions of the agreement. <eos/><bos/>While such a clause is not binding on the courts, it stresses the seriousness of the obligations involved and provides evidence that an injunction may be an appropriate remedy in the circumstances.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Since it is often difficult to determine what the courts will consider to be a reasonable covenant, many employers make use of a series of clauses or subclauses which outline different geographical restraints and scopes of prohibited activity. <eos/><bos/>This allows the court to decide what is reasonable without rendering the entire covenant unenforceable. <eos/><bos/>As long as the integrity of the covenant can be maintained, the courts may be willing to “sever” a restrictive covenant.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id9b65b908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">5</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Id9b634808e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>See, for example, <cite.query w-src-number="0492176001" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1966075753" w-pub-number="0005149" ID="I78c787808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Northern Messenger (Calgary) Ltd. v. Frost</ital> (1966), 57 D.L.R. (2d) 456, 56 W.W.R. 412 (Alta. S.C.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492176001" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1981180250" w-pub-number="0004655" ID="I78c787838e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Reed Shaw Osler Ltd. v. Wilson</ital> (1981), 35 A.R. 451</cite.query>, 17 Alta. L.R. (2d) 81 (C.A.); <cite.query w-src-number="0492176001" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1983171047" w-pub-number="0005150" ID="I78c787858e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Western Inventory Service Ltd. v. Sager</ital> (1983), 148 D.L.R. (3d) 434, 42 O.R. (2d) 166 (H.C.J.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id9b634818e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492176001" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1975145700" w-pub-number="0005150" ID="I78c7d5a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Computer Centre Personnel Ltd. v. Lagopoulos</ital> (1975), 58 D.L.R. (3d) 352, 8 O.R. (2d) 480 (H.C.J.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id9b634828e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492176001" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1961017647" w-pub-number="0005149" ID="I78c7fcb08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Gordon v. Ferguson</ital> (1961), 30 D.L.R. (2d) 420, 38 C.P.R. 1 (N.S.S.C.)</cite.query>, <case.history>affd</case.history> [1962] S.C.R. viii, <cite.query w-src-number="0492176001" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1962062052" w-pub-number="0005151" ID="I78c7fcb38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">40 C.P.R. 43</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id9b634838e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>4</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>See, for example, <cite.query w-src-number="0492176001" w-seq-number="00007" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1923021271" w-pub-number="0005162" ID="I78c823c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Dominion Art Co. v. Murphy</ital> (1922), 54 O.L.R. 332, 23 O.W.N. 453 (S.C.A.D.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id9b65b908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>5</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492176001" w-seq-number="00008" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1983171968" w-pub-number="0005150" ID="I78c871e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Nelson Burns &amp; Co. v. Gratham Industries Ltd.</ital> (1983), 150 D.L.R. (3d) 692, 42 O.R. (2d) 705 (H.C.J.)</cite.query>, <case.history>affd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492176001" w-seq-number="00009" w-ref-type="ER" w-normalized-cite="30DLR4CA158n" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I78c871e38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">30 D.L.R. (4th) 158<ital>n</ital>, 55 O.R. (2d) 426<ital>n</ital> (C.A.)</cite.query>, leave to appeal to S.C.C. refused <cite.query w-src-number="0492176001" w-seq-number="00010" w-ref-type="ER" w-normalized-cite="56OR2CA604n" w-pub-number="0005505" ID="I78c871e68e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">56 O.R. (2d) 604<ital>n</ital>, 18 O.A.C. 238<ital>n</ital></cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 8:20<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
