<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 2:7<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I4e5fc390411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>2.</label.designator><headtext>Legal Bases Used by the Courts for the Protection of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I4e678bc0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>II.</label.designator><headtext>Property Theory</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f5c3126ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>2:7.</label.designator><headtext>Criticism—Difficulty in Determining Questions of Liability</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Gareth Jones, one of the leading commentators on the law of confidential information, cites what he states are two difficulties in determining liability if the property theory is invoked by the courts. <eos/><bos/>One problem is the imposition of liability on a person who innocently exploits a secret:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>No property theory can satisfactorily determine, even with the aid of equity, the question of the liability of the person who innocently exploits a secret. <eos/><bos/>For example, there may be circumstances where it is just that a volunteer would be free of any liability to account for profits made through the use of confidential information.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0002"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id0ccb6008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The second problem involves the liability of third parties who are strangers to the confidential relationship. <eos/><bos/>Gareth Jones states that, in the case of confidential business information, <begin.quote ID="QT_0004"/>“the defendant and others claiming from, through, or under him shall not knowingly take unfair advantage of the plaintiff&apos;s confidence”<end.quote refid="QT_0004"/>. <eos/><bos/>There is an obligation to act in good faith. <eos/><bos/>Unconscionable conduct is to be deterred. <eos/><bos/><begin.quote ID="QT_0003"/>“The fact that a plaintiff may obtain relief against third parties who acquire such information is not a manifestation of a proprietary interest in confidential information but merely of an equitable good faith doctrine.”<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0003"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id0ccdd108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>] Finally, Jones argues that even if the belief of the defendant is reasonable at the time the information is acquired, as soon as the defendant discovers that the information is confidential, he or she has an equitable obligation to the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>This would be so even if the defendant were a bona fide purchaser for value without notice. <eos/><bos/>It has been argued, however, that only the property theory satisfactorily determines the question of the liability of the person who innocently exploits a secret. <eos/><bos/>All other theories lead to the conclusion that there is no liability, which is contrary to the findings in many of the cases.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id0ccdd118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">3</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175822" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1967018556" w-pub-number="0004891" ID="I145592118e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Seager v. Copydex</cite.query> Ltd.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id0ccdd128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">4</footnote.reference>] for example, the plaintiff was negotiating with the defendant to manufacture and distribute his invention to improve carpet grip. <eos/><bos/>Without being requested by the defendant, he disclosed the details of his invention in the course of negotiations. <eos/><bos/>After the negotiations had failed, the defendant began manufacturing a carpet grip similar to the plaintiff&apos;s. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff was awarded damages for breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>It was held on appeal that:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0007"/>The law on this subject does not depend on any implied contract. <eos/><bos/>It depends on the broad principle of equity that he who has received information in confidence shall not take unfair advantage of it. <eos/><bos/>He must not make use of it to the prejudice of him who gave it without obtaining his consent.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0007"/></paratext></para></display.quote><paratext>This ruling was given even though there was no evidence of any conscious plagiarism of the plaintiff&apos;s invention. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff simply provided the defendant with the germ of an idea which, over a prolonged period, the defendant developed. <eos/><bos/>More importantly, the Court of Appeal expressly held that the defendant company and its officers had not acted in bad faith.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Similarly, in <ital>Talbot v. General Television Corporation Pty. Ltd.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id0ccdd138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">5</footnote.reference>] Harris J. held that an employee of a television station had subconsciously drawn upon the memory of what he had been told by the plaintiff, although the defendant&apos;s employee honestly thought the idea was his own. <eos/><bos/>Harris J. concluded, on the basis of this finding, that the television company should be restrained from making use of the idea which was originally imparted by the plaintiff in confidence.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Neither of these two cases can be explained using the equitable doctrine of good faith, as, in both cases, there was no evidence of bad faith on the part of the defendant.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175822" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1968018312" w-pub-number="0004831" ID="I14567c718e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Coco v. A.N. Clark (Engineers)</cite.query> Ltd.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id0cd04208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">6</footnote.reference>] Megarry J. attempted to resolve the problem by applying the common law reasonable man test to the equitable doctrine of good faith:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0010"/>It seems to me that if the circumstances are such that any reasonable man standing in the shoes of the recipient of the information would have realized that upon reasonable grounds the information was given to him in confidence, then this should suffice to impose upon him the equitable obligation of confidence.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0010"/></paratext></para></display.quote><paratext>The reasonable man test is problematic where a defendant acts honestly but unreasonably and gives consideration before discovering that the information is in fact confidential.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id0cd04218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">7</footnote.reference>] The “reasonable man” test provides that if the defendant&apos;s belief was unreasonable, the fact that the defendant was acting in good faith will not absolve the defendant of liability. <eos/><bos/>M. Neave and M. Weinberg in their article, <begin.quote ID="QT_0008"/>“The Nature and Function of Equities (Part II)”<end.quote refid="QT_0008"/>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id0cd04228e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">8</footnote.reference>] submitted that:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0011"/>… it would be unprecedented for equity to require a defendant who had acted in good faith to restore lost benefits to a plaintiff unless a proprietary interest of the plaintiff had been infringed … Occasionally the defendant will be described as a “fiduciary” but this label merely conceals the fact that a constructive trust is deemed to exist, and the plaintiff is treated as the equitable owner of the property.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0011"/></paratext></para></display.quote><paratext>Occasionally the defendant will be described as a “fiduciary”, but this label merely conceals the fact that the plaintiff is in fact treated as the equitable owner of the property. <eos/><bos/>Thus, the claim for protection of confidential business information is a proprietary action based on an equitable and not a legal interest in the information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id0cd2b308e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">9</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Furthermore, the courts have often held that a bona fide purchaser for value without notice will acquire confidential business information free from any claim that the plaintiff might have.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id0cd2b318e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">10</footnote.reference>] The English Law Commission[<footnote.reference refid="Id0cd2b328e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">11</footnote.reference>] has concluded that the defence of bona fide purchaser ought to operate in this area. <eos/><bos/>It expressly rejected the “change of circumstances” criterion. <eos/><bos/>The American <ital>Restatement of the Law of Torts</ital> also supports the view that the defence of bona fide purchaser ought to prevail in actions for breach of confidence.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id0cd2b338e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">12</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In view of what has just been stated, there is strong reason to believe that there is a property right in confidential business information, but that the plaintiff ought to have no rights against a defendant who is a bona fide purchaser, for value, of the confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff&apos;s right should only be against the party that wrongfully imparted the confidential information to the defendant. <eos/><bos/>As one commentator stated, the courts:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0015"/>… have acted so as to create a proprietary interest, but which has not yet reached the stage when it can be said to a plaintiff <begin.quote ID="QT_0014"/>“bring yourself within that category and you will be protected”<end.quote refid="QT_0014"/>. <eos/><bos/>Instead, all that can be said is that the remedies are available for protection. <eos/><bos/>Prove that yours is a situation where they should be employed. <eos/><bos/>But this does not mean that the “interest” once recognized as an equity is any the less a proprietary interest of a sort.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0015"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id0cd52408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">13</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Id0ccb6008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>G. Jones, <begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>“Restitution of Benefits Obtained in Breach of Another&apos;s Confidence”<end.quote refid="QT_0001"/> (1970), 86 L.Q.R. 463 at p. 465.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id0ccdd108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>G. Jones, <begin.quote ID="QT_0005"/>“Restitution of Benefits Obtained in Breach of Another&apos;s Confidence”<end.quote refid="QT_0005"/> (1970), 86 L.Q.R. 463, at pp. 466 and 492.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id0ccdd118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>G. Jones, “Restitution of Benefits Obtained in Breach of Another&apos;s Confidence” (1970), 86 L.Q.R. 463, at p. 465. <eos/><bos/>Note, however, that Jones concludes that confidential information should be seen as a <ital>sui generis</ital> concept.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id0ccdd128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>4</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175822" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1967018556" w-pub-number="0004891" ID="I1459d7d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Seager v. Copydex Ltd.</ital>, [1967] 1 W.L.R. 923 (C.A.), at p. 931</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id0ccdd138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>5</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>Talbot v. General Television Corporation Pty. Ltd.</ital>, (unreported, 1977, S.C. Vict., No. 1998), affd <cite.query w-src-number="0492175822" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="U2" w-serial-number="1981032033" w-pub-number="0004888" ID="I145a4d008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">[1980] V.R. 224</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id0cd04208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>6</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175822" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1968018312" w-pub-number="0004831" ID="I145c6fe08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Coco v. A.N. Clark (Engineers) Ltd.</ital>, [1969] R.P.C. 41 (Ch.), at p. 48</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id0cd04218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>7</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>R.P. Meagher, W.M. Gummow and J.F. Lehane, <ital>Equity, Doctrine and Remedies</ital> (Sydney, Australia: Butterworths, 1975), p. 46.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id0cd04228e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>8</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>M. Neave and M. Weinberg in their article, “The Nature and Function of Equities (Part II)”, (1979), 6 U. Tas. <eos/><bos/>L.R. 115 at p. 121.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id0cd2b308e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>9</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>See <cite.query w-src-number="0492175822" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1966015849" w-pub-number="0004651" ID="I145d0c208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Boardman v. Phipps</ital>, [1967] 2 A.C. 46 (H.L.)</cite.query>, where a proprietary interest was held to arise by means of a constructive trust; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175822" w-seq-number="00007" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1964015497" w-pub-number="0004891" ID="I145d0c228e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Printers &amp; Finishers Ltd. v. Holloway</ital>, [1965] 1 W.L.R. 1 (Ch.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175822" w-seq-number="00008" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1851042779" w-pub-number="0005000" ID="I145d0c248e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Morison v. Moat</ital> (1851), 9 Hare. 241, 68 E.R. 492 (Ch.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id0cd2b318e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>10</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>M. Neave and M. Weinberg in their article, <begin.quote ID="QT_0013"/>“The Nature and Function of Equities (Part II)”<end.quote refid="QT_0013"/>, (1979), 6 U. Tas. <eos/><bos/>L.R. 115 at p. 123; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175822" w-seq-number="00009" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1849049683" w-pub-number="0005801" ID="I145d5a408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Prince Albert v. Strange</ital> (1849), 1 H. &amp; Tw. 1, 47 E.R. 1302 (Ch.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175822" w-seq-number="00010" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1964015497" w-pub-number="0004891" ID="I145d5a438e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Printers &amp; Finishers Ltd. v. Holloway</ital>, [1965] 1 W.L.R. 1 (Ch.)</cite.query>; <ital>De Beer v. Graham</ital> (1891), <cite.query w-src-number="0492175822" w-seq-number="00011" w-ref-type="U3" w-normalized-cite="12NSWRAU144" w-pub-number="0005139" ID="I145d5a458e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">12 N.S.W.R. 144 (Eq.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id0cd2b328e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>11</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Working Paper No. 58 (1974); but see <cite.query w-src-number="0492175822" w-seq-number="00012" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1952014147" w-pub-number="0004831" ID="I14628a608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Stephenson, Jordan and Harrison Ltd. v. MacDonald and Evans</ital> (1952), 69 R.P.C. 10 (C.A.), at p. 16</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175822" w-seq-number="00013" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1851042779" w-pub-number="0005000" ID="I14628a628e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Morison v. Moat</ital> (1851), 9 Hare. 241, 68 E.R. 492 (Ch.)</cite.query>, where Turner V.C. found for the plaintiff in an action for breach of confidence, but added: <begin.quote ID="QT_0012"/>“It might be different if the defendant was a purchaser for value of the secret without notice of any obligation affecting it.”<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0012"/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id0cd2b338e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>12</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>American Law Institute, <ital>Restatement of the Law of Torts</ital> (1963), § 758.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id0cd52408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>13</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>D.C. Jackson, <ital>Principles of Property Law</ital> (Sydney, Australia: Law Book Co., 1967), p. 69.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 2:7<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
