<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 8:22<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I59ba4210411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>8.</label.designator><headtext>Practical Advice for Protecting Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I59fa7f60411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>III.</label.designator><headtext>Employment Duties and Written Contracts</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I5a0d9230411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>D.</label.designator><headtext>Departure of an Employee</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f770a46ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>8:22.</label.designator><headtext>Generally</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Each of the relevant legal obligations related to confidential information—the duty of confidence, restrictive covenants and fiduciary duties—should be reviewed carefully with a departing employee. <eos/><bos/>The employer should specifically reference any consideration or notice given to the employee to reinforce the obligation not to compete. <eos/><bos/>Where possible, the departing employee should sign an agreement or acknowledgment regarding any continuing obligations. <eos/><bos/>In the alternative, the employee should be provided with a letter which sets forth his or her duties and reminds the employee of continuing obligations.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The manner in which exit interviews are conducted is also critical. <eos/><bos/>There are a number of ways for employees to increase the likelihood of getting the truth when employees leave. <eos/><bos/>If possible, the person conducting the interview should be someone the employee likes or trusts. <eos/><bos/>As much as possible, the interview should be friendly and conversational. <eos/><bos/>Knowing why an employee is leaving and where they are going can be quite useful to the employer. <eos/><bos/>If necessary, consider using a third party to conduct the interview. <eos/><bos/>The process should be structured and focused on key issues.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>As applicable, an employer should ensure that all physical and electronic documents, materials and other company information have been returned. <eos/><bos/>To the degree possible, employers should be very specific as to what information must be returned <ital>(i.e.</ital>, project information, customer lists, etc.).<eos/><bos/> This is particularly important where the employee worked on a home computer or personal laptop.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In some cases, it will also be important to notify the departing employee&apos;s new employer of the employee&apos;s ongoing duty of confidentiality, non-competition agreement or fiduciary duties. <eos/><bos/>This will serve to put the new employer on notice and may be useful as evidence if litigation is necessary. <eos/><bos/>This should, however, be done in a manner which avoids improper allegations or misinformation or gives rise to a possible claim of defamation by the former employee.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>When the employer is suspicious about a departing employee&apos;s activities, it may want to conduct some due diligence. <eos/><bos/>While privacy issues and technology use policies are relevant, it may be useful to look at telephone, fax, e-mail, internet and courier use in the period prior to departure. <eos/><bos/>As well, most security systems will allow the employer to figure out whether a departing employee had any strange attendance patterns. <eos/><bos/>While employers will want to be very careful in how they address these issues, some basic investigation can shed light on situations where employees undertake improper activities prior to departure in relation to customers, other employees and competitors.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Where appropriate, the company should also advise its remaining employees and its customers, suppliers and others that the employee has departed. <eos/><bos/>This will often prevent the former employee from taking advantage of existing relationships to improperly obtain information or to compete with the company.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></section.body></section><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 8:22<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
