<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 4:31<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I5089a870411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>4.</label.designator><headtext>Confidential Business Information and the Employment Relationship</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I52517020411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>V.</label.designator><headtext>Fiduciary Duty</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I5251be40411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>A.</label.designator><headtext>Analysis</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f65f346ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>4:31.</label.designator><headtext>Unfair Use of Information—Impact Planning to Depart</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Felker v. Cunningham</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id4d0b2108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>] a well-publicized decision, the Ontario Court of Appeal re-emphasized the strict duty of full disclosure placed on fiduciary employees. <eos/><bos/>The analysis in the decision is worth quoting from at length:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>Since <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175885" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1983169415" w-pub-number="0005505" ID="I3f87c4818e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Canadian</cite.query> Aero</ital> it has been established law in Canada that high echelon managers and directors of an organization owe their employer a fiduciary obligation that transcends their implied duty of fidelity as a regular employee. <eos/><bos/>Thus, an employee who stands in a fiduciary relationship to his or her employer has an equitable obligation of loyalty, good faith, honesty and avoidance of conflict of duty and self-interest. <eos/><bos/>The employee must act honestly, in good faith and with a view to advancing the employer&apos;s best interests. <eos/><bos/>This court has held that fiduciary employees cannot enter into engagements in which they have a personal interest that conflict with anything the employer does, or realistically may do, without first making full disclosure and obtaining the employer&apos;s consent: <ital>Manley Inc. v. Fallis</ital> (1977), 2 B.L.R. 277. <eos/><bos/>Moreover, as the fiduciary duty is based on trust, loyalty and confidence, and not economic cost to the employer, fiduciary employees are not relieved of their fiduciary duties if the business opportunity sought to further their own ends is one that the employer would have been unwilling or incapable of exploiting: Re <cite.query w-src-number="0492175885" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1983176309" w-pub-number="0005505" ID="I3f87c4838e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Berkey Photo (Canada) Ltd. v. Ohlig</ital> (1983), 43 O.R. (2d) 518 (H.C.J.)</cite.query> at 530-531.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0001"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>The trial judge found as a fact that Felker was a “valuable and trusted key employee” of Electro Source. <eos/><bos/>There is no doubt that this finding was supported by the evidence. <eos/><bos/>Felker joined Electro Source to “run the company”, being responsible for its sales in the Toronto area and the day-to-day operation of the Toronto office. <eos/><bos/>Toronto was the key revenue region for the company. <eos/><bos/>He acted in a managerial capacity and reported to its president and sole shareholder, Cunningham.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0002"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0003"/>In my view, given the trial judge&apos;s finding that Felker was a key, valuable and trusted employee and taking into account the duties he performed, Felker was a fiduciary employee whose duty of loyalty required that he devote his full time, ability and energy to furthering the best interests of Electro Source. <eos/><bos/>The duty to avoid conflict of interest and self-interest required Felker to avoid putting himself in a position where his own interests, or other commercial interests with which he was aligned, would be paramount to Electro Source&apos;s interests or would detract from his ability to work fully and completely for the benefit of Electro Source. <eos/><bos/>Moreover, Felker&apos;s duty of good faith required that he be open, honest and forthright with Electro Source and make full disclosure of all material facts that, as his employer, it would be entitled to know to successfully operate its business.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0003"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0004"/>In this regard, Felker was required to make full disclosure to Electro Source that he was engaged in preparing a presentation to Microchip, with the intention of acquiring Microchip as a client for his fledgling company and, thereafter, carrying on a business in competition with Electro Source. <eos/><bos/>In my view, Felker was in breach of his fiduciary duties when he failed to do so. <eos/><bos/>The only way that Felker could have pursued the Microchip opportunity while an employee of Electro Source without being in breach of his fiduciary duties, would have been to make full disclosure to Electro Source and obtain its consent to do so.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0004"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0005"/>This brings me to the main issue. <eos/><bos/>It is little wonder, when he learned of Felker&apos;s closet plan to acquire the Microchip opportunity, that Cunningham lost trust in Felker and made the decision to terminate his employment. <eos/><bos/>Although the trial judge recognized that Felker had acted improperly by “going behind [Cunningham&apos;s] back”, he concluded that Electro Source was not justified in dismissing him for cause based on a casual comment which he had made to Cunningham several months earlier at a time when an employment relationship between Electro Source and Felker was not in their contemplation and long before the Microchip opportunity presented itself.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0005"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0006"/>It may be, as the trial judge found, that in view of these comments, Cunningham was aware that Felker would start his own manufacturers&apos; representative business if the opportunity to do so presented itself. <eos/><bos/>However, this did not relieve Felker from his fiduciary duties when that opportunity arose after he had become a fiduciary employee of Electro Source. <eos/><bos/>In my view, the trial judge erred in elevating Felker&apos;s comments made when he was not an employee of Electro Source to the fulfilment of his duty of full disclosure which he acquired after he had become an employee. <eos/><bos/>On his essential duty of integrity to his employer, Felker&apos;s conduct must stand impeached. <eos/><bos/>In my view, there was just cause for his dismissal.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0006"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0007"/>Had Felker been aware of the Microchip opportunity when he and Cunningham were negotiating his employment by Electro Source, had he disclosed it to Cunningham and indicated his intention to pursue it, and had he been nevertheless hired, Electro Source would not have been justified in terminating him on learning of his subsequent pursuit of the opportunity: <cite.query w-src-number="0492175885" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1983169415" w-pub-number="0005505" ID="I3f9299f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Courtright v. Canadian Pacific Ltd.</ital> (1983), 45 O.R. (2d) 52, 5 D.L.R (4th) 488 (H.C.J..)</cite.query>; <case.history>affirmed</case.history> (1985), <cite.query w-src-number="0492175885" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="ER" w-normalized-cite="50OR2CA560n" w-pub-number="0005505" ID="I3f9299f38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">50 O.R. (2d) 560<ital>n</ital> (C.A.)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>But that is not what happened. <eos/><bos/>The casual comments which Felker made about his future plans to own his own business months before he became a fiduciary employee cannot serve as justification for his closet attempt to obtain the Microchip opportunity after he became a fiduciary employee.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0007"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0008"/>In my view, the trial judge erred in finding that Electro Source did not have just cause to dismiss Felker. <eos/><bos/>For the foregoing reasons, Electro Source had the right to dismiss him for cause and without notice, or salary in lieu of notice.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0008"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id4d0d9208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>With respect to <cite.query w-src-number="0492175885" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2000550136" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I3f93d2718e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Felker</ital></cite.query>, other decisions have taken the view that, had the employee disclosed an opportunity and indicated an intention to pursue it, and nevertheless been hired, the former employer would not have been justified in terminating him on learning of his subsequent pursuit of the opportunity.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4d0d9218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">3</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Id4d0b2108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175885" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2000550136" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I3f93f9808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Felker v. Cunningham</ital> (2000), 191 D.L.R. (4th) 734, 135 O.A.C. 172, 1</cite.query> C.C.E.L. (3d) 182, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175885" w-seq-number="00007" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2000550136" w-pub-number="0005628" ID="I3f93f9838e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2000 C.L.L.C. ¶ 210-035 (C.A.)</cite.query>, leave to appeal to S.C.C. refused 197 D.L.R. (4th) vii, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175885" w-seq-number="00008" w-ref-type="ER" w-normalized-cite="149OACCA398n" w-pub-number="0005460" ID="I3f93f9858e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">149 O.A.C. 398<ital>n</ital>, 171 N.R. 195<ital>n</ital></cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4d0d9208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175885" w-seq-number="00009" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2000550136" w-pub-number="0003591" w-pinpoint-page="739" ID="I3f9447a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Felker v. Cunningham</ital> (2000), 191 D.L.R. (4th) 734, at pp. 739-741 135 O.A.C. 172, 1</cite.query> C.C.E.L. (3d) 182, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175885" w-seq-number="00010" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2000550136" w-pub-number="0005628" ID="I3f9447a38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2000 C.L.L.C. ¶ 210-035 (C.A.)</cite.query>, leave to appeal to S.C.C. refused 197 D.L.R. (4th) vii, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175885" w-seq-number="00011" w-ref-type="ER" w-normalized-cite="149OACCA398n" w-pub-number="0005460" ID="I3f9447a58e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">149 O.A.C. 398<ital>n</ital>, 171 N.R. 195<ital>n</ital></cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>As to activities prior to departure, see also <cite.query w-src-number="0492175885" w-seq-number="00012" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2002062654" w-pub-number="0003986" ID="I3f9447a88e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cross Border Carriers Ltd. v. Getz</ital>, [2002] 11 W.W.R. 367, 220 Sask. R. 83 (Q.B.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4d0d9218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>See, for example, the decision of <cite.query w-src-number="0492175885" w-seq-number="00013" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1983169415" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I3f9495c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Courtright v. Canadian Pacific Ltd.</ital> (1983), 5 D.L.R. (4th) 488, 45 O.R. (2d) 52 (H.C.J.)</cite.query>, <case.history>affd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175885" w-seq-number="00014" w-ref-type="ER" w-normalized-cite="18DLR4CA639n" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I3f9495c38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">18 D.L.R. (4th) 639<ital>n</ital>, 50 O.R. (2d) 560<ital>n</ital> (C.A.)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>See also <cite.query w-src-number="0492175885" w-seq-number="00015" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2022068867" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I3f9495c68e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Aquafor Beech Ltd. v. Whyte</ital> (2010), 188 A.C.W.S. (3d) 509, [2010] O.J. No. 2011 (Comm. List)</cite.query>).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 4:31<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
