<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 4:12<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I5089a870411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>4.</label.designator><headtext>Confidential Business Information and the Employment Relationship</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I50976410411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>III.</label.designator><headtext>Confidentiality</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f611416ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>4:12.</label.designator><headtext>Customer Information and Solicitation</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Some of the most sensitive confidential information, and that most frequently at issue in litigation, relates to the identification of an employer&apos;s customers, customer needs, purchasing history and contact persons. <eos/><bos/>Unfortunately, as a result of efforts by the courts to balance the competing interests of employers and employees, decisions have often been inconsistent. <eos/><bos/>Where an employer is sophisticated, some courts have altered that balance toward the employee.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3d254e08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>] Each case will turn on its own facts and surrounding circumstances.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3d27bf08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>] A review of the case law will, however, produce some general guidelines that can be used to determine when and how a former employee may make use of information regarding customers.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The courts generally acknowledge that an employer has a valid interest in seeking to protect its customer connections.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id3d27bf18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">3</footnote.reference>] In <ital>Drake International Inc. v. Tennenbaum</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id3d27bf28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">4</footnote.reference>] the court held that information regarding <begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>“field staff and the matching of appropriate customers”<end.quote refid="QT_0001"/> was confidential, specifically noting that the information was a <begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>“valuable trade asset of the plaintiff”<end.quote refid="QT_0002"/> that was deserving of protection.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Monarch Messenger Services Ltd. v. Houlding</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id3d27bf38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">5</footnote.reference>] the Alberta Court of Queen&apos;s Bench held that a former “driver” of the plaintiff, who had left to form his own competing business, could be restrained from using customer information gained during the course of his employment. <eos/><bos/>The court held that former employees cannot use for their own benefit confidential information acquired during the course of their employment or information that is “special or peculiar” to the employer. <eos/><bos/>The court also emphasized that employees are free to use any skills or general knowledge that they acquired during the course of their employment. <eos/><bos/>The challenge is drawing the line between the two: <begin.quote ID="QT_0003"/>“The difficult question is to determine what knowledge so acquired is to be considered as confidential or ‘special or peculiar’ and subject to protection for the benefit of the ex-employer.”<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0003"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id3d27bf48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">6</footnote.reference>] In its decision, the court emphasized that the defendant had, for some period before his termination: (i) represented the former employer in dealing with the two major customers at issue; (ii) become intimately familiar with the special needs of those customers; and (iii) developed a personal relationship with the individuals representing the customers who were responsible for retaining the employer&apos;s services. <eos/><bos/>The judge then outlined the information that it considered to be confidential to the former employer and “special or peculiar” to the employer&apos;s business:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0004"/>[The defendant] had become intimately familiar with the special needs of these two companies … He was familiar with the rates charged by [the plaintiff] to these companies. <eos/><bos/>In my opinion, this is the type of information which an employee is prohibited from using for his own benefit during or after his term of employment … In the circumstances of this case … I am of the view that the specific and intimate knowledge which he acquired concerning [the plaintiff&apos;s] business dealings with the two large oil companies was of a confidential nature and must be considered as special or peculiar to [the plaintiff&apos;s] business.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0004"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id3d2a3008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">7</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Clayburn Industries Ltd. v. Piper</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id3d2a3018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">8</footnote.reference>] the court concluded that the former employees had misused confidential information, including information regarding key contacts, decision-making ability, products installed, customer preferences, employees, budgets, bid information, mark-ups and technical information. <eos/><bos/>Similarly, in <ital>A.R. Thomson Ltd. v. Stock</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id3d2a3028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">9</footnote.reference>] the court held as follows:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0005"/>The reasoning in the cases on the issue is this: information about customers from whom repeat business can be expected, developed over time at the employer&apos;s expense, is confidential information and forms part of the goodwill of the employer. <eos/><bos/>Access to this information puts the employee in a position to seriously injure the business of their employer, for it gives the employee a springboard for activities detrimental to the employer.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0005"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id3d2ca108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">10</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175866" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1999494906" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I298c2c718e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Ebco Industries Ltd. v. Kaltech Manufacturing</cite.query> Ltd.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id3d2ca118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">11</footnote.reference>] the defendants were prevented from soliciting certain customers on the basis that the personal defendants, during their employment, had had exclusive regular contact and specialized knowledge of customer needs.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The case law, most notably <ital>Edgar T. Alberts Ltd. v. Mountjoy</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id3d2ca128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">12</footnote.reference>] confirms that it is beyond argument that a departed employee normally has the right to solicit the customers of his or her former employer. <eos/><bos/>Other prominent cases, such as the Supreme Court&apos;s decision in <ital>Elsley v. J.G. Collins Insurance Agencies Ltd.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id3d2ca138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">13</footnote.reference>] have supported the notion that there is an important public interest in discouraging restraints of trade and in maintaining free and open competition.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>An employee will generally have the right to solicit the customers of his or her former employer, and even to make use of information obtained during the employment relationship. <eos/><bos/>Normally, to establish a breach of confidence the employer must prove an unauthorized use of the confidential information to its detriment and prejudice. <eos/><bos/>In <ital>ATI Technologies Inc. v. Henry</ital>, the court summarized:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0006"/>It is an attempt to get over that last hurdle that the plaintiff invokes the aid of doctrine of “inevitable disclosure”.<eos/><bos/> The plaintiff argues that in order to aid or perform his new functions adequately the defendant will inevitably disclose or use the confidential information, which he acquired in the employ of the plaintiff.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0006"/></paratext></para><head parent="display.quote"><headtext>…..</headtext></head><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0007"/>There is nothing in the circumstances surrounding the defendant&apos;s resignation from the plaintiff corporation and the assumption of his new employment that raises questions about the defendant&apos;s trustworthiness. <eos/><bos/>In fact the information provided to the plaintiff by the defendant prior to his departure in a document called “Exit Interview” is illustrative of his unusually frank approach. <eos/><bos/>This approach stands in stark contrast to the circumstances in the American cases in which the cloud of suspicion surrounding the defendant virtually required the courts to disbelieve that he would refrain from disclosing secrets in his new position.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0007"/></paratext></para><head parent="display.quote"><headtext>…..</headtext></head><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0008"/>The plaintiff&apos;s failure to join NVIDIA as a party lends some credence to the defendants uncontested allegations that in bringing this action, the plaintiff is motivated less by the fear of the defendant&apos;s breach of his contractual obligation than by its interest in discouraging other employees from leaving to work for a competitor and in hindering NVIDIA&apos;s plans to market new products in competition with those of the plaintiff.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0008"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id3d2ca148e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">14</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In 2008, the Supreme Court of Canada summarized this area of the law in the case of <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175866" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2011192292" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I298f60c18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">RBC Dominion Securities Inc. v. Merrill Lynch Canada</cite.query> Inc.</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id3d2f1208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">15</footnote.reference>] as follows:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0009"/>The majority of the Court of Appeal, by contrast, held that once the investment advisors left RBC, they were no longer under a duty not to compete with it. <eos/><bos/>The view of the Court of Appeal on the law for the purposes of this issue may be summed up as follows. <eos/><bos/>Generally, an employee who has terminated employment is not prevented from competing with his or her employer during the notice period, and the employer is confined to damages for failure to give reasonable notice (Southin J.A. for the majority).<eos/><bos/> To this general proposition Rowles J.A. may be read as adding the qualification that a departing employee might be liable for specific wrongs such as improper use of confidential information during the notice period. <eos/><bos/>This appears to be consistent with the current law, which restricts post-employment duties to the duty not to misuse confidential information, as well as duties arising out of a fiduciary duty or restrictive covenant: see G. England, <ital>Employment Law in Canada</ital> (4th ed. loose-leaf), vol. 2, § 11.141. <eos/><bos/>Neither of the latter duties are at issue here.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0009"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0010"/>For the purposes of this case, the law may be accepted as summarized by the preceding paragraph. <eos/><bos/>The contract of employment ends when either the employer or the employee terminates the employment relationship, although residual duties may remain. <eos/><bos/>An employee terminating his or her employment may be liable for failure to give reasonable notice and for breach of specific residual duties. <eos/><bos/>Subject to these duties, the employee is free to compete against the former employer.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0010"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0011"/>To the extent the trial judge awarded damages on the basis that the employees continued to be a under a general duty not to compete, this award of damages was wrong in law.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0011"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id3d2f1218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">16</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Id3d254e08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175866" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2011192292" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I2990c0508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>RBC Dominion Securities Inc. v. Merrill Lynch Canada Inc.</ital> (2007), 275 D.L.R. (4th) 385 (B.C.C.A.)</cite.query>, at paras. 57-58. <eos/><bos/>However, see the decision of the Supreme Court of Canada, which reinstated the damages of the trial court: <case.history>appeal allowed in part</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175866" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017227608" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I2990c0528e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">298 D.L.R. (4th) 1 (S.C.C.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3d27bf08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175866" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2011192292" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I299442c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>RBC Dominion Securities Inc. v. Merrill Lynch Canada Inc.</ital> (2007), 275 D.L.R. (4th) 385 (B.C.C.A.)</cite.query>, at paras. 57-58; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175866" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1992235153" w-pub-number="0004660" ID="I299442c28e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Universal Thermosensors Ltd. v. Hibben</ital>, [1992] 3 All E.R. 257 (Ch. D.), at pp. 266-267</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3d27bf18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>See <cite.query w-src-number="0492175866" w-seq-number="00007" w-ref-type="ER" w-normalized-cite="2004AJNOCA408" w-pub-number="0006690" ID="I299506108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Am-Con Insulation Industries Ltd. v. Willard</ital>, [2004] A.J. No. 408 (Q.B.)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>But see also <cite.query w-src-number="0492175866" w-seq-number="00008" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2004315516" w-pub-number="0006698" ID="I299506128e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>MD Management Ltd. v. Dhut</ital>, [2004] B.C.J. No. 764 (S.C.)</cite.query>, where a former employee could reconstruct information using publicly available sources; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175866" w-seq-number="00009" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2032466376" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I299506148e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>A Big Mobile Sign Co. v. Marshall</ital>, 2014 CarswellOnt 15, 2014 ONSC 16</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3d27bf28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>4</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175866" w-seq-number="00010" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1986268204" w-pub-number="0005653" ID="I29963e908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Drake International Inc. v. Tennenbaum</ital> (1986), 10 C.P.R. (3d) 119 (Ont. H.C.J.), at p. 121</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3d27bf38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>5</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175866" w-seq-number="00011" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1984192374" w-pub-number="0004655" ID="I2996dad18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Monarch Messenger Services Ltd. v. Houlding</ital></cite.query> (1984), 5 C.C.E.L. 219 at p. 227, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175866" w-seq-number="00012" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1984192374" w-pub-number="0004655" ID="I2996dad28e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">56 A.R. 147 (Q.B.)</cite.query>, <case.history>affd</case.history> 13 C.C.E.L. xxxvi (Alta. C.A.).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3d27bf48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>6</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175866" w-seq-number="00013" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1984192374" w-pub-number="0004655" ID="I299750018e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Monarch Messenger Services Ltd. v. Houlding</ital></cite.query> (1984), 5 C.C.E.L. 219, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175866" w-seq-number="00014" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1984192374" w-pub-number="0004655" ID="I299750028e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">56 A.R. 147 (Q.B.)</cite.query>, <case.history>affd</case.history> 13 C.C.E.L. xxxvi (Alta. C.A.).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3d2a3008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>7</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175866" w-seq-number="00015" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1984192374" w-pub-number="0004655" ID="I29983a618e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Monarch Messenger Services Ltd. v. Houlding</ital></cite.query> (1984), 5 C.C.E.L. 219 at p. 228, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175866" w-seq-number="00016" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1984192374" w-pub-number="0004655" ID="I29983a628e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">56 A.R. 147 (Q.B.)</cite.query>, <case.history>affd</case.history> 13 C.C.E.L. xxxvi (Alta. C.A.).<eos/><bos/> However, to the contrary, see <ital>Gertz v. Meda Ltd.</ital> (2002), 16 C.C.E.L. (3d) 79 (Ont. S.C.J.).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3d2a3018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>8</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>Clayburn Industries Ltd. v. Piper</ital> (1998), 62 B.C.L.R. (3d) 24 at p. 34, 44 C.C.E.L. (2d) 129 (S.C.).<eos/><bos/> On this point, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175866" w-seq-number="00017" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1997415151" w-pub-number="0003986" ID="I299999f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Capitanescu v. Universal Weld Overlays Inc.,</ital> [1997] 10 W.W.R. 666, 204 A.R. 81 (Q.B.)</cite.query>, <case.history>revd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175866" w-seq-number="00018" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1999484752" w-pub-number="0004655" ID="I299999f38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">232 A.R. 334, 195 W.A.C. 334 (C.A.)</cite.query>, supports the view that the improper use of customer lists will almost automatically result in a finding for the former employer. <eos/><bos/>See also <ital>Sanford Evans List Brokerage v. Trauzzi</ital> (2000), 50 C.C.E.L. (2d) 105 (Ont. S.C.J.); <cite.query w-src-number="0492175866" w-seq-number="00019" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2032466376" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I299999f68e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>A Big Mobile Sign Co. v. Marshall</ital>, 2014 CarswellOnt 15, 2014 ONSC 16</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3d2a3028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>9</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175866" w-seq-number="00020" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1990323184" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I2999e8108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>A.R. Thomson Ltd. v. Stock</ital> (1990), 23 A.C.W.S. (3d) 280 (B.C.S.C.)</cite.query>, supp. reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175866" w-seq-number="00021" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1991344710" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I2999e8128e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">27 A.C.W.S. (3d) 1129 (B.C.S.C.)</cite.query>, <case.history>revd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175866" w-seq-number="00022" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1998456985" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I2999e8148e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">156 D.L.R. (4th) 105, [1998] 8 W.W.R. 120, 48</cite.query> B.C.L.R. (3d) 169 (C.A.).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3d2ca108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>10</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175866" w-seq-number="00023" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1990323184" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I299a5d408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>A.R. Thomson Ltd. v. Stock</ital> (1990), 23 A.C.W.S. (3d) 280 (B.C.S.C.)</cite.query>, supp. reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175866" w-seq-number="00024" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1991344710" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I299a5d428e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">27 A.C.W.S. (3d) 1129 (B.C.S.C.)</cite.query>, <case.history>revd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175866" w-seq-number="00025" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1998456985" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I299a5d448e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">156 D.L.R. (4th) 105, [1998] 8 W.W.R. 120, 48</cite.query> B.C.L.R. (3d) 169 (C.A.) at p. 139 of the judgment. <eos/><bos/>See also, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175866" w-seq-number="00026" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2000669102" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I299a5d478e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Metafore Corp. v. Protek Systems (London) Inc.</ital> (2000), 102 A.C.W.S. (3d) 335 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query> at paras. 8-10; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175866" w-seq-number="00027" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2030699569" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I299a5d498e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Eagle Professional Resources Inc. v. MacMullin</ital>, 2013 CarswellOnt 7745, 2013 ONSC 2501</cite.query>, <case.history>affirmed</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175866" w-seq-number="00028" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2031807121" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I299a5d4c8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2013 CarswellOnt 14173, 2013 ONCA 639</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175866" w-seq-number="00029" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2025787341" w-pub-number="0005481" ID="I299a5d4f8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Exfo inc. c. Réseaux Accedian inc. (Duplessis)</ital>, 2011 CarswellQue 7760, 2011 QCCS 3767</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175866" w-seq-number="00030" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2030930033" w-pub-number="0006821" ID="I299a5d528e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Whitmar Publications Ltd. v. Gamage &amp; Ors</ital>, [2013] EWHC 1881 (Ch. D.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3d2ca118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>11</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175866" w-seq-number="00031" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1999494906" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I299ad2708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ebco Industries Ltd. v. Kaltech Manufacturing Ltd.</ital> (1999), 91 A.C.W.S. (3d) 1025 (B.C.S.C.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3d2ca128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>12</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175866" w-seq-number="00032" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1977148370" w-pub-number="0005150" ID="I299ad2728e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgar T. Alberts Ltd. v. Mountjoy</ital> (1977), 79 D.L.R. (3d) 108, 16 O.R. (2d) 682 (H.C.J.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3d2ca138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>13</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175866" w-seq-number="00033" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1978024877" w-pub-number="0005150" w-pinpoint-page="5" ID="I299af9808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Elsley v. J.G. Collins Insurance Agencies Ltd.</ital> (1978), 83 D.L.R. (3d) 1 at p. 5, [1978] 2 S.C.R. 916</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3d2ca148e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>14</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>ATI Technologies Inc. v. Henry</ital>,, (2000), 5 C.C.E.L. (3d) 101 (Ont. S.C.J.) at paras. 13, 19 and 20. <eos/><bos/>See also, <ital>Callpro Canada Inc. v. Prima Telematique Inc.</ital> (2001), 16 B.L.R. (3d) 202 (Ont. S.C.J.).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3d2f1208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>15</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175866" w-seq-number="00034" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2011192292" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I299d43718e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>RBC Dominion Securities Inc. v. Merrill Lynch Canada Inc.</ital></cite.query> (2003), 55 C.C.E.L. (3d) 179 (B.C.S.C.), supp. reasons 55 C.C.E.L. (3d) 208 (B.C.S.C.), appeal allowed in part <cite.query w-src-number="0492175866" w-seq-number="00035" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2011192292" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I299d43728e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">275 D.L.R. (4th) 385 (B.C.C.A.)</cite.query>, <case.history>appeal allowed in part</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175866" w-seq-number="00036" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017227608" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I299d43748e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">298 D.L.R. (4th) 1 (S.C.C.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id3d2f1218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>16</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175866" w-seq-number="00037" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2011192292" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I299e2dd18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>RBC Dominion Securities Inc. v. Merrill Lynch Canada Inc.</ital></cite.query> (2003), 55 C.C.E.L. (3d) 179 (B.C.S.C.), supp. reasons 55 C.C.E.L. (3d) 208 (B.C.S.C.), appeal allowed in part <cite.query w-src-number="0492175866" w-seq-number="00038" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2011192292" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I299e2dd28e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">275 D.L.R. (4th) 385 (B.C.C.A.)</cite.query>, <case.history>appeal allowed in part</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175866" w-seq-number="00039" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017227608" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I299e2dd48e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">298 D.L.R. (4th) 1 (S.C.C.)</cite.query>, at paras. 18-20, <ital>per</ital> McLachlin C.J.C. for the majority. <eos/><bos/><cite.query w-src-number="0492175866" w-seq-number="00040" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2032466376" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I299e2dd68e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>A Big Mobile Sign Co. v. Marshall</ital>, 2014 CarswellOnt 15, 2014 ONSC 16</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 4:12<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
