<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information ยง 1:28<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I4d7849c0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>1.</label.designator><headtext>Confidential Business Information in Historical Context</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I4e5a4550411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>V.</label.designator><headtext>Conclusion</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f5c2fd6ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>ยง </label.name><label.designator>1:28.</label.designator><headtext>Generally</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Whether information should be protected in a given case should depend upon the circumstances surrounding the plaintiff&apos;s claimed property interest, the nature of the relationship involved and/or the defendant&apos;s alleged violation of business ethics. <eos/><bos/>The policy reasons invoked to protect confidential information ought to involve the balancing of the strength of the right to information with public policy interests in the encouragement of business ethics and the dissemination of information.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Although the rules for the protection of confidential business information may not always provide an incentive to individual investors or produce a just and equitable result, the protection of confidential business information is often required to produce a return on investment and an incentive to invest in new ideas. <eos/><bos/>However, although the resources devoted to creations outside the scope of existing patents have resulted in valuable additional innovations, it is impossible to know what other innovations would have been made if information were freely available.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></section.body></section><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI ยง 1:28<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
