<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 4:29<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I5089a870411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>4.</label.designator><headtext>Confidential Business Information and the Employment Relationship</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I52517020411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>V.</label.designator><headtext>Fiduciary Duty</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I5251be40411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>A.</label.designator><headtext>Analysis</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f6384e6ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>4:29.</label.designator><headtext>Competition by a Fiduciary Employee</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The courts have frequently held that even an employee in a “top management position” can immediately go into competition with his or her former employer and solicit the former employer&apos;s customers.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bab9108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>] However, they have often drawn a much stricter line between the fiduciary employee&apos;s knowledge and skill and the employer&apos;s confidential information.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The central issue in <ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id4bab9118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>] was the extent to which the Departing Physicians were entitled to take steps during the 60 Day Period to be able continue their practices in competition with Genesis after the 60 Day Period. <eos/><bos/>The physicians organized and carried on their practice in reproductive medicine through the corporation Genesis. <eos/><bos/>Their relationship was governed by an Amended and Restated Shareholders&apos; Agreement that contained a provision pursuant to which any shareholder could give notice to any other shareholder, thereby requiring the other shareholder to elect either to sell his or her shares or purchase the shares of the person giving the notice. <eos/><bos/>In 2012, the Departing Physicians decided they could no longer practice with Dr. Kashya and they gave notice pursuant to the provision, which required Dr. Kashyap either to sell her shares to them or purchase all of their shares. <eos/><bos/>Dr. Kashyap gave notice that she had elected to purchase the shares of the Departing Physicians.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bab9128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">3</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Prior to January 31, 2013, the Departing Physicians were shareholders of Genesis through their respective professional corporations. <eos/><bos/>Up to that time they were also directors of Genesis. <eos/><bos/>From January 2013, Drs. Taylor and Hitkari were shareholders of the defendant, Olive either directly or through their professional corporations. <eos/><bos/>Olive was organized in December 2012 and was the company under which the Departing Physicians carried on their medical practices since February 1, 2013. <eos/><bos/>The defendant Dr. Nakhuda was a medical doctor who was employed by Genesis from February 2011 until April 2013 pursuant to an employment contract. <eos/><bos/>In June 2013, he moved his practice to Olive. <eos/><bos/>The defendants Wylie and St. Pierre were formerly senior management employees of Genesis. <eos/><bos/>On December 1, 2012, they gave notices of resignation to Genesis. <eos/><bos/>At the end of their notice period, they took up positions with Olive performing essentially the same functions for that company that they had formerly performed for Genesis.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bab9138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">4</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Departing Physicians continued to be employees, directors, and officers of Genesis in the 60 Day Period. <eos/><bos/>The procedures set out in the Shareholders&apos; Agreement required a number of steps to be taken in the 60 Day Period to complete the sale and purchase of the interest of the Departing Physicians. <eos/><bos/>There was no indication that the parties did anything to frustrate the completion of the sale transaction and the sale did complete as agreed. <eos/><bos/>As soon as Dr. Kashyap notified the Departing Physicians that she had elected to buy their shares, they, together with Wylie and St. Pierre, began to make plans to establish a new clinic in which they would continue to provide fertility treatments and consultations in the same manner that they had at Genesis. <eos/><bos/>Wylie and St. Pierre had been long time employees of Genesis and felt a great deal of personal loyalty to the Departing Physicians. <eos/><bos/>On December 1, 2012, they gave notices of termination of their employment with Genesis, effective December 31, 2012. <eos/><bos/>It is agreed that this was the required notice period under their employment contracts. <eos/><bos/>In early December 2012, the defendants took steps to incorporate Olive. <eos/><bos/>On January 1, 2013, Olive opened a temporary office in the same building in which Genesis was located. <eos/><bos/>On January 15, 2013, the Departing Physicians sent out a notice through the British Columbia Medical Association member announcement mailing service to other members of the BCMA, announcing that they were continuing their clinical practices at Olive&apos;s temporary facility and booking patients, effective immediately. <eos/><bos/>However, the Departing Physicians continued to practice at Genesis until the end of January. <eos/><bos/>On February 1, 2013, Genesis began providing some fertility medicine services from the temporary location. <eos/><bos/>The Departing Physicians used the services of Wylie and St. Pierre, during their notice period in December 2012 to assist them in setting up their new temporary and permanent clinics. <eos/><bos/>However, the great majority of time spent by Wylie and St. Pierre on establishing Olive in that month was done on their own time. <eos/><bos/>Wylie and Ms. St. Pierre were not recruited by the Departing Physicians. <eos/><bos/>They actively declared their intention to continue to work with the Departing Physicians as soon as it became possible for them to do so. <eos/><bos/>Ten Genesis employees signed employment contracts with Olive or the Departing Physicians on behalf of Olive prior to January 31, 2013. <eos/><bos/>The ten included all of the senior management team at Genesis. <eos/><bos/>Of the ten, 4 commenced employment with Olive before February 1, 2013.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bab9148e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">5</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Departing Physicians and Senior Managers admitted that they occupied fiduciary positions with Genesis. <eos/><bos/>In Justice Sewell&apos;s view, the nature of the duties owed during the 60 Day Period must be examined in the context of the relationship between the parties. <eos/><bos/>The critical question was the extent of the duties owed by the defendants in the particular circumstances. <eos/><bos/>The Shareholders&apos; Agreement, the professional responsibilities of the Departing Physicians and the ways in which income was earned and distributed were all circumstances relevant to the determination of the extent of the permissible activities open to the Departing Physicians.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bab9158e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">6</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Sewell was of the view that the contractual relationship between the parties could inform the scope of the fiduciary obligations owed by one party to the other. <eos/><bos/>It was necessary to determine the nature of the relationship between the parties and, in particular, the nature of the relationship between the physicians who owned Genesis. <eos/><bos/>The starting point for that determination was the Shareholders&apos; Agreement. <eos/><bos/>The parties intended their relationship with respect to the conduct of the affairs of Genesis to be governed by the terms of the Shareholders&apos; Agreement. <eos/><bos/>The unanimity provisions of the Shareholders&apos; Agreement significantly limited the power of its directors to act in a manner that could prejudice other shareholders or Genesis itself. <eos/><bos/>Justice Laskin&apos;s explanation for the rationale of the strict application of fiduciary duties to directors of a company in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1973144068" w-pub-number="0005150" ID="I3ddd96f18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Canadian Aero Service</ital></cite.query> emphasized that the reason for the rule lies in the power that fiduciaries have to affect the rights of other stakeholders in the company. <eos/><bos/>In this case, that power was significantly reduced by the terms of the Shareholders&apos; Agreement. <eos/><bos/>Justice Sewell also consider that the fact that Genesis was a corporation set up to permit the physicians to practice medicine together was relevant because, as practicing physicians, they were subject to a number of express regulations, fiduciary duties and ethical constraints with respect to the provision of medical services to patients. <eos/><bos/>The most important of these was the ethical duty all the physicians to facilitate continuity of care for patients and the right of those patients to receive care from the physician of their choice. <eos/><bos/>The ethical code and standards stress the importance of the patient-physician relationship and generally oppose the termination of the relationship without “legitimate reasons”.<eos/><bos/> The board of the College adopted the Canadian Medical Association&apos;s Code of Ethics as the baseline for all conduct of physicians in B.C. One such fundamental responsibility stated in the Code of Ethics is that a physician must <begin.quote ID="QT_0003"/>“consider first the well-being of the patient.”<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0003"/> Rule 19 of the Code of Ethics states that a physician must <begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>“having accepted professional responsibility for a patient, continue to provide services until they are no longer required or wanted; until another suitable physician has assumed responsibility for the patient; or until the patient has been given reasonable notice that you intend to terminate the relationship”<end.quote refid="QT_0002"/>. <eos/><bos/>The College has provided a further practice standard titled “Ending the Patient-Physician Relationship” that expands on the duties that physicians owe to their patients. <eos/><bos/>The practice standard states: <begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>“the patient-physician relationship is a fiduciary relationship based on honesty, respect and trust, where the physician prioritizes the patient&apos;s care and well-being, and acknowledges the patient&apos;s autonomy with regard to personal choice, including lifestyle or treatment options. <eos/><bos/>One such personal choice is the ability of patients to choose which physician should treat them. <eos/><bos/>It is also clear that the patient-physician relationship should not be ended by a physician unless there are serious reasons for doing so.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0001"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id4bae0208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">7</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Sewell explained that if physicians are to uphold their ethical obligations to their patient and respect patient choice, the patient must have the right to be informed of changes to a medical practice and has the right to choose which physician is to treat them, including the right to change clinics at any time. <eos/><bos/>The jurisprudence recognizes that the nature of the fiduciary duties owed in a corporation established to deliver professional services must be modified to accommodate the fiduciary and ethical duties owed to patients and clients and the ethical responsibilities of professionals.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bae0218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">8</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Sewell appreciated that there were a number of factual differences between the authorities and this case. <eos/><bos/>Genesis was a corporation and the Departing Physicians owed fiduciary duties to it. <eos/><bos/>The solicitation to which the plaintiffs objected in this case was not made to patients but to referring physicians. <eos/><bos/>The Departing Physicians left Genesis pursuant to the terms of the Shareholders&apos; Agreement and received a substantial payment for their interest in Genesis. <eos/><bos/>However, the underlying principle that giving priority to the duties owed by doctors to their patients takes precedence over some fiduciary duties to their employer that might apply in other circumstances applied in this case.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bae0228e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">9</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiffs expressly stated that they did not object to the defendants communicating with patients. <eos/><bos/>They did, however, say that the notice to the medical profession sent out in January 2013 was a breach of duty. <eos/><bos/>The difficulty that Justice Sewell had with that submission was that the Departing Physicians were specialists. <eos/><bos/>As a general rule in British Columbia, patients must be referred to a specialist by another physician for consultations. <eos/><bos/>A restriction on the ability of the Departing Physicians to communicate with referring doctors is also an unacceptable restriction on the right of patients to be treated by the doctor of their choice. <eos/><bos/>It is also in the public interest that referring physicians be provided with up to date and accurate information as to the professional staff of a clinic to whom they are making referrals.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bae0238e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">10</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The combined effect of the contractual arrangement between the parties and the fiduciary, regulatory and ethical duties owed to patients led Justice Sewell to conclude that the Departing Physicians were entitled to take significant steps to establish a new clinic as soon as they knew they were being bought out of Genesis and would no longer be practicing there. <eos/><bos/>Within the 60 Day Period the Departing Physicians were entitled to secure new premises for their practices, to make arrangements to permit them to provide uninterrupted medical services to their patients and to inform other physicians of the establishment of their new practice. <eos/><bos/>These steps included making staffing arrangements within reasonable limits. <eos/><bos/>The Departing Physicians did not breach their fiduciary duties as directors of Genesis by taking immediate steps to set up a new clinic once they were made aware that they could not practice at Genesis, provided that they acted fairly in doing so.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bae0248e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">11</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiffs alleged that many steps taken by the defendants damaged Genesis&apos;s interests and constituted breaches of fiduciary duty or unauthorized use of confidential information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bae0258e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">12</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>With respect to the removal of payroll information as well as the information used by Olive in the preparation of its business plan, it was a breach of confidence and breach of fiduciary duty to use that information without Genesis&apos;s consent.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bb07308e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">13</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Sewell considered that it was a breach of fiduciary duty on the part of the Departing Physicians not to inform Dr. Kashyap that they had entered into employment contracts with the Senior Managers and to use the services of the Senior Managers while they were still employed by Genesis. <eos/><bos/>However, once they were no longer employed by Genesis, the Senior Managers were entitled to work to prepare the Olive clinic to be able to begin providing patient care on February 1, 2013. <eos/><bos/>There were times when Wylie and St. Pierre performed services relating to setting up Olive while they were working in Genesis&apos;s office. <eos/><bos/>However, this occurred only rarely and both Wylie and St. Pierre competently carried out their duties for Genesis during December 2012. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence of any material amount of Olive related services being carried out by either of these defendants when they should have been working for Genesis.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bb07318e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">14</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The signing of employment contracts with other Genesis employees within the 60 Day Period without making full disclosure to Genesis was a breach of fiduciary duty on the part of the Departing Physicians.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bb07328e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">15</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Sewell accepted that Wylie used financial information about Genesis&apos;s operations in preparing the Olive Business Plan and for the purpose of preparing contracts of employment with Genesis employees. <eos/><bos/>This was a breach of fiduciary duty and an appropriation of Genesis&apos;s confidential information. <eos/><bos/>However, this information was not of significant importance to Olive or Genesis.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bb07338e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">16</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>While Justice Sewell did not accept that Dr. Kashyap was kept completely in the dark about their activities, Genesis was entitled to be kept informed of the Departing Physicians&apos; activities to allow it to manage its own future. <eos/><bos/>As fiduciaries, the Departing Physicians had a duty of candour as well as loyalty. <eos/><bos/>In Justice Sewell&apos;s view, they did not fulfill their duty of candour during the 60 Day Period. <eos/><bos/>Genesis did go through a period of uncertainty and disruption after Dr. Kashyap elected to purchase the Departing Physicians shares. <eos/><bos/>However, those difficulties were not primarily attributable to any breaches of duty or wrongdoing on the part of the defendants. <eos/><bos/>Dr. Kashyap undoubtedly had the right to buy out the Departing Physicians. <eos/><bos/>However, she did not think through the practical consequences of her decision in several important respects. <eos/><bos/>The first of these was she was purchasing a company whose most valuable assets were the doctors who practiced in the clinic. <eos/><bos/>Dr. Kashyap must be taken to have realized that much of the financial success of Genesis was derived from the personal reputations and abilities of the doctors who practiced in it. <eos/><bos/>Her decision to buyout the Departing Physicians resulted in the immediate loss of three of its five Physicians, and the likely departure of a fourth. <eos/><bos/>The second consideration was that the number of employees, the amount of equipment and the infrastructure associated with Genesis were all designed to support a clinic in which 4 or 5 doctors would be practicing. <eos/><bos/>In this regard, the number of doctors practicing at Genesis was the limiting factor on both its size and the amount of revenue it could generate. <eos/><bos/>The third consideration was that the Shareholders&apos; Agreement made it clear that the Departing Doctors had an unrestricted right to immediately begin competing with Genesis as soon as they ceased to be Shareholders. <eos/><bos/>The fourth consideration was that many of the employees of Genesis would be likely to leave that company and seek work elsewhere as soon as they were in a position to do so. <eos/><bos/>This was so for two reasons. <eos/><bos/>Firstly, Genesis clearly had more staff than it reasonably required to provide support for a one or two physician practice. <eos/><bos/>Secondly, many of the staff had worked closely with the Departing Physicians for many years and would naturally have wished to continue to do so. <eos/><bos/>Dr. Kashyap lacked a plan for dealing with these difficulties. <eos/><bos/>The lack of such a plan greatly contributed to her difficulties. <eos/><bos/>None of these difficulties can be attributed to any wrongful acts on the part of the defendants.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bb07348e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">17</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiffs alleged that the defendants breached their fiduciary duties after the 60 Day Period by continuing to use confidential information belonging to Genesis and by continuing to covertly gather information about Genesis and its employees from Collings and using that information to recruit Genesis employees Collings continued to work at Genesis in a managerial role after she had decided to move to Olive. <eos/><bos/>It was clear that she was acting in the interests of Olive in making decisions about staffing matters at Genesis. <eos/><bos/>Collings remained at Genesis until May 16, 2013. <eos/><bos/>During that period, she frequently communicated with Wylie about Genesis employees and made recommendations as to which employees Olive should consider hiring. <eos/><bos/>Utilizing information obtained from Collings was a breach of fiduciary duty on the part of the fiduciary defendants. <eos/><bos/>It also constituted improper use of confidential information about Genesis&apos;s operations and human resources challenges. <eos/><bos/>Unlike many of the other breaches complained of, the actions of Collings were damaging to Genesis.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bb07358e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">18</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Genesis had established some breaches of fiduciary duty and some breaches of confidence. <eos/><bos/>A plaintiff that establishes breaches of fiduciary duty and breach of confidence is entitled to compensation either as damages for losses incurred or by an order requiring the defendant to account for any gains wrongfully obtained. <eos/><bos/>The defendants submitted that Genesis was required to elect what remedy it sought for the wrongs it alleged were committed against it by the time it closed its case. <eos/><bos/>The defendants relied on the judgement of Justice Myers in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2030436470" w-pub-number="0006459" ID="I3ded9c808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>First Majestic Silver Corp. v. Davila</ital>, 2013 BCSC 717 at para. 200</cite.query>, <case.history>aff&apos;d</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2033538552" w-pub-number="0006458" ID="I3ded9c828e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2014 BCCA 214</cite.query>, leave to appeal to the S.C.C refused, 35962 (27 November 2014), quoting from <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1995257032" w-pub-number="0004891" ID="I3ded9c848e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Island Records Ltd v. Tring International Plc.</ital>, [1996] 1 W.L.R. 1256</cite.query> (H.C.J. ChD. (Eng.)):</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0004"/>200. <eos/><bos/>He [the Judge in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1995257032" w-pub-number="0004891" ID="I3dee38c18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Island Records]</cite.query> then went on to consider the issue before him (where the trial <ital>was</ital> split):</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext>7. Four principles are clear. <eos/><bos/>First whilst a plaintiff can apply in proceedings in the alternative for damages and an account of profits, he cannot obtain judgment for both: he can only obtain judgment for one or the other: see Neilson v Betts LR5 HL1 and De Vitre v Belts (1873) LR6 HL 319 at 321. <eos/><bos/>Second once judgment has been entered either for damages or an account of profits, any right-of election is lost: any claim to the remedy other than that for which judgment is entered is forever lost: see <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1940033761" w-pub-number="0004651" w-pinpoint-page="30" ID="I3def23208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">United Australia v Barclays Bank [1941] AC 1 at 30</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>Third a party should in general not be required to elect or be found to have elected between remedies unless and until he is able to make an informed choice. <eos/><bos/>A right of election, if it is to be meaningful and not a mere gamble, must embrace the right to readily available information as to his likely entitlement in case of both the two alternative remedies. <eos/><bos/>It is quite unreasonable to require the plaintiff to speculate totally in the dark as to whether or not the sum recoverable by way of damages will exceed that recoverable under an account of profits. <eos/><bos/>In an analogous situation, it has been held unreasonable to require a plaintiff to speculate whether a payment into Court is sufficient to satisfy his claim for damages for infringement of copyright before he has been afforded inspection of the records of sales in the defendants books: see Mate &amp; Son v Samuel Stephen Ltd (1928-1935) Mac CC 257 at 261. <eos/><bos/>Fourth the exercise of the right of election should not be unreasonably delayed to the prejudice of the defendant.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0004"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id4bb2e408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">19</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Sewell concluded that <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00007" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2030436470" w-pub-number="0006459" ID="I3defe6718e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>First Majestic</ital></cite.query> was distinguishable because in that case the plaintiffs were seeking to defer making an election as to remedy until after the court quantified the relief they would be entitled to under the alternative claims. <eos/><bos/>Justice Myers did not accede to that request and required the plaintiffs to elect the remedy they sought at the end of the trial. <eos/><bos/>Justice Sewell did not take any of the cases cited by the defendants to stand for the proposition that a plaintiff who has established a wrong and seeks a particular remedy that the court does not consider appropriate should be left with no remedy. <eos/><bos/>The law gives the court a considerable degree of discretion in fashioning an appropriate remedy once it determines that the defendants are liable. <eos/><bos/>In this case, the plaintiffs set out the relief they sought in their closing submissions. <eos/><bos/>There was nothing that precluded them from seeking alternative remedies if the court determined that their preferred remedy was unavailable.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bb2e418e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">20</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In Justice Sewell&apos;s view, the correct approach to determining the remedy in a case in which either an accounting of profits attributable to a breach of fiduciary duty or damages for loss suffered by the principal as a result of the breach is set out in <ital>Moore International (Canada) Ltd. v. Carter</ital> (1984), 56 B.C.L.R. 207 (C.A.):</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0006"/>19. <eos/><bos/>The availability of these remedies was discussed by Mr. Justice Laskin in the <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00008" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1973144068" w-pub-number="0005150" w-pinpoint-page="621" ID="I3df146018e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Can. Aero case at pp. 621-2</cite.query>.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0006"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0007"/>20. <eos/><bos/>In my opinion the plaintiff is not required to elect one remedy or the other. <eos/><bos/>He may lead evidence of both his own loss and his fiduciary&apos;s profit. <eos/><bos/>And the trial judge may then make an award of compensation that is supported by the evidence.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0007"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0008"/>21. <eos/><bos/>In this case, Mr. Justice Legg made an award of damages. <eos/><bos/>But he did not think that the direct evidence in support of the loss sustained by Moore was as helpful in determining that loss as the indirect evidence of the loss constituted by the evidence of Salton&apos;s profit. <eos/><bos/>The decision to adopt that train of reasoning depended on an assessment of the weight to be attached to the testimony of particular witnesses and belongs in the province of the trial judge. <eos/><bos/>It is not wrong in principle.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0008"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0009"/>22. <eos/><bos/>I have two further general comments.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0009"/></paratext></para><para><paratext>23. <eos/><bos/>The first is this. <eos/><bos/>The fiduciary or his accomplice should not be permitted to gain from the breach of the fiduciary&apos;s obligation of trust and good faith. <eos/><bos/>So, if their profit is greater than the loss by the former employer, an accounting is a better standard of compensation than damages. <eos/><bos/>But, conversely, the employer should not be penalized for any business ineptitude of the fiduciary or his accomplice. <eos/><bos/>So, if the loss by the employer is greater than the profit of the fiduciary, damages would be the better standard of compensation. <eos/><bos/>It follows that, where the evidence will support a sound assessment based on an accounting of profits and also a sound assessment based on a calculation of loss, and where, in the particular circumstances, both remedies are available and both are supported by the pleadings and the evidence, the compensation awarded should be the higher of the two. <eos/><bos/>I think that this is the principle adopted, even before the fusion of law and equity, in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00009" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1867078213" w-pub-number="0005775" ID="I3df453408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Wightman v. Helliwell (1867), 13 Gr. 330 (Upper Canada, Chancery)</cite.query> where, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00010" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1867078213" w-pub-number="0005775" w-pinpoint-page="344" ID="I3df453428e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">at p. 344</cite.query>, Chancellor VanKoughnet said that: “The principle and the object in every case is to make good the loss caused by the acts of omission or commission of the trustee, or to wrest from him any benefit he has, or is taken to have, derived from the use of the trust moneys.”<eos/><bos/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0011"/>24. <eos/><bos/>My second comment is that I consider it the better practice not to make an award of damages to the nearest cent, unless it is intended as compensation for a specific debt or expenditure. <eos/><bos/>Damages are a matter of assessment, not a matter of calculation. <eos/><bos/>The purpose of calculation is not to provide a substitute for an assessment but to anchor the assessment in the evidence. <eos/><bos/>In this case, Mr. Justice Legg was assessing Moore&apos;s loss and was using Salton&apos;s profit as an aid in the assessment of Moore&apos;s loss. <eos/><bos/>I do not think that it is an error of law to reach an assessment of damages to the nearest cent in those circumstances, but I think that it gives a misleading appearance of precision to an assessment that ought to transcend mathematics. <eos/><bos/>And it invites attacks based on flaws in the starting figures and imperfections in the arithmetic.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0011"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id4bb2e428e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">21</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Genesis left it up to the court to determine an award of compensation that was supported by the evidence. <eos/><bos/>Justice Sewell concluded that it was entitled to do so and was not required to elect one remedy or the other.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bb2e438e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">22</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Determining an appropriate remedy in this case presented challenges that were not present in many of the cases relied upon by the plaintiffs. <eos/><bos/>Most of those cases involved a central act that was a breach of fiduciary duty. <eos/><bos/>In such cases, less serious breaches of duty can be viewed as being done pursuant to an object that was itself a breach. <eos/><bos/>In this case, however, the Departing Physicians had the right to set up a competing clinic within which to practice and the benefit they obtained came from that lawful activity. <eos/><bos/>Justice Sewell explained that the Court must be careful not to deprive them of that benefit in any remedy granted.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bb55508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">23</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In addition, the authorities make it clear that any remedy must be restitutionary and the object should be to put the plaintiff in as good a position it would have been in had there been no breach. <eos/><bos/>The court must therefore fashion a remedy that is appropriate to the wrong established. <eos/><bos/>The Departing Physicians breached their fiduciary duty to Genesis to act fairly in the following ways: a) By entering into employment agreements with Wylie and St. Pierre and other Genesis employees while the Departing Physicians continued to be directors of Genesis without making proper disclosure of that fact to Genesis b) By utilizing confidential information of Genesis in the preparation of Olive&apos;s business plan c) By utilizing confidential information of Genesis in connection with hiring Genesis employees. <eos/><bos/>The Departing Physicians breached the Shareholders&apos; Agreement by utilizing Genesis&apos;s financial information. <eos/><bos/>Wylie wrongfully used confidential information belonging to Genesis and failed to disclose to Dr. Kashyap that she had signed an employment contract with the Departing Physicians. <eos/><bos/>As a fiduciary, Wylie owed a duty to disclose that fact to Dr. Kashyap. <eos/><bos/>She also breached her fiduciary duty by conferring with Collings about what Genesis employees Olive should offer employment to while Collings was employed as head of the nursing department at Genesis. <eos/><bos/>The only breach of fiduciary duty St. Pierre committed was her failure to disclose to Dr. Kashyap that she had signed an employment agreement with the Departing Physicians. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence that St. Pierre removed or misused any confidential information belonging to Genesis.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bb55518e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">24</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The preferred remedy sought by the plaintiffs was a judgment equal to the price the Plaintiffs paid to purchase the business of Genesis. <eos/><bos/>The fundamental factual premise of this was that the Defendants, immediately upon Dr. Kashyap becoming obliged to pay the $4.275 million for their shares, set out to destroy that very business that they had just sold to Dr. Kashyap.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bb55528e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">25</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Sewell concluded that the plaintiffs failed to establish entitlement to this remedy. <eos/><bos/>The fundamental obstacle to granting this remedy was that Genesis was not a party to the share purchase agreement. <eos/><bos/>This remedy would therefore be appropriate only if Dr. Kashyap established a basis for it. <eos/><bos/>She had not established a breach of the contract pursuant to which the shares were purchased from the Departing Physicians. <eos/><bos/>On this ground alone, the claim for return of the purchase price must fail. <eos/><bos/>In addition, the plaintiffs failed to demonstrate that the Departing Physicians set out to destroy the business they had just sold to Dr. Kashyap. <eos/><bos/>The object pursued by the Departing Physicians was to continue to practice medicine together in their area of specialty. <eos/><bos/>In pursuing that objective, they breached certain duties to Genesis. <eos/><bos/>They did not destroy Dr. Kashyap&apos;s practice or deprive her of the right to utilize the assets of Genesis for that purpose. <eos/><bos/>The wrongful acts of the Departing Physicians were not the reason for most of the difficulties Genesis faced.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bb55538e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">26</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>As an alternative remedy, the plaintiffs sought an order that the Departing Physicians disgorge all benefits earned by the Defendants for a period of two years. <eos/><bos/>Justice Sewell concluded that such a remedy would be disproportionate to any wrongs done by the defendants. <eos/><bos/>The first difficulty with it was that it ignored the contractual right of the Departing Physicians to compete with Genesis. <eos/><bos/>Genesis&apos;s claim for a disgorgement of profits also failed to recognize that the defendants were only required to disgorge any benefits they received from their breach of duty. <eos/><bos/>They are not required to disgorge any benefits they obtained from lawful activity on their part. <eos/><bos/>Substantially all of the benefits the Departing Shareholders earned from Olive were acquired from their skill, effort and professional standing in the medical profession. <eos/><bos/>There was no indication that the Departing Physicians received a significant benefit from their breaches of fiduciary duty. <eos/><bos/>The breaches they committed did not make any material contribution to their success. <eos/><bos/>The stringent rule requiring a fiduciary to account for profits should not be carried to extremes and should not be transformed into a vehicle for the unjust enrichment of the plaintiff.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bb55548e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">27</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The defendant&apos;s conduct with respect to recruiting Genesis&apos;s employees and their failure to be candid with Genesis about their organizational activities in the 60 Day Period, did cause some harm to Genesis. <eos/><bos/>In addition, the conduct of Collings constituted unfair competition after the 60 Day Period. <eos/><bos/>As these were breaches of equitable duties, compensation for them must be assessed on equitable principles. <eos/><bos/>In assessing claims for damages or equitable compensation for breach of fiduciary duty and breach of confidence, the courts do not require the same degree of certainty as in cases of breach of contract or tort. <eos/><bos/>Nevertheless, there must still be a connection between the breach and the damages claimed. <eos/><bos/>Justice Sewell observed:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0012"/>The principles were discussed <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00011" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1991346037" w-pub-number="0005156" ID="I3dfcb7b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Canson Enterprises Ltd. v. Boughton &amp; Co., [1991] 3 S.C.R. 534 at para. 72</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>Justice La Forest drew a distinction between cases in which a trustee or fiduciary has obtained property that properly belongs to its principal and those in which the fiduciary has acted in breach of its duty and thereby injured its principal:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext>The appellants urged us to accept the manner of calculating compensation adopted by the courts in trust cases or situations akin to a trust, and they relied in particular on the Guerin case, supra. <eos/><bos/>I think the courts below were perfectly right to reject that proposition. <eos/><bos/>There is a sharp divide between a situation where a person has control of property which in the view of the court belongs to another, and one where a person is under a fiduciary duty to perform an obligation where equity&apos;s concern is simply that the duty be performed honestly and in accordance with the undertaking the fiduciary has taken on; see Sealy, “Some Principles of Fiduciary Obligation”, [1963] Cambridge L.J. 119; Sealy, “Fiduciary Relationships”, [1962] Cambridge L.J. 69. <eos/><bos/>In the case of a trust relationship, the trustee&apos;s obligation is to hold the res or object of the trust for his cestui que trust, and on breach the concern of equity is that it be restored to the cestui que trust or if that cannot be done to afford compensation for what the object would be worth. <eos/><bos/><ital>In the case of a mere breach of duty, the concern of equity is to ascertain the loss resulting from the breach of the particular duty. <eos/><bos/>Where the wrongdoer has received some benefit, that benefit can be disgorged, but the measure of compensation where no such benefit has been obtained by the wrongdoer raises different issues. <eos/><bos/>I turn then specifically to that situation.<eos/><bos/></ital> (Emphasis added.)<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0012"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id4bb7c608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">28</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In Justice Sewell&apos;s view, compensation must be assessed by determining the loss suffered by Genesis from the breaches found to have occurred. <eos/><bos/>Genesis advanced a claim for damages ranging from $1,071,949 to $1,278,050 for losses attributable to the defendants&apos; wrongful conduct.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bb7c618e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">29</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Sewell was satisfied that there was a causal link between additional training time for new nurses and conduct of Collings on Olive&apos;s behalf. <eos/><bos/>However, the evidence as to the actual amount of training time incurred was deficient. <eos/><bos/>However, many nurses left Genesis for reasons unrelated to any actions on the part of the defendants. <eos/><bos/>Genesis was entitled to an award of $10,000 for this claim. <eos/><bos/>This award took into account the fact that it would have been expected that there would have been significant staffing changes that resulted from the departure of the Departing Physicians and the attendant reduction of the size of its operations. <eos/><bos/>Many of the nurses who left Genesis did so because of their long association with the Departing Physicians and unhappiness with the working environment at Genesis and not because of any wrongful recruiting activities. <eos/><bos/>These factors justified a lower assessment of damages for this claim.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bb7c628e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">30</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Genesis claimed for lost revenue from PGD cycles that Lafreniere referred on to Olive while he was employed at Genesis. <eos/><bos/>Olive accepted these referrals without seeking or obtaining Genesis&apos;s consent. <eos/><bos/>The opportunity to do these cycles was a corporate opportunity belonging to Genesis that Olive had no right to appropriate without Genesis&apos;s informed consent or if the patient made an independent decision to choose to use Olive. <eos/><bos/>Malice or bad faith are not essential elements of a claim for the wrongful appropriation of a corporate opportunity. <eos/><bos/>To succeed in a claim to require an accounting all that Genesis needs to establish is that it did not give its informed consent. <eos/><bos/>Genesis established a claim for the diversion of referrals. <eos/><bos/>Justice Sewell accepted Genesis&apos;s evidence that it earned a profit of $7,458 per cycle and therefore award rounded damages of $40,000 for this claim.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bb7c638e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">31</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Genesis advanced a claim of $61,643 for wages paid to staff members for December 2012 and January 2013. <eos/><bos/>All of the employees in question continued to fulfill their employment obligations to Genesis in the relevant periods and Genesis accordingly has had the benefit of the services they performed. <eos/><bos/>However, Genesis was entitled to some measure of compensation for the time the named staff employees were paid while they were performing services for Olive. <eos/><bos/>It is impossible to determine the value of that time with any degree of certainty. <eos/><bos/>An award of $15,000, being approximately 25% of the wages paid was reasonable. <eos/><bos/>This award was primarily based on the conduct of Collings and Wylie&apos;s cooperation in and knowledge of that conduct.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bb7c648e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">32</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Genesis claimed reimbursement of a number of expenses it paid which it alleged should be charged to the Departing Physicians. <eos/><bos/>The Departing Physicians retained Weir and Company to provide advice with respect to the tax implications of purchasing Dr. Kashyap&apos;s shares in Genesis. <eos/><bos/>Genesis paid these fees. <eos/><bos/>These expenses should properly have been born by the shareholders who incurred them. <eos/><bos/>Genesis paid dues for the Departing Physicians in January 2013 for the College of Physicians and Surgeons of British Columbia, the British Columbia Medical Association and another professional organization to which Dr. Yuzpe belonged. <eos/><bos/>These dues presumably related to the 2013 calendar year, during which the Departing Physicians worked at Olive for 11 months. <eos/><bos/>Genesis should not have paid for dues which permitted the Departing Physicians to continue their practice at Olive. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, the defendants were liable for 11/12 of these items. <eos/><bos/>The total of these items was $10,274.49. 11/12ths of that amount was rounded to $9,420.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bb7c658e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">33</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The defendants conceded that fees related to billings for private practice billings to MSP were properly chargeable to the Departing Physicians. <eos/><bos/>Genesis was entitled to judgment in the amount of $3,477 for this claim.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bb7c668e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">34</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Genesis claimed $3,679.20 for membership fees paid on behalf of staff that resigned to work for Olive. <eos/><bos/>While many Genesis staff members left it of their own volition after January 31, 2013, Collings was acting improperly in assisting Olive in evaluating Genesis staff as future Olive employees. <eos/><bos/>Olive obtained a benefit from the prepayment of these fees. <eos/><bos/>When the fees were paid, the Departing Physicians had an expectation that many of the employees on whose behalf they were paid would eventually move to their new clinic. <eos/><bos/>The defendants failed to make adequate disclosure of their intention to hire these staff members. <eos/><bos/>Even if the defendants did not wrongfully recruit these employees they should not have caused Genesis to pay their fees in full without fully informing Dr. Kashyap that they considered it appropriate to offer employment to them. <eos/><bos/>In these particular circumstances, Justice Sewell allowed this claim, which was rounded up to $3680.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bba3708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">35</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Although it was not specifically sought by Genesis, Justice Sewell considered that some award was appropriate for the disruption caused to it by the lack of candour of the Departing Physicians in informing Genesis about their activities during the 60 Day Period. <eos/><bos/>The unfair competition engaged in by Olive through Collings&apos; activities also warranted an award of compensation. <eos/><bos/>The amount of such an award could not be tied to any specific claim, nor could it be measured with any degree of certainty. <eos/><bos/>Given the size of Genesis&apos;s operation, the amounts paid to the Departing Shareholders, the revenue generated by Olive and the fact that Olive did make use of confidential information belonging to Genesis, particularly in preparing its application for Bank financing and from information obtained from Collings, Justice Sewell considered an award of $100,000 to be appropriate.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bba3718e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">36</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Genesis sought an award of punitive damages. <eos/><bos/>Justice Sewell concluded that the conduct of the defendants did not rise to the level of a marked departure from the ordinary standards of human decency.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The defendants no doubt exhibited a high level of animosity to Dr. Kashyap. <eos/><bos/>However, the case against them rested principally upon an allegation of breaches of fiduciary duty. <eos/><bos/>The underpinning of Genesis&apos;s case was that the defendants who were found to be fiduciaries preferred their own interests over that of the company to which they owed fiduciary duties. <eos/><bos/>However, Justice Sewell rejected Genesis&apos;s submission that the defendants set out to destroy it or acted maliciously and with a view to injure it. <eos/><bos/>In the particular context of this case, in which the defendants genuinely felt aggrieved at losing the business they had built up over many years, their conduct, although wrongful in some respects, was not so egregious as to warrant an award of punitive damages.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bba3728e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">37</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Genesis was awarded damages as equitable compensation against the Departing Physicians as follows:</paratext><tbl ID="I530752a0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><table frame="all"><eos/><bos/><tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="left"><colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="3*"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="22*"/><colspec colnum="3" colname="3" colwidth="11*"/><tbody><row><entry colname="1">1.</entry><entry colname="2">New nurse training costs</entry><entry colname="3">$10,000</entry></row><row><entry colname="1">2.</entry><entry colname="2">PGD cycles referred to Olive</entry><entry colname="3">$40,000</entry></row><row><entry colname="1">3.</entry><entry colname="2">Staff Wages</entry><entry colname="3">$15,000</entry></row><row><entry colname="1">4.</entry><entry colname="2">Weir and Company billings</entry><entry colname="3">$5,600</entry></row><row><entry colname="1">5.</entry><entry colname="2">Professional Dues</entry><entry colname="3">$9,420</entry></row><row><entry colname="1">6.</entry><entry colname="2">MSP registration fees</entry><entry colname="3">$3,477</entry></row><row><entry colname="1">7.</entry><entry colname="2">Memberships for employees</entry><entry colname="3">$3,680</entry></row><row><entry colname="1">8.</entry><entry colname="2">Damages for disruption and breach of confidence</entry><entry colname="3">$100,000</entry></row><row><entry colname="1"/><entry colname="2">Total</entry><entry colname="3">$187,000[<footnote.reference refid="Id4bbf1908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">38</footnote.reference>]</entry></row></tbody></tgroup><eos/></table></tbl><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00012" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2047411774" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3e0b0f918e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cantol v. State Chemical</ital></cite.query>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id4bbf1918e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">39</footnote.reference>] the Plaintiff sued the Defendants alleging breach of fiduciary duty and breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>The Defendants Daniska and Hanick who had worked for the Plaintiff company that made and sold industrial and specialty chemicals both quit and started working for State. <eos/><bos/>Hanick felt he had been treated poorly by the company and had been denied his commissions. <eos/><bos/>He had been employed with the company for six years as a salesperson. <eos/><bos/>Daniska too felt poorly treated and subject to threats made by the owner that if he did not make his sales he would be fired. <eos/><bos/>Daniska had been a salesperson with the company for 34 years. <eos/><bos/>Neither of the men had any enforceable restrictive covenants in their Employment Agreements with the Plaintiff.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bbf1928e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">40</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Nakatsuru observed the law is quite settled that a fiduciary employee cannot solicit the employer&apos;s customers for a reasonable period of time after the end of their employment. <eos/><bos/>If one is not a fiduciary employee, they are free to solicit like any other employee. <eos/><bos/>The question of whether a fiduciary duty exists depends upon the individual facts of the case. <eos/><bos/>The question is often cast this way: Is the degree of responsibility, dependency, and vulnerability strong enough to support the finding of a fiduciary status? <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiff submitted that Daniska was effectively a part of management and he was a key employee. <eos/><bos/>By the time he resigned, he was titled VP of Marketing. <eos/><bos/>It was argued that Daniska was the head person in sales and product knowledge in a small company with few employees and an informal structure. <eos/><bos/>Daniska, along with Hanick, represented the majority of the Plaintiff&apos;s gross sales in Canada. <eos/><bos/>Given his longevity in the company and knowledge, Daniska was a primary source of knowledge about the Plaintiff&apos;s products and was responsible for training sales staff. <eos/><bos/>It was submitted that the Plaintiff entrusted its relationship with its customers to Daniska who was the face of the company for them. <eos/><bos/>Therefore, according to the Plaintiff, it was vulnerable to solicitation of its customers by Daniska upon his departure.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bbf1938e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">41</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Nakatsuru concluded that Daniska was not a fiduciary employee. <eos/><bos/>Clearly, the owner, who was the President, the only officer, the sole director, and majority shareholder was in charge. <eos/><bos/>The owner was the only person who had access to the financial and the business plans for the Plaintiff, who hired and fired staff, and to whom all sales staff ultimately reported. <eos/><bos/>The owner did not sell products or manage client relationships. <eos/><bos/>However, salespeople would ask him for approval for volume discounts or free shipping for its customers. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiff had some active 700 clients in total. <eos/><bos/>The owner testified that in Canada, outside of Quebec, Daniska serviced about 60% of the Plaintiff&apos;s clients while Hanick serviced the remaining 40%. <eos/><bos/>Quebec-based clients, which represented about 30% of all clients, were handled by Simard and Gosselin. <eos/><bos/>Simard reported to Gosselin who in turn reported to the owner.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bbf1948e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">42</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Having regard to the factual context and looking at the actual job that Daniska performed, Justice Nakatsuru concluded that he was a salesperson and explained that, of course, this finding was not determinative of the issue of whether he owed fiduciary obligations. <eos/><bos/>However, it was an important factor. <eos/><bos/>Justice Nakatsuru did not agree that based Daniska was effectively management.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bbf1958e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">43</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Nakatsuru acknowledged that there were some factors that supported the Plaintiff&apos;s position. <eos/><bos/>For example, Daniska was titled VP of Marketing. <eos/><bos/>However, despite the title, Daniska did not exercise any executive functions and had little or no discretion in that regard. <eos/><bos/>He was VP only in name. <eos/><bos/>Other factors supporting the Plaintiff&apos;s position included the fact that Daniska was with the Plaintiff&apos;s operations in Canada the longest, working there before the owner bought the company, and the fact that the business had a relatively small sales staff. <eos/><bos/>As he was the longest serving employee, Daniska was the person that others went to for information about the products sold by the Plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>Justice Nakatsuru acknowledged that Daniska&apos;s knowledge of the products made him a valuable employee.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bc18a08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">44</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Further, the Plaintiff raised the fact that Daniska had close relationships with the Plaintiff&apos;s customers that he built up over time, while the owner did not. <eos/><bos/>Daniska&apos;s book of business was about $350,000 a year. <eos/><bos/>He serviced around 200 clients. <eos/><bos/>However, in Justice Nakatsuru&apos;s view, when considered in the context of the totality of the circumstances, these factors did not make Daniska a key employee or the face of the company. <eos/><bos/>Fundamentally, Daniska was still an ordinary salesperson, albeit a long-term one.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bc18a18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">45</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Nakatsuru observed that other factors militated against the finding of a fiduciary relationship. <eos/><bos/>Daniska had no involvement in the management of the company and had access to little information regarding its financial operation. <eos/><bos/>Even within the area of sales, aside from servicing his book of customers, he had little power or discretion. <eos/><bos/>Daniska would sometimes recommend products to the owner, but it was the latter who made the decision whether to add the product to the Plaintiff&apos;s catalogue. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiff had a product brochure, but Daniska did not produce or update it. <eos/><bos/>Further, it was the owner who hired the salespeople. <eos/><bos/>On occasion, Daniska may have given input into the potential applicants, but the owner handled the hiring of the 12 to 15 salespersons they had employed over the years. <eos/><bos/>It was true that Daniska would train new employees on product knowledge but he would not train them on sales techniques as they already had such experience. <eos/><bos/>Furthermore, Daniska had no supervisory role over other salespersons. <eos/><bos/>Daniska did not even know how many customers Hanick serviced. <eos/><bos/>The two salespeople had separate accounts for different regions of Canada.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bc18a28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">46</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In Justice Nakatsuru&apos;s opinion, Daniska&apos;s superior knowledge of the products did not leave the Plaintiff dependent on him or vulnerable. <eos/><bos/>Neither the Plaintiff nor its owner was at Daniska&apos;s mercy if he departed. <eos/><bos/>Many salespeople become quite familiar with the products they sell given their experience with them. <eos/><bos/>This is not a form of secret or unique knowledge that Daniska had. <eos/><bos/>Further, his was not a type of encyclopedic or exclusive knowledge relevant to the successful operation of the Plaintiff, thus rendering Daniska&apos;s functions essential. <eos/><bos/>His knowledge could be acquired with a reasonable expenditure of effort. <eos/><bos/>It also could be transferred, as shown by Daniska&apos;s training of other sales staff. <eos/><bos/>In other words, his knowledge of the Plaintiff&apos;s products was not something that made Daniska a key employee. <eos/><bos/>The fact that the owner chose to utilize that knowledge over the years, rather than acquiring it himself or relying more on others did not make the Plaintiff dependent on Daniska. <eos/><bos/>To accept that it did in these circumstances would be a significant extension of the concept of a fiduciary employee.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bc18a38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">47</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Nakatsuru also appreciated that the Plaintiff was a small shop and not a large corporate organization. <eos/><bos/>It was thus true that Daniska was the primary contact for the customers that he served. <eos/><bos/>However, he was far from being the face of the company. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence, aside from customer interactions, that he ever represented the Plaintiff as a spokesperson or company representative. <eos/><bos/>There was little evidence to suggest that being the “face” of the company in this type of limited interaction was outside of the industry norm. <eos/><bos/>It is not unusual for ordinary salespeople, as the primary point of contact, to develop these types of relationships. <eos/><bos/>This fact alone could not transform such a salesperson, no matter how successful, productive, or valued, into a fiduciary employee. <eos/><bos/>This must be so even taking into account the relatively small nature of the Plaintiff&apos;s business. <eos/><bos/>Otherwise, in such a small business setting, every salesperson would come to have fiduciary obligations. <eos/><bos/>An undue reliance on this factor would make Hanick, Gosselin and Simard all fiduciaries.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bc18a48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">48</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Nakatsuru acknowledged that the fact Daniska serviced a significant portion of the Plaintiff&apos;s customers in certain regions of this country was a factor in support of the existence of a fiduciary relationship. <eos/><bos/>However, this had to be tempered by the fact the other salespeople also serviced a significant number of clients in other regions. <eos/><bos/>In other words, the Plaintiff&apos;s reliance upon Daniska was not significantly out-of-proportion with its reliance on its other salespersons who also had a significant number of customers. <eos/><bos/>This was not a case where a single salesperson had control over all or nearly all of a company&apos;s business.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bc18a58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">49</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Finally, and perhaps most importantly, Justice Nakatsuru observed that Daniska had little scope for the exercise of any form of discretion or power. <eos/><bos/>The discretion and the power of running the Plaintiff resided with the owner, which he duly exercised. <eos/><bos/>Daniska, like all the other salespeople, remained under his direction. <eos/><bos/>It could not remotely be suggested that Daniska ran the Plaintiff along with the owner. <eos/><bos/>Daniska had little discretion or power that he could exercise that could affect the Plaintiff&apos;s legal or practical interests.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bc3fb08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">50</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A claim for breach of confidence is made out when the information in question has the necessary quality of confidence about it, the information was imparted in circumstances importing an obligation of confidence, and there was an unauthorized use of that information to the detriment of the party communicating it. <eos/><bos/>In this case, the Plaintiff acknowledged that it had no documentary evidence of any breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence that Daniska misappropriated or took any customer lists or physical files with him. <eos/><bos/>Daniska returned everything to the owner when he left and did not make any copies. <eos/><bos/>Daniska testified that he found contact information of former customers through the Internet or LinkedIn. <eos/><bos/>He also made personal visits to customers he knew.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bc3fb18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">51</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>However, the Plaintiff submitted that Daniska admitted to a breach of confidence in his examination for discovery. <eos/><bos/>It argued that the purchasing habits of the Plaintiff&apos;s customers including the types of products, quantities, and prices paid, was confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiff pointed to the following answers given by Daniska as an admission that he used this confidential information to the detriment of the Plaintiff:</paratext><dialogue.block><dialogue.item><speaker>Q.</speaker><dialogue><para><paratext>… was there a situation where you noticed that the State product was more expensive?<eos/><bos/></paratext></para></dialogue></dialogue.item><dialogue.item><speaker>A.</speaker><dialogue><para><paratext>In some cases State&apos;s products were more expensive, in some cases some of their products were … it depended on the product.<eos/><bos/></paratext></para></dialogue></dialogue.item><dialogue.item><speaker>Q.</speaker><dialogue><para><paratext>Would you adjust prices so that they would be more competitive?<eos/><bos/></paratext></para></dialogue></dialogue.item><dialogue.item><speaker>A.</speaker><dialogue><para><paratext>I could adjust prices, yes.<eos/><bos/></paratext></para></dialogue></dialogue.item><dialogue.item><speaker>Q.</speaker><dialogue><para><paratext>And did you, for some customers, because Cantol products were cheaper?<eos/><bos/></paratext></para></dialogue></dialogue.item><dialogue.item><speaker>A.</speaker><dialogue><para><paratext>Cantol products were cheaper … well, it depends on the … I mean, I can&apos;t recall. <eos/><bos/>Yes, I adjusted certain prices for people but it depends. <eos/><bos/>Some products weren&apos;t even related to Cantol products. <eos/><bos/>You know, for example, one was a water treatment project, which Cantol doesn&apos;t even have, so that is … And I adjusted that price. <eos/><bos/>So, I … you know, it depends on the customer.<eos/></paratext></para></dialogue></dialogue.item></dialogue.block><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Nakatsuru concluded that the exchange was not the admission as alleged by the Plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>On its face, Daniska did not admit that he used the Plaintiff&apos;s pricing information to price products more competitively. <eos/><bos/>Daniska testified that he “could” adjust prices, not that he did do so. <eos/><bos/>This ability to engage in competitive pricing depended on the product Daniska was dealing with, since some products were not even sold by the Plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>Essentially, Daniska admitted he “could” have adjusted prices to make them more competitive but he really could not recall any time he did. <eos/><bos/>In Justice Nakatsuru&apos;s opinion, these answers were far too equivocal to base a factual finding that Daniska did in fact use confidential pricing information to advance the corporate defendant&apos;s interests. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiff did not secure an admission against interest during this part of its examination. <eos/><bos/>Secondly, when this passage is placed in the context of the entirety of Daniska&apos;s examination for discovery and his affidavit where he adamantly denied ever using the Plaintiff&apos;s confidential information, Justice Nakatsuru found no support for the Plaintiff&apos;s argument that Daniska had admitted to a breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>Indeed, immediately before the cited passage, Daniska denied ever telling the corporate defendant about the volume of product the Plaintiff&apos;s customers used to purchase.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bc3fb28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">52</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Regarding the evidence against Hanick in his own capacity, there was even less reason to find him a fiduciary employee than Daniska. <eos/><bos/>Further, the Plaintiff had no evidence that Hanick took or misused any confidential information. <eos/><bos/>At its core, the Plaintiff&apos;s position was that he, like Daniska in many respects, solicited its clients, whose identity he came to know through working for the Plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>In Justice Nakatsuru&apos;s view, this was not sufficient to ground a finding of breach of confidence.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bc3fb38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">53</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>OIBC v. KO</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id4bc3fb48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">54</footnote.reference>] Ko had worked for OIBC, an insurance brokerage in Richmond Hill owned and operated by husband and wife, Lau and Chik. <eos/><bos/>Ko resigned saying she was tired and wanted to spend more time for herself after 23 years of service. <eos/><bos/>Ko changed her mind the next day and contacted the defendant insurance brokerage to inquire about a job. <eos/><bos/>She started actively working for them within one week. <eos/><bos/>Overtime, a significant number of OIBC&apos;s clients transferred over to Ko.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bc66c08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">55</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Nakatsuru explained that he was not ignorant of the fact that the timing of the resignation and subsequent acceptance of employment at the defendant brokerage raised a red flag. <eos/><bos/>However, while Justice Nakatsuru did not find Ko&apos;s explanation as to why she resigned and then started working at a competitor so quickly particularly compelling, he was satisfied that this did not raise an issue requiring a trial. <eos/><bos/>The bottom line was that she moved quickly to a competitor. <eos/><bos/>Her motivation for doing so was a factor to be considered and was something that could be considered properly on a summary judgment motion.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bc66c18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">56</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Nakatsuru observed that the determination of the establishment of a fiduciary relationship in an employment context is very much a fact-based assessment. <eos/><bos/>The legal test regarding the establishment of a fiduciary relationship in this context is flexible and can capture individuals who are not just directing minds of a company or who have top management roles in a corporate employer. <eos/><bos/>Justice Nakatsuru concluded that Ko was not in a fiduciary relationship with OIBC for the following reasons: OIBC was owned and operated by Lau and his wife. <eos/><bos/>Aside from the two, there was no other formal management structure. <eos/><bos/>There were customer service representatives, sales people, and a few others. <eos/><bos/>Ko&apos;s business card had her listed as “Assistant Manager” but it also listed her as an Insurance Broker. <eos/><bos/>Ko&apos;s evidence was that this title was only essentially given to her for public relations purposes and perhaps to help her gain some advantage such as assisting with her sister&apos;s immigration issues. <eos/><bos/>However, this title did not change the fundamentals of what she did at OIBC which was far from management like duties. <eos/><bos/>Ko did not have the type of access to all the information of OIBC like Lau and Chik had. <eos/><bos/>Her ability to unilaterally make any decisions affecting the business was limited. <eos/><bos/>Ko did not perform any significant management functions of the business. <eos/><bos/>A significant part of Ms. Ko&apos;s responsibilities was to sell insurance policies, either renewals or new ones. <eos/><bos/>She was not the only one to do so at OIBC. <eos/><bos/>She was involved directly in the interactions of some but not all of the customers. <eos/><bos/>She was far from being a primary contact for customers or a person that OIBC significantly relied upon to obtain new business or keep existing business. <eos/><bos/>The fact that Ko had worked a long time with OIBC and developed trusting relationships with many clients supported OIBC&apos;s position. <eos/><bos/>However, this was but one factor and was one tempered by the fact that this type of relationship established is an industry norm and the evidence did not establish frequent contact or interactions with each customer. <eos/><bos/>Evidence that Ko had some unique function or knowledge gained through her employment that no one else had that made her indispensable or had unique value to OIBC was significantly lacking.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bc66c28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">57</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Nakatsuru observed that although Ko was a long-time employee with OIBC, she was fundamentally an ordinary salesperson and customer service representative with some supervisory role, who due to her length of time there had a closer working relationship with Lau and Chik than others. <eos/><bos/>This fell significantly short of being in top management or a key employee. <eos/><bos/>Her duties and responsibilities were not such that one could reasonably characterize her as essential to the OIBC&apos;s business.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bc66c38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">58</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Nakatsuru was satisfied that OIBC was not at the mercy of Ko&apos;s discretion. <eos/><bos/>There was no relationship of dependency and OIBC was not vulnerable. <eos/><bos/>Ko was entitled to compete with OIBC by working for its competitor.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bc66c48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">59</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Jetco Heavy Duty Lighting v. Fonteyne</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id4bc66c58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">60</footnote.reference>] the Plaintiff, Jetco sued its former employee Fonteyne for breach of fiduciary duty. <eos/><bos/>Jetco was an importer and distributor of heavy duty vehicle and industrial lighting. <eos/><bos/>Fonteyne was its long-time sales employee. <eos/><bos/>There was no written employment contract. <eos/><bos/>Fonteyne became the vice-president of sales and marketing for Jetco. <eos/><bos/>Once Fonteyne started at Jetco, Sadru relinquished all customers and customer relationships to him. <eos/><bos/>Essentially the totality of the sales function in Jetco was left to Fonteyne.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bc66c68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">61</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Munof, the son of Sadru decided to leave the practice of law in 2004 to enter the family business as the Vice President, Operations. <eos/><bos/>Munof was a forward thinker and was focused on growing the business. <eos/><bos/>Jetco had many smaller customers at the time but had yet to make significant inroads with any larger customers, particularly distributors. <eos/><bos/>Munof realized that Jetco&apos;s strength was in its off-road products. <eos/><bos/>He realized the strategy that would enable Jetco to sell in bulk into larger distribution channels was to go directly to big customers, get them interested in Jetco products to create demand, and then approach the distributors who would order from Jetco in order to supply the big customers. <eos/><bos/>Jetco developed a number of lighting products for use in oil sands mining while working with Suncor. <eos/><bos/>The strategy was successful, resulting in SMS carrying Jetco products for supply to Suncor. <eos/><bos/>During this time, Munof and Fonteyne worked closely as a team. <eos/><bos/>Fonteyne accompanied Munof on all meetings with higher level management in a distribution organization. <eos/><bos/>It was necessary to use a dual approach by developing a relationship both with top management and with the rank and file sales people and line users. <eos/><bos/>Fonteyne dealt with the latter category. <eos/><bos/>By the spring of 2006, Jetco had acquired not just SMS as a customer but also FGI, a distributor of heavy truck after-market parts for both fleets and owner-operators. <eos/><bos/>By the time Munof left Jetco in the fall of 2007, it had been transformed by him from a small family business to a major supplier of heavy duty lighting for both the on-road and off-road markets.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bc8dd08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">62</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Shaffina, the daughter of Sadru, was given the title of Vice President, Operations in 2009. <eos/><bos/>Shaffina completed administrative duties, including reviewing expense claims. <eos/><bos/>Fonteyne viewed Shaffina&apos;s involvement as more significant. <eos/><bos/>He saw her as coming in to run the family business and occupy the same role as Munof. <eos/><bos/>He considered that there was a change in supervision after Shaffina joined the company. <eos/><bos/>Whereas he had reported directly to Sadru, he was now reporting to Shaffina. <eos/><bos/>Fonteyne resigned effective December 31, 2009 following Shaffina&apos;s insertion into Jetco&apos;s operations.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bc8dd18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">63</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The real reason that Fonteyne left Jetco was because he had created a new career for himself. <eos/><bos/>He had revived GE&apos;s interest in retaining him as an agent but knew he had to take on at least one other line of product in order to make his agency viable. <eos/><bos/>During 2008, while researching LED lighting technology on the internet, he discovered the JWS line of trucking and industrial lighting. <eos/><bos/>At some point in 2008, Fonteyne initiated overtures to JWS about opening up a market in Western Canada. <eos/><bos/>In particular, he perceived that JWS&apos;s offering of industrial lighting might be a good fit for end users in the oil sands industry. <eos/><bos/>Fonteyne cultivated a relationship with JWS throughout the remainder of 2008 and throughout 2009. <eos/><bos/>On December 8, 2009, Fonteyne executed an Agency Agreement on behalf of Copper Creek. <eos/><bos/>Three different versions of the agreement were produced at the trial. <eos/><bos/>The difference between the Agreements was that on one of them the signing date for both parties was December 9, 2009 and on the other two versions, the signing dates for one or the other of the parties was shown to be in early January, 2010. <eos/><bos/>The obvious inference drawn by the judge was that Fonteyne knew that it was wrong to be a party to an operative Agency Agreement with JWS while at the same time being an employee of Jetco. <eos/><bos/>The Agreement was accordingly re-dated to a date subsequent to his resignation from Jetco. <eos/><bos/>Starting on December 23, 2009, Fonteyne began having JWS sample products delivered to him. <eos/><bos/>Shaffina later discovered that JWS had become the supplier of choice for Suncor with respect to the haul truck, the light vehicle fleet and the giant shovel lighting. <eos/><bos/>Jetco no longer had any personal relationships with the end users at Suncor. <eos/><bos/>She believed that Fonteyne had scooped Jetco&apos;s Suncor business.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bc8dd28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">64</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>As the trial judge saw it, the main problem that Jetco faced in discharging its burden of proof was that the claims about Fonteyne&apos;s wrongdoing were speculative at best. <eos/><bos/>While making assertions regarding Fonteyne&apos;s unlawful conduct in many respects, Jetco was unable to move beyond mere assertions into the realm of proof on a balance of probabilities due primarily to (a) Fonteyne being able to answer those assertions with credible responses, and (b) Jetco not calling any witnesses to prove the assertions. <eos/><bos/>The evidence allowing the Court to make the inferences was not strong enough in the face of Fonteyne&apos;s explanations and the absence of corroboration or other support.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bc8dd38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">65</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Mah observed that in general, to determine fiduciary employee status, the court must look at the content of the employee&apos;s role and the nature of that employee&apos;s relationship to the employer: citing <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00013" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2000668478" w-pub-number="0006457" ID="I3e2b1ab08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Firemaster Oilfield Services Ltd v Safety Boss (Canada) (1993) Ltd.</ital>, 2000 ABQB 929, at para. 42</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00014" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2011192292" w-pub-number="0003591" w-pinpoint-page="para" ID="I3e2b1ab38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>RBC</ital> at para</cite.query>. 50; <ital>Anderson, Smyth</ital> at para. 17; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00015" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027308870" w-pub-number="0006457" ID="I3e2b1ab48e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>ADM Measurements v Bullet Electric Ltd.</ital>, 2012 ABQB 150</cite.query>, at paras. 73 and 74, and stating that the key concept in these cases was that the employer&apos;s vulnerability is created by the employee&apos;s ability to exercise unilateral power or discretion so as to affect the employer&apos;s legal or practical interests. <eos/><bos/>The critical question is whether the employee has <begin.quote ID="QT_0013"/>“actual authority or control over the employer&apos;s operation”<end.quote refid="QT_0013"/> or <begin.quote ID="QT_0014"/>“is imbued with discretion or control”<end.quote refid="QT_0014"/>.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bcb4e08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">66</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Mah further observed that it is also important not to conflate a valuable employee with a fiduciary employee. <eos/><bos/>Given the onerous obligations held by a fiduciary, it is necessary to actually find that the employee is a “key employee” as opposed to merely being a good or valuable employee.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bcb4e18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">67</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>With respect to sales employees, Justice Mah also noted that it is important not to make a fiduciary finding based entirely on relationships with clients. <eos/><bos/>The focus of the assessment is whether the employee is a key employee such that the employee has sufficient control and authority over the employer&apos;s business. <eos/><bos/>Client relationships are only one part of that context. <eos/><bos/>To ground a fiduciary relationship, the required vulnerability is based on the employee&apos;s ability to exercise discretion or authority over the employer&apos;s operations.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bcb4e28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">68</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>While any decision regarding the existence of a fiduciary duty is contextual and highly fact dependent, nonetheless the common thread is the reposing, by the employer, of sufficient discretion and power to make business decisions such that the employer&apos;s legal or practical interests are vulnerable to the exercise of that power or discretion. <eos/><bos/>The value or competence of the employee does not, by itself, provide the required degree of vulnerability.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bcb4e38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">69</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Mah observed that there was no question that Fonteyne was the “face of Jetco”.<eos/><bos/> Sadru had long abandoned the sales side of the business. <eos/><bos/>Munof had worked on customer development but left Jetco in 2007. <eos/><bos/>As of Munof&apos;s departure, Fonteyne was solely responsible for the sales and marketing, at least until Shaffina showed up. <eos/><bos/>He was the one who interacted with all the customers who actually placed orders of the product, either at the distribution or the end user level. <eos/><bos/>However, Munof had the real ability to change the legal and practical interests of Jetco. <eos/><bos/>He thought out the business strategy that led to the SMS distributorship and led Jetco&apos;s efforts to join the HDCC which resulted in acquiring other major customers. <eos/><bos/>The evidence did not show that Fonteyne wielded such influence at Jetco.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bcb4e48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">70</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Mah observed that in a case where a requisite level of power or influence is part of the legal test, there was not an abundance of evidence about Fonteyne&apos;s authority level while at Jetco. <eos/><bos/>There was no job description or written performance reviews put in evidence. <eos/><bos/>The employment contract was not signed. <eos/><bos/>Justice Mah concluded that Fonteyne had authority for calling on customers, maintaining and developing sales, taking orders and facilitating delivery, and he also passed along information and recommendations to Sadru. <eos/><bos/>He seems to have exercised some discretion with respect to pricing but was still prone to checking in with Sadru in that regard. <eos/><bos/>Sadru maintained control over all aspects of Jetco&apos;s business and made all the important decisions while Fonteyne was there. <eos/><bos/>Sadru&apos;s disagreement with Munof, leading to Munof&apos;s departure from Jetco, was over the schedule for relinquishing control of the company. <eos/><bos/>Sadru wished to maintain control. <eos/><bos/>Contracts with customers needed to be approved by Sadru. <eos/><bos/>Justice Mah was given no information at the trial as how the conferral of discretion or power upon Fonteyne could guide the direction of the company or render it vulnerable.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bcb4e58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">71</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Shaffina was involved with sales. <eos/><bos/>She was copied with all the email sent to Sadru in which Fonteyne was reporting, providing input, making requests or seeking instructions. <eos/><bos/>Her insertion into Jetco changed the management dynamic and diluted Fonteyne&apos;s influence, even though Sadru was still firmly in charge of the whole of the company.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bcb4e68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">72</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>While it was suggested that Fonteyne&apos;s power and influence over Jetco resided in the personal relationships he had forged with customers, Justice Mah was of the view that this was not borne out in the evidence. <eos/><bos/>Justice Mah therefore could not say that the evidence supported the contention that the personal relationships formed by Fonteyne while at Jetco imbued him with a particular power or influence that rendered Jetco vulnerable.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bcdbf08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">73</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Mah concluded that the vulnerability that Jetco experienced as a result of Fonteyne&apos;s departure related to his value and competence as a salesperson. <eos/><bos/>Fonteyne was central to Jetco&apos;s success. <eos/><bos/>That was a function of his capability as a sales person, not because of any discretion or power that he was given. <eos/><bos/>Jetco&apos;s vulnerability was exposed by the level of performance of the employee, not the level of authority given to that employee.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bcdbf18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">74</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>It was also suggested that Fonteyne was privy to Jetco&apos;s confidential marketing strategies, thereby converting him to a fiduciary. <eos/><bos/>Fonteyne was shown the way by Munof. <eos/><bos/>Fonteyne employed the method to some success in placing JWS products at Suncor. <eos/><bos/>In broader terms, the method could be described as a “pull” strategy of marketing, something well known in the marketing world. <eos/><bos/>There was nothing secret or proprietary about this. <eos/><bos/>Munof&apos;s other strategy for the heavy duty side of the business, joining the HDCC in order to gain access to major after-market distributors, could similarly be said not to be confidential in nature.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bcdbf28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">75</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Jetco&apos;s counsel stated that Mr. Fonteyne was a fiduciary because he was a <begin.quote ID="QT_0015"/>“vice president of sales and marketing”<end.quote refid="QT_0015"/>. <eos/><bos/>However, in determining the existence of a fiduciary duty, the law has migrated from the formalism of titles to examination of the actual substance of the role. <eos/><bos/>While Fonteyne may have recommended new products, it was Sadru who was solely responsible for new product development, working directly with the overseas suppliers and taking charge of all supplier relationships. <eos/><bos/>Fonteyne, while an employee at Jetco, could not unilaterally exercise power or discretion so as to affect Jetco&apos;s legal or practical interests so as to make Jetco peculiarly vulnerable. <eos/><bos/>Justice Mah concluded that Fonteyne was not a key or fiduciary employee of Jetco.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bcdbf38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">76</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The duty not to use or disclose confidential information gathered in the course of employment applies to both “mere” employees and fiduciary employees, but is restricted in that the obligation may not cover information which is only “confidential” in the sense that an unauthorized disclosure of such information to a third party while the employment subsisted would be a clear breach of the duty of good faith. <eos/><bos/>On the other hand, it is equally clear that following termination of the relationship an employee is free to use for his own benefit or for the benefit of third parties any skill and general knowledge which he acquires during the course of his employment.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bcdbf48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">77</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>To determine whether information is confidential enough to attract this protection, Courts have considered the following factors: (a) The extent to which the information is known outside the business; (b) The extent to which it is known by employees and others involved in the business; (c) Measures taken to guard the secrecy of the information; (d) The value of the information to the holder of the secret and to its competitors; (e) The effort or money expended in developing the information; (f) The ease or difficulty with which the information can be properly acquired or duplicated by others; and (g) Whether the holder and taker of the secret treat the information as secret. <eos/><bos/>In employment-related cases, the courts also consider whether: (a) the employer possesses a trade secret; (b) the employee knew it was a secret; (c) the employee acquired knowledge [of] it during his/her employment; (d) the employee has, after termination of his/her employment, used of this knowledge improperly.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bcdbf58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">78</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Mah observed that the threshold is quite high for information to qualify as confidential. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence that Fonteyne took any confidential information or trade secrets from Jetco in the form of hard copy or digital documentation. <eos/><bos/>Any information he took was in his head. <eos/><bos/>The “pull” strategy implemented by Munof was not proprietary or confidential, nor would be the identities of the contacts in the distributor and end user organizations. <eos/><bos/>These organizations used many suppliers and the identities of the contact people would be known in the supplier community. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, Justice Mah could not find that Fonteyne used confidential information of Jetco, as a “springboard” or otherwise in breach of his fiduciary duty, if any.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bcdbf68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">79</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00016" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2044400672" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3e39c0b18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Nexim v. Yacoob, MIY</cite.query> and Ask4Care</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id4bd03008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">80</footnote.reference>] Justice McArthur concluded that there was no genuine issue requiring a trial, and that summary judgment must be granted and the Plaintiffs&apos; action dismissed.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bd03018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">81</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Yacoob worked for Nexim, a temporary staffing agency which supplied labour to health care organizations in the GTA, for a number of years. <eos/><bos/>Six months after resigning from Nexim, Yacoob began to work for one of its competitors, Ask4Care. <eos/><bos/>The president and CEO of Nexim, discovered that in the months after Yacoob left his employment, Ask4Care began to provide services to one of Nexim&apos;s long standing customers, BCCL.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bd03028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">82</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In Justice McArthur&apos;s view, the Plaintiffs failed to provide evidence in a number of key areas required to support their claims. <eos/><bos/>First, there was no evidence of any confidentiality agreement entered into by Yacoob. <eos/><bos/>Second, there was no evidence that Yacoob ever took or misused any confidential information. <eos/><bos/>In order to establish breach of confidence, the Plaintiffs would have to establish that confidential information had been misused by Yacoob. <eos/><bos/>The absence of such evidence meant that this claim could not succeed. <eos/><bos/>Third, the evidence did not support that Yacoob owed a fiduciary duty to Nexim. <eos/><bos/>While in most cases fiduciary duties have been limited to senior officials or management of a company, the courts have at times extended fiduciary obligations to lower level employees where that individual is found to be a key employee. <eos/><bos/>A key employee is one whose position and responsibilities are essential to the employer&apos;s business, making the employer particularly vulnerable to competition upon that employee&apos;s departure. <eos/><bos/>While Yacoob&apos;s job title was General Manager, his title must be assessed in light of his actual duties. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence that his duties were such as to unilaterally affect Nexim&apos;s interests, nor was there evidence that Nexim was particularly vulnerable or dependent on Yacoob. <eos/><bos/>Further, there was no evidence that Yacoob&apos;s responsibilities were such as to make Nexim particularly vulnerable to competition upon his resignation.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bd03038e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">83</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>If, however, Yacoob did owe a fiduciary duty to Nexim, that did not end the inquiry. <eos/><bos/>The issue was whether Yacoob solicited any clients of Nexim&apos;s. <eos/><bos/>After employment ends, a fiduciary employee cannot directly solicit the employer&apos;s customers for a reasonable period of time. <eos/><bos/>In the absence of a restrictive covenant, however, the fiduciary is free to otherwise compete once his or her employment ends, provided that he or she does not do so unfairly. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence that Yacoob directly solicited Nexim&apos;s customers. <eos/><bos/>The sole client that Yacoob was alleged to have solicited was BCCL. Ask4Care, however, entered into a contract with BCCL before Yacoob met with Ask4Care. <eos/><bos/>The principal of Ask4Care did not hear about BCCL from Yacoob, rather he had known of BCCL for some time and he had been referred to BCCL for services for his autistic son. <eos/><bos/>Ultimately, Ask4Care entered into a contract with BCCL on June 2, 2015. <eos/><bos/>It was not until almost three months later that Yacoob was hired. <eos/><bos/>While the Plaintiffs argued that the timing was suspicious, that does not equate to evidence. <eos/><bos/>There was simply no evidence that Yacoob solicited BCCL, or had anything to do with Ask4Care entering into a contract with BCCL.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bd03048e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">84</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Finally, the Plaintiffs proffered no evidence that they suffered damages. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiffs provided unaudited financial statements for the year ended December 31, 2015, which showed that in 2015 Nexim had a net loss. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiffs, however, failed to file financial statements for 2016 or 2017. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiffs were required to put their best foot forward on this motion. <eos/><bos/>They failed to file financial statements for 2016 and 2017, the very years in which they claimed to have suffered a loss. <eos/><bos/>Moreover, Nexim actually gained additional locations and additional hours at existing locations with BCCL after Yacoob left the company. <eos/><bos/>Indeed, Nexim had more sales to BCCL in 2016, than it did in 2014 when Yacoob was still an employee.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bd03058e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">85</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00017" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2042193556" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3e488dc18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Kerzner v. American Iron &amp; Metal Company</cite.query> Inc.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id4bd03068e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">86</footnote.reference>] Kerzner was first hired in 1980 by a privately owned family business providing recyclable products to foundries and smelters and steel mills in Canada and elsewhere. <eos/><bos/>Kerzner eventually became a one third owner of the company. <eos/><bos/>He also became the company&apos;s president. <eos/><bos/>In August 2008, the company was purchased by ArcelorMittal. <eos/><bos/>Part of the arrangement with ArcelorMittal was that Kerzner would continue to be employed as the general manager (Non-Ferrous Products) of ArcelorMittal Ottawa. <eos/><bos/>Kerzner worked for ArcelorMittal under a series of employment agreements. <eos/><bos/>The 2014 Employment Agreement was a two-year fixed term contract. <eos/><bos/>It contained provisions governing payments due to Kerzner in the event of early termination of his employment by the employer.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bd03078e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">87</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In March 2015, ArcelorMittal Ottawa was acquired by the defendant. <eos/><bos/>Kerzner&apos;s employment was transferred to AIM. <eos/><bos/>On 11 September 2015, AIM provided Kerzner with one week of working notice of the termination of his employment. <eos/><bos/>He was advised that he would be provided with six months&apos; salary continuation and benefits coverage, purportedly in accordance with the provisions of his May 2014 employment agreement. <eos/><bos/>When, Kerzner accepted a position with an Ottawa-based direct competitor of ArcelorMittal Ottawa, AIM purported to invoke its right under the 2014 Employment Agreement to suspend or terminate all remaining termination payments and benefits that would otherwise have been owed to Kerzner.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bd2a108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">88</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The agreement in place at the time of the plaintiff&apos;s termination was the 2014 Employment Agreement. <eos/><bos/>Kerzner, through his family trust, which was one of the sellers of Bakermet shares, entered into a “Non-Competition and Non-Solicitation Agreement” with Bakermet and ArcelorMittal Montréal Inc., effective for five years. <eos/><bos/>The non-competition clause precluded Kerzner from being employed by any business related to the acquisition, processing and marketing of superior recyclable products from all types of ferrous and non-ferrous metal as conducted by ArcelorMittal Ottawa, ArcelorMittal Montréal and ArcelorMittal SA in Ontario, Québec and the Atlantic Provinces for eighteen months following the termination of his employment. <eos/><bos/>The non-solicitation provision related to the same territory and was effective for two years.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bd2a118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">89</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>To be enforceable, restrictive covenants must be reasonable in all of the circumstances. <eos/><bos/>The parties agreed that a determination of whether a restrictive covenant is reasonable will be influenced by whether it was negotiated as part of the sale of the business by Bakermet to ArcelorMittal, or as part of an employment agreement. <eos/><bos/>There could be no doubt that it was important to ArcelorMittal, at the time of its acquisition of Bakermet, that Kerzner should be both retained as a senior employee but also restricted in his ability to compete with ArcelorMittal or solicit its business in the event that he left the company. <eos/><bos/>This was reflected not only in the employment contracts but, also, in a separate Non-Competition and Non-Solicitation Agreement, which was signed concurrently with the share purchase transaction in August 2008 and which was effective for five years. <eos/><bos/>However, by the time the 2014 Employment Agreement was entered into, the separate Non-Competition and Non-Solicitation Agreement had run its course.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bd2a128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">90</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The judge concluded that although the 2014 Employment Agreement contained non-solicitation and non-competition terms that replicated those found in the 2011 agreement and that were similar, but not identical, to those contained in the 2008 Employment Agreement, AIM could not, on the one hand, argue that the plaintiff was subject to a series of short-term contracts with his rights as an employee limited accordingly, but simultaneously argue that the non-competition and non-solicitation clauses contained in those employment agreements should be assessed in the context of the plaintiff&apos;s sale of his Bakermet shares. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, the reasonableness of the non-competition and non-solicitation provisions in the 2014 Employment Agreement was be assessed having regard to the other provisions of that agreement rather than the longer-term relationship between the plaintiff and the defendant&apos;s predecessors, and in particular the plaintiff&apos;s sale of his shares in Bakermet.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bd2a138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">91</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The 2014 Employment Agreement was for a term of two years. <eos/><bos/>The non-competition obligation survived for eighteen months following the termination of employment. <eos/><bos/>The non-solicitation provisions survived for two years following the termination of employment.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bd2a148e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">92</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>It is well settled that a factor determining the reasonableness of a covenant in restraint of trade in an employment contract is the duration of the restraint. <eos/><bos/>In circumstances where there is a fixed term contract of employment, one of the factors to be taken into account when considering the reasonableness of the restrictive covenant is whether it is temporally proportionate to the term of the employment. <eos/><bos/>The judge observed that while there are plenty of examples of cases in which eighteen month or two year restrictive covenants for senior employees in positions comparable to Kerzner&apos;s had been deemed by courts to be reasonable, none of those decisions involved fixed term employment contracts for a relatively short term of employment. <eos/><bos/>The judge concluded that AIM could not have it both ways. <eos/><bos/>It was unreasonable for an employer in the position of AIM to insist on a fixed term arrangement, yet simultaneously restrain Kerzner from working elsewhere in the only business he had been involved in for the past 35 years, for a period of time that, in the case of the non-solicitation restriction, was for the same length of time as the employment contract itself.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bd51208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">93</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Kerzner&apos;s acknowledgement that the defendant required protection of its legitimate business interest was a factor to be taken into consideration. <eos/><bos/>However, the judge concluded that read and considered in the context of a short, fixed-term contract with unreasonably broad geographic restrictions, and even allowing for the fact that the 2014 Employment Agreement provided Kerzner with an entitlement to compensation upon termination that was more generous than his statutory entitlement, the non-competition and non-solicitation clauses were unreasonable and, hence, unenforceable.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bd51218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">94</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>AIM&apos;s statement of defence and counterclaim requested a declaration that Kerzner breached his fiduciary obligations to AIM by commencing employment with a competitor in November 2015. <eos/><bos/>No particulars of Kerzner&apos;s alleged breach of his fiduciary obligations were pleaded, but a clue could be found in a paragraph addressing damages which referred to confidential and proprietary information having been taken and/or used by Kerzner.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bd78308e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">95</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The judge accepted the basic premise that Kerzner&apos;s fiduciary responsibilities did not automatically end with his employment. <eos/><bos/>The assertion that the taking up of employment with Palmer was in breach of his fiduciary responsibilities was harder to sustain given the finding that the restrictive covenants were unenforceable. <eos/><bos/>Kerzner scrupulously refrained from soliciting any and all customers of AIM. <eos/><bos/>Beyond the bald assertion in the counterclaim that AIM had been damaged by its confidential and proprietary information having been taken or used by Kerzner, AIM presented no evidence to the contrary. <eos/><bos/>The record was insufficient to support any finding that Kerzner breached any continuing fiduciary obligations he may have had to AIM.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bd78318e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">96</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00018" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2042093727" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3e507d018e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cosolo v. Geo. A. Kelson Limited</ital></cite.query>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id4bd78328e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">97</footnote.reference>] the Plaintiff engineer was employed by the Defendant engineering firm between 2005 and October 30, 2015 and ultimately achieved the position of Vice President, Supply Chain &amp; Procurement. <eos/><bos/>Throughout the plaintiff&apos;s employment, there was no written employment contract. <eos/><bos/>At the time of his departure, the Plaintiff was one of the five senior executives of the firm. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiff was approached by an executive recruiter, a “head-hunter,” seeking to secure a Chief Executive Officer for a small mechanical contractor that the firm sometimes used as a sub-contractor for the supply of sheet medal. <eos/><bos/>It shortly became a part of ENGIE which was a large global engineering firm and a direct competitor of the firm. <eos/><bos/>ENGlE had approximately 150,000 employees worldwide. <eos/><bos/>During his employment, he acquired and sold 43,000 Class E common shares of the firm for $891,820, for which he was to receive ten installment payments of $89,182 plus interest on the outstanding balance. <eos/><bos/>He received the first installment before his employment ended, but in 2016, after he was no longer an employee and had become the CEO of a rival engineering firm, the installments stopped. <eos/><bos/>The firm refused to make further payments and it alleged that he had breached his fiduciary duties and asserted by way of defence a right of setoff for damages from the breach of fiduciary duty.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bd78338e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">98</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motions judge described the law associated with the fiduciary duties of a departing senior executive who is not also bound by a written employment contract that might restrict his or her rights to compete against the former employer. <eos/><bos/>A departing servant has the right to compete with his former employer and he or she may bring to that business the knowledge and skill acquired while in the former service, including knowledge and skill directly obtained from the previous employer. <eos/><bos/>Further, the departing employee may solicit business from the former employer&apos;s customers provided that: (a) there is no valid restrictive clause preventing him or her from doing so; (b) the departing employee does not use material obtained or retained in fraud of the employer; and (c) the departing employee does not misappropriate the employer&apos;s confidential information. <eos/><bos/>Where the departing employee is also a fiduciary of the employer, he or she may not directly solicit the former employer&apos;s customers for the reasonable period of time necessary to enable the former employer to retain the loyalty of the customers and to ameliorate the disruption caused by the fiduciary&apos;s departure. <eos/><bos/>The duration and the extent to which fiduciary obligations continue after an employee with fiduciary obligations departs is determined on a case by case basis and depends upon a matrix of factors. <eos/><bos/>After employment ends, the fiduciary employee generally cannot directly solicit the employer&apos;s customers for a reasonable period of time, but in the absence of a restrictive covenant, the fiduciary is free to otherwise compete once his or her employment ends, provided that he does not do so unfairly. <eos/><bos/>The law, however, is cautious in imposing restrictive duties on departing employees in less than clear circumstances because of the public interest in free competition and the public policy of allowing citizens the freedom to pursue economic advantage through mobility in employment. <eos/><bos/>After the termination of the fiduciary relationship, competition, as such, is not prohibited because the law does not favour restraints on trade or impeding a person&apos;s ability to make a living. <eos/><bos/>Rather, the prohibitions focus on the manner of the competition, which must be fair and honourable. <eos/><bos/>The former fiduciary may accept orders from former clientele of the employer, but the former fiduciary may not directly solicit that trade until a reasonable period of time has elapsed Similarly, it is a breach of fiduciary duty if a former fiduciary solicits the former employer&apos;s exclusive suppliers to switch their allegiance to supply a business until a reasonable period of time has passed. <eos/><bos/>What is a reasonable length of time for fiduciary duties to persist is determined on a case-by-case basis.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bd78348e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">99</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motions judge found as a fact that the Plaintiff had a fiduciary relationship with firm. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiff had access to sensitive, confidential and proprietary information about the firm&apos;s business, its workplace, and its overall affairs. <eos/><bos/>He had confidential information about suppliers&apos; discounts and information about the pricing of materials and items in the context of complex construction projects and he knew the details of the firm&apos;s relationships with various subcontractors and suppliers. <eos/><bos/>From time to time during his tenure with the firm, the Plaintiff was involved in preparing bids for projects and was privy to confidential internal budget information and pricing methodology.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bd78358e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">100</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motions judge observed that in certain circumstances, a defendant may set off his or her liquidated or unliquidated claim against the plaintiff&apos;s claim. <eos/><bos/>Equitable setoff is available where: (1) the defendant can show some equitable ground for being protected against the plaintiff&apos;s demands; (2) the equitable ground must go to the very root of the plaintiff&apos;s claim; (3) the setoff must be clearly connected with the plaintiff&apos;s demand that it would be manifestly unjust to allow the plaintiff to enforce payment without taking into consideration the cross-claim; and (4) the plaintiff&apos;s claim and the setoff need not arise out of the same contract. <eos/><bos/>However, the motions judge concluded that there was no genuine issue requiring a trial that the Plaintiff breached his fiduciary duties. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiff&apos;s new employer was entitled to compete with the firm for business in Ontario, and there was nothing unfair or improper in the Plaintiff&apos;s recruitment of several employees of the firm that left the firm to work with ENGIE. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiff did not use any confidential or proprietary information from the firm while he was at ENGIE. <eos/><bos/>There was no substance to the firm&apos;s breach of fiduciary duty setoff claim and there were no genuine issues requiring a trial.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bd78368e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">101</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>On appeal in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00019" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2044171037" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3e5315118e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cosolo v. Geo. A. Kelson Company Limited</ital></cite.query>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id4bd9f408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">102</footnote.reference>] the appellant argued that the motion judge made palpable and overriding errors in finding that Cosolo did not breach his fiduciary duty by communicating with two current Kelson employees and that even if he did, the communications were meaningless breaches.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bd9f418e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">103</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Court of Appeal rejected the appellant&apos;s submission that a breach of fiduciary duty case such as this was in a special category that is not suitable for summary judgment, and therefore the motion judge should have declined to act on the evidence put before the court on the summary judgment motion. <eos/><bos/>Instead he should have ordered a trial, or possibly one or more mini-trials, with full documentary discovery. <eos/><bos/>The motion judge&apos;s conclusion that the respondent breached no fiduciary duty owed to his employer causing damage was amply supported by the evidence. <eos/><bos/>There was nothing raised in the cross-examinations on the affidavits to suggest the need for any further exploration of either documentary or testimonial evidence to resolve any of the issues that the motion judge was asked to decide. <eos/><bos/>There was no genuine issue for trial raised on the record. <eos/><bos/>A breach of fiduciary duty is not a special category that is not amenable to summary judgment where no genuine issue for trial is raised.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bd9f428e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">104</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00020" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2035348352" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I3e57a8f18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Dillon v. Dillon Hillstead Melanson C.G.A. Prof.</cite.query> Corp.</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id4bd9f438e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">105</footnote.reference>] DHM commenced an action against Gord Dillon and Mike Dillon for conspiracy to breach fiduciary obligations. <eos/><bos/>Mike Dillon was terminated from his employment with DHM. In addition to being an employee, Mike Dillon was one of the shareholders and directors of DHM. Immediately upon his termination, Mike Dillon took no further role in the operation or management of DHM. In July 2010, Gordon Dillon, a former partner in the predecessor to DHM, came out of retirement and set up a new accounting firm. <eos/><bos/>Shortly after Gord Dillon opened his new firm, a substantial number of clients from DHM switched their business to Gord Dillon&apos;s firm and three former employees of DHM commenced employment at Gord Dillon&apos;s firm. <eos/><bos/>DHM formed the belief that Gord Dillon and Mike Dillon were working together in the new firm.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bd9f448e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">106</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>There is an existing cause of action in Saskatchewan for conspiracy to breach fiduciary obligations. <eos/><bos/>The court observed that it was important at the outset to recognize that Gord Dillon owed no fiduciary obligations to DHM. Gord Dillon had not practised accounting for four and one half years at the point when he again began practicing, well beyond the three year term of the restrictive covenant contained in the Withdrawal Agreement and also beyond the reach of any fiduciary obligations owed by Gord Dillon. <eos/><bos/>There were no restrictions of any kind on Gord Dillon re-entering the practice of accounting in Regina, taking clients from DHM or hiring staff away from DHM. Gord Dillon&apos;s only potential liability came from a claim that he conspired with Mike Dillon to breach Mike Dillon&apos;s fiduciary obligation.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bd9f458e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">107</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The court first had to determine what fiduciary obligations, if any, were owed by Mike Dillon to DHM. As of June 30, 2010, Mike Dillon was a senior management employee who had been terminated for cause. <eos/><bos/>At the time of his termination, he was also a director of DHM. The court observed that it is well settled that a senior management employee or a director of a corporation owes a fiduciary obligation to his former employer or the corporation he is or was a director of. <eos/><bos/>Mike Dillon was not subject to a non-competition or non-solicitation agreement, but his fiduciary obligations existed even in the absence of such a contract. <eos/><bos/>This fiduciary obligation does not exist only if the employee, officer or director resigns or retires. <eos/><bos/>It may also continue if such a person involuntarily leaves. <eos/><bos/>A fiduciary obligation does not continue, or at least is significantly reduced, if an employee is wrongfully dismissed. <eos/><bos/>The fiduciary duty, however, will continue if the employee is terminated for cause. <eos/><bos/>The continuation of a fiduciary duty upon termination for cause will continue because the former employer is not in breach of the contract of employment or its duties owed to the employee. <eos/><bos/>Such a rule avoids the mischief of an employee who wishes to depart from engaging in behaviour which leaves the employer with no choice but to terminate the employee for cause which would then free the employee to breach his obligations in a manner harmful to the employer. <eos/><bos/>If an employer has acted in good faith and upheld its end of the employment contract, the fiduciary obligation will continue.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bd9f468e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">108</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge concluded that Mike Dillon clearly owed a fiduciary obligation to DHM which continued after his termination for cause on June 30, 2010. <eos/><bos/>He was a key management employee and a director of DHM. He had significant responsibilities and access to confidential and important information in these roles. <eos/><bos/>However, not every action taken by Mike Dillon that had a connection to DHM&apos;s former clients, employees of DHM or the operation of Gord Dillon&apos;s new business would result in a breach of Mike Dillon&apos;s fiduciary obligations. <eos/><bos/>While DHM was highly suspicious that Mike Dillon and Gord Dillon were working in concert in an effort to take DHM&apos;s employees and clients, DHM failed to prove any of the following: a. Any contact between Mike Dillon and DHM&apos;s current or former employees after June 30, 2010 and before the former employees commenced working for Gord Dillon; b. Any contact between Mike Dillon and any clients or former clients of DHM between June 30, 2010 and July 1, 2011; c. Any accounting work done for any of DHM&apos;s former clients, or for any other client, by Mike Dillon between June 30, 2010 and July 1, 2011; d. Any solicitation of DHM&apos;s clients by Mike Dillon at any point in time after June 30, 2010, despite over four years having passed since his termination; e. Any communication of any kind between Mike Dillon and Gord Dillon regarding the solicitation of DHM&apos;s clients or enticement of DHM&apos;s employees; f. The provision of any of DHM&apos;s confidential information or client lists from Mike Dillon to Gord Dillon; g. The use of any of DHM&apos;s confidential information or client lists by Mike Dillon or Gord Dillon; and h. Any communications between Mike Dillon and Gord Dillon whereby Gord Dillon induced or encouraged Mike Dillon to breach any agreements or duties with DHM. Accordingly, DHM failed to prove Mike Dillon solicited clients, enticed employees away from DHM, used confidential information or provided confidential information to Gord Dillon. <eos/><bos/>The actions taken by Mike Dillon subsequent to his termination did not constitute a breach of fiduciary obligations. <eos/><bos/>The assistance provided to Gord Dillon in setting up his office in the summer of 2010 did not involve the use of any confidential information or involve activities directly related to any of DHM&apos;s clients. <eos/><bos/>The fact of Mike Dillon subsequently working as a staff accountant for Gord Dillon one year after his termination, using his skills and knowledge to provide accounting services to some of the same clients he serviced at DHM did not constitute a breach of his fiduciary obligation. <eos/><bos/>With regard to the alleged conspiracy, there was no evidence of any communications or plans between Mike Dillon and Gord Dillon for Gord Dillon to use information obtained from Mike Dillon in breach of his fiduciary obligations. <eos/><bos/>There was no breach simply as a result of Gord Dillon taking staff and clients directly from DHM. While the circumstances and timing of Gord Dillon&apos;s new accounting practice coming into existence were suspicious, the setting up of a new office by Gord Dillon, and the exodus of clients and staff, was not, on its own, capable of proving a breach of fiduciary obligations by Mike Dillon.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bdc6508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">109</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge observed that the onus was on DHM to prove the breach, but noted that DHM did not call any of the independent witnesses who had direct knowledge of the activities allegedly engaged in by Mike Dillon and Gord Dillon. <eos/><bos/>None of the three former DHM employees were called as witnesses by DHM to testify about what they observed in the office from July 2010 to July 2011. <eos/><bos/>These witnesses were all well known to DHM, worked on a daily basis in Gord Dillon&apos;s new office and would have been able to provide independent testimony regarding the presence and activities of Mike Dillon in Gord Dillon&apos;s new office, but none of them were called to testify. <eos/><bos/>Likewise, DHM was well aware of the names and addresses of all 70 clients that transferred their business to Gord Dillon&apos;s new firm, but none of them were called to testify. <eos/><bos/>Again, the former clients had no vested interest in the outcome of the matter and could have provided evidence regarding whether or not they were solicited by Mike Dillon. <eos/><bos/>None of DHM&apos;s witnesses had any knowledge of any contact by Mike Dillon with his former clients, any accounting work done by Mike Dillon for those clients or any contact with the staff. <eos/><bos/>The court was left with the uncontradicted evidence of Mike Dillon and Gord Dillon which established the absence of a breach of a fiduciary obligation by Mike Dillon.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bdc6518e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">110</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Absent wrongful conduct, a fiduciary will almost always be allowed to compete immediately with his or her former employer. <eos/><bos/>It is not mere competition that is a breach of fiduciary duty.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bdc6528e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">111</footnote.reference>] Further, the fiduciary employee will normally be free to advertise a new business and to accept business from customers of the former employer.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bdc6538e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">112</footnote.reference>] By way of example, in <ital>309925 Ontario Ltd. v. Tyrrell</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id4bdc6548e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">113</footnote.reference>] the court acknowledged that:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0016"/>It must be kept in mind in looking at the factors present, in any case, that employers are, or should be aware, that customers of a business who have the benefit of good advice, skill and attention of an employee such as the defendant, tend to seek out his services as opposed to those of other employees. <eos/><bos/>Where such an employee changes employment and becomes a competitor, it is not unusual to find former satisfied customers bringing their business to his new location. <eos/><bos/>Even a senior management employee has the right, in the absence of agreement, or statutory restriction, to enter business in direct competition with his former employer and to advertise the change, including the availability of his services.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0016"/></paratext></para></display.quote><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Some cases, such as the previously cited case of <ital>W.J. Christie &amp; Co. v. Greer</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id4bdc6558e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">114</footnote.reference>] have made it clear that, in some circumstances, a fiduciary employee will even be allowed to solicit the former employer&apos;s customers, so long as there is no misuse of trade secrets and customer lists.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In terms of the obligation of all employees not to misuse confidential information of the former employer, the courts have held that trade secrets and customer lists are confidential. <eos/><bos/>However, there is some ambiguity as to whether “confidential information” includes the names of such customers, and their needs and preferences, that the employee has learned during his period of service and can recall. <eos/><bos/>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00021" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2027291812" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I3e720ec18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Parrish &amp; Heimbecker Ltd. v. Delmar Commodities</cite.query> Ltd</ital>.,[<footnote.reference refid="Id4bded608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">115</footnote.reference>] the plaintiff sought from both Hodgson and Delmar return of its confidential information and an injunction enjoining them from using such confidential information or soliciting its customers, particularly in an area of Manitoba described as the “northeast territory”.<eos/><bos/> The defendant Hodgson was employed by the plaintiff until September 6, 2011 when he went to work for Delmar, a supplier and competitor of the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>In the winter of 2010/11, Delmar decided that because the plaintiff had chosen not to extend its reach into the northeast territory with a facility in the area, it would do so. <eos/><bos/>It entered into an agreement to acquire land and engaged local contractors to do the construction work. <eos/><bos/>Delmar did not advise the plaintiff of its intention to build this facility until after Hodgson had joined the company. <eos/><bos/>On September 6, 2011, Hodgson resigned from his employment with the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>He had sought out other employment and as a result secured two offers, one from Delmar for the position of Territory Manager for Eastern Manitoba. <eos/><bos/>He took the job and began work shortly thereafter. <eos/><bos/>Hodgson denied that he took any customer list or other property of the plaintiff when he left its employ. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff had no evidence that he took any such documentation. <eos/><bos/>There was no formal employment contract between Hodgson and the plaintiff, although he did endorse his acknowledgement on the plaintiff&apos;s employee handbook which contained a provision obliging all employees to maintain in strict confidence information received by the plaintiff or its customers and requiring them not to disclose this information either during the period of employment or at any time thereafter.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bded618e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">116</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motions judge observed that there was limited, if any, evidence of Hodgson having or using confidential information of the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence that he had any documentation belonging to the plaintiff, including customer lists. <eos/><bos/>He had no secret information about pricing of Legend Seed, as all sellers were required to sell at the same price. <eos/><bos/>There was no evidence that he had targeted the plaintiff&apos;s customers. <eos/><bos/>The names of all farmers in the area were public information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bded628e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">117</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>It was possible that, at trial, Hodgson would not be found to have been a key employee. <eos/><bos/>However, the evidence was quite convincing that he was. <eos/><bos/>As General Manager, he was more than a sales manager. <eos/><bos/>He had general managerial responsibilities over a large facility with a substantial sales volume. <eos/><bos/>In terms of his reassignment to Customer Service Manager, he held this position for only the last two or three months of his employment with the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>In both positions, he acquired considerable knowledge about the plaintiff&apos;s customers.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bded638e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">118</footnote.reference>] If Hodgson did no more than pass on his business card and advise of where he was working, it was possible that, at trial, this might be found not to constitute solicitation. <eos/><bos/>However, this seemed unlikely. <eos/><bos/>By personally attending at the farms, Hodgson had clearly done more than generally advertise his new employment. <eos/><bos/>He directly approached farmers, knowing that some of them were customers of the plaintiff, in an attempt to secure their business. <eos/><bos/>And he has successfully concluded sales with some of these individuals.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>However, the plaintiff had not established that it would suffer irreparable harm if the injunction were denied. <eos/><bos/>The court was not persuaded that the plaintiff&apos;s customers were moving to Delmar because of any solicitation on the part of Hodgson. <eos/><bos/>Instead, any loss of market share would appear to result from Delmar now selling Legend Seed and having a facility in the area and, probably even more importantly, from the plaintiff&apos;s decision to no longer sell Legend Seed.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The balance of convenience weighed in favour of denying an injunction. <eos/><bos/>The reality was that the sale of soybean seeds was a highly competitive business. <eos/><bos/>While Delmar hired Hodgson to assist in its entry into the northeast territory market, there was scant evidence that it or Hodgson was using confidential information or targeting the plaintiff&apos;s customers. <eos/><bos/>Further, even if Hodgson was a key employee of the plaintiff, the law provides that he could join a competitor, sell to its customers, and advertise.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bded648e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">119</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The courts have sometimes concluded that where an employer&apos;s business is set up in a manner that creates close working relationships between an employee and customers, the employer runs the risk that if the employee departs, the customers will end up transferring their business to that employee.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>However, cases such as <ital>Hudson&apos;s Bay Co. v. McClocklin</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id4bded658e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">120</footnote.reference>] demonstrate how precarious this area of the law can be. <eos/><bos/>While the <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00022" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1986268597" w-pub-number="0003986" ID="I3e7654818e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Hudson&apos;s Bay</ital></cite.query> case was decided on the basis of unique facts, it held that the hearing aid specialist of a department store was a fiduciary.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4bded668e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">121</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Some courts have been more specific in defining the steps that can be taken by a fiduciary. <eos/><bos/>In <ital>Moore International (Canada) Ltd. v. Carter</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id4be14708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">122</footnote.reference>] the British Columbia Supreme Court held that departed fiduciary employees cannot specifically solicit customers of their former employer. <eos/><bos/>Rather, any solicitation must be general in nature, to the public as a whole. <eos/><bos/>There is no absolute prohibition against a fiduciary sending out promotional materials or generally advertising a new business. <eos/><bos/>The prohibition is against actively soliciting the business of specific customers for a reasonable period of time after termination of employment.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4be14718e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">123</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In considering whether a former employee was a “key employee” for the purpose of attracting a fiduciary duty, the court will look at a former employee&apos;s job duties; the extent or frequency of contact between the employee and customers and/or suppliers; whether the employee was the primary contact with customers and/or suppliers; to what extent the employee had access and made use of knowledge of the former employee&apos;s customers, their accounts, pricing practices and the pricing of product and services; and to what extent the former employee&apos;s information was confidential. <eos/><bos/>In <ital>Canadian Hedge Watch Inc. v. Street</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id4be14728e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">124</footnote.reference>] the plaintiff was granted an interlocutory order prohibiting the defendants from using the plaintiff&apos;s confidential information; soliciting or accepting business from the current and prospective sponsors, clients, and attendees of the plaintiff&apos;s conference; usurping, taking, or converting any corporate assets or opportunities belonging to the plaintiff; unfairly competing with the plaintiff; interfering with the plaintiff&apos;s contractual relations with third parties; misrepresenting that they are associated with the plaintiff or its conferences; and, from arranging, presenting, promoting, sponsoring, or hosting The Alliance for Institutional Dialogue&apos;s “Annual Symposium” in Niagara-on-the-Lake, or elsewhere, and/or any conference of the same or a similar nature in southern Ontario.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4be14738e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">125</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff was a commercial entity that ran conferences as a revenue-generating business activity. <eos/><bos/>It had established goodwill in its conference. <eos/><bos/>The defendant, Street, had been the Vice President of Sales of the plaintiff since 2009. <eos/><bos/>She became the Chief Operating Officer of the NID Conference upon its creation in 2010. <eos/><bos/>Street resigned from the plaintiff&apos;s employ in 2013 in order to spend more time with her husband and possibly to help him produce practice management conferences in his business. <eos/><bos/>However, she agreed to continue to consult to the plaintiff on a part-time basis under the terms of a written consulting agreement in relation to the NID Conference. <eos/><bos/>As COO of the NID Conference Street was also a member of the Advisory Board. <eos/><bos/>She was the representative of the plaintiff with principal responsibility for running the conference. <eos/><bos/>Together with the defendants Lett and Holt, Street was very successful in developing the NID Conference to its premier place in the industry. <eos/><bos/>There was a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that under a veil of secrecy the defendants agreed to and proceeded to unlawfully take the plaintiff&apos;s corporate assets and its corporate opportunities associated with those assets. <eos/><bos/>At a time when the defendant Street was contractually bound to diligently and faithfully serve the plaintiff, she and the other defendants agreed to take the plaintiff&apos;s conference goodwill and opportunity. <eos/><bos/>Rather than competing openly and honestly, there was a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case, from the defendants&apos; own evidence, that the defendants surreptitiously carried out overt acts to implement their agreement to take the plaintiff&apos;s conference.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4be14748e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">126</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motions judge concluded that there was at least one serious issue to be tried as to whether Street was a fiduciary in light of her acknowledged significance as the face of the plaintiff in respect of the NID Conference. <eos/><bos/>She had “encyclopedic knowledge” of the plaintiff&apos;s business, market opportunity, customers, and suppliers. <eos/><bos/>If Street was a fiduciary, then she fell under the prohibition against unfair post-employment competition. <eos/><bos/>An important factor in deciding whether a fiduciary&apos;s competition is unfair is whether it is infected by improper conduct prior to the time that the fiduciary left her role with the employer. <eos/><bos/>The defendants had met, agreed to their plan, took the hotel reservations, and prepared to commence sales as if they were the NID Conference before Street even left the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>They incorporated the corporate defendant one week later with Street as a director. <eos/><bos/>Under cross-examination the defendants agreed that Street&apos;s appointment to the board was intentionally done but was reversed later purportedly at Street&apos;s request. <eos/><bos/>The motions judge observed that her appointment was an “error” only in the sense that Street realized that she should not have done it. <eos/><bos/>It was not accidental.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4be14758e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">127</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The other defendants all knew and participated in Street&apos;s conduct. <eos/><bos/>The motions judge noted that a subordinate who participates in a fiduciary&apos;s breach of duty is liable with the fiduciary. <eos/><bos/>In this case, arguably, it was the other defendants who were the seniors members of the new entity who wished to create a business and induced a subordinate who had duties to the plaintiff to join them and to breach her duties in doing so. <eos/><bos/>Holt and Lett never resigned from the plaintiff&apos;s Advisory Board. <eos/><bos/>While there was no doubt that Holt and Lett were free to compete with the plaintiff generally, there was at least a serious issue to be tried as to whether in agreeing to sit on the plaintiff&apos;s Advisory Board for consideration there was an implied duty that Holt and Lett would act in the best interests of the plaintiff and avoid conflicts of interest vis-à-vis the subject matter of their appointment and not try to usurp the conference for themselves. <eos/><bos/>The defendants Holt and Lett argued that they could not be fiduciaries because they never undertook to sacrifice their interests to protect those of the plaintiff. <eos/><bos/>The question of whether by agreeing to join the plaintiff&apos;s Advisory Board, the defendants undertook such duties to the plaintiff in relation to the NID Conference was a serious issue to be tried.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4be3b808e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">128</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Innersolutions Ltd. v. Hooper</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id4be3b818e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">129</footnote.reference>] the Applicant sought injunctive relief to prohibit the Respondents from operating a directly competing business, soliciting and using the Applicant&apos;s trade connections, soliciting and providing services to any of the Applicant&apos;s clients, and disclosing and using the Applicant&apos;s confidential information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4be3b828e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">130</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Applicant provided a specialized counselling program that included psychotherapy and education services to individuals suffering from severe mental illnesses, as well as to their families. <eos/><bos/>The Respondents Hooper and Woolsey were former employees or independent contractors of the Applicant. <eos/><bos/>Woolsey and Hooper incorporated Inspired Minds Inc. while they were working for the Applicant. <eos/><bos/>The Applicant hired Woolsey in April 2007 and Hooper in April 2012. <eos/><bos/>The Applicant required Woolsey and Hooper to sign agreements, which stated that they would learn the design and operation of the Applicant&apos;s DBT program, they would provide treatment using that program, and the Applicant had interests that it wanted to protect. <eos/><bos/>Each agreement required that they not compete for business, clients, or professional services during their employment and that they provide three months&apos; notice of termination. <eos/><bos/>Hooper&apos;s agreement included additional express terms that all patients were to remain with the Applicant in the event of her termination and she would not offer or advertise private practice services in the specialized nature of the Applicant within a four hundred kilometer radius of Calgary for twenty-four months from the date of termination. <eos/><bos/>Woolsey&apos;s agreement also required that all clients were to have the first option to remain with the Applicant in the event of her termination. <eos/><bos/>In June 2012, Woolsey and her husband wanted to explore the possibility of purchasing the Applicant&apos;s business. <eos/><bos/>To facilitate this exploration, they signed a confidentiality/non-competition agreement.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4be3b838e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">131</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The modified first branch of the test for an interlocutory injunction required the Court to consider whether the Applicant had established a strong <ital>prima facie</ital> case that the restrictions were enforceable against the Respondents. <eos/><bos/>This was the Applicant&apos;s onus and the Court found that although the Applicant had a proprietary interest that was worthy of protection, there was insufficient evidence that would allow the Court fully to assess the reasonableness of the restrictive covenant it was seeking against the Respondents. <eos/><bos/>That was not to say that such evidence was not available. <eos/><bos/>It simply meant that the Applicant had not met its onus on the motion.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4be3b848e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">132</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motions judge found that the agreements that bound the respondents were too broad or ambiguous which pointed to their unreasonableness. <eos/><bos/>The Applicant argued that either or both of Hooper and Woolsey had fiduciary duties towards the Applicant. <eos/><bos/>The motions judge observed that there is no doubt that a director and officer of corporation acts in a fiduciary capacity towards the corporation. <eos/><bos/>Fiduciary obligations can extend beyond those roles. <eos/><bos/>Although the Applicant provided the respondents with certain confidential information, they did not have the authority to affect the Applicant&apos;s “legal and economic interests”.<eos/><bos/> They did, however, have exclusive access to certain of the Applicant&apos;s clients. <eos/><bos/>The motions judge stated:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0017"/>But does that place them in a fiduciary relationship vis-á-vis the Applicant? <eos/><bos/>In <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00023" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1981177092" w-pub-number="0005150" w-pinpoint-page="477" ID="I3e8855e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>WJ Christie &amp; Co v Greer</ital> (1981), 121 DLR (3d) 472 at 477 (Man CA)</cite.query>, the Manitoba Court of Appeal said the following:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext>There is nothing to prevent an ordinary employee from terminating his employment, and normally that employee is free to compete with his former employer. <eos/><bos/>The right to compete freely may be constrained by contract….<eos/><bos/> But it is different for a director/officer/key management person who occupies a fiduciary position. <eos/><bos/>Upon his resignation and departure, that person is entitled to accept business from former client, but direct solicitation of that business is not permissible. <eos/><bos/>Having accepted a position of trust, the individual is not entitled to allow his own self-interest to collide and conflict with fiduciary responsibilities. <eos/><bos/>The direct solicitation of former clients traverses the boundary of acceptable conduct….<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0017"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id4be3b858e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">133</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The motions judge concluded that it did not appear that the respondents were “key employees” or “key management”.<eos/><bos/> At best, they were “ordinary employees”.<eos/><bos/> Thus, they were <begin.quote ID="QT_0018"/>“free to compete with the Applicant. <eos/><bos/>That was not to say that with more evidence a court might find that they were key employees. <eos/><bos/>That issue would be left to the trial judge.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0018"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id4be62908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">134</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>With respect to a duty of fidelity and good faith to his employer, a duty much narrower in scope than the duty owed by a departing employee who stands in the position of a fiduciary, the respondents gave the clients an option to stay with the Applicant. <eos/><bos/>Further, on their departure from the Applicant&apos;s employ, they shredded their patient lists and left the patient files with the Applicant. <eos/><bos/>Again, further evidence might be extracted during the trial that might provide more information concerning a breach of their duty of fidelity and good faith, but such information was simply not before the motions judge.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4be62918e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">135</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>IT/Net Inc. v. Doucette</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id4be62928e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">136</footnote.reference>] the court considered whether an enforceable non-competition or non-solicitation clause also brings an obligation “to reject or resist offers” from the employer&apos;s customers. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff argued that there was not only <begin.quote ID="QT_0019"/>“a prohibition against actively seeking business from your former employer&apos;s customers, but also, in addition, there is a duty to decline unsolicited offers which may come your way.”<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0019"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id4be62938e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">137</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff relied on the case of <ital>DiFlorio v. Con Structural Steel Ltd.</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id4be62948e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">138</footnote.reference>] After reviewing the facts, the court stated:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0022"/>In discussing the distinction between passively attracting former customers to a new business, and actively approaching them to get their business, the trial judge had this to say at paragraph 205 at page 43:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext>The extent of the fiduciary duty and the question as to whether there has been breach of such a duty would differ with the factual situations in each individual case. <eos/><bos/>If [a former employee], by reason of his own qualifications and abilities attracts customers to his new business, such a result accrues from a personal asset of [the former employee]. <eos/><bos/>On the other hand, if [the former employee] acquires a connection or a relationship with a customer of the [former employer] during the course of his employment with the [former employer] and, after his resignation, he affirmatively approaches that customer with a view of enticing the customer to cease doing business with the [former employer], that would be an act which would pass over the boundary and constitute breach of a fiduciary duty.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0022"/></paratext></para></display.quote></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0023"/>The trial judge eventually found in favour of the plaintiffs, based on the particular facts present in the case, as expressed as follows at paragraphs 216 and 217 at page 46:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext>In these circumstances, I conclude that the non-solicitation obligation of Roland and Bertolo precluded them from quoting on a project in response to a contact that may have been initiated by a former Rocca client in light of the generalized solicitation that is admitted to have taken place. <eos/><bos/>As employees of Con Steel, Bertolo and Roland were entitled to compete vigorously and head-to-head for new clients. <eos/><bos/>However, the “stranger principle” would be violated if, on the facts of this case, Con Steel were permitted to exploit Bertolo&apos;s relationships with former Rocca clients simply because direct contact may have been initiated by those clients after Con Steel&apos;s generalized solicitation in this small community.<eos/><bos/></paratext></para><para><paratext>I conclude that an overly rigid view of what constitutes solicitation is not appropriate in the facts of this case. <eos/><bos/>That conclusion is reinforced by the decision of Chapnik J. in <ital>Sure-Grip Fasteners v. Allgrade Bolt &amp; Chain</ital>, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00024" w-ref-type="ER" w-serial-number="2027308870" w-pub-number="0006457" w-pinpoint-page="291" ID="I3e9268008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">supra at 291</cite.query> (C.C.E.L.).<eos/><bos/> She confirms that, when there has been direct solicitation of former customers in the business community, it is not important to ascertain subsequently whether the former client requested a price quotation from the fiduciary:</paratext></para><para><paratext>Clearly, the defendants set out, to establish their own business by gaining customers cultivated and nourished, if not nurtured, while in the plaintiffs employ. <eos/><bos/>Their business diligence was utilized for the most part to pursue the plaintiff&apos;s customers, in an attempt to create a diversion of business to their own company. <eos/><bos/>King himself contacted 40 to 50 former customers during the first week after his departure.<eos/><bos/></paratext></para><para><paratext>The defendants could have chosen to allow news of their departure and the establishment of Allgrade to reach the plaintiffs customers without resort to the direct approach. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, whether or not the quotations on orders were requested by any or all of the common customers, in the particular circumstances here, I have no hesitation in finding the actions of the defendants to have been in breach of their fiduciary responsibility to the plaintiff.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0023"/></paratext></para></display.quote></para></display.quote><paratext>The Ontario Court of Appeal upheld the trial judge&apos;s decision that, based on the facts of the case, there was no breach of a non-solicitation clause. <eos/><bos/>The court emphasized that it <begin.quote ID="QT_0020"/>“should not be taken as saying that the non-solicitation clause in issue is unenforceable”<end.quote refid="QT_0020"/>, only that <begin.quote ID="QT_0021"/>“the facts as found by the trial judge do not constitute a breach”<end.quote refid="QT_0021"/>.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4be89a08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">139</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Ontario decision of <ital>White Oaks Welding Supplies v. Tapp</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id4be89a18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">140</footnote.reference>] also held that fiduciaries are prevented from directly and deliberately soliciting the customers of their former employer:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0024"/>The obligation of [the defendant] was of an altogether higher nature and was to refrain, not from competition, but from deliberately soliciting customers of the plaintiff, other than as part of the general customer public to whom general solicitation might be made.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0024"/></paratext></para></display.quote><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>However, in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00025" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2001464023" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I3e97bf318e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Eversoft Fibre &amp; Foam Ltd. v. James</ital></cite.query>, the court, relying heavily on <ital>Canadian Aero Service Limited v. O&apos;Malley</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id4be89a28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">141</footnote.reference>] disagreed with the contention <begin.quote ID="QT_0025"/>“that it is quite proper and fair to advertise [a] new business, and that if it results in customers of the Plaintiff choosing [the former employee&apos;s] business over that of the Plaintiff, that is no breach”<end.quote refid="QT_0025"/>.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4be89a38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">142</footnote.reference>] On the other hand, <ital>Axiom Services Ltd. v. Weigert</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id4be89a48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">143</footnote.reference>] the court held:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0026"/>Generally, however, such duties will not include a duty not to compete with the former employer, nor will they prohibit the former employee from attempting to woo the existing clients of the former employer …<end.quote refid="QT_0026"/></paratext></para></display.quote><paratext>Numerous cases, both allowing and prohibiting various kinds of solicitation, have considered this issue.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id4be89a58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">144</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Id4bab9108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00026" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1981177092" w-pub-number="0005150" w-pinpoint-page="477" ID="I3e9834608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>W.J. Christie &amp; Co. v. Greer</ital> (1981), 121 D.L.R. (3d) 472 at p. 477, [1981] 4 W.W.R. 34 (Man. C.A.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bab9118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00027" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I3e985b708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bab9128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00028" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I3e9882808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 2-6.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bab9138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>4</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00029" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I3e98a9908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 9-12.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bab9148e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>5</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00030" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I3e98f7b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 42, 45-46, and 48-56.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bab9158e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>6</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00031" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I3e991ec08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 87, and 95-96.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bae0208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>7</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00032" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I3e9945d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 98 and 101-111.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bae0218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>8</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00033" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I3e996ce08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 112-113.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bae0228e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>9</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00034" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I3e9993f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233, at para. 116</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bae0238e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>10</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00035" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I3e99bb008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 118-119.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bae0248e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>11</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00036" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I3e9a09208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 123, 125, and 134.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bae0258e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>12</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00037" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I3e9a30308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 135 and 138.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bb07308e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>13</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00038" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I3e9a57408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233, at para. 145</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bb07318e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>14</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00039" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I3e9a7e508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 154-156.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bb07328e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>15</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00040" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I3e9aa5608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233, at para. 164</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bb07338e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>16</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00041" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I3e9acc708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233, at para. 172</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bb07348e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>17</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00042" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I3e9af3808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 186-195.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bb07358e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>18</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00043" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I3e9b1a908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 201-206.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bb2e408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>19</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00044" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I3e9b68b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 276-278.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bb2e418e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>20</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00045" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I3e9b8fc08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 279-281.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bb2e428e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>21</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00046" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I3e9bb6d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233, at para. 282</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bb2e438e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>22</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00047" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I3e9c04f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233, at para. 284</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bb55508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>23</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00048" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I3e9c2c008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 285-287.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bb55518e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>24</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00049" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I3e9c7a208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 288-294.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bb55528e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>25</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00050" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I3e9ca1308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233, at para. 296</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bb55538e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>26</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00051" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I3e9cc8408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 297-300.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bb55548e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>27</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00052" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I3e9cef508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 310, 312-313, 331, and 334-335.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bb7c608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>28</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00053" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I3e9d3d708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 336-339.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bb7c618e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>29</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00054" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I3e9d64808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 341 and 343.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bb7c628e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>30</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00055" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I3e9d8b908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 349-350.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bb7c638e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>31</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00056" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I3e9dd9b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 360, 364-366, and 370.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bb7c648e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>32</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00057" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I3e9e00c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233, at para. 371</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bb7c658e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>33</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00058" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I3e9e27d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 399, 402, and 409.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bb7c668e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>34</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00059" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I3e9e4ee08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 417-418.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bba3708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>35</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00060" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I3e9e75f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233, at para. 419</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bba3718e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>36</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00061" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I3e9e9d008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 436-437.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bba3728e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>37</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00062" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I3e9ec4108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233</cite.query>, at paras. 438, and 440-441.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bbf1908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>38</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00063" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047640597" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I3e9eeb208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Genesis Fertility Centre Inc. v. Yuzpe</ital>, 2019 CarswellBC 366, 2019 BCSC 233, at para. 444</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bbf1918e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>39</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00064" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047411774" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3e9f12308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cantol v. State Chemical</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 1084, 2019 ONSC 531</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bbf1928e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>40</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00065" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047411774" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3e9f39408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cantol v. State Chemical</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 1084, 2019 ONSC 531</cite.query>, at paras. 1-2.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bbf1938e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>41</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00066" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047411774" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3e9f60508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cantol v. State Chemical</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 1084, 2019 ONSC 531</cite.query>, at paras. 6-8.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bbf1948e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>42</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00067" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047411774" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3e9fae708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cantol v. State Chemical</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 1084, 2019 ONSC 531</cite.query>, at paras. 9-11.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bbf1958e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>43</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00068" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047411774" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3e9fd5808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cantol v. State Chemical</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 1084, 2019 ONSC 531, at para. 13</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bc18a08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>44</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00069" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047411774" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3e9ffc908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cantol v. State Chemical</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 1084, 2019 ONSC 531</cite.query>, at paras. 14-15.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bc18a18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>45</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00070" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047411774" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea023a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cantol v. State Chemical</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 1084, 2019 ONSC 531</cite.query>, at paras. 16-17.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bc18a28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>46</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00071" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047411774" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea04ab08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cantol v. State Chemical</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 1084, 2019 ONSC 531, at para. 18</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bc18a38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>47</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00072" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047411774" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea071c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cantol v. State Chemical</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 1084, 2019 ONSC 531, at para. 19</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bc18a48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>48</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00073" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047411774" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea098d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cantol v. State Chemical</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 1084, 2019 ONSC 531, at para. 20</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bc18a58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>49</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00074" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047411774" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea098d38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cantol v. State Chemical</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 1084, 2019 ONSC 531, at para. 21</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bc3fb08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>50</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00075" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047411774" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea0e6f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cantol v. State Chemical</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 1084, 2019 ONSC 531</cite.query>, at paras. 22-23.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bc3fb18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>51</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00076" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047411774" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea10e008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cantol v. State Chemical</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 1084, 2019 ONSC 531</cite.query>, at paras. 26-27.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bc3fb28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>52</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00077" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047411774" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea135108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cantol v. State Chemical</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 1084, 2019 ONSC 531</cite.query>, at paras. 28-29.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bc3fb38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>53</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00078" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2047411774" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea15c208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cantol v. State Chemical</ital>, 2019 CarswellOnt 1084, 2019 ONSC 531, at para. 32</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bc3fb48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>54</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00079" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2045161580" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea183308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>OIBC v. KO</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 12412, 2018 ONSC 4612</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bc66c08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>55</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00080" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2045161580" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea1aa408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>OIBC v. KO</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 12412, 2018 ONSC 4612, at para. 1</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bc66c18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>56</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00081" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2045161580" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea1aa438e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>OIBC v. KO</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 12412, 2018 ONSC 4612, at para. 13</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bc66c28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>57</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00082" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2045161580" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea1f8608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>OIBC v. KO</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 12412, 2018 ONSC 4612</cite.query>, at paras. 14-15.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bc66c38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>58</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00083" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2045161580" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea21f708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>OIBC v. KO</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 12412, 2018 ONSC 4612, at para. 16</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bc66c48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>59</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00084" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2045161580" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea21f738e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>OIBC v. KO</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 12412, 2018 ONSC 4612, at para. 18</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bc66c58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>60</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00085" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044444806" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3ea246808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jetco Heavy Duty Lighting v. Fonteyne</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 831, 2018 ABQB 345</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bc66c68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>61</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00086" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044444806" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3ea294a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jetco Heavy Duty Lighting v. Fonteyne</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 831, 2018 ABQB 345</cite.query>, at paras. 1-2, and 13-14.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bc8dd08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>62</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00087" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044444806" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3ea2bbb08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jetco Heavy Duty Lighting v. Fonteyne</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 831, 2018 ABQB 345</cite.query>, at paras. 16-20.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bc8dd18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>63</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00088" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044444806" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3ea2e2c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jetco Heavy Duty Lighting v. Fonteyne</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 831, 2018 ABQB 345</cite.query>, at paras. 27-31.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bc8dd28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>64</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00089" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044444806" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3ea309d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jetco Heavy Duty Lighting v. Fonteyne</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 831, 2018 ABQB 345</cite.query>, at paras. 36-39, 43, 45, and 47.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bc8dd38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>65</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00090" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044444806" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3ea330e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jetco Heavy Duty Lighting v. Fonteyne</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 831, 2018 ABQB 345, at para. 53</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bcb4e08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>66</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00091" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044444806" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3ea357f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jetco Heavy Duty Lighting v. Fonteyne</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 831, 2018 ABQB 345, at para. 58</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bcb4e18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>67</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00092" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044444806" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3ea37f008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jetco Heavy Duty Lighting v. Fonteyne</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 831, 2018 ABQB 345, at para. 59</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bcb4e28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>68</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00093" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044444806" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3ea3a6108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jetco Heavy Duty Lighting v. Fonteyne</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 831, 2018 ABQB 345</cite.query>, at paras. 60-61.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bcb4e38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>69</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00094" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044444806" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3ea3cd208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jetco Heavy Duty Lighting v. Fonteyne</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 831, 2018 ABQB 345, at para. 65</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bcb4e48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>70</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00095" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044444806" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3ea3f4308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jetco Heavy Duty Lighting v. Fonteyne</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 831, 2018 ABQB 345</cite.query>, at paras. 66-67.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bcb4e58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>71</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00096" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044444806" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3ea41b408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jetco Heavy Duty Lighting v. Fonteyne</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 831, 2018 ABQB 345</cite.query>, at paras. 71 and 73.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bcb4e68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>72</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00097" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044444806" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3ea442508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jetco Heavy Duty Lighting v. Fonteyne</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 831, 2018 ABQB 345, at para. 74</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bcdbf08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>73</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00098" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044444806" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3ea469608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jetco Heavy Duty Lighting v. Fonteyne</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 831, 2018 ABQB 345</cite.query>, at paras. 75-77.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bcdbf18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>74</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00099" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044444806" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3ea490708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jetco Heavy Duty Lighting v. Fonteyne</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 831, 2018 ABQB 345, at para.78</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bcdbf28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>75</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00100" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044444806" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3ea4b7808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jetco Heavy Duty Lighting v. Fonteyne</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 831, 2018 ABQB 345, at para. 79</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bcdbf38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>76</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00101" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044444806" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3ea4de908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jetco Heavy Duty Lighting v. Fonteyne</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 831, 2018 ABQB 345</cite.query>, at paras. 81-83.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bcdbf48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>77</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00102" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044444806" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3ea505a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jetco Heavy Duty Lighting v. Fonteyne</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 831, 2018 ABQB 345, at para. 145</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bcdbf58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>78</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00103" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044444806" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3ea52cb08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jetco Heavy Duty Lighting v. Fonteyne</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 831, 2018 ABQB 345, at para. 146</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bcdbf68e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>79</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00104" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044444806" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3ea553c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jetco Heavy Duty Lighting v. Fonteyne</ital>, 2018 CarswellAlta 831, 2018 ABQB 345, at para. 152</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bd03008e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>80</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00105" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044400672" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea57ad08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Nexim v. Yacoob, MIY and Ask4Care</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 6307, 2018 ONSC 2584</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bd03018e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>81</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00106" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044400672" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea5a1e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Nexim v. Yacoob, MIY and Ask4Care</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 6307, 2018 ONSC 2584, at para. 5</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bd03028e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>82</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00107" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044400672" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea5c8f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Nexim v. Yacoob, MIY and Ask4Care</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 6307, 2018 ONSC 2584, at para. 1</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bd03038e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>83</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00108" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044400672" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea5f0008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Nexim v. Yacoob, MIY and Ask4Care</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 6307, 2018 ONSC 2584</cite.query>, at paras. 10, and 13-16.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bd03048e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>84</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00109" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044400672" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea617108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Nexim v. Yacoob, MIY and Ask4Care</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 6307, 2018 ONSC 2584</cite.query>, at paras. 17-18.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bd03058e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>85</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00110" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044400672" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea63e208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Nexim v. Yacoob, MIY and Ask4Care</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 6307, 2018 ONSC 2584</cite.query>, at paras. 22 and 24.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bd03068e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>86</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00111" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042193556" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea665308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Kerzner v. American Iron &amp; Metal Company Inc.</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 11049, 2017 ONSC 4352</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bd03078e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>87</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00112" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042193556" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea68c408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Kerzner v. American Iron &amp; Metal Company Inc.</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 11049, 2017 ONSC 4352</cite.query>, at paras. 1-8.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bd2a108e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>88</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00113" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042193556" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea6da608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Kerzner v. American Iron &amp; Metal Company Inc.</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 11049, 2017 ONSC 4352</cite.query>, at paras. 10, 12, and 38.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bd2a118e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>89</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00114" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042193556" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea701708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Kerzner v. American Iron &amp; Metal Company Inc.</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 11049, 2017 ONSC 4352</cite.query>, at paras. 26-27, and 29.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bd2a128e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>90</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00115" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042193556" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea728808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Kerzner v. American Iron &amp; Metal Company Inc.</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 11049, 2017 ONSC 4352</cite.query>, at paras. 81, and 84-85.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bd2a138e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>91</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00116" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042193556" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea776a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Kerzner v. American Iron &amp; Metal Company Inc.</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 11049, 2017 ONSC 4352</cite.query>, at paras. 86-87.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bd2a148e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>92</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00117" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042193556" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea776a38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Kerzner v. American Iron &amp; Metal Company Inc.</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 11049, 2017 ONSC 4352, at para. 88</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bd51208e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>93</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00118" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042193556" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea7c4c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Kerzner v. American Iron &amp; Metal Company Inc.</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 11049, 2017 ONSC 4352</cite.query>, at paras. 89-90, and 92-93.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bd51218e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>94</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00119" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042193556" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea7ebd08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Kerzner v. American Iron &amp; Metal Company Inc.</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 11049, 2017 ONSC 4352, at para. 101</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bd78308e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>95</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00120" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042193556" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea812e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Kerzner v. American Iron &amp; Metal Company Inc.</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 11049, 2017 ONSC 4352</cite.query>, at paras. 137-138.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bd78318e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>96</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00121" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042193556" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea839f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Kerzner v. American Iron &amp; Metal Company Inc.</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 11049, 2017 ONSC 4352</cite.query>, at paras. 139-141.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bd78328e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>97</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00122" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042093727" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea861008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cosolo v. Geo. A. Kelson Limited</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 10589, 2017 ONSC 4150</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00123" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042381523" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea861038e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellOnt 12659, 2017 ONSC 4928</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bd78338e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>98</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00124" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042093727" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea8af208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cosolo v. Geo. A. Kelson Limited</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 10589, 2017 ONSC 4150</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00125" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042381523" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea8af238e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellOnt 12659, 2017 ONSC 4928</cite.query>, at paras. 1, 21, and 27-28.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bd78348e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>99</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00126" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042093727" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea8d6308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cosolo v. Geo. A. Kelson Limited</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 10589, 2017 ONSC 4150</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00127" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042381523" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea8d6338e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellOnt 12659, 2017 ONSC 4928</cite.query>, at paras. 8-17.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bd78358e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>100</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00128" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042093727" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea924508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cosolo v. Geo. A. Kelson Limited</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 10589, 2017 ONSC 4150</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00129" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042381523" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea924538e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellOnt 12659, 2017 ONSC 4928, at para. 22</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bd78368e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>101</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00130" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042093727" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea94b608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cosolo v. Geo. A. Kelson Limited</ital>, 2017 CarswellOnt 10589, 2017 ONSC 4150</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00131" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2042381523" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea94b638e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2017 CarswellOnt 12659, 2017 ONSC 4928</cite.query>, at paras. 72, 75, and 77.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bd9f408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>102</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00132" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044171037" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea999808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cosolo v. Geo. A. Kelson Company Limited</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 4791, 2018 ONCA 318</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bd9f418e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>103</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00133" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044171037" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea9c0908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cosolo v. Geo. A. Kelson Company Limited</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 4791, 2018 ONCA 318, at para. 6</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bd9f428e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>104</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00134" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2044171037" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3ea9e7a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cosolo v. Geo. A. Kelson Company Limited</ital>, 2018 CarswellOnt 4791, 2018 ONCA 318</cite.query>, at paras. 8-9.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bd9f438e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>105</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00135" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035348352" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I3eaa0eb08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Dillon v. Dillon Hillstead Melanson C.G.A. Prof. Corp.</ital>, 2015 CarswellSask 34, 2015 SKQB 18</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bd9f448e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>106</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00136" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035348352" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I3eaa35c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Dillon v. Dillon Hillstead Melanson C.G.A. Prof. Corp.</ital>, 2015 CarswellSask 34, 2015 SKQB 18</cite.query>, at paras. 1-3.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bd9f458e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>107</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00137" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035348352" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I3eaa83e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Dillon v. Dillon Hillstead Melanson C.G.A. Prof. Corp.</ital>, 2015 CarswellSask 34, 2015 SKQB 18</cite.query>, at paras. 209-210.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bd9f468e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>108</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00138" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035348352" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I3eaaaaf08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Dillon v. Dillon Hillstead Melanson C.G.A. Prof. Corp.</ital>, 2015 CarswellSask 34, 2015 SKQB 18</cite.query>, at paras. 211-216.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bdc6508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>109</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00139" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035348352" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I3eaad2008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Dillon v. Dillon Hillstead Melanson C.G.A. Prof. Corp.</ital>, 2015 CarswellSask 34, 2015 SKQB 18</cite.query>, at paras. 217, 226-230 and 232.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bdc6518e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>110</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00140" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035348352" w-pub-number="0005477" ID="I3eab20208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Dillon v. Dillon Hillstead Melanson C.G.A. Prof. Corp.</ital>, 2015 CarswellSask 34, 2015 SKQB 18</cite.query>, at paras. 233-235.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bdc6528e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>111</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>See <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00141" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1996449587" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I3eabe3718e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Physique Health Club Ltd. v. Carlsen</ital></cite.query> (1996), 45 Alta. L.R. (3d) 383 at p. 386, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00142" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1996449587" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I3eabe3738e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">141 D.L.R. (4th) 64, [1997] 4 W.W.R. 609 (Alta. C.A.)</cite.query>, leave to appeal to S.C.C. refused 145 D.L.R. (4th) vii, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00143" w-ref-type="ER" w-normalized-cite="212ARCA26n" w-pub-number="0004655" ID="I3eabe3768e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">212 A.R. 26<ital>n</ital>, 72</cite.query> C.P.R. (3d) vi and <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00144" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2000673345" w-pub-number="0004655" ID="I3eabe3788e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sulphur Experts Inc. v. O&apos;Connell</ital> (2000), 279 A.R. 246 (Q.B.)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>See also <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00145" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2020991139" w-pub-number="0006457" ID="I3eabe37a8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Easyhome Ltd. v. Casey</ital> (2009), 20 Alta. L.R. (5th) 199, 2009 ABQB 735</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bdc6538e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>112</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00146" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1977148370" w-pub-number="0005150" w-pinpoint-page="120" ID="I3eac58a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Edgar T. Alberts Ltd. v. Mountjoy</ital> (1977), 79 D.L.R. (3d) 108, at p. 120, 16 O.R. (2d) 682 (H.C.J.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00147" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1983169894" w-pub-number="0005161" w-pinpoint-page="424" ID="I3eac58a38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Hawboldt Industries Ltd. v. Chester Basin Hydraulics &amp; Machine Ltd.</ital> (1983), 57 N.S.R. (2d) 413 at p. 424, 22</cite.query> B.L.R. 215 (S.C.).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bdc6548e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>113</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00148" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1981177530" w-pub-number="0005150" ID="I3eae54708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>309925 Ontario Ltd. v. Tyrrell</ital> (1981), 127 D.L.R. (3d) 99 (Ont. H.C.J.), at p. 107</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bdc6558e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>114</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00149" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1981177092" w-pub-number="0005150" w-pinpoint-page="477" ID="I3eae7b808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>W.J. Christie &amp; Co. v. Greer</ital> (1981), 121 D.L.R. (3d) 472 at p. 477, [1981] 4 W.W.R. 34 (Man. C.A.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bded608e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>115</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00150" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027291812" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I3eaea2908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Parrish &amp; Heimbecker Ltd. v. Delmar Commodities Ltd</ital>., 2012 CarswellMan 114, 2012 MBQB 48</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bded618e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>116</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00151" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027291812" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I3eaec9a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Parrish &amp; Heimbecker Ltd. v. Delmar Commodities Ltd</ital>., 2012 CarswellMan 114, 2012 MBQB 48</cite.query>, at paras. 1-2, 6, 14, 18-19, and 33.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bded628e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>117</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00152" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027291812" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I3eaef0b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Parrish &amp; Heimbecker Ltd. v. Delmar Commodities Ltd</ital>., 2012 CarswellMan 114, 2012 MBQB 48, at para. 34</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bded638e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>118</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00153" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027291812" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I3eaf17c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Parrish &amp; Heimbecker Ltd. v. Delmar Commodities Ltd</ital>., 2012 CarswellMan 114, 2012 MBQB 48, at para. 39</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bded648e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>119</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00154" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2027291812" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I3eaf65e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Parrish &amp; Heimbecker Ltd. v. Delmar Commodities Ltd</ital>., 2012 CarswellMan 114, 2012 MBQB 48</cite.query>, at paras. 44, 50 and 56.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bded658e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>120</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00155" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1986268597" w-pub-number="0003986" ID="I3eaf8cf08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Hudson&apos;s Bay Co. v. McClocklin</ital>, [1986] 5 W.W.R. 29, 42 Man. R. (2d) 283 (Q.B.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4bded668e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>121</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>See also, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00156" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1986187661" w-pub-number="0005653" ID="I3eafb4008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Gemologists International Inc. v. Gem Scan International Inc.</ital> (1986), 9 C.P.R. (3d) 255 (Ont. H.C.J.)</cite.query> and <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00157" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2001360648" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I3eafb4028e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Golden Images Management Ltd. v. Champers Enterprises Ltd.</ital> (2001), 105 A.C.W.S. (3d) 1059, [2001] B.C.J. No. 1308 (S.C.)</cite.query>, which demonstrate that each situation will be considered fact specific. <eos/><bos/>See also <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00158" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2006204149" w-pub-number="0007214" ID="I3eafb4058e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Axiom Services Ltd. v. Weigert</ital> (2005), 2 B.L.R. (4th) 185 (B.C.S.C.)</cite.query>, judgment on costs <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00159" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2006541852" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I3eafb4078e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">139 A.C.W.S. (3d) 235</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4be14708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>122</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>Moore International (Canada) Ltd. v. Carter</ital> (1982), 40 B.C.L.R. 322 (S.C.), at p. 344.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4be14718e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>123</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>See <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00160" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="1996449587" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I3eb1afd18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Physique Health Club Ltd. v. Carlsen</ital></cite.query> (1996), 45 Alta. L.R. (3d) 383 at p. 386, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00161" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1996449587" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I3eb1afd38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">141 D.L.R. (4th) 64, [1997] 4 W.W.R. 609 (Alta. C.A.)</cite.query>, leave to appeal to S.C.C. refused 145 D.L.R. (4th) vii, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00162" w-ref-type="ER" w-normalized-cite="212ARCA26n" w-pub-number="0004655" ID="I3eb1afd68e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">212 A.R. 26<ital>n</ital>, 72</cite.query> C.P.R. (3d) vi; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00163" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2000673345" w-pub-number="0004655" ID="I3eb1afd88e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Sulphur Experts Inc. v. O&apos;Connell</ital> (2000), 279 A.R. 246 (Q.B.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00164" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1989312830" w-pub-number="0005161" ID="I3eb1afda8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Metropolitan Commercial Carpet Centre Ltd. v. Donovan</ital> (1989), 91 N.S.R. (2d) 99, 42</cite.query> B.L.R. 306 (S.C.).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4be14728e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>124</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00165" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035342984" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3eb1fdf08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Canadian Hedge Watch Inc. v. Street</ital>, 2015 CarswellOnt 881, 2015 ONSC 454</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4be14738e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>125</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00166" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035342984" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3eb225008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Canadian Hedge Watch Inc. v. Street</ital>, 2015 CarswellOnt 881, 2015 ONSC 454</cite.query>, at paras. 1-2.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4be14748e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>126</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00167" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035342984" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3eb273208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Canadian Hedge Watch Inc. v. Street</ital>, 2015 CarswellOnt 881, 2015 ONSC 454</cite.query>, at paras. 8-9, and 29.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4be14758e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>127</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00168" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035342984" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3eb29a308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Canadian Hedge Watch Inc. v. Street</ital>, 2015 CarswellOnt 881, 2015 ONSC 454</cite.query>, at paras. 30-31.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4be3b808e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>128</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00169" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2035342984" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I3eb2c1408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Canadian Hedge Watch Inc. v. Street</ital>, 2015 CarswellOnt 881, 2015 ONSC 454</cite.query>, at paras. 32-34.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4be3b818e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>129</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00170" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036173265" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3eb2e8508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Innersolutions Ltd. v. Hooper</ital>, 2015 CarswellAlta 722, 2015 ABQB 258</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4be3b828e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>130</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00171" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036173265" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3eb30f608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Innersolutions Ltd. v. Hooper</ital>, 2015 CarswellAlta 722, 2015 ABQB 258, at para. 1</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4be3b838e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>131</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00172" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036173265" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3eb336708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Innersolutions Ltd. v. Hooper</ital>, 2015 CarswellAlta 722, 2015 ABQB 258</cite.query>, at paras. 4-6, 10-13, and 16-18.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4be3b848e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>132</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00173" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036173265" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3eb35d808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Innersolutions Ltd. v. Hooper</ital>, 2015 CarswellAlta 722, 2015 ABQB 258, at para. 68</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4be3b858e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>133</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00174" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036173265" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3eb384908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Innersolutions Ltd. v. Hooper</ital>, 2015 CarswellAlta 722, 2015 ABQB 258, at para. 63</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4be62908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>134</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00175" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036173265" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3eb3aba08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Innersolutions Ltd. v. Hooper</ital>, 2015 CarswellAlta 722, 2015 ABQB 258, at para. 64</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4be62918e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>135</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00176" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036173265" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3eb3d2b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Innersolutions Ltd. v. Hooper</ital>, 2015 CarswellAlta 722, 2015 ABQB 258, at para. 66</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4be62928e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>136</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00177" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2006548687" w-pub-number="0007214" ID="I3eb3f9c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>IT/Net Inc. v. Doucette</ital> (2005), 5 B.L.R. (4th) 71 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at paras. 12-13, <case.history>affd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00178" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2011314537" w-pub-number="0007214" ID="I3eb3f9c28e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">25 B.L.R. (4th) 49 (Ont. C.A.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4be62938e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>137</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>See <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00179" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1973144068" w-pub-number="0005150" ID="I3eb447e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Canadian Aero Service Ltd. v. O&apos;Malley</ital> (1973), 40 D.L.R. (3d) 371, [1974] 1 S.C.R. 592</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00180" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2021409421" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I3eb447e38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Loreto v. Little</ital> (2010), 185 A.C.W.S. (3d) 230, [2010] O.J. No. 679</cite.query>; and <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00181" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2022068867" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I3eb447e68e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Aquafor Beech Ltd. v. Whyte</ital> (2010), 188 A.C.W.S. (3d) 509, 2010 ONSC 2733 (Comm. List)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4be62948e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>138</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>DiFlorio v. Con Structural Steel Ltd.</ital> (2000), 6 B.L.R. (3d) 253 (Ont. S.C.J.), affd 21 B.L.R. (3d) 22 <ital>sub nom.</ital><ital>DiFlorio v. Con Steel Ltd.</ital> (C.A.), leave to appeal to S.C.C. refused [2002] 3 S.C.R. vi <ital>sub nom.</ital><ital>Con Steel <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00182" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2022068867" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I3eb5ce818e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Ltd. v. Rocca Steel Ltd.</cite.query></ital></paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4be89a08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>139</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00183" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2006548687" w-pub-number="0007214" ID="I3eb61ca08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>IT/Net Inc. v. Doucette</ital> (2005), 5 B.L.R. (4th) 71 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query>, at para. 4, <case.history>affd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00184" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2011314537" w-pub-number="0007214" ID="I3eb61ca28e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">25 B.L.R. (4th) 49 (Ont. C.A.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4be89a18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>140</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00185" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1983171055" w-pub-number="0005150" w-pinpoint-page="163" ID="I3eb643b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>White Oaks Welding Supplies v. Tapp</ital> (1983), 149 D.L.R. (3d) 159 at p. 163, 42 O.R. (2d) 445 (H.C.J.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4be89a28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>141</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00186" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1973144068" w-pub-number="0005150" ID="I3eb66ac08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Canadian Aero Service Limited v. O&apos;Malley</ital>,, (1973), 40 D.L.R. (3d) 371, [1974] 1 S.C.R. 592 at pp. 606-607</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4be89a38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>142</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>(2001), <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00187" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2001464023" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I3eb6b8e08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">108 A.C.W.S. (3d) 363 (Ont. S.C.J.)</cite.query> at para. 8.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4be89a48e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>143</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00188" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2006204149" w-pub-number="0007214" ID="I3eb6dff08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Axiom Services Ltd. v. Weigert</ital> (2005), 2 B.L.R. (4th) 185 (B.C.S.C.)</cite.query>, at para. 34, judgment on costs <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00189" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2006541852" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I3eb6dff28e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">139 A.C.W.S. (3d) 235 (B.C.S.C.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id4be89a58e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>144</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>For example, see <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00190" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1999482256" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I3eb8b4b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Barton Insurance Brokers Ltd. v. Irwin</ital> (1999), 170 D.L.R. (4th) 69 (B.C.C.A.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00191" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2011192292" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I3eb8b4b28e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>RBC Dominion Securities Inc. v. Merrill Lynch Canada Inc.</ital> (2007), 275 D.L.R. (4th) 385 (B.C.C.A.)</cite.query>, <case.history>appeal allowed in part</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00192" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2017227608" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I3eb8b4b48e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">298 D.L.R. (4th) 1 (S.C.C.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00193" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1999494906" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I3eb8b4b68e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Ebco Industries Ltd. v. Kaltech Manufacturing Ltd.</ital> (1999), 91 A.C.W.S. (3d) 1025 (B.C.S.C.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00194" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2011192292" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I3eb8b4b98e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>RBC Dominion Securities Inc. v. Merrill Lynch Canada Inc.</ital></cite.query> (2000), 7 C.C.E.L. (3d) 257 (B.C.S.C.); <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00195" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2000671032" w-pub-number="0006564" ID="I3eb8b4ba8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Merrill Lynch Canada Inc. v. Pastro</ital> (2000), 96 A.C.W.S. (3d) 474 (B.C.C.A.)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00196" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2001351620" w-pub-number="0005158" ID="I3eb8b4bc8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>G.M.G. Fish Services Ltd. v. McGrattan</ital> (2001), 240 N.B.R. (2d) 146 (C.A.)</cite.query>; <ital>R.T. Investment Counsel Inc. v. Werry</ital> (1999), 46 B.L.R. (2d) 66 (B.C.S.C.); <ital>Matrix Photocatalytic Inc. v. Purifics Environmental Technologies Inc.</ital> (2000), 10 B.L.R. (3d) 296 (Ont. S.C.J.); <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00197" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1998460163" w-pub-number="0003986" ID="I3eb8b4be8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Polar Bear Rubber Ltd. v. Brothers Industrial Supply Ltd.</ital>, [1999] 1 W.W.R. 522 (Man. Q.B.)</cite.query>, <case.history>affd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00198" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1998468800" w-pub-number="0003986" ID="I3eb8b4c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">[1999] 7 W.W.R. 633 (Man. C.A.)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>See also <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00199" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2006204149" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I3eb8b4c28e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Axiom Services Ltd. v. Weigert</ital>, 2005 CarswellBC 357, 2005 BCSC 145</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00200" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2006541852" w-pub-number="0005472" ID="I3eb8b4c58e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2005 CarswellBC 1076, 2005 BCSC 665</cite.query>; and <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00201" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2020159714" w-pub-number="0003986" ID="I3eb8b4c88e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Soost v. Merrill Lynch Canada Inc.</ital>, [2010] 3 W.W.R. 94, 2009 ABQB 591</cite.query>, <case.history>revd</case.history> <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00202" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2022888984" w-pub-number="0006455" ID="I3eb8b4cb8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2010 ABCA 251</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00203" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2023883812" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3eb8b4cd8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2010 CarswellAlta 2286</cite.query>, leave to appeal refused <cite.query w-src-number="0492175883" w-seq-number="00204" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2025089168" w-pub-number="0005471" ID="I3eb8b4cf8e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2011 CarswellAlta 582</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 4:29<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
