<n-docbody>
	<doc bill="N">
		<content.metadata.block>
			<cmd.identifiers>
				<cmd.cites>
					<cmd.second.line.cite>Law of Confidential Business Information Preliminary Materials</cmd.second.line.cite>
				</cmd.cites>
			</cmd.identifiers>
		</content.metadata.block>
		<prop.block>
			<prop.head toc-guid="">
				<headtext>Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext>
			</prop.head>
			<prop.head toc-guid="I4a23c350a11e11eaadf4bd150ee02bff">
				<headtext />
			</prop.head>
			<content.metadata.block>
				<cmd.dates>
					<cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501" />
				</cmd.dates>
			</content.metadata.block>
			<author.line>
				<author>Keith G. Fairbairn</author>
			</author.line>
			<author.line>
				<author>Julie A. Thorburn</author>
			</author.line>
		</prop.block>
		<message.block>
			<include.copyright n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA" n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" />
		</message.block>
		<grade.notes ID="I9b303ea09c6d11ea960ec8a096213537">
			<doc.title toc-guid="I4a23c350a11e11eaadf4bd150ee02bff">
				<head parent="doc.title">
					<headtext>Preliminary Materials</headtext>
				</head>
			</doc.title>
			<intro.block>
				<head style="l" parent="intro.block">
					<headtext>Foreword</headtext>
				</head>
				<para>
					<paratext>The legal methods of protecting business information ( <ital>i.e.</ital>  , patents, trade-marks, industrial design and copyright) have received extensive academic coverage. This is not true of confidential information and trade secrets. Case law, most notably <ital>LAC Minerals Ltd. v. International Corona Resources Ltd.</ital>  , highlights this gap and emphasizes the increasing importance and utility of this subject to businesses that rely on information and technology. </paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>
						<ital>Law of Confidential Business Information</ital>  provides a clear and concise review of this area of the law. The authors provide a comprehensive summary and analysis of the law relating to confidential business information, trade secrets and know-how. The book includes a review of the historical development of the law, an analysis of the policies behind the protection of confidential business information in a global marketplace, and an outline of the causes of action which may be brought, the defences which may be raised, and the remedies which may be granted. </paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>The chapters dealing with history and policy analysis have an academic focus, while the chapters covering causes of action, defences and remedies will be of particular interest to practising lawyers. The book also deals with employment law and the intellectual property aspects of confidential information.</paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>As a former member of the High Court of Justice, I was particularly pleased to be asked to write a foreword for this excellent book, as Julie Thorburn, a co-author, is fondly remembered as one of our outstanding law clerks. The authors of <ital>Law of Confidential Business Information</ital>  have succeeded in untangling a complex and developing area of the law. The book is an indispensable tool for lawyers dealing with intellectual property and employment issues, as well as for businesses seeking to protect their confidential business information. I endorse the book wholeheartedly. </paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>Mr. Justice Jean Marc Labrosse</paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>Court of Appeal</paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>December 1997</paratext>
				</para>
				<head style="l" parent="intro.block">
					<headtext>Preface</headtext>
				</head>
				<para>
					<paratext>The basic economic resource of the modern economy is no longer capital, nor is it natural resources or labour it is knowledge. The consequence of this is that:</paratext>
					<display.quote>
						<para>
							<paratext>
								<?begin.quote ID="QT_0001"?>  Because it reduces a need for raw materials, labour, time and capital, knowledge becomes a central resource of the advanced economy. And as this happens, its value soars. <?end.quote refid="QT_0001"?>  [ <footnote.reference refid="I1f84dac0a11f11eaa600e10a9eb50a3c">1</footnote.reference>  ] </paratext>
						</para>
					</display.quote>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>Not all knowledge will be protected by the courts. To merit protection, knowledge must be in some way unique, identifiable, novel and relatively secret. Furthermore, normally only certain relationships will create a requirement to keep information confidential and not use it to the detriment of the person imparting it. Finally, unauthorized use of protected information may trigger the enforcement of rights of various kinds: contractual, fiduciary, property and others.</paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>The law of confidential information is rapidly changing, a pattern which is consistent with the rapid increase in the importance of information as a commodity. In this book, our goal is to provide the reader with an understanding of what confidential information is, the rights and obligations of those in possession of it, and the history and policy implications of protecting it. Keith Fairbairn has provided a comprehensive definition of confidential information, dealt with the treatment of confidential information in the employment context, and given practical guidelines for protecting confidential information. In addition, he has provided an appendix containing sample documents for use in creating contract clauses to protect confidential information and for use in court actions for breach of confidential information. Julie Thorburn has dealt with the history of confidential information and with policy and intellectual property considerations. In addition, she has addressed the subjects of causes of action, defences and remedies.</paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>We hope that the reader will find this a useful guide to navigate the murky and ever-changing laws related to confidential business information.</paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>We would like to acknowledge with gratitude the considerable assistance, suggestions and good humour of Fran Cudlipp and Sharon Currens of Canada Law Book. We would also like to thank the partners of Cassels Brock &amp; Blackwell for their confidence and support in our efforts, and Canada Trust for lending its support to this endeavour. Thanks also to David Wei for his insight and research. We owe special thanks to Gina McCabe for her diligence and painstaking efforts in the preparation of the manuscript, and to Kathy Wallcraft and Connie Lobello for their ongoing assistance.</paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>We are particularly grateful to the Honourable Mr. Justice J.M. Labrosse for taking the time out of his very busy schedule to assist us and for his support.</paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>Most of all, we would like to thank our families. Without them, none of this would have been possible.</paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>Keith G. Fairbairn</paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>Julie A. Thorburn</paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>December 1997</paratext>
				</para>
			</intro.block>
		</grade.notes>
		<footnote.block>
			<footnote ID="I1f84dac0a11f11eaa600e10a9eb50a3c">
				<label.designator>1</label.designator>
				<footnote.body>
					<para>
						<paratext>A. Toffler, <ital>Powershift</ital>  (New York: Bantam, 1990). </paratext>
					</para>
				</footnote.body>
			</footnote>
		</footnote.block>
		<content.metadata.block>
			<cmd.royalty>
				<cmd.copyright>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document "as is". Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.</cmd.copyright>
			</cmd.royalty>
			<cmd.identifiers>
				<cmd.cites>
					<cmd.first.line.cite>THORBURNBI-WL PREMAT</cmd.first.line.cite>
				</cmd.cites>
			</cmd.identifiers>
		</content.metadata.block>
	</doc>
</n-docbody> 