<n-docbody>
	<doc bill="N">
		<content.metadata.block>
			<cmd.identifiers>
				<cmd.cites>
					<cmd.second.line.cite>Profiting from Risk Management and Compliance Preliminary Materials</cmd.second.line.cite>
				</cmd.cites>
			</cmd.identifiers>
		</content.metadata.block>
		<prop.block>
			<prop.head toc-guid="">
				<headtext>Profiting from Risk Management and Compliance</headtext>
			</prop.head>
			<prop.head toc-guid="Id90f2281a11e11eaa14a96ef8b1b3a38">
				<headtext />
			</prop.head>
			<content.metadata.block>
				<cmd.dates>
					<cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501" />
				</cmd.dates>
			</content.metadata.block>
			<author.line>
				<author>Todd L. Archibald</author>
			</author.line>
			<author.line>
				<author>Kenneth E. Jull</author>
			</author.line>
		</prop.block>
		<message.block>
			<include.copyright n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA" n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" />
		</message.block>
		<grade.notes ID="I724399f09c6e11eaa5b1c99e8f4ac64f">
			<doc.title toc-guid="Id90f2281a11e11eaa14a96ef8b1b3a38">
				<head parent="doc.title">
					<headtext>Preliminary Materials</headtext>
				</head>
			</doc.title>
			<intro.block>
				<head style="c" parent="intro.block">
					<headtext>Preface</headtext>
				</head>
				<para>
					<paratext>We are very pleased to announce the launch of <bold>
							<ital>Profiting from Risk Management and Compliance</ital>
						</bold>, completely replacing the former <ital>Regulatory and Corporate Liability: From Due Diligence to Risk Management</ital>  by Todd Archibald, Kenneth Jull and Kent Roach, with a Forward by the Honourable Dennis O&#8217;Connor. </paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>Over the last 14 years since <bold>
							<ital>Regulatory and Corporate Liability: From Due Diligence to Risk Management</ital>
						</bold>was published, the accumulated cases and other materials reached the point where it became necessary to reorganize and refocus the Work into a framework that more cohesively and systematically examines the legal issues surrounding risk management and compliance. </paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>
						<bold>
							<ital>Profiting from Risk Management and Compliance</ital>
						</bold>includes analysis of the new regime for deferred prosecution agreements which became the vortex of the SNC-Lavalin affair, captivating Canadian media for much of 2019. </paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>There are new chapters on the following topics:</paratext>
				</para>
				<list>
					<list.item>
						<para>
							<head parent="para">
								<label.designator>&#8226;</label.designator>
							</head>
							<paratext>COMPLIANCE: BEHAVIORAL THEORY, GENDER AND DIVERSITY</paratext>
						</para>
					</list.item>
					<list.item>
						<para>
							<head parent="para">
								<label.designator>&#8226;</label.designator>
							</head>
							<paratext>GOVERNANCE AND THE BEST INTERESTS OF THE CORPORATION IN A GLOBAL CONTEXT</paratext>
						</para>
					</list.item>
					<list.item>
						<para>
							<head parent="para">
								<label.designator>&#8226;</label.designator>
							</head>
							<paratext>COMPETITION ACT OFFENCES, VIOLATIONS AND EFFICIENCY</paratext>
						</para>
					</list.item>
					<list.item>
						<para>
							<head parent="para">
								<label.designator>&#8226;</label.designator>
							</head>
							<paratext>INSIDER TRADING AND SECURITIES OFFENCES</paratext>
						</para>
					</list.item>
					<list.item>
						<para>
							<head parent="para">
								<label.designator>&#8226;</label.designator>
							</head>
							<paratext>ENVIRONMENTAL OFFENCES</paratext>
						</para>
					</list.item>
					<list.item>
						<para>
							<head parent="para">
								<label.designator>&#8226;</label.designator>
							</head>
							<paratext>OCCUPATIONAL HEALTH AND SAFETY</paratext>
						</para>
					</list.item>
					<list.item>
						<para>
							<head parent="para">
								<label.designator>&#8226;</label.designator>
							</head>
							<paratext>COMPLIANCE SYSTEMS AND OPERATIONAL CHANGE</paratext>
						</para>
					</list.item>
					<list.item>
						<para>
							<head parent="para">
								<label.designator>&#8226;</label.designator>
							</head>
							<paratext>INTERNAL INVESTIGATIONS</paratext>
						</para>
					</list.item>
					<list.item>
						<para>
							<head parent="para">
								<label.designator>&#8226;</label.designator>
							</head>
							<paratext>DEFERRED PROSECUTION AGREEMENTS, IMMUNITY AND LENIENCY: PERMISSIBLE AND PROHIBITED ROUTES</paratext>
						</para>
					</list.item>
				</list>
				<head style="l" parent="intro.block">
					<headtext>
						<ital>Profiting from Risk Management: A Positive Matrix</ital>
					</headtext>
				</head>
				<para>
					<paratext>There is hard data that the more financially successful companies value leadership, fairness and the interests of their constituencies more highly than the lower-yielding firms. <ital>In other words, higher risk control and better governance leads to higher rewards financially</ital>  . </paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>A core concept of this book is that governance and risk management priorities must be related to a theory of justice. We use the framework developed by John Rawls in his famous &#8220;veil of ignorance&#8221; concept whereby a justice system of rules can only be conceived of by people from behind a conceptual veil of ignorance where they do not know their own wealth, position, gender, race or attributes. The Rawls framework results in four basic rules, discussed below, which will lead to both justice as fairness within organizations and profitable rewards.</paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>A positive matrix based on justice and profit can be used as an effective mechanism of changing behaviour by providing rewards and incentives which will lead to corporate and organizational growth and prosperity.</paratext>
				</para>
				<head style="l" parent="intro.block">
					<headtext>
						<ital>A Wide Spectrum of Subject Areas</ital>
					</headtext>
				</head>
				<para>
					<paratext>The methodology of risk management articulated in this book can be applied to a wide spectrum of diverse subject areas ranging from serious criminal offences such as bribery and price fixing to regulatory standards in areas such as the environment, occupational health and safety and advertising law.</paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>The allegations against Hollywood mogul Harvey Weinstein and the #MeToo movement details harm within a working environment that ranges from the criminal offence of sexual assault to sexual harassment in the workplace and society.</paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>The harm caused to a person who has lost life savings to a fraudulent scheme can be devastating and have severe health effects. Price fixing or bid rigging may not cause as dramatic personal harm but nevertheless causes widespread losses to consumer welfare and incomes. Corporate white collar crime may cause significant harm because of the national or international reach of many modern corporations.</paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>For the person who has lost a loved one in an occupational health accident that violated regulatory standards, it is of little comfort that the offence is called regulatory instead of criminal. Violations such as deceptive marketing cause harm to both consumers and the efficiency of the market which is based on the exchange of accurate information. The #MeToo movement has publicly revealed harms within the workplace and associated environments that were previously often unspoken and hidden.</paratext>
				</para>
				<head style="l" parent="intro.block">
					<headtext>
						<ital>Hollywood and White Collar Crime</ital>
					</headtext>
				</head>
				<para>
					<paratext>A different but equally challenging public perception is that white collar crimes are glamorous because of the lavish lifestyles that they fund. Movies such as <ital>The Wolf of Wall Street</ital>  (which did an exceptional job of telling the true story of the rise and fall of a white collar criminal, Jordan Belfort) sell more tickets because of the glamour associated with yachts, large houses, exotic cars and seemingly endless parties. The victims of these schemes may be forgotten or overshadowed by the images of success. </paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>The ultimate irony is the allegation that the <ital>Wolf of Wall Street</ital>  was funded by the proceeds of a massive fraud perpetrated against the Malaysian government. The allegations are that a Malaysian named Jho Low defrauded the Malaysian government of $700 million in an elaborate scheme of shell companies and promises of investment opportunities in the Middle East. Jho Low allegedly conspired with former Prime Minister Najib, who is on trial over his alleged involvement in the looting of sovereign wealth fund 1MDB, a state investment vehicle. Jho Low became known for partying with Britney Spears and Paris Hilton, who are also alleged to have received enormous amounts of 1MDB money. Low, who allegedly used 1MDB cash to bankroll the 2013 Leonardo DiCaprio film <ital>The Wolf of Wall Street</ital>  , is a fugitive, believed by some to be in hiding in China. </paratext>
				</para>
				<head style="l" parent="intro.block">
					<headtext>
						<ital>Corporate and individual liability</ital>
					</headtext>
				</head>
				<para>
					<paratext>Corporations may be liable for the criminal acts of employees, agents and contractors, which is a separate topic in itself and the subject of a chapter in this book.</paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>In the context of the highly publicized case of SNC-Lavalin, corporate liability requires an analysis of the level of responsibility of those persons alleged to have committed acts of bribery and how widespread the allegations of wrongdoing are. A sound understanding of corporate criminal responsibility, as set out in s. 22.2 of the <ital>Criminal Code</ital>  , is essential to undertake this analysis. </paratext>
				</para>
				<head style="l" parent="intro.block">
					<headtext>
						<ital>A template approach</ital>
					</headtext>
				</head>
				<para>
					<paratext>The multi-disciplinary risk management systems articulated in this book offer a template approach that applies to the wide spectrum of diverse subject areas. While the risks will be different and the levels of harm will vary, the essential components of the risk management approach remain constant and allow organizations to benefit from the efficiencies of enterprise risk management. We use techniques such as flowcharts, checklists and codes of conduct to assist organizations to develop systems to profit from risk management and compliance.</paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>In this book, we develop a matrix approach as a core concept of risk management applied to regulatory and corporate criminal liability. The matrix measures the prevention of harm on one axis, in relation to the probability of that harm occurring on the other axis. Matrix analysis can be viewed on multi-disciplinary levels including a macro level, micro level, and operational level.</paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>Matrix analysis has been accepted by the courts and endorsed by regulatory authorities. Case studies bring to life the concepts underlying the matrix. A person or entity may feel overwhelmed and defeated when faced with an event which violates regulatory standards across the spectrum of harm. In the face of that event, the defence of due diligence may seem logically impossible or out of reach. The risk matrix applies mathematical principles to demonstrate that risk management and due diligence may be available as a defence after an adverse event, if the proper risk priorities were followed over the appropriate course of time to address that type or category of problem.</paratext>
				</para>
				<head style="l" parent="intro.block">
					<headtext>
						<ital>Behavioural perspectives</ital>
					</headtext>
				</head>
				<para>
					<paratext>Rational cost-benefit calculation in relation to crimes and offences dates back to the model proposed by Jeremy Bentham. The problem with the rational cost-benefit model is that it does not take into account the behavioural school of thought. The explanation for non-compliance with law is complex. We attempt to integrate new work that explores the role of biology and chemistry in decision making, which can be linked to psychological and cultural explanations for behaviour. This work can then be linked to the design of corporate compliance programmes. In short, it is essential to understand the complex reasons for non-compliance in order to draft a blueprint for change.</paratext>
				</para>
				<head style="l" parent="intro.block">
					<headtext>
						<ital>Gender, diversity, risk management and compliance</ital>
					</headtext>
				</head>
				<para>
					<paratext>Gender issues apply at every level of analysis of risk management and compliance. Curiously, the issue of gender and feminist analysis has not been in the forefront of most writing about risk management, compliance, or white collar crime. We attempt to start a dialogue about how these areas of research can be better integrated.</paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>The &#8220;reasonable man&#8221; is used as a standard in various fields of law ranging from negligence to criminal law. It is overly simplistic to change nomenclature by substituting the words &#8220;reasonable person&#8221;. Research suggests that reasonable women have been left out of the equation in the development of the standard.</paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>Women are conspicuously absent from the ranks of prominent white collar criminals. There are many competing explanations for this trend. For example, cultural feminists argue that female values such as caring and connection to the community will play a larger role as gender equality permeates the boardroom. Extending this theory into regulatory law would suggest that as boards of directors become more populated with women, there will be a greater care taken by corporations with respect to their workforce and the community.</paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>By contrast, dominance theorists focus on righting the power imbalance. This theory would argue that female directors will make corporate governance decisions in the same way men do. A socialization theory refutes suggestions that innate characteristics or traits preclude women from behaviour that leads to white-collar criminality.</paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>In a similar manner, there needs to be more discussion of the link between racial diversity and compliance. Racial diversity in the boardroom may counteract against the tendency for groupthink. This leads to a discussion of the importance of a theory of justice as part of profiting from risk management and compliance.</paratext>
				</para>
				<head style="l" parent="intro.block">
					<headtext>
						<ital>Risk Priorities and a Theory of Justice</ital>
					</headtext>
				</head>
				<para>
					<paratext>Rawls constructed his theory of &#8220;justice as fairness&#8221; by utilizing an imaginary society that would be created by an original agreement where no one knows his or her place in society, his or her class position or social status, nor does anyone know their fortune in the distribution of natural assets and abilities, their intelligence, strength, and the like. Included in the list of unknowns is gender and race.</paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>We inject a human needs model into the Rawls framework which results in four basic rules, as follows:</paratext>
				</para>
				<list>
					<list.item>
						<para>
							<head parent="para">
								<label.designator>1.</label.designator>
							</head>
							<paratext>Regulatory measures must promote human health and safety as a first priority;</paratext>
						</para>
					</list.item>
				</list>
				<list>
					<list.item>
						<para>
							<head parent="para">
								<label.designator>2.</label.designator>
							</head>
							<paratext>Regulations should promote the growth of community to the greatest extent possible by making basic services accessible to all;</paratext>
						</para>
					</list.item>
				</list>
				<list>
					<list.item>
						<para>
							<head parent="para">
								<label.designator>3.</label.designator>
							</head>
							<paratext>Social and economic inequalities are to be arranged so that they are to the greatest benefit of the least advantaged;</paratext>
						</para>
					</list.item>
				</list>
				<list>
					<list.item>
						<para>
							<head parent="para">
								<label.designator>4.</label.designator>
							</head>
							<paratext>Long term gains should be balanced against short term costs with respect to community based groups.</paratext>
						</para>
					</list.item>
				</list>
				<head style="l" parent="intro.block">
					<headtext>
						<ital>Internal investigations and Coming in From the Cold</ital>
					</headtext>
				</head>
				<para>
					<paratext>A separate chapter sets out protocols for internal investigations. We devote a chapter to the topic of immunity and deferred prosecution agreements. The &#8220;SNC-Lavalin affair&#8221; has made the terms <?begin.quote ID="QT_0001"?>  &#8220;deferred prosecution agreements (DPAs) and &#8221;remediation agreements&#8220; household names. <?end.quote refid="QT_0001"?>
					</paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>The legislation for remediation agreements contains six purposes or objectives and nine factors to be weighed. We apply matrix analysis to organize this balancing.</paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>In our view, a driving force is whether an organization &#8220;comes in from the cold&#8221; to voluntarily self-report from the zone of non-discovery by government regulators. While this factor does not &#8220;trump&#8221; the other factors, it will impact them. Two extremes prove the point. Early self-disclosure, as soon as an organization determines that something is amiss, will minimize any future impact of the illegal act as well as eliminating the potential for a repetition of the conduct. This then impacts the other factors such as reparations for harm done and the gravity of the act and its impact on victims. Conversely, late disclosure of details after the authorities have already discovered the illegal act will not have prevented harm to victims as early as was possible and may have permitted those responsible to repeat the illegal acts.</paratext>
				</para>
				<head style="l" parent="intro.block">
					<headtext>
						<ital>Academic and Practical Applications</ital>
					</headtext>
				</head>
				<para>
					<paratext>This book is used as a textbook for the course &#8220;Financial Crimes and Corporate Compliance&#8221; at the University of Toronto Faculty of Law, taught every Fall term.</paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>The framework for this book has its origins in a graduate course on &#8220;Crimes and Regulatory Offences&#8221; in the part-time Masters programme in Criminal Law at Osgoode Hall Law School. This course is now titled <?begin.quote ID="QT_0002"?>  &#8220;Corporate and Financial Crimes and Compliance&#8221; <?end.quote refid="QT_0002"?>  , and also uses this book as a text. We continue to benefit from the ideas of the students in these courses. </paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>We are also gratified that business schools are using our text, such as the Ted Rogers School of Management at Ryerson University in Toronto, which has a cutting edge course taught by Professor Gil Lan.</paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>The book attempts to reach beyond academic venues to a wider audience including industry and government regulators. We hope that the various charts and diagrams are user friendly and assist in the practical implementation of <?begin.quote ID="QT_0003"?>  &#8220;Profiting from Risk Management and Compliance&#8221; <?end.quote refid="QT_0003"?>  . </paratext>
				</para>
				<head style="l" parent="intro.block">
					<headtext>
						<ital>Acknowledgements</ital>
					</headtext>
				</head>
				<para>
					<paratext>Wewould like to acknowledge Professor Kent Roach for his co-authorship of the former <ital>Regulatory and Corporate Liability: From Due Diligence to Risk Management</ital>  , which is the foundation for this new work on <ital>Profiting from Risk Management and Compliance</ital>  . </paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>Thomson Reuters has supported this endeavor in many ways. Renee LeBlanc has been our tireless editor for many years, and has endured the rebirth of this new book. Peter Clark has diligently worked on the voluminous sentencing and due diligence tables. Pamela Corrigan has guided the marketing of this new book.</paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>We would also like to acknowledge the support of Gardiner Roberts LLP, where Kenneth Jull is Counsel. Kellie Engelhardt provided invaluable formatting assistance.</paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>Over the years we have benefited tremendous assistance from research assistants and clerks at the Superior Court of Justice who generously volunteered their time and research expertise.</paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>And we would like to recognize the Competition Bureau which facilitated an interchange for a two year period with Kenneth Jull in the position of General Counsel with the Competition Bureau Legal Services. That interchange provided many of the insights in the new Competition chapter.</paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>Of course, the views of the authors do not reflect the views of the Competition Bureau, Department of Justice, Gardiner Roberts LLP or the Superior Court of Justice.</paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>Finally, we acknowledge our families, who endured not only the writing of <ital>Profiting from Risk Management and Compliance</ital>  , but continue to endure the writing of the updates. </paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>Todd Archibald</paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>Kenneth Jull</paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>Toronto, Ontario</paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>2019</paratext>
				</para>
				<head style="c" parent="intro.block">
					<headtext>Foreword to the First Edition</headtext>
				</head>
				<para>
					<paratext>One of the key lessons of Walkerton is the importance of risk management and risk assessment in our society. This book is an important contribution to the legal assessment, application, and understanding of these important concepts in the context of regulatory and corporate liability.</paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>In analyzing the principles underlying both regulatory offences and defences such as due diligence, the authors provide a sound analytical framework for the development of the law in this increasingly important area. Readers will benefit from the discussion of the precautionary principle, situated in the risk management context. As organizations expand their global reach, and government regulation adapts to modern economic realities, this book will be of great assistance to lawyers, regulators, academics and courts.</paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>The discussions of evolving theories of corporate liability, the roles of directors, officers and employees, ethical issues and performance management are a valuable contribution to understanding the theory and practice of corporate liability. In addition to providing a sound basis for analyzing corporate liability, the authors also investigate other aspects of regulatory compliance. For example, the authors provide a perceptive analysis of the tension between individual and corporate due diligence, a tension which increasingly courts are required to address in cases involving regulatory law.</paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>The <ital>Canadian Charter of Rights and Freedoms</ital>  is central to any contemporary Canadian analysis of regulatory liability and defences, and the authors thoroughly review the application and interpretation of Charter principles in the context of risk management and regulatory liability. </paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>Sentencing is also an area of critical importance in regulatory law and it is a subject which receives particular attention in this book. The authors are to be commended for the thorough, principled and thoughtful manner in which they address this area. They situate specific issues such as piercing the corporate veil, corporate sentencing, the role of deterrence and the concept of restorative justice, in the context of the development of emerging principles of sentencing in the regulatory context.</paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>The events of Walkerton demonstrated that voluntary compliance must be backed by effective enforcement. The authors conceive of a regulatory pyramid in the realm of compliance and enforcement mechanisms. They suggest an approach to corporate and regulatory liability that combines risk management with restorative justice.</paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<paratext>All members of the public have a stake in effective regulation. This book is a timely contribution to the development of this emerging area of legal scholarship, and it will be a valuable resource for practitioners and academics in the field of regulatory law.</paratext>
				</para>
				<para>
					<tbl ID="I7268fc409c6e11eaa5b1c99e8f4ac64f">
						<table>
							<tgroup cols="2">
								<colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="3*" />
								<colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="7*" />
								<tbody>
									<row>
										<entry colname="1" align="left">Toronto, Ontario</entry>
										<entry colname="2" align="right">The Honourable Justice Dennis O&#8217;Connor</entry>
									</row>
									<row>
										<entry colname="1" align="left">December 2004</entry>
										<entry colname="2" align="right">Court of Appeal of Ontario</entry>
									</row>
								</tbody>
							</tgroup>
						</table>
					</tbl>
				</para>
			</intro.block>
		</grade.notes>
		<content.metadata.block>
			<cmd.royalty>
				<cmd.copyright>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document "as is". Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.</cmd.copyright>
			</cmd.royalty>
			<cmd.identifiers>
				<cmd.cites>
					<cmd.first.line.cite>ARCHIBALDRC-WL PREMAT</cmd.first.line.cite>
				</cmd.cites>
			</cmd.identifiers>
		</content.metadata.block>
	</doc>
</n-docbody>