<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 1:3<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I4d7849c0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>1.</label.designator><headtext>Confidential Business Information in Historical Context</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I4d790d10411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>I.</label.designator><headtext>Origins of Intellectual Property</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f59be36ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>1:3.</label.designator><headtext>Feudal Age</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Property law concepts were created during medieval times when land was the central source of wealth. <eos/><bos/>During the Dark Ages, land was the central source of subsistence. <eos/><bos/>The Feudal Age was a reaction to the Dark Ages, and a complex system of rights and obligations was developed to satisfy the need for order and security. <eos/><bos/>In the Feudal Age, land was used as a means of survival, and was also expanded to create a system of wealth and a complex system of organized agricultural production and physical protection for both master and serf.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The feudal system was a system where status, not private agreements, determined the activities of the members of that society.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Icd91af408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>] One writer has put it this way:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0003"/>One man, the vassal, commends to another man,whom he chooses as his master … the vassal owes his master fealty, counsel, military and material assistance. <eos/><bos/>The master—the lord—owes his vassal fealty, protection and the means of subsistence. <eos/><bos/>This last can be provided in various ways, usually by conceding to the vassal a piece of land known as a “benefice” or “fief”.<eos/><bos/> Thus the hierarchy among individuals was very soon accompanied by a hierarchy of rights over land, due to an <begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>“extreme parcelling out of property rights”<end.quote refid="QT_0002"/>.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0003"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Icd91d6508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>It was also at this time that the concept of trade secrets arose to keep the secrets of one guild from members of other guilds. <eos/><bos/>However, there were few problems with copying because reproduction of textual or visual images was done by hand, rendering it difficult to copy the work of another. <eos/><bos/>Writings were generally the works of religious scholars, and it was believed that if more copies were made, this would better advance the cause of religion.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Icd91af408e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>G. Klueck, <begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>“The Coming Jurisprudence of the Information Age: Examinations of the Three Past Socio-Economic Ages Suggest the Future”<end.quote refid="QT_0001"/> (1984), 21 San Diego L. Rev. 1077, 1082. <eos/><bos/>See also <cite.query w-src-number="0492175790" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="ER" w-normalized-cite="EDWUK3" w-pub-number="0004991" ID="I115e72208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Statute of Labourers, 1349</ital> (U.K.), 23 Edw. 3</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>This statute provided that able-bodied persons were to work at reasonable rates and were not to refuse to work for anyone.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Icd91d6508e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>G. Fourquin, <ital>Lordship and Feudalism in the Middle Ages</ital>, I. and A.L. Lytton Sells, trans. (<eos/><bos/>London: Allen &amp; Unwin, 1976), p. 11.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 1:3<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
