<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 1:4<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I4d7849c0411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>1.</label.designator><headtext>Confidential Business Information in Historical Context</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I4d790d10411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>I.</label.designator><headtext>Origins of Intellectual Property</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f59be66ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>1:4.</label.designator><headtext>Commercial Age</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The end of the 15th century is generally regarded as the beginning of the Commercial Age. <eos/><bos/>The feudal system had created strong monarchies and financial success. <eos/><bos/>Self-sufficiency was no longer the goal. <eos/><bos/>Commerce was revived, and cities grew and began to ship goods for trade as well as transporting them by land. <eos/><bos/>Commerce became the focus of European affairs and the means to determine status and power, and European states regulated their economies in order to inspire more growth and trade.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Icdc67ae08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Venetian Council of 1474 enacted the first explicit legislative protection for new inventions. <eos/><bos/>The council held that:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>There are in this city … men … capable of devising and inventing all manner of ingenious contrivances. <eos/><bos/>And it should be provided, that the works and contrivances invented by them, others having seen them could not make them and take their honour, men of such kind would exert their minds, invent and make things which would be of no small utility and benefit to our State.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0001"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Icdc7da708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In 1476, Caxton brought the printing press to England. <eos/><bos/>The printing press was one of the most significant developments of the Renaissance, and it became a means of controlling the dissemination of information as the number of published books greatly increased. <eos/><bos/>This enabled a vast number of people who had previously not been able to afford books to obtain copies at a reasonable price. <eos/><bos/>In the latter half of the 15th century, up to 20 million books were printed (average print run of 500 copies), almost all of which were filled with information that had previously been unavailable to the average person.<eos/><bos/><cite.query w-src-number="0492175791" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="ER" w-normalized-cite="3IN1518" w-pub-number="0000440" ID="I11d5ec108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">[<footnote.reference refid="Icdc801808e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">3</footnote.reference>] In 1518</cite.query>, the Crown began to issue royal privileges and patents to printers for the exclusive right to print a particular book. <eos/><bos/>In 1529, Henry VIII passed an Act which established privilege for the printing of books through the exercise of Crown prerogative.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Icdc801818e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">4</footnote.reference>] These privileges and prerogatives were used by the monarchy to control information. <eos/><bos/>Henry VIII published a list of prohibited books, and in 1538, the first licensing system was introduced. <eos/><bos/>In 1555, a proclamation was issued by Philip and Mary forbidding the printing, selling or reading of the sacraments. <eos/><bos/>Queen Elizabeth issued a proclamation in 1558 requiring the burning of all heretical documents. <eos/><bos/>The Tudor monarchs followed a pattern of <begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>“comprising grants of patents for specified books, confinement of printing to authorized presses, licensing books before publication, use of trade organizations and government agencies for enforcement”<end.quote refid="QT_0002"/>.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Icdc828908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">5</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>These royal grants became so numerous that they were regarded as oppressive and unjust. <eos/><bos/>Thus, in the reign of James I, a statute was enacted which declared void all monopolies that were oppressive to British subjects. <eos/><bos/>In 1695 the <ital>Printing Act</ital> expired through non-renewal, which stripped the stationers of their statutory trade monopoly. <eos/><bos/>There was an exception from this expiry for letters patent and grants of privilege for new inventions which were not to be copied on the grounds that they would raise the price of commodities in Britain or damage British trade generally. <eos/><bos/>These principles were later integrated into the Patent Act of 1883.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Icdc828918e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">6</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In 1709, the predecessor to the English <ital>Copyright Act</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Icdc84fa08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">7</footnote.reference>] was enacted, granting exclusive printing rights in books and sheet music to owners of the copyright. <eos/><bos/>Modern copyright laws are derived from the royal licences which accorded printing privileges to a limited number of persons for a limited time, just as modern patent laws are derived from the grants of monopoly for new inventions. <eos/><bos/>However, these rights did not exist at common law but only by reason of a royal grant.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Icdc84fa18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">8</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The statute of 1709[<footnote.reference refid="Icdc84fa28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">9</footnote.reference>] provided that, after April 10, 1710, the author of any book already printed or any bookseller, printer or other entity which acquired the sole right to print the work would retain the right to print the book for 21 years and no longer. <eos/><bos/>Authors of books which had not been printed had the sole power to print the work for 14 years. <eos/><bos/>Penalties for printing without the consent of the copyright owner were provided, but only if title to the book published had been entered in the Register Book of the Company of Stationers.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>During the 18th century, Britain had a technological advantage over its European competitors. <eos/><bos/>Trade and commerce were extremely important sources of wealth, and it was especially important to prevent skilled workers from being enticed abroad. <eos/><bos/>Their personal skills and their knowledge of trade secrets were valuable assets which the state and their employers could not afford to lose to foreign competitors. <eos/><bos/>However, the distinction between trade secrets and the general knowledge and skill of a worker was not as important as it is now, for it was only the ability to put the new skill into practice which was the economically important asset.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>European nation states encouraged foreigners to bring their skills but enacted strict laws to prevent skilled workers from leaving their jurisdiction. <eos/><bos/>For example, the <begin.quote ID="QT_0003"/>“Act to prevent the Inconvenience arising from seducing Artificers in the Manufactures of Great Britain into foreign Parts”<end.quote refid="QT_0003"/>, 1718,[<footnote.reference refid="Icdc876b08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">10</footnote.reference>] was aimed at:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0004"/>… divers ill-disposed Persons [who had] drawn away and transported … several Artificers and Manufacturers … out of his Majesty&apos;s Dominions into foreign Countries, by entring into Contracts with them to give them greater Wages and Advantages than they have or can reasonably expect within this Kingdom, and by making them large Promises and using other Arts to inveigle and draw them away …<end.quote refid="QT_0004"/></paratext></para></display.quote><paratext>This Act contained fines of up to £100 and imprisonment for up to three months if the fine was not paid, for any person enticing any worker in wool, iron, steel, brass or other metal trades, or any watchmaker, clockmaker or other manufacturer. <eos/><bos/>Workers who were enticed abroad were deemed to be aliens and forfeited all their lands and goods and were incapable of receiving any legacy or gift.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Icdc876b18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">11</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Export of economically important machinery, particularly new technology embodying trade secrets which could be discovered by proceeding backwards through the steps involved to recreate the idea or invention, was also prohibited, and there were criminal sanctions for such export. <eos/><bos/>Similar legislation was enacted some time later in France, Germany and Switzerland.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>At the same time, the English law of fiduciaries began to develop. <eos/><bos/>In 1726, the court in <ital>Keech v. Sandford</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Icdc89dc08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">12</footnote.reference>] made it clear that a trustee could not profit from a trust even if no damage was done to the trust as a result.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Most of the early common law cases involved the author&apos;s rights in unpublished manuscripts, and the right was often cited as a property or an equitable right. <eos/><bos/>In the case of <ital>Millar v. Taylor</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Icdc89dc18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">13</footnote.reference>] Mr. Justice Yates held that an author&apos;s right in an unpublished manuscript <begin.quote ID="QT_0005"/>“is, in every sense, his peculiar property; and no man can take it from him, or make any use of it which he has not authorized, without being guilty of a violation of his property”<end.quote refid="QT_0005"/>. <eos/><bos/>The author was held to have perpetual copyright at common law which was not affected by the statute of 8 Ann., c. 19,[<footnote.reference refid="Icdc8c4d08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">14</footnote.reference>] as the court held that that Act only applied to published works. <eos/><bos/>This right was upheld in <ital>Donaldson v. Beckett</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Icdc8c4d18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">15</footnote.reference>] wherein the court held that published works were protected only by statute, but unpublished works maintained their perpetual common law copyright.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In the 18th century, the courts held that an injunction could be granted to restrain the violation of legal rights on the grounds of irreparable injury even before the rights of the parties had been determined at law. <eos/><bos/>The rights to be protected included letters patent, copyright and restraining provisions in a contract.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The earliest reported cases in which an injunction was granted to restrain an abuse of confidence were cases in which the author of an unpublished work or the author&apos;s representative was entitled to restrain those in possession of the manuscript from publishing it.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Icdc8ebe08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">16</footnote.reference>] The landmark case of the <ital>Duke of Queensberry v. Shebbeare</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Icdca4b708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">17</footnote.reference>] concerned Lord Clarendon&apos;s <ital>History of the Reign of Charles the Second from the Restoration to the year 1667</ital>. <eos/><bos/>The defendant argued that 33 years previously the Earl of Clarendon had given the history to Mr. Gwynne so that he might <begin.quote ID="QT_0006"/>“make use of the same as he should think fit”<end.quote refid="QT_0006"/>.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Icdca4b718e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">18</footnote.reference>] Gwynne gave the work to Doctor Shebbeare. <eos/><bos/>Although Gwynne was entitled to make use of the history for his personal use, the court held that:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0007"/>… it was not to be presumed that Lord <ital>Clarendon</ital>, when he gave a copy of his work to Mr. <ital>Gwynne</ital>, intended that he should have the profit of multiplying it in print … Mr. Gwynne might make every use of it, except that.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0007"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Icdca72808e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">19</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><paratext>An injunction was granted to prevent the printing of the work.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Following the King&apos;s Bench decision in <ital>Millar v. Taylor</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Icdca72818e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">20</footnote.reference>] the Court of Chancery granted injunctions which often provided final determinations of the parties&apos; rights that were treated as precedents in the Court of Chancery and even in the courts of common law.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>One of the first intellectual property cases in which an injunction was awarded prior to trial was <ital>Abernethey v. Hutchinson</ital>.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Icdca99908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">21</footnote.reference>] This case involved a surgeon at St. Bartholomew&apos;s Hospital who was to give a course of 30 lectures which had never been published. <eos/><bos/>Students paid fees to attend. <eos/><bos/>After the first lecture, an advertisement appeared stating that each lecture would be published in a journal. <eos/><bos/>The first three lectures were published and as a result Dr. Abernethey brought legal action. <eos/><bos/>Lord Eldon concluded that the relationship between the plaintiff and the students was one of contract and that there was an implied term not to publish. <eos/><bos/>The evidence was that the students had obtained the lectures without the plaintiff&apos;s consent. <eos/><bos/>The court granted an injunction to restrain the third party from using the information and ideas contained in the lectures since they had been improperly obtained by the students. <eos/><bos/>Lord Eldon did state, however, that the <begin.quote ID="QT_0008"/>“case could be viewed two ways—either as a question of trust, or a question of property”<end.quote refid="QT_0008"/>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Similarly, in <ital>Prince Albert v. Strange</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Icdca99918e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">22</footnote.reference>] when etchings drawn by Prince Albert and Queen Victoria for their personal use were obtained by a third party who attempted to have them published against the plaintiff&apos;s will, the court held that <begin.quote ID="QT_0010"/>“this case by no means depends solely on the question of property; for a breach of trust, confidence or contract itself would entitle the Plaintiff to the injunction”<end.quote refid="QT_0010"/>. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff was entitled to <begin.quote ID="QT_0009"/>“keep [the etchings] wholly for his private use and pleasure, and to withhold [them] altogether, or so far as he may please, from the knowledge of others”<end.quote refid="QT_0009"/>. <eos/><bos/>The court added that regardless of whether or not a contract existed, equity would intervene to prevent the defendant from taking advantage of such a breach of trust or confidence.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The principle of providing protection against unconscionable abuses was extended and adapted in the early 19th century <begin.quote ID="QT_0011"/>“to other intellectual rights and processes such as patent medicines, new inventions and trade secrets”<end.quote refid="QT_0011"/>.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Icdcac0a08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">23</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Icdc67ae08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>S. Clough and R. Rapp, <ital>European Economic History</ital>, 3rd ed. (New York: McGraw-Hill, 1975), p. 147.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Icdc7da708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>S.P. Ladas, <ital>Patents, Trade-marks and Related Rights: National and International Protection</ital>, vol. 1 (Cambridge, Mass.: Harvard University Press, 1975), p. 6.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Icdc801808e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>W. Stanbury and I. Vertinsky, <ital>Assessing the Impact of New Information Technologies on Interest Group Behaviour and Policy Making</ital> (Kingston: Queens University Press, 1994), p. 7.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Icdc801818e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>4</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>Cum privilegio regali ad imprimendum solum</ital>, as described in S.M. Stewart, <ital>International Copyright and Neighbouring Rights</ital>, 2nd ed. (London: Butterworths, 1989), p. 20.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Icdc828908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>5</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>Cum privilegio regali ad imprimendum solum</ital>, as described in S.M. Stewart, <ital>International Copyright and Neighbouring Rights</ital>, 2nd ed. (London: Butterworths, 1989), p. 20.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Icdc828918e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>6</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>Patents, Designs and Trade Marks Act, 1883</ital> (U.K.), 46 &amp; 47 Vict., c. 57.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Icdc84fa08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>7</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>“Act for the Encouragement of Learning, by vesting the Copies of printed Books in the Authors or Purchasers of such Copies, during the Times therein mentioned”, 1709 (U.K.), 8 Ann., c. 19.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Icdc84fa18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>8</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>G.F. Henderson, ed., <ital>Trade-Marks Law of Canada</ital> (Scarborough: Carswell, 1993), p. 10.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Icdc84fa28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>9</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>“Act for the Encouragement of Learning, by vesting the Copies of printed Books in the Authors or Purchasers of such Copies, during the Times therein mentioned”, 1709 (U.K.), 8 Ann., c. 19.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Icdc876b08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>10</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>“Act to prevent the Inconvenience arising from seducing Artificers in the <cite.query w-src-number="0492175791" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="ER" w-normalized-cite="5GEO1" w-pub-number="0003647" ID="I11dd8d308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Manufactures of Great Britain into foreign Parts”, 1718, (U.K.), 5 Geo. 1</cite.query>, c. 27.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Icdc876b18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>11</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A. Coleman, <ital>The Legal Protection of Trade Secrets</ital> (London: Sweet &amp; Maxwell, 1992), p. 94.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Icdc89dc08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>12</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175791" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1726008768" w-pub-number="0004930" ID="I11dddb518e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Keech v. Sandford</ital> (1726), Sel. Cas. T. King 61, 25 E.R. 223 (Ch.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Icdc89dc18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>13</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175791" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1769085203" w-pub-number="0003533" w-pinpoint-page="2379" ID="I11de02608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Millar v. Taylor</ital> (1769), 4 Burr. 2303 at p. 2379, 98 E.R. 201 (K.B.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Icdc8c4d08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>14</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>“Act for the Encouragement of Learning, by vesting the Copies of printed Books in the Authors or Purchasers of such Copies, during the Times therein mentioned”, 1709 (U.K.), 8 Ann., c. 19.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Icdc8c4d18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>15</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175791" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1774150015" w-pub-number="0003523" ID="I11de50808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Donaldson v. Beckett</ital> (1774), 2 Brown. 129, 1 E.R. 837 (H.C. Parliament)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Icdc8ebe08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>16</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175791" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="ER" w-normalized-cite="4BURR2330" w-pub-number="0003533" ID="I11de77908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Webb v. Rose</ital> (1732), cited in 4 Burr. 2330, 98 E.R. 216</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175791" w-seq-number="00007" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1758083539" w-pub-number="0005726" ID="I11de77938e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Duke of Queensberry v. Shebbeare</ital> (1758), 2 Eden 329, 28 E.R. 924 (Ch.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Icdca4b708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>17</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175791" w-seq-number="00008" w-ref-type="ER" w-normalized-cite="4BURR2330" w-pub-number="0003533" ID="I11dec5b08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Webb v. Rose</ital> (1732), cited in 4 Burr. 2330, 98 E.R. 216</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Icdca4b718e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>18</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175791" w-seq-number="00009" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1758083539" w-pub-number="0005726" ID="I11deecc08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Duke of Queensberry v. Shebbeare</ital> (1758), 2 Eden 329, 28 E.R. 924 (Ch.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Icdca72808e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>19</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175791" w-seq-number="00010" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1758083539" w-pub-number="0005726" w-pinpoint-page="330" ID="I11deecc38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Duke of Queensberry v. Shebbeare</ital> (1758), 2 Eden 329, at p. 330, 28 E.R. 924 (Ch.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Icdca72818e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>20</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175791" w-seq-number="00011" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1769085203" w-pub-number="0003533" ID="I11df13d08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Millar v. Taylor</ital> (1769), 4 Burr. 2303, 98 E.R. 201 (K.B.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Icdca99908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>21</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175791" w-seq-number="00012" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1825063549" w-pub-number="0005801" ID="I11df3ae08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Abernethey v. Hutchinson</ital> (1825), 1 H. &amp; Tw. 28, 47 E.R. 1313 (Ch.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Icdca99918e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>22</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175791" w-seq-number="00013" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1849049683" w-pub-number="0005801" w-pinpoint-page="23" ID="I11df61f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Prince Albert v. Strange</ital> (1849), 1 H. &amp; Tw. 1 at p. 23, 47 E.R. 1302 (Ch.)</cite.query>; (1849), <cite.query w-src-number="0492175791" w-seq-number="00014" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1849035923" w-pub-number="0005038" w-pinpoint-page="43" ID="I11df61f38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">1 Mac. &amp; G. 25 at p. 43, 41 E.R. 1171 (Ch.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Icdcac0a08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>23</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>R.G. Hammond, <begin.quote ID="QT_0012"/>“Developments in the Equitable Doctrine of Breach of Confidence”<end.quote refid="QT_0012"/>, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175791" w-seq-number="00015" w-ref-type="N3" w-normalized-cite="1976NZLJNZ278" w-pub-number="0007238" ID="I11df89008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">[1976] N.Z.L.J. 278</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 1:4<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
