<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information § 5:19<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Thorburn, Law of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501"><bop/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><prop.head toc-guid="I540dc620411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>5.</label.designator><headtext>Claims for Breach of Confidential Business Information</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I540ded30411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>I.</label.designator><headtext>Civil Actions</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I55b9ef80411c11ea9bd78ece924bfde3"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>E.</label.designator><headtext>Claims Against Third Parties</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Ie9f6ad7a6ad411eaa31f88aec239341d"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>5:19.</label.designator><headtext>Breach of Confidence Actions</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>As stated previously, an action for breach of confidence may be brought whether or not a direct relationship exists, provided the third party has knowledge that the information was improperly obtained.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7450d708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">1</footnote.reference>] Furthermore, once the third party obtains knowledge that the information was improperly obtained, that party no longer has the right to use the information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7450d718e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">2</footnote.reference>] The third party may be liable for any unauthorized use of the information whether that party at the time of acquisition of the information had actual, imputed or constructive knowledge that the information was confidential.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7450d728e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">3</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Husky Injection Molding Systems Ltd. v. Schad</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id7450d738e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">4</footnote.reference>] there was no evidence that a third party SIPA knew how Athena had developed the A150 machine. <eos/><bos/>SIPA had no reason to ask whether the information or drawings were developed using Husky confidential information and there was no reason for SIPA to suspect that Athena was misusing Husky&apos;s confidential information in the development of its machines, particularly given Schad&apos;s lengthy experience in the injection molding industry and his sterling reputation. <eos/><bos/>The defendant Schad started Husky in a garage in 1953. <eos/><bos/>He built Husky into a world-wide manufacturer and distributor of injection molding machines, parts and services. <eos/><bos/>Schad was Husky&apos;s sole shareholder from the time the company was founded and remained Husky&apos;s controlling shareholder after an earlier IPO until December 2007 when Husky was sold to Onex Corporation. <eos/><bos/>In June 2008 Schad formed the defendant, Athena. <eos/><bos/>Athena eventually developed certain types of injection molding machines. <eos/><bos/>On December 18, 2012 Athena and SIPA, an Italian injection molding machine manufacturer and a competitor of Husky, announced that they had entered into a partnership to market injection molding machines developed by Athena.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7450d748e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">5</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Husky&apos;s claim against SIPA was based on breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>Husky relied on the fact that after the handshake agreement on December 18, 2012 between SIPA and Athena, SIPA was put on notice of Husky&apos;s claim for misuse of Husky confidential information before it signed the agreement with Athena on September 19, 2013 by reason of the statement of claim in this action issued on May 24, 2013 and served on SIPA before it signed the agreement with Athena. <eos/><bos/>In the statement of claim, Husky alleged that the Schad defendants and SIPA had misused Husky confidential information.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7450d758e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">6</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>For a third party in receipt of confidential information to be held liable, the third party must have received the information with knowledge that it was communicated in breach of confidence, or the third party must afterwards acquire such knowledge. <eos/><bos/>In <cite.query w-src-number="0492175930" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1999428661" w-pub-number="0005156" ID="I5091a5208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Cadbury Schweppes Inc. v. FBI Foods Ltd.</ital>, [1999] 1 S.C.R. 142, 1999 CarswellBC 77 (S.C.C.)</cite.query>, the Supreme Court of Canada confirmed the principle by which third party recipients of confidential information may be held liable. <eos/><bos/>In that case Justice Binnie stated:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>19 Equity, as a court of conscience, directs itself to the behaviour of the person who has come into possession of information that is in fact confidential, and was accepted on that basis, either expressly or by implication. <eos/><bos/>Equity will pursue the information into the hands of a third party who receives it with the knowledge that it was communicated in breach of confidence (or afterwards acquires notice of that fact even if innocent at the time of acquisition) and impose its remedies.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0001"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id74534808e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">7</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The trial judge took the words “notice of that fact” used by Justice Binnie to mean notice of knowledge that the information was communicated in breach of confidence, not notice of an allegation that the information was communicated in breach of confidence. <eos/><bos/>An allegation in a statement of claim is not knowledge. <eos/><bos/>Pleadings that make allegations that later cannot be proven are commonplace in litigation. <eos/><bos/>Husky&apos;s argument, if accepted, would mean that an allegation in a statement of claim would result in a self-imposed injunction. <eos/><bos/>In the circumstances, for the law to now tell SIPA that it is liable for proceeding with its agreement with Athena in the face of allegations that SIPA denied from the start does not make sense and would work an injustice.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id74534818e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">8</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <cite.query w-src-number="0492175930" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2036247282" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I509723618e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Grant v. Winnipeg Regional Health Authority</ital></cite.query>,[<footnote.reference refid="Id74534828e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">9</footnote.reference>] the plaintiff appealed the decision of the motion judge, dismissing an appeal from the decision of the Master, striking parts of an amended statement of claim as disclosing no reasonable cause of action. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff was the sister of the late Sinclair and the administrator of his estate. <eos/><bos/>Sinclair, age 45, died in the emergency waiting room of the Health Sciences Centre after a prolonged stay there without receiving medical attention. <eos/><bos/>Subsequently, the plaintiff commenced an action on her own behalf, and also in her capacity as administrator, over the alleged disregard of Sinclair at the HSC leading up to his death, and the conduct of officials with the defendant, Winnipeg Regional Health Authority, shortly after his death. <eos/><bos/>An issue on appeal involved a claim for the negligent disclosure of confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff, on her own behalf, sought damages for the alleged misuse of Sinclair&apos;s personal medical information by hospital officials during statements to the media after his death. <eos/><bos/>The motion judge determined that a third party cannot sue in negligence for the deliberate release of personal information of another person. <eos/><bos/>The appeal was allowed on the claim arising from the disclosure of confidential information. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiff alleged that, in order to deflect blame from itself and its employees, certain officials of the Winnipeg Regional Health Authority stated publicly that Sinclair had never approached the triage desk, information that could only have been gleaned from the hospital&apos;s records. <eos/><bos/>That information proved to be incorrect given the closed-circuit television (CCTV) footage. <eos/><bos/>As well, it was alleged that the WRHA communicated confidential patient information concerning Sinclair to the Government of Manitoba who, in turn, repeated the information to the media.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id74534838e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">10</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Monnin expressed some concerns with the comments of the motion judge that a duty of care to maintain the confidentiality of records and not to use them without consent is a duty owed only to the party whose records are being disclosed noting that current jurisprudence has recognized the expansion of tort law in dealing with confidential information. <eos/><bos/>Whether that expansion also encompasses claims by third parties who may also be harmed by an unauthorized disclosure of information is something which remains open. <eos/><bos/>Tort law has recognized that a breach of confidence in certain circumstances may create a cause of action. <eos/><bos/>Courts have recognized that the unauthorized use of confidential information to the detriment of the party communicating it, and from which damages ensue, may lead to a cause of action. <eos/><bos/>The facts as set out in the statement of claim disclose that the disclosure defendants used admittedly confidential information (personal health records) in an unauthorized fashion. <eos/><bos/>The disclosure detrimentally affected Sinclair as it portrayed him as being the author of his own misfortunes. <eos/><bos/>Justice Monnin cited the English jurisprudence, stating:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>Claims on the basis of the tort of a breach of an obligation of confidence have been used more extensively in the English courts (see <cite.query w-src-number="0492175930" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1968018312" w-pub-number="0004831" ID="I509994608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Coco v. A.N. Clark (Engineers) Ltd</ital>. (1968), [1969] R.P.C. 41 (Eng. Ch. Div.)</cite.query>).<eos/><bos/> It has also been expanded not only to situations where the information had not been confided to a confidant, but where a person knew or ought to have known that there was a reasonable expectation of privacy (see <ital>Attorney General v. Guardian Newspaper Ltd. (No. 2)</ital> (1988), <cite.query w-src-number="0492175930" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1988181722" w-pub-number="0004651" ID="I509994628e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">[1990] 1 A.C. 109 (U.K. H.L.)</cite.query>, at 281; <cite.query w-src-number="0492175930" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2004349622" w-pub-number="0006452" ID="I509994648e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Campbell v. Mirror Group Newspaper Ltd.</ital>, [2004] UKHL 22, [2004] 2 A.C. 457 (U.K. H.L.)</cite.query>; and <cite.query w-src-number="0492175930" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2012130763" w-pub-number="0006452" ID="I509994678e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>OBG Ltd. v. Allan</ital>, [2007] UKHL 21, [2008] 1 A.C. 1 (U.K. H.L.)</cite.query>).<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0002"/></paratext></para><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0003"/>As well, it is not necessarily limited to a claim by the individual whose confidence has been directly breached. <eos/><bos/>In <cite.query w-src-number="0492175930" w-seq-number="00007" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1994260296" w-pub-number="0004717" ID="I509a30a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>R. v. Broadcasting Complaints Commission</ital> (1994), [1995] E.M.L.R. 163</cite.query> (Eng. &amp; Wales C.A. (Civil)), the parents of two children who had suffered tragic deaths complained concerning the broadcast of television programs featuring photographs and details of the children&apos;s death. <eos/><bos/>The cause of action was that the disclosure violated the parents&apos; right to privacy under relevant legislation. <eos/><bos/>The English Court of Appeal found that privacy was not confined to matters concerning the individual, but also extended to family, in that case the parents of the deceased children.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0003"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id74534848e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">11</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Monnin observed that there is another area of developing jurisprudence in the area of tort law relating to privacy interests as set out by the Ontario Court of Appeal in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175930" w-seq-number="00008" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2026903830" w-pub-number="0007352" ID="I509a7ec08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Jones v. Tsige</ital>, 2012 ONCA 32, 287 O.A.C. 56 (Ont. C.A.)</cite.query>, where it recognized the availability of an action for the invasion of personal privacy, intrusion upon seclusion.<eos/><bos/></paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0004"/>In a recent decision, <cite.query w-src-number="0492175930" w-seq-number="00009" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036064119" w-pub-number="0007352" ID="I509c7a908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Hopkins v. Kay</ital>, 2015 ONCA 112, 380 D.L.R. (4th) 506 (Ont. C.A.)</cite.query>, the Ontario Court of Appeal had the opportunity to elaborate on its decision in <cite.query w-src-number="0492175930" w-seq-number="00010" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2026903830" w-pub-number="0007352" ID="I509c7a948e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Jones</cite.query> and to confirm that the cause of action for intrusion upon seclusion could be applied to a situation involving the unauthorized disclosure of patient hospital records notwithstanding the existence of the <ital>Personal Health Information and Protection Act, 2004</ital>, S.O. 2004, c. 3, Sched. <eos/><bos/>A, of Ontario similar to <ital>The Personal Health Information Act</ital> of Manitoba; see also <cite.query w-src-number="0492175930" w-seq-number="00011" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2034800724" w-pub-number="0007685" ID="I509c7a968e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Hynes v. Western Regional Integrated Health Authority</ital>, 2014 NLTD(G) 137, 357 Nfld. &amp; P.E.I.R. 138 (N.L. T.D.)</cite.query>.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0004"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Id7455b908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">12</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Justice Monnin concluded that it was clear from the emerging jurisprudence that, had Sinclair survived, he may have advanced a claim for breach of confidence or intrusion upon seclusion or perhaps for publicity which placed him in a false light in the public eye. <eos/><bos/>Whether family members, who claim to have suffered as a result of a breach of a privacy interest of another member, are in sufficient proximity to the victim in a tort context and are therefore able to advance a claim in their own right, remains an open question. <eos/><bos/>It would not be appropriate to dismiss at the pleadings stage the possibility of a court recognizing that damages suffered by immediate or close family members as a result of such a breach are compensable. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, the motion judge erred when he dismissed the plaintiff&apos;s claim for negligent disclosure on the grounds that there was no duty of care owed to the plaintiff in her personal capacity. <eos/><bos/>The matter was referred back to the motion court with leave to the plaintiff to amend the pleadings to reflect a cause of action based upon a breach of confidence or intrusion upon seclusion or publicity, using the facts as set out in the statement of claim.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7455b918e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">13</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The moving Defendants in <ital>Chamberlain Architect Services Ltd. v. Saplys</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Id7455b928e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">14</footnote.reference>] sought an order striking out various portions of the Statement of Claim. <eos/><bos/>The Plaintiff was an architectural firm that had employed the Linas, Eva, and Barnard in various capacities relating to architectural work. <eos/><bos/>Linas was the controlling mind of the corporate defendants. <eos/><bos/>At some point Linas, Eva and Barnard left the Chamberlain firm. <eos/><bos/>Chamberlain later came to believe they had misappropriated drawings belonging to Chamberlain and used them to secure architectural contracts for themselves. <eos/><bos/>The moving Defendants argued that there was no tenable claim pleaded in “breach of confidence” against that Eva&apos;s husband and the corporate defendants.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7455b938e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">15</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In the case of a third party who has come into possession of information that is in fact confidential, the claim must plead that it was accepted on that basis, either expressly or by implication, or that the recipient later acquired notice of its nature. <eos/><bos/>The Statement of Claim clearly alleged that Linas misused confidential information that he received from Chamberlain. <eos/><bos/>It was undisputed that Linas was the controlling mind of two of the corporate defendants. <eos/><bos/>Whether he received and misused confidential information in his personal capacity or through the corporations he controlled was irrelevant. <eos/><bos/>Otherwise an individual could shield himself from liability by using his company for any potentially contentious dealings. <eos/><bos/>Therefore, the claims for breach of confidence against the corporate defendants would stand.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7455b948e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">16</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>As for Eva&apos;s husband and his and his entity, the Statement of Claim asserted that the husband&apos;s initials appeared on the impugned permit drawings that were allegedly used by the Defendants to secure an architectural contract. <eos/><bos/>However, there was no allegation that he was aware at any point of the confidential nature of that information, and to that extent this claim against him and his corporate entity was deficient. <eos/><bos/>The motions judge ordered that it either be amended or struck.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7455b958e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">17</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The plaintiff&apos;s motion for summary judgment against the Defendant for breach of confidence was granted in <ital>Canada (Attorney General) v. Rundle</ital>.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id7455b968e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">18</footnote.reference>] The Second Language Evaluation reading and writing tests are copyrighted, confidential, and developed at great cost to taxpayers. <eos/><bos/>Their value derived from the fact they were not known to the public. <eos/><bos/>Canada established that the Defendant surreptitiously obtained and used confidential SLE test content without the PSC&apos;s consent. <eos/><bos/>Rundle admitted that she compiled practice test questions from her students&apos; recollection of the official tests after they took them. <eos/><bos/>She was also able to obtain, copy, and distribute exact photocopies of certain SLE tests. <eos/><bos/>In doing so, she gave her students an unfair advantage over other applicants to federal jobs, she undermined the PSC&apos;s ability to fulfill its mandate and caused it to incur the expense of creating new SLEs to replace the versions she compromised.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id74582a08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">19</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Each of the elements of the cause of action for breach of confidence was established. <eos/><bos/>The SLE tests were confidential and treated as such. <eos/><bos/>All SLE test booklets are marked “Protected B” on the cover and on every page of the test booklet containing test content. <eos/><bos/>The Treasury Board security policy defines “Protected B” as information which, if compromised, could result in grave injury, such as loss of reputation or competitive advantage. <eos/><bos/>Test administrators must protect the security of the test materials at all times. <eos/><bos/>Testing material must be stored in a locked cabinet in a closed room. <eos/><bos/>No part of any test material may be reproduced, and no test material can be left unattended while a test is being administered. <eos/><bos/>Any material that is not accounted for must be reported immediately to the PPC. The administration manual for SLE tests advises test administrators of the protected nature of the tests and underscores the importance of test security. <eos/><bos/>The manual also includes instructions for test takers advising them that they are not to share test content with anyone and of the consequences of so doing. <eos/><bos/>On the inside of the test booklet the Crown copyright is clearly noted. <eos/><bos/>The PSC takes steps to prevent copying and warns test takers not to share the test content with anyone. <eos/><bos/>It could be assumed that the Defendant, an experienced teacher, knew about the confidential nature of these tests. <eos/><bos/>There is a breach of confidence when, as here, a third party comes into possession of confidential information with the knowledge that it was communicated in confidence. <eos/><bos/>The existence of a relationship between the parties is not required for the cause of action to arise. <eos/><bos/>Rather, the issue is whether <begin.quote ID="QT_0005"/>“the information is indeed confidential and whether the circumstances of the disclosure are such that the recipient of the confidential information would know that the information is confidential”<end.quote refid="QT_0005"/>. <eos/><bos/>The Defendant knew that the SLE tests could not be used as assessment tools once they became public, yet she methodically sought out information communicated to her students in confidence for the sole purpose of recreating them. <eos/><bos/>The Defendant&apos;s use of the PSC&apos;s confidential SLE tests caused it financial harm and undermined the Government&apos;s statutory obligations. <eos/><bos/>Since the release of the PSC Audit, the PSC discontinued the use of the SLE tests which it had concluded had been compromised. <eos/><bos/>The PSC replaced them with new tests, which it developed at great expense. <eos/><bos/>In addition to the financial harm, the Defendant hampered the Federal government&apos;s ability to perform its statutory duties. <eos/><bos/>Allowing unqualified persons to obtain excellent French SLE scores and to acquire bilingual positions in the Public Service undermines its ability to serve the public in the official language of choice. <eos/><bos/>The Defendant surreptitiously obtained confidential test materials belonging to the PSC and used them for financial gain. <eos/><bos/>She obtained the information from her students, who knew that they were under a duty not to disclose them. <eos/><bos/>There was no genuine issue requiring a trial on the Plaintiff&apos;s claim for breach of confidence.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id74582a18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">20</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital><cite.query w-src-number="0492175930" w-seq-number="00012" w-ref-type="IS" w-serial-number="2036746571" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I50a469d18e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">Teti v. Mueller Water Products</cite.query> Inc</ital>.,[<footnote.reference refid="Id74582a28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">21</footnote.reference>] the plaintiffs sued four corporate entities. <eos/><bos/>The defendants agreed that the claim against M-Can would proceed to trial but asked that the actions against the remaining entities be summarily dismissed. <eos/><bos/>The plaintiffs alleged that the defendants were a “common enterprise” that together and in concert misappropriated the plaintiff&apos;s confidential information and used it as a “springboard” for the development of their own competing product, and did so in breach of their relationship of confidence and the obligation to perform the 2009 agreement honestly and in good faith. <eos/><bos/>The motions judge noted that the plaintiffs were not placing all their eggs in the “breach of contract” basket. <eos/><bos/>They also alleged an equitable breach of confidence that did not require a contractual relationship. <eos/><bos/>A viable issue requiring trial included whether the defendants misappropriated the plaintiffs&apos; confidential information and used it as a “springboard” for the development of their own competing product, in breach of their relationship of confidence and the obligation to perform the 2009 agreement honestly and in good faith. <eos/><bos/>Given the complexity of the evidence about the inter-corporate connections and interactions, the “group enterprise” allegation alone required a trial. <eos/><bos/>These were not findings that could or should be made summarily. <eos/><bos/>The same could be said about the breach of confidence/springboard claim that would, in any event, involve the same defendants and the same parade of evidence. <eos/><bos/>The claim against M-Can was proceeding to trial in any event. <eos/><bos/>Much if not all of the same evidence would have to be considered again at the M-Can trial. <eos/><bos/>The defendants presented no evidence that the trial would be any sooner or any shorter if three of the four defendants were removed from the proceeding. <eos/><bos/>There was also a risk of duplicative proceedings and inconsistent judicial findings, neither of which was in the interest of justice. <eos/><bos/>The motions judge was not confident that he could summarily adjudicate the claims the remaining entities and achieve a fair and just result. <eos/><bos/>Exercising his discretion, the motions judge declined to use the enhanced fact-finding powers for a partial adjudication. <eos/><bos/>It was in the interest of justice that the action proceed to trial in its entirety.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Id74582a38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac">22</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Id7450d708e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175930" w-seq-number="00013" w-ref-type="ER" w-normalized-cite="29RPCUK639" w-pub-number="0004831" ID="I50a4b7f08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Liquid Veneer Co. v. Scott</ital> (1912), 29 R.P.C. 639 (Ch.)</cite.query>, at p. 644.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7450d718e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175930" w-seq-number="00014" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1981032033" w-pub-number="0004831" ID="I50aa5d408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Talbot v. General Television Corporation Pty. Ltd.</ital>, [1981] R.P.C. 1 (S.C. Vict.), at p. 18</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7450d728e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175930" w-seq-number="00015" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="1998460288" w-pub-number="0003591" ID="I50aa84508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Apotex Fermentation Inc. v. Novopharm Ltd.</ital> (1998), 162 D.L.R. (4th) 111, [1998] 10 W.W.R. 455 (Man. C.A.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7450d738e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>4</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175930" w-seq-number="00016" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038729462" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I50aaab608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Husky Injection Molding Systems Ltd. v. Schad</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 6406, 2016 ONSC 2297 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7450d748e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>5</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175930" w-seq-number="00017" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038729462" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I50aaf9808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Husky Injection Molding Systems Ltd. v. Schad</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 6406, 2016 ONSC 2297 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>, at paras. 2–4.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7450d758e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>6</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175930" w-seq-number="00018" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038729462" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I50ab20908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Husky Injection Molding Systems Ltd. v. Schad</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 6406, 2016 ONSC 2297 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>, at para. 331.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id74534808e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>7</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175930" w-seq-number="00019" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038729462" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I50ab47a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Husky Injection Molding Systems Ltd. v. Schad</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 6406, 2016 ONSC 2297 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>, at para. 332.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id74534818e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>8</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175930" w-seq-number="00020" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2038729462" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I50ab6eb08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Husky Injection Molding Systems Ltd. v. Schad</ital>, 2016 CarswellOnt 6406, 2016 ONSC 2297 (Ont. S.C.J. [Commercial List])</cite.query>, at paras. 333, and 335.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id74534828e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>9</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175930" w-seq-number="00021" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036247282" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I50ab95c08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Grant v. Winnipeg Regional Health Authority</ital>, 2015 CarswellMan 224, 2015 MBCA 44</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id74534838e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>10</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175930" w-seq-number="00022" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036247282" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I50abbcd08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Grant v. Winnipeg Regional Health Authority</ital>, 2015 CarswellMan 224, 2015 MBCA 44</cite.query>, at paras. 1–2, 5 and 103.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id74534848e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>11</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175930" w-seq-number="00023" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036247282" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I50ac0af08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Grant v. Winnipeg Regional Health Authority</ital>, 2015 CarswellMan 224, 2015 MBCA 44</cite.query>, at paras. 116–121.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7455b908e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>12</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175930" w-seq-number="00024" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036247282" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I50ac32008e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Grant v. Winnipeg Regional Health Authority</ital>, 2015 CarswellMan 224, 2015 MBCA 44</cite.query>, at paras. 122 and 125.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7455b918e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>13</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175930" w-seq-number="00025" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036247282" w-pub-number="0005478" ID="I50ac59108e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Grant v. Winnipeg Regional Health Authority</ital>, 2015 CarswellMan 224, 2015 MBCA 44</cite.query>, at paras. 126–128.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7455b928e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>14</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175930" w-seq-number="00026" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036903081" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I50ac80208e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Chamberlain Architect Services Ltd. v. Saplys</ital>, 2015 CarswellOnt 12403, 2015 ONSC 5145</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7455b938e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>15</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175930" w-seq-number="00027" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036903081" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I50aca7308e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Chamberlain Architect Services Ltd. v. Saplys</ital>, 2015 CarswellOnt 12403, 2015 ONSC 5145</cite.query>, at paras. 1–3, and 6.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7455b948e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>16</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175930" w-seq-number="00028" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036903081" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I50acce408e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Chamberlain Architect Services Ltd. v. Saplys</ital>, 2015 CarswellOnt 12403, 2015 ONSC 5145</cite.query>, at paras. 9–10.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7455b958e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>17</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175930" w-seq-number="00029" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036903081" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I50acf5508e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Chamberlain Architect Services Ltd. v. Saplys</ital>, 2015 CarswellOnt 12403, 2015 ONSC 5145, at para. 11</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id7455b968e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>18</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175930" w-seq-number="00030" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2030578391" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I50ad1c608e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Canada (Attorney General) v. Rundle</ital>, 2013 CarswellOnt 5920, 2013 ONSC 2747</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id74582a08e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>19</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175930" w-seq-number="00031" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2030578391" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I50ad43708e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Canada (Attorney General) v. Rundle</ital>, 2013 CarswellOnt 5920, 2013 ONSC 2747</cite.query>, at paras. 3–4.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id74582a18e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>20</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175930" w-seq-number="00032" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2030578391" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I50ad6a808e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Canada (Attorney General) v. Rundle</ital>, 2013 CarswellOnt 5920, 2013 ONSC 2747</cite.query>, at paras. 24–33.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id74582a28e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>21</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175930" w-seq-number="00033" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036746571" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I50ad91908e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Teti v. Mueller Water Products Inc</ital>., 2015 CarswellOnt 11047, 2015 ONSC 4434</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175930" w-seq-number="00034" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036903203" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I50ad91938e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2015 CarswellOnt 12429, 2015 ONSC 5135</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Id74582a38e3111ea9d59caa7de6e97ac"><label.designator>22</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0492175930" w-seq-number="00035" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036746571" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I50adb8a08e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52"><ital>Teti v. Mueller Water Products Inc</ital>., 2015 CarswellOnt 11047, 2015 ONSC 4434</cite.query>, additional reasons <cite.query w-src-number="0492175930" w-seq-number="00036" w-ref-type="IC" w-serial-number="2036903203" w-pub-number="0005476" ID="I50adb8a38e3311ea8105c4ef24d07c52">2015 CarswellOnt 12429, 2015 ONSC 5135</cite.query>, at paras. 13–14, 26, and 29–31.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/><bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/><bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>ELL-THORBURNBI § 5:19<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
