<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Multidistrict Lit Man § 3:13<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Multidistrict Litigation Manual</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20190501"><bop/><bos/>May 2019 Update<eos/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><author.line><bop/><bos/><author>David F. Herr[<footnote.reference refid="If21dbb916b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">a0</footnote.reference>]</author><eos/><eop/></author.line><prop.head toc-guid="I97b7f560933b11da99e2b07024dacc26"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Part</label.name><label.designator>I.</label.designator><headtext>Handling Cases Before the Judicial Panel on Multidistrict Litigation</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I9f85f1c0933b11da99e2b07024dacc26"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>3.</label.designator><headtext>Powers of the Panel</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="I94eda904e1e311da9c26e67ca3b71335"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>3:13.</label.designator><headtext>Limitations on Panel&apos;s power—No power over state court cases</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Perhaps the most serious limitation on the Panel&apos;s power is its inability to facilitate coordinated or consolidated pretrial proceedings in actions that are pending in both state and federal courts. <eos/><bos/>The Panel has no authority over actions pending in state courts.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If21de2a06b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">1</footnote.reference>] This limitation on the Panel&apos;s authority is part of the inherently limited jurisdiction of federal courts and is therefore fundamentally inflexible.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If21de2a16b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">2</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In many cases coordination or consolidation of discovery between state and federal court actions would be very desirable, but the Panel is unable to implement transfer of the state actions. <eos/><bos/>The Panel may transfer a case pending in a federal court following removal from a state court.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If21e09b06b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">3</footnote.reference>] If the state actions are pending in a single state, however, the Panel can consider transfer of the federal actions to the appropriate federal district. <eos/><bos/>This does not mandate the coordination or consolidation of pretrial proceedings, but it does make it possible for the state and federal courts to coordinate the proceedings before them. <eos/><bos/>The Panel has considered this factor in selecting a transferee forum and has favored transfer to a district where coordination of state and federal actions can be effectively coordinated.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If21e09b16b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">4</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The inability to transfer state cases and limited, though hardly insignificant, effectiveness of voluntary coordination of cases and cooperation of the state and federal judiciary is one of recognized potential areas for court reform. <eos/><bos/>An expanded role for the Panel is cornerstone of many proposals.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If21e30c16b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">5</footnote.reference>] Despite a general trend toward restricting federal court subject matter jurisdiction, reformers have proposed amendment of the statute to establish federal court jurisdiction.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If21e30c26b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">6</footnote.reference>] Reform proposals have also included the Uniform Transfer of Litigation Act to transfer and coordinate cases pending in state court.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If21e30c36b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">7</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>One solution to this limitation on the Panel&apos;s ability to manage complex litigation is to make state court actions subject to federal court jurisdiction and to make removal to federal court easier. <eos/><bos/>Congress has turned to this approach in three significant instances. <eos/><bos/>In 2002 it passed both the Multiparty, Multiforum Trial Jurisdiction Act of 2002[<footnote.reference refid="If21e30c46b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">8</footnote.reference>] and the Terrorism Risk Insurance Act of 2002.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If21e57d06b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">9</footnote.reference>] Both statutes contain provisions that create jurisdiction in federal court over state court cases and both are designed for the specific purpose of allowing transfer by the Panel, while the latter is more vague on the details of venue and management of the actions once in federal court.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Multiparty, Multiforum Trial Jurisdiction Act of 2002, creates original federal jurisdiction over single event accidents from a single location in which there is minimal diversity between adverse parties (a defendant resides in one state and a substantial part of the accident occurs in another, or any two defendants reside in different states, or substantial parts of the accident occur in different states) and at least 75 persons have died. <eos/><bos/>This statute is similar to some of the earlier proposals, although the 75-death threshold is new. <eos/><bos/>Also new is a limitation on the federal court&apos;s jurisdiction: under <cite.query w-src-number="0304913961" w-seq-number="00009" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="28USCAS1369" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I531f10c06b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">§ 1369(b)</cite.query> the court must abstain if a substantial majority of all plaintiffs are citizens of a single state of which the “primary defendants” are residents and the claims will be governed by the laws of that state. <eos/><bos/>The statute requires the court where an action invoking jurisdiction under this section is pending to advise the Judicial Panel on Multidistrict Litigation. <eos/><bos/>Significantly, the statute also provides for removal of actions where jurisdiction under this statute would have existed when the action was commenced.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>This statute also creates an innovative approach to remand. <eos/><bos/>Section 1367(e)(3) provides for an order for remand when liability issues are determined in the court to which an action is removed or transferred by the Panel. <eos/><bos/>If remand is ordered, the remand order is stayed for 60 days to permit an appeal of the liability decision to the court having appellate jurisdiction over the remanding court; if an appeal is taken, then the remand order is stayed until the appeal is decided. <eos/><bos/>The statute also provides for national service of process in actions proceeding under section 1367.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Terrorism Risk Insurance Act of 2002 creates a federal cause of action for property damage, personal injury and death arising out of an act of terrorism. <eos/><bos/>The statute is invoked by a determination by the Secretary of the Treasury, <begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>“in concurrence with the Secretary of State and the Attorney General of the United States”<end.quote refid="QT_0001"/> that an act of terrorism has occurred. <eos/><bos/>Section 107(a)(2) provides that this federal action would preempt all state court action. <eos/><bos/>Section 107(a)(4) requires that the Judicial Panel on Multidistrict Litigation designate a single district court to hear the federal action or actions. <eos/><bos/>The statute gives the district court selected by the Panel the equivalent of national authority to issue process by deeming it to sit in all judicial districts in the United States. <eos/><bos/>This statute does not apply to pending actions, but only those relating to acts of terrorism occurring after its enactment.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Class Action Fairness Act of 2005 (“CAFA”) contains provisions similar to those in the Multiparty, Multiforum Trial Jurisdiction Act of 2002, although it will undoubtedly have greater impact. <eos/><bos/>The 2002 law applies only to cases involving 75 or more deaths from a single event or tort problem; the 2005 legislation applies to class actions in any substantive area where $5,000,000 is involved.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext> CAFA significantly expanded the practical usefulness of Panel transfer by creating federal jurisdiction over certain state court class actions with only minimal diversity requirements, allowing them to be brought in federal court, and thus subject to transfer under § 1407. <eos/><bos/>Additionally, it provides for an expanded power to remove class actions from state court, including relaxed requirements on when removal may be sought. <eos/><bos/>The Act also creates new requirements for notice to state and federal regulatory officials, for review of coupon settlements, and for review of attorneys&apos; fees. <eos/><bos/>These substantive provisions are not discussed here.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If21e7ee06b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">10</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>One very important impact of CAFA is to broaden the reach of the Panel. <eos/><bos/>Once class actions are filed or removed to federal court, transfer under <cite.query w-src-number="0304913961" w-seq-number="00013" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="28USCAS1407" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I53226c206b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">28 U.S.C.A. § 1407</cite.query> becomes an available case management option. <eos/><bos/>One curious limitation in the Act relates to its application to “mass actions.” <eos/><bos/>A “mass action” is defined by the Act to be an action in which the claims brought by 100 or more plaintiffs are proposed to be tried jointly.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If21e7ee16b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">11</footnote.reference>] The statute allows mass actions to be treated like class actions for the purpose of removal, subject to certain limitations,[<footnote.reference refid="If21ea5f06b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">12</footnote.reference>] but explicitly mandates that such a removed action <begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>“shall not thereafter be transferred to any other court pursuant to <cite.query w-src-number="0304913961" w-seq-number="00016" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="28USCAS1407" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I532811706b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">section 1407</cite.query>, or the rules promulgated thereunder, unless a majority of the plaintiffs in the action request transfer pursuant to <cite.query w-src-number="0304913961" w-seq-number="00017" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="28USCAS1407" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I532811716b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">section 1407</cite.query>.”<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0002"/>[<footnote.reference refid="If21ea5f16b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">13</footnote.reference>] The anomalous result of this provision is that conflicting federal court class actions would be transferred to a single federal district court for coordinated or consolidated pretrial proceedings, but a mass action or mass actions filed in state courts and thereafter removed would have to remain in the original district. <eos/><bos/>The statute does not limit transfer of mass actions pursuant to <cite.query w-src-number="0304913961" w-seq-number="00019" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="28USCAS1404" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I5328d4c06b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">28 U.S.C.A. § 1404(a)</cite.query>, however, and it does not prevent the court from ordering severance and separate filing of these actions if they involve improper joinder under federal law.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The impact of CAFA is hard to assess. <eos/><bos/>Most of the reported decisions have dealt with questions of applicability and jurisdiction, and relatively few class actions have been settled and subjected to its substantive provisions. <eos/><bos/>The Federal Judicial Center&apos;s September 2006 report on The Impact of the Class Action Fairness Act of 2005 [available for download in PDF format at http://www.fjc.gov/public/pdf.nsf/lookup/cafa0906.pdf/$file/cafa0906.pdf] concludes there has been a substantial increase in class action activity in federal courts, both in original filings and removals. <eos/><bos/>This report does not specifically address any impact on the Panel&apos;s caseload or effectiveness, though if more class actions are pending in the federal courts, presumably the Panel will have greater ability to assist in managing those cases. <eos/><bos/>The Federal Judicial Center has continued to study the impact of CAFA on class actions.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If21ea5f26b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">14</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></section.body></section><author.footnotes><footnote ID="If21dbb916b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>a0</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Maslon Edelman Borman &amp; Brand, LLP, Minneapolis, Minnesota.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></author.footnotes><footnote.block><footnote ID="If21de2a06b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304913961" w-serial-number="1975105005" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000344" ID="I5316d3616b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">In re Celotex Corp. “Technifoam” Products Liability Litigation, 68 F.R.D. 502 (J.P.M.L. 1975)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If21de2a16b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>For a more thorough discussion of the constitutional and statutory limitations on the powers of the federal courts, see 13 to <cite.query w-src-number="0304913961" w-serial-number="0104500917" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="TS" w-pub-number="0102228" ID="I531748906b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">14C <csc>Charles Alan Wright, Arthur R. Miller &amp; Edward H. Cooper, Federal Practice and Procedure</csc> §§ 3501</cite.query> to <cite.query w-src-number="0304913961" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="ER" w-normalized-cite="14CFPPs3800" w-pub-number="0102228" ID="I531748916b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">3800 (3rd ed. 1998, 4th ed. 2011 &amp; Supp. 2018)</cite.query>; <csc>David F. Herr, Roger S. Haydock &amp; Jeffrey W. Stempel, Motion Practice</csc>§ 10.1 (8th ed. 2018).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If21e09b06b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304913961" w-serial-number="1969100254" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="1405" ID="I5317e4d16b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">In re Antibiotic Drugs, 299 F. Supp. 1403, 1405 (J.P.M.L. 1969)</cite.query>; <ital>see also</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304913961" w-serial-number="1970115313" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="927" ID="I5317e4d36b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">In re IBM, 319 F. Supp. 926, 927 (J.P.M.L. 1970)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If21e09b16b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>4</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>This factor, and the Panel decisions relating to it, are discussed in greater detail in <cite.query w-ref-type="NA" w-normalized-cite="MDLITMANs6:13" w-pub-number="185218" ID="If21e30c06b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">§ 6:13</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If21e30c16b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>5</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See</ital> William W Schwarzer, Alan Hirsch &amp; Edward Sussman, <cite.query w-src-number="0304913961" w-serial-number="0105556662" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="LR" w-pub-number="0001251" ID="I531944616b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8"><ital>Judicial Federalism: A Proposal to Amend the Multidistrict Litigation Statute to Permit Discovery Coordination of Large-Scale Litigation Pending in State and Federal Courts</ital>, 73 <csc>Tex. L. Rev.</csc> 1529 (1995)</cite.query>; <csc>American Law Institute, Complex Litigation: Statutory Recommendations and Analysis</csc> (1994).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If21e30c26b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>6</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Multiparty, Multiforum Jurisidiction Act of 1993, H.R. 1100, 103rd Cong., 1st Sess. (1993).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If21e30c36b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>7</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Uniform Transfer of Litigation Act (1991).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If21e30c46b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>8</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Multiparty, Multiforum Trial Jurisdiction Act of 2002, <ital>codified as</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304913961" w-seq-number="00007" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="28USCAS1369" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I531af2106b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">28 U.S.C.A. § 1369</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If21e57d06b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>9</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Terrorism Risk Insurance Act of 2002, <cite.query w-seq-number="00008" w-ref-type="SL" w-normalized-cite="I818B7F17CE-A84E01833D5-81D193C8E4D" w-pub-number="1077005" ID="I531b8e516b3e11e9ac68aff86f85b2c9">Pub. L. 107-297</cite.query>, Nov. 26, 2002, 116 Stat. 2322.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If21e7ee06b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>10</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>These provisions, not related directly to the Panel, are discussed in greater detail in <cite.query w-seq-number="00010" w-ref-type="NA" w-normalized-cite="MCLANNs21.1" w-pub-number="0148162" ID="I5321f6f16b3e11e9ac68aff86f85b2c9"><csc>David F. Herr, Annotated Manual for Complex Litigation 4th</csc> §§ 21.1</cite.query> (new notice requirements); <cite.query w-seq-number="00011" w-ref-type="NA" w-normalized-cite="MCLANNs20.32" w-pub-number="0148162" ID="I5321f6f36b3e11e9ac68aff86f85b2c9">20.32</cite.query> (jurisdiction and removal of class actions); <cite.query w-seq-number="00012" w-ref-type="NA" w-normalized-cite="MCLANNs21.6" w-pub-number="0148162" ID="I53221e016b3e11e9ac68aff86f85b2c9">21.6</cite.query> (review of coupon settlements); and 21.7 (review of attorneys&apos; fees) (West 2019 ed.).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If21e7ee16b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>11</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0304913961" w-seq-number="00014" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="28USCAS1332" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I532293306b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">28 U.S.C.A. § 1332(d)(11)(B)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If21ea5f06b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>12</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304913961" w-seq-number="00015" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="28USCAS1332" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I5322e1506b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">28 U.S.C.A. § 1332(d)(11)(A)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If21ea5f16b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>13</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0304913961" w-seq-number="00018" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="28USCAS1332" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I53285f906b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">28 U.S.C.A. § 1332(d)(11)(C)(i)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If21ea5f26b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>14</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See, e.g</ital>., <cite.query w-src-number="0304913961" w-seq-number="00020" w-ref-type="LR" w-normalized-cite="FJC2008" w-pub-number="0101610" ID="I532a0d416b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">Emory G. Lee III &amp; Thomas E. Willging, et al., Impact of the Class Action Fairness Act on the Federal Courts (FJC 2008</cite.query>), available for download in PDF format at http://www.fjc.gov/public/pdf.nsf/lookup/cafa1108.pdf/$file/cafa1108.pdf</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Westlaw. © 2019 Thomson Reuters.  <eos/><bos/>No Claim to Orig. U.S. Govt. <eos/><bos/>Works.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>MDLITMAN § 3:13<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
