<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Multidistrict Lit Man § 5:56<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Multidistrict Litigation Manual</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20190501"><bop/><bos/>May 2019 Update<eos/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><author.line><bop/><bos/><author>David F. Herr[<footnote.reference refid="If4c730b16b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">a0</footnote.reference>]</author><eos/><eop/></author.line><prop.head toc-guid="I97b7f560933b11da99e2b07024dacc26"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Part</label.name><label.designator>I.</label.designator><headtext>Handling Cases Before the Judicial Panel on Multidistrict Litigation</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="Id8e3eb20933b11da99e2b07024dacc26"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>5.</label.designator><headtext>Factors in Deciding Whether Transfer Is Appropriate</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="I94f34e57e1e311da9c26e67ca3b71335"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>5:56.</label.designator><headtext>Timing of transfer decision</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Panel may consider the timing of other events in the litigation in determining when to consider a transfer motion or when to issue a decision on it. <eos/><bos/>The reasons for the Panel&apos;s considering the timing of action by it are myriad. <eos/><bos/>Some of the reasons are never articulated by the Panel. <eos/><bos/>Clearly the Panel can act very promptly on motions for transfer, and has done so in cases where the issues appear pressing.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4c757c06b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">1</footnote.reference>] The promptness or delay in issuing decisions is never overtly discussed either in the decisions or in subsequent opinions. <eos/><bos/>The Panel has not had any noted breaches of confidentiality of its staff, so there appears to be little material from which to speculate on specific timing decisions of the Panel in using its decisions.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4c757c16b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">2</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Panel has stated in its decisions, however, reasons for delaying hearings on transfer motions. <eos/><bos/>The Panel has stayed proceedings before it indefinitely until certain class action determinations could be free of appellate review, whether by appeal or writ.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4c757c26b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">3</footnote.reference>] The Panel has also refrained from deciding the question of transfer as to one defendant until the court of appeals could consider an appeal from a consolidation order entered by the transferor court.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4c77ed06b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">4</footnote.reference>] The Panel ordered transfer of the claims against that party as soon as the court of appeals ruled.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4c77ed16b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">5</footnote.reference>] In another case the Panel determined, after the hearing on a motion to transfer, to stay Panel action while the parties continued in settlement discussions.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4c77ed26b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">6</footnote.reference>] The stay was of limited duration, and the Panel then ordered transfer of the non-settled cases for coordinated or consolidated pretrial proceedings.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4c77ed36b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">7</footnote.reference>] The Panel has also stayed transfer of a single action until a pending motion to dismiss could be decided in the transferor court.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4c77ed46b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">8</footnote.reference>] The Panel has similarly stayed its decision on transfer pending appeal in one of the underlying actions.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4c77ed56b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">9</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Panel has also rejected a request that it postpone a decision on transfer until the transferor court could determine a motion to remand a matter to state court.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4c77ed66b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">10</footnote.reference>] That decision is consistent with the Panel&apos;s general practice of deferring to the transferee court on such matters. <eos/><bos/>The Panel&apos;s presumptive response to the pendency of motions is to order transfer and point out that the motions can be decided by the transferee court after transfer.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4c77ed76b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">11</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In one mass disaster case the Panel declined to order transfer because only a few of an inevitably larger number of actions had been filed, and the Panel determined that it was premature to decide the transfer question and to select a transferee district. <eos/><bos/>The Panel did make it clear, however, that its decision did not foreclose a later motion to transfer.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4c7a5e06b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">12</footnote.reference>] In another massive disaster case, however, the Panel ordered transfer after only a few of the expected thousands of cases had been filed.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4c7a5e26b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">13</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Panel has also delayed decision on transfer motions under <cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-seq-number="00016" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="28USCAS1407" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I8615f0c06b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">28 U.S.C.A. § 1407</cite.query> to transfer for pretrial proceedings in order to permit the courts in which the actions are then pending to determine motions for transfer under <cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-seq-number="00017" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="28USCAS1404" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I8615f0c16b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">28 U.S.C.A. § 1404(a)</cite.query> for all purposes.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4c7a5e36b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">14</footnote.reference>] This practice is not uniform, however, and the Panel has refused to delay its decision on this ground.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4c7ccf06b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">15</footnote.reference>] The Panel has generally declined to delay its decision on the transfer question until the transferor court could rule on a pending motion. <eos/><bos/>In one case the Panel declined to postpone its decision until the transferor court could decide a motion to remand to state court seven tag-along actions removed to federal court.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4c7ccf26b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">16</footnote.reference>] By a stronger argument, the pendency of multiple motions for transfer under <cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-seq-number="00024" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="28USCAS1404" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I861b47f06b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">§ 1404(a)</cite.query> militates strongly towards transfer.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4c7ccf36b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">17</footnote.reference>] The pendency of summary judgment motions or other dispositive motions in a transferor court will not generally result in postponement of a transfer hearing or decision, however.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4c7ccf46b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">18</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Panel has similarly stayed decision on the transfer question until an administrative agency could consider a request for relief similar to that sought in the civil actions.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4c7ccf56b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">19</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Panel ruled in 1975 that the automatic stay provisions of the bankruptcy laws[<footnote.reference refid="If4c7f4006b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">20</footnote.reference>] do not prevent it from ordering transfer of multidistrict litigation.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4c7f4016b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">21</footnote.reference>] The Panel stated in that case:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>Transfer of these actions under <cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-seq-number="00032" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="28USCAS1407" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I862337306b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">Section 1407</cite.query> in no way affects the operation of Bankruptcy Rule 401. <eos/><bos/>We are simply indicating the place where the pretrial proceedings of these actions will occur. <eos/><bos/>The question of the effect of the bankruptcy stay and any modification thereof is entirely a problem to be worked out by the transferee court, the bankruptcy court and the parties. <eos/><bos/>A <cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-seq-number="00033" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="28USCAS1407" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I862337316b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">Section 1407</cite.query> transfer will produce the salutary consequence of having a single judge coordinate these actions with the bankruptcy proceedings and thereby eliminate the possibility of inconsistent rulings.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0001"/>[<footnote.reference refid="If4c7f4026b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">22</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>As a general rule, however, the Panel does not hold up a ruling on a motion for transfer because of the expected or possible development in either the transferee or transferor court. <eos/><bos/>The Panel has, for example, refused to delay a decision on transfer to permit a party to seek summary judgment in the transferor court.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4c7f4036b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">23</footnote.reference>] The Panel has also determined that, in addition to having the power to transfer cases to permit the transferee judge to determine motions challenging personal and subject-matter jurisdiction,[<footnote.reference refid="If4c7f4046b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">24</footnote.reference>] it would exercise that power in the ordinary case.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4c81b116b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">25</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Clearly the Panel has a general preference not to delay transfer because of the pendency of a pretrial motion in the transferor court. <eos/><bos/>In some cases, the pendency of such a motion may give the transfer motion increased urgency since transfer would give the opportunity to expand the effect of a pretrial ruling. <eos/><bos/>In one group of patent cases the Panel considered the fact that a summary judgment motion was pending in one court and that such a motion was not ripe in any of the other actions. <eos/><bos/>This fact thus affected both the timing and the selection of a transferee district.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4c81b126b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">26</footnote.reference>] Where a motion is pending in one of many closely related cases, the Panel&apos;s reaction is not to delay transfer, but to order it, for the single motion can be given effect in multiple actions. <eos/><bos/>In one case the Panel stated:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>We see no reason for delaying our decision. <eos/><bos/>The New York and New Jersey actions are completely subsumed in the District of Columbia action and, a fortiori, common questions of fact exist among them. <eos/><bos/>Transfer under <cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-seq-number="00039" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="28USCAS1407" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I862951b06b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">Section 1407</cite.query> will ensure the prevention of duplicative discovery, regardless of the outcome of the dismissal motions and any subsequent maneuvering by the parties. <eos/><bos/>Moreover, the institution of coordinated or consolidated pretrial proceedings at this time will allow a single judge to consider all three actions and will thereby conserve judicial effort and prevent inconsistent rulings.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0002"/>[<footnote.reference refid="If4c81b156b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">27</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The number of actions pending may affect the Panel&apos;s decision regarding timing. <eos/><bos/>The Panel has declined to delay transfer in view of the fact that only five of many anticipated actions from a single disaster had been filed.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4c842206b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">28</footnote.reference>] The Panel did note that early transfer would facilitate the handling of later cases that it anticipated. <eos/><bos/>The Panel determined that sufficient facts about the probable litigation had developed to permit it to select an appropriate transferee district.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4c842216b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">29</footnote.reference>] A defendant once sought to delay transfer so that separate class action certification motions could be decided in six different potential transferor courts.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4c842226b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">30</footnote.reference>] The Panel has traditionally viewed multiple, potentially conflicting, class actions as a factor strongly favoring transfer,[<footnote.reference refid="If4c842236b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">31</footnote.reference>] and followed that policy in this case.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4c842256b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">32</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Panel has delayed transfer where a pending motion relates directly to the Panel&apos;s decision. <eos/><bos/>In one case a motion to retransfer a case pursuant to <cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-seq-number="00046" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="28USCAS1404" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I862c10d06b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">28 U.S.C.A. § 1404(a)</cite.query> was pending in the transferor court and all parties agreed to exclude that case from the Panel&apos;s consideration.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4c9a1b06b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">33</footnote.reference>] The Panel accepted this stipulation, but indicated that it might treat the action as a tag-along action if the retransfer motion were denied by the transferor court.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></section.body></section><author.footnotes><footnote ID="If4c730b16b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>a0</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Maslon Edelman Borman &amp; Brand, LLP, Minneapolis, Minnesota.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></author.footnotes><footnote.block><footnote ID="If4c757c06b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See, e.g.,</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-serial-number="1985107566" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" ID="I860f3a016b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Union Carbide Corp. Gas Plant Disaster at Bhopal, India in Dec., 1984, 601 F. Supp. 1035 (J.P.M.L. 1985)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4c757c16b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>There has not, for example, been any discussion in the press or public disclosures from the law clerks of the members of the Panel. <eos/><bos/><ital>Cf.</ital> <csc>Robert Woodward &amp; Scott Armstrong, The Brethren</csc> (1979) (United States Supreme Court Justices&apos; law clerks quoted at length on confidential matters).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4c757c26b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-serial-number="1969114852" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="249" ID="I861072816b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Concrete Pipe, 302 F. Supp. 244, 249 (J.P.M.L. 1969)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4c77ed06b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>4</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-serial-number="1973107520" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="1318" ID="I8610e7b16b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Nat. Student Marketing Litigation, 368 F. Supp. 1311, 1318 (J.P.M.L. 1972)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4c77ed16b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>5</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-serial-number="1973105452" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" ID="I861135d16b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re National Student Marketing Litigation, 358 F. Supp. 1303 (J.P.M.L. 1973)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4c77ed26b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>6</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-serial-number="1969100054" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="1340" ID="I8611ab016b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Admission Tickets, 302 F. Supp. 1339, 1340 (J.P.M.L. 1969)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4c77ed36b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>7</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-serial-number="1969100054" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="1340" ID="I8611f9216b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">302 F. Supp. at 1340–42</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4c77ed46b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>8</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-serial-number="1970103277" w-seq-number="00007" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="1344" ID="I861295616b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Kaehni Patent, 311 F. Supp. 1342, 1344 (J.P.M.L. 1970)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/><ital>See also</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-serial-number="2007906257" w-seq-number="00008" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0004637" ID="I861295636b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Medtronic, Inc., Implantable Defibrillators Products Liability Litigation, 408 F. Supp. 2d 1351 (J.P.M.L. 2005)</cite.query> (transfer ordered for all actions except for one, pending decision on motion to be decided shortly).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4c77ed56b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>9</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-serial-number="1970104203" w-seq-number="00009" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" ID="I86130a916b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Motor Vehicle Air Pollution Control Equipment, 311 F. Supp. 1349 (J.P.M.L. 1970)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4c77ed66b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>10</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-serial-number="1975106243" w-seq-number="00010" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="1095" ID="I8613cde16b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Franklin National Bank Securities Litigation, 393 F. Supp. 1093, 1095 (J.P.M.L. 1975)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/><ital>See also</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-serial-number="2014605292" w-seq-number="00011" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0004637" ID="I8613cde36b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re American Home Mortg. Securities Litigation, 528 F. Supp. 2d 1376 (J.P.M.L. 2007)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-serial-number="2008986108" w-seq-number="00012" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0004637" ID="I8613cde56b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Marsh &amp; McLennan Companies, Inc., Securities Litigation, 429 F. Supp. 2d 1376 (J.P.M.L. 2006)</cite.query> (Panel declines to defer decision on motion for transfer despite pending motion before transferor court).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4c77ed76b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>11</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See, e.g.</ital>, <cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-serial-number="2009567310" w-seq-number="00013" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000999" ID="I86146a216b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">People of New York v. Guidant Corp, 2006 WL 1984688 (J.P.M.L. 2006)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4c7a5e06b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>12</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-serial-number="1972105063" w-seq-number="00014" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="756" ID="I861506616b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Air Crash Disaster at Anchorage, Alaska on November 27, 1970, 342 F. Supp. 755, 756 (J.P.M.L. 1972)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>The finality of Panel decisions on transfer is discussed in greater detail in <cite.query w-ref-type="NA" w-normalized-cite="MDLITMANs5:59" w-pub-number="185218" ID="If4c7a5e16b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">§ 5:59</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4c7a5e26b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>13</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-serial-number="1985107566" w-seq-number="00015" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" ID="I86157b916b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Union Carbide Corp. Gas Plant Disaster at Bhopal, India in Dec., 1984, 601 F. Supp. 1035 (J.P.M.L. 1985)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4c7a5e36b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>14</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-serial-number="1970116046" w-seq-number="00018" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" ID="I86163ee16b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Deering Milliken Patent, 328 F. Supp. 504 (J.P.M.L. 1970)</cite.query>; <ital>see also</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-serial-number="2004373861" w-seq-number="00019" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0004637" ID="I86163ee36b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Oxycontin Antitrust Litigation, 314 F. Supp. 2d 1388 (J.P.M.L. 2004)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4c7ccf06b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>15</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-serial-number="2009751431" w-seq-number="00020" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0004637" ID="I8618afe16b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re H &amp; R Block, Inc., Express IRA Marketing Litigation, 444 F. Supp. 2d 1339 (J.P.M.L. 2006)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-serial-number="1972104531" w-seq-number="00021" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="1277" ID="I8618afe36b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Trade Secrets in Mfg. High Molecular Weight Polyethylene, 339 F. Supp. 1276, 1277 n.2 (J.P.M.L. 1972)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>The Panel&apos;s treatment of motions under <cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-seq-number="00022" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="28USCAS1404" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I8618afe46b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">section 1404(a)</cite.query> generally is discussed in <cite.query w-ref-type="NA" w-normalized-cite="MDLITMANs5:49" w-pub-number="185218" ID="If4c7ccf16b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">§ 5:49</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4c7ccf26b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>16</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-serial-number="1973105921" w-seq-number="00023" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="1407" ID="I86194c216b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Air Crash Disaster at Juneau, Alaska, on September 4, 1971, 360 F. Supp. 1406, 1407 (J.P.M.L. 1973)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4c7ccf36b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>17</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-serial-number="2004341806" w-seq-number="00025" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0004637" ID="I861bbd216b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Union Pacific Railroad Co. Employment Practices Litigation, 314 F. Supp. 2d 1383 (J.P.M.L. 2004)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4c7ccf46b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>18</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-serial-number="2004341694" w-seq-number="00026" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0004637" ID="I861c32516b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Zyprexa Products Liability Litigation, 314 F. Supp. 2d 1380 (J.P.M.L. 2004)</cite.query>; <ital>see</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-serial-number="1990057258" w-seq-number="00027" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000350" ID="I861c32536b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Ivy, 901 F.2d 7 (2d Cir. 1990)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4c7ccf56b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>19</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-serial-number="1971104459" w-seq-number="00028" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="1015" ID="I861cce916b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Air Fare Litigation, 322 F. Supp. 1013, 1015 (J.P.M.L. 1971)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4c7f4006b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>20</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See</ital> R. <eos/><bos/><cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-seq-number="00029" w-ref-type="ES" w-normalized-cite="USFRBPR401" w-pub-number="1000611" ID="I861d43c06b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">Bankr. P. 401</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-seq-number="00030" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="11USCAS362" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I861d43c16b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">11 U.S.C.A. § 362 (1982)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4c7f4016b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>21</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-serial-number="1975106243" w-seq-number="00031" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="1095" ID="I861d91e16b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Franklin National Bank Securities Litigation, 393 F. Supp. 1093, 1095 (J.P.M.L. 1975)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4c7f4026b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>22</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-serial-number="1975106243" w-seq-number="00034" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="1095" ID="I86235e416b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">393 F. Supp. at 1095–96</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4c7f4036b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>23</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-serial-number="1973107469" w-seq-number="00035" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="807" ID="I862421916b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Holiday Magic Securities and Antitrust Litigation, 368 F. Supp. 806, 807 (J.P.M.L. 1973)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/><ital>Accord</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-serial-number="1981114874" w-seq-number="00036" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="1227" ID="I862421936b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Data General Corp. Antitrust Litigation, 510 F. Supp. 1220, 1227 (J.P.M.L. 1979)</cite.query> (transfer not delayed for pending motion to dismiss for failure to state a claim); <cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-serial-number="1979102646" w-seq-number="00037" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="1301" ID="I862421956b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Cement and Concrete Antitrust Litigation, 465 F. Supp. 1299, 1301 (J.P.M.L. 1979)</cite.query> (same).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4c7f4046b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>24</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The power of the Panel to transfer actions regardless of the pendency of motions to dismiss for lack of jurisdiction in the transferor court is discussed in <cite.query w-ref-type="NA" w-normalized-cite="MDLITMANs5:40" w-pub-number="185218" ID="If4c81b106b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">§ 5:40</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4c81b116b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>25</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Panel&apos;s willingness to have the transferee court decide pretrial motions is discussed in Chapter 9.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4c81b126b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>26</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-serial-number="1974106796" w-seq-number="00038" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="795" ID="I8625cf416b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Molinaro/Catanzaro Patent Litigation, 380 F. Supp. 794, 795 (J.P.M.L. 1974)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>The possible role of this factor in selection of a transferee district is discussed in §§ <cite.query w-ref-type="NA" w-normalized-cite="MDLITMANs5:27" w-pub-number="185218" ID="If4c81b136b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">5:27</cite.query> and  <cite.query w-ref-type="NA" w-normalized-cite="MDLITMANs6:21" w-pub-number="185218" ID="If4c81b146b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">6:21</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4c81b156b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>27</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-serial-number="1975106614" w-seq-number="00040" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="1403" ID="I862978c16b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Griseofulvin Antitrust Litigation, 395 F. Supp. 1402, 1403 (J.P.M.L. 1975)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4c842206b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>28</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-serial-number="1975108219" w-seq-number="00041" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="479" ID="I862a15016b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Air Crash Disaster Near Saigon, South Vietnam, on April 4, 1975, 404 F. Supp. 478, 479 (J.P.M.L. 1975)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4c842216b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>29</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-seq-number="00042" w-ref-type="ER" w-normalized-cite="404FS479" w-pub-number="0000345" ID="I862a8a316b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">404 F. Supp. 479 n.1</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4c842226b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>30</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-serial-number="1975108590" w-seq-number="00043" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="1403" ID="I862aff616b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Piper Aircraft Distribution System Antitrust Litigation, 405 F. Supp. 1402, 1403 (J.P.M.L. 1975)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/><ital>Accord</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-serial-number="1976128147" w-seq-number="00044" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="507" ID="I862aff636b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Bristol Bay, Alaska, Salmon Fishery Antitrust Litigation, 424 F. Supp. 504, 507 (J.P.M.L. 1976)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4c842236b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>31</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The role of conflicting class actions as a factor favoring transfer is discussed in <cite.query w-ref-type="NA" w-normalized-cite="MDLITMANs5:24" w-pub-number="185218" ID="If4c842246b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">§ 5:24</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4c842256b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>32</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-serial-number="1975108590" w-seq-number="00045" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="1403" ID="I862bc2b16b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">405 F. Supp. at 1403–04</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4c9a1b06b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>33</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304914058" w-serial-number="1977125797" w-seq-number="00047" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" ID="I862c37e16b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Cenco Inc. Securities Litigation, 434 F. Supp. 1237, 1237–1238 (J.P.M.L. 1977)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Westlaw. © 2019 Thomson Reuters.  <eos/><bos/>No Claim to Orig. U.S. Govt. <eos/><bos/>Works.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>MDLITMAN § 5:56<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
