<n-docbody>
	<doc bill="Y">
		<content.metadata.block>
			<cmd.identifiers>
				<cmd.cites>
					<cmd.second.line.cite>
						<bop/>
						<bos/>Ga. Evidence § 3:6<eos/>
						<eop/>
					</cmd.second.line.cite>
				</cmd.cites>
			</cmd.identifiers>
		</content.metadata.block>
		<prop.block>
			<prop.head toc-guid="">
				<bop/>
				<bos/>
				<headtext>Agnor&apos;s Georgia Evidence</headtext>
				<eos/>
				<eop/>
			</prop.head>
			<content.metadata.block>
				<cmd.dates>
					<cmd.currency.default iso.d="20191101">
						<bop/>
						<bos/>November 2019 Update<eos/>
						<eop/>
					</cmd.currency.default>
				</cmd.dates>
			</content.metadata.block>
			<author.line>
				<bop/>
				<bos/>
				<author>Ana Marcela Rountree</author>
				<eos/>
				<eop/>
			</author.line>
			<prop.head toc-guid="I260dc1c0630a11eab5989292d3e01631">
				<bop/>
				<bos/>
				<label.name>Chapter</label.name>
				<label.designator>3.</label.designator>
				<headtext>Statutory Privileges</headtext>
				<eos/>
				<eop/>
			</prop.head>
		</prop.block>
		<message.block>
			<include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copr. (C) West 2005 No Claim to Orig. U.S. Govt. Works</include.copyright>
		</message.block>
		<section>
			<section.front>
				<doc.title toc-guid="Id71f2ccf682311ea83aee46e6decbb85">
					<head parent="doc.title">
						<bop/>
						<bos/>
						<label.name>§ </label.name>
						<label.designator>3:6.</label.designator>
						<headtext>Accountant-client privilege</headtext>
						<eos/>
						<eop/>
					</head>
				</doc.title>
			</section.front>
			<section.body>
				<para>
					<bop/>
					<bos/>
					<paratext>Georgia excludes from evidence communications between an accountant and client on grounds of public policy under <cite.query w-src-number="0287018103" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="GAST24-5-501" w-pub-number="1000468" ID="Ia50c1c9074d211eab2f0b920da2605c5">O.C.G.A. § 24-5-501(a)(9)</cite.query> and <cite.query w-src-number="0287018103" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="GAST43-3-29" w-pub-number="1000468" ID="Ia50c1c9174d211eab2f0b920da2605c5">O.C.G.A. § 43-3-29</cite.query> which provides:</paratext>
					<display.quote>
						<para>
							<paratext>
								<begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>(a) All statements, records, schedules, working papers, computer printouts, computer tapes, and memoranda made by a certified public accountant incident to, or in the course of, professional service to clients by such certified public accountant, except reports submitted by a certified public accountant to a client, shall be and remain the property of such certified public accountant and his or her partners, fellow shareholders, or fellow members of the firm, in the absence of an express agreement between such certified public accountant and his or her client to the contrary. <eos/>
								<bos/>No such statement, record, schedule, working paper, or memorandum shall be sold, transferred, or bequeathed, without the consent of the client or his or her personal representative or assignee, to anyone other than one or more surviving partners, fellow shareholders, or fellow members of the firm of such certified public accountant.<eos/>
								<bos/>
							</paratext>
						</para>
						<para>
							<paratext>(b) All communications between a certified public accountant or employee of such certified public accountant acting in the scope of such employment and the person for whom such certified public accountant or employee shall have made any audit or other investigation in a professional capacity and all information obtained by a certified public accountant or such an employee in his or her professional capacity concerning the business and affairs of clients shall be deemed privileged communications in all courts or in any other proceedings whatsoever; and no such certified public accountant or employee shall be permitted to testify with respect to any of such matters, except with the written consent of such person or client or such person&apos;s or client&apos;s legal representative; provided, however, that nothing in this subsection shall be construed as prohibiting a certified public accountant or such an employee from:</paratext>
						</para>
						<para>
							<paratext>(1) Disclosing any data required to be disclosed by the standards of the accounting profession in rendering an opinion on the presentation of financial statements or in making disclosure where the practices or diligence of the accountant in preparing, or in expressing an opinion upon, such financial statements are contested;</paratext>
						</para>
						<para>
							<paratext>(2) Disclosing any data when the practice of public accountancy by the accountant is being contested by or against the client for whom the practice of public accountancy was performed or any representative or assignee of such client;</paratext>
						</para>
						<para>
							<paratext>
								<?page no="61"?>(3) Disclosing any data to other certified public accountants or employees thereof in connection with practice reviews and ethics reviews sponsored by professional groups, the purpose of which reviews is to survey such accountant&apos;s business practices, audits, and work papers or to review ethical considerations concerning such accountant; or</paratext>
						</para>
						<para>
							<paratext>(4) Disclosing any data pertaining to an application, investigation by the board, or hearing on its behalf, so long as such data shall be received by the board in camera and shall not be disclosed to the public; and provided, further, that no disclosure provided for in this paragraph shall constitute a waiver of the privilege established in this subsection.<eos/>
								<bos/>
							</paratext>
						</para>
						<para>
							<paratext>(c) The proceedings of and data obtained through peer review or by the board pursuant to paragraph (3) of subsection (b) of this Code section shall not be subject to discovery or introduction into evidence in any civil action, except in a hearing before the board, against a certified public accountant for matters which are the subject of evaluation and review by such peer review or the board; and no individual who was in attendance at a meeting of such peer review or the board shall be permitted or required to testify in any such civil action, except in a hearing before the board, as to any evidence or the matters produced or presented during the proceedings of such peer review or the board or as to any findings, recommendations, evaluations, opinions, or actions of such peer review or the board or any members thereof; provided, however, that any information, documents, or records otherwise available from original sources shall not be construed as immune from discovery or use in any such civil action merely because they were presented during proceedings of such peer review or the board; and provided, further, that no individual who testifies before such peer review or the board or who is a member of such peer review or the board shall be prevented from testifying as to matters within his or her knowledge, provided that such witness may not be questioned regarding such witness&apos;s testimony before such peer review or the board or opinions formed by the witness as a result of such hearings of such peer review or the board.<eos/>
								<end.quote refid="QT_0001"/>
							</paratext>
						</para>
					</display.quote>
					<eop/>
				</para>
				<para>
					<bop/>
					<bos/>
					<paratext>The purpose of the privilege is to <begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>“insure an atmosphere wherein the client will transmit all relevant information to his accountant without fear of any future disclosure in subsequent litigation. <eos/>
						<bos/>Without an atmosphere of confidentiality, the client might withhold facts he considers unfavorable to This situation thus rendering the accountant powerless to adequately perform the services he renders.”<eos/>
						<bos/>
						<end.quote refid="QT_0002"/>[<footnote.reference refid="I7711fb1074d311ea92c4fb7908f1a7b5">1</footnote.reference>] In practice, the privilege is applied in much the same manner as the attorney-client privilege,[<footnote.reference refid="I7712222074d311ea92c4fb7908f1a7b5">2</footnote.reference>
						<?page no="62"?>] and the courts often look to cases interpreting the attorney-client privilege as a guide for applying the privilege to confidential communications with an accountant.[<eos/>
						<bos/>
						<footnote.reference refid="I7712493074d311ea92c4fb7908f1a7b5">3</footnote.reference>]</paratext>
					<eos/>
					<eop/>
				</para>
				<para>
					<bop/>
					<bos/>
					<paratext>No general accountant-client privilege exists under federal law.[<eos/>
						<bos/>
						<footnote.reference refid="I7712493174d311ea92c4fb7908f1a7b5">4</footnote.reference>]</paratext>
					<eos/>
					<eop/>
				</para>
			</section.body>
		</section>
		<footnote.block><?page no="61"?>
			<footnote ID="I7711fb1074d311ea92c4fb7908f1a7b5">
				<label.designator>1</label.designator>
				<footnote.body>
					<para>
						<bop/>
						<bos/>
						<paratext>See <cite.query w-src-number="0287018103" w-serial-number="1974129189" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="Ia50eb4a274d211eab2f0b920da2605c5">Gearhart v. Etheridge, 232 Ga. 638, 639–640, 208 S.E.2d 460 (1974)</cite.query>.<eos/>
						</paratext>
						<eop/>
					</para>
				</footnote.body>
			</footnote>
			<footnote ID="I7712222074d311ea92c4fb7908f1a7b5">
				<label.designator>2</label.designator>
				<footnote.body>
					<para>
						<bop/>
						<bos/>
						<paratext>See discussion, §§ <cite.query w-ref-type="DA" w-normalized-cite="GAEVIDENCES3:4" w-pub-number="160247" ID="I7712222174d311ea92c4fb7908f1a7b5">3:4</cite.query>,  <cite.query w-ref-type="DA" w-normalized-cite="GAEVIDENCES3:5" w-pub-number="160247" ID="I7712222274d311ea92c4fb7908f1a7b5">3:5</cite.query>
							<?page no="62"?>, supra.<eos/>
						</paratext>
						<eop/>
					</para>
				</footnote.body>
			</footnote>
			<footnote ID="I7712493074d311ea92c4fb7908f1a7b5">
				<label.designator>3</label.designator>
				<footnote.body>
					<para>
						<bop/>
						<bos/>
						<paratext>See <cite.query w-src-number="0287018103" w-serial-number="1985143267" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="Ia50f77f274d211eab2f0b920da2605c5">In re Hall County Grand Jury Proceedings, 175 Ga. App. 349, 333 S.E.2d 389 (1985)</cite.query>.<eos/>
						</paratext>
						<eop/>
					</para>
				</footnote.body>
			</footnote>
			<footnote ID="I7712493174d311ea92c4fb7908f1a7b5">
				<label.designator>4</label.designator>
				<footnote.body>
					<para>
						<bop/>
						<bos/>
						<paratext>In the matter of <cite.query w-src-number="0287018103" w-serial-number="1982143158" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000350" ID="Ia50fed2174d211eab2f0b920da2605c5">Matter of International Horizons, Inc., 689 F.2d 996, 11 Fed. R. Evid. Serv. 1772, 35 Fed. R. Serv. 2d 82 (11th Cir. 1982)</cite.query> (citing <cite.query w-src-number="0287018103" w-serial-number="1973126311" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000708" ID="Ia50fed2774d211eab2f0b920da2605c5">Couch v. U.S., 409 U.S. 322, 93 S. Ct. 611, 34 L. Ed. 2d 548 (1973)</cite.query>).<eos/>
						</paratext>
						<eop/>
					</para>
				</footnote.body>
			</footnote>
		</footnote.block>
		<content.metadata.block>
			<cmd.royalty>
				<cmd.copyright>
					<bop/>
					<bos/>Westlaw. © 2019 Thomson Reuters.  <eos/>
					<bos/>No Claim to Orig. U.S. Govt. <eos/>
					<bos/>Works.<eos/>
					<eop/>
				</cmd.copyright>
			</cmd.royalty>
			<cmd.identifiers>
				<cmd.cites>
					<cmd.first.line.cite>
						<bop/>
						<bos/>GAEVIDENCE § 3:6<eos/>
						<eop/>
					</cmd.first.line.cite>
				</cmd.cites>
			</cmd.identifiers>
		</content.metadata.block>
	</doc>
</n-docbody>
