<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Ga. Evidence § 7:6<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Agnor&apos;s Georgia Evidence</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20191101"><bop/><bos/>November 2019 Update<eos/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><author.line><bop/><bos/><author>Ana Marcela Rountree</author><eos/><eop/></author.line><prop.head toc-guid="I2774a4c0630a11eab5989292d3e01631"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>7.</label.designator><headtext>Lay and Expert Opinion Testimony</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copr. (C) West 2005 No Claim to Orig. U.S. Govt. Works</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Id71fa1e7682311ea83aee46e6decbb85"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>7:6.</label.designator><headtext>Qualification of expert witnesses</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Any witness with such skill, knowledge or experience in a field or calling as to be able to draw an inference that could not be drawn by the average layman may be qualified as an expert. <eos/><bos/>In <cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="2028572526" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="RT" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15a69af27fc011ea988285db8533e975"><ital>Humphrey v. Riley,</ital></cite.query>[<footnote.reference refid="Ic3b52b207fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">1</footnote.reference>] the Georgia Supreme Court upheld the trial court&apos;s exclusion of expert testimony from the defense psychologist regarding police interrogation tactics leading to false confessions because false confession theory had not reached a “verifiable stage of scientific certainty” and knowledge that the police may obtain false confessions was not beyond the “ken of the average juror.”<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>An expert&apos;s knowledge may be derived from books, experience, or a combination of both.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Ic3b52b217fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">2</footnote.reference>] In our specialized society, it is becom<page no="184"/>ing more necessary to secure a witness whose special expertise includes the particular question at issue.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Ic3b552307fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">3</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A witness&apos; qualification as an expert rests entirely in the sound discretion of the judge,[<footnote.reference refid="Ic3b552317fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">4</footnote.reference>] even when the witness himself questions his own expertise.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Ic3b552327fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">5</footnote.reference>] The Georgia Court of Appeals held in <cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="1986113439" w-seq-number="00019" w-ref-type="RT" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15ab7cf27fc011ea988285db8533e975"><ital>Howard v. State</ital></cite.query>[<footnote.reference refid="Ic3b552337fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">6</footnote.reference>] that a judge is not required to make a specific ruling that a witness is qualified to testify as an expert. <eos/><bos/>However, in <cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="1986125362" w-seq-number="00021" w-ref-type="RT" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15ac40427fc011ea988285db8533e975"><ital>Ingram v. State</ital></cite.query>,[<footnote.reference refid="Ic3b579407fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">7</footnote.reference>] the court stated that such a ruling was better practice because <begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>“Then all parties and the jury would know the character of the testimony, and, also, when the charge on expert opinion was given regarding its legal ramifications, there would be no mistake about what evidence the charge referred to.”<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0002"/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Whether a witness is qualified to render an opinion as an expert is a legal determination for the trial court and will not be disturbed on appeal absent manifest abuse of discretion.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Ic3b579417fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">8</footnote.reference>] In <cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="2014246426" w-seq-number="00024" w-ref-type="RT" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15ad9fd27fc011ea988285db8533e975"><ital>Spacht v. Troyer</ital></cite.query>, the Georgia Court of Appeals held that the trial court could address the issue of whether patient&apos;s expert witness was qualified as a “practicing expert” or “teaching expert” in deciding a motion to dismiss, based on an expert affidavit.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Ic3b579427fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">9</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>According to the court in <cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="1990066231" w-seq-number="00026" w-ref-type="RT" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15ae8a327fc011ea988285db8533e975"><ital>Jones v. State</ital></cite.query>, the decision of a trial court to qualify an expert witness will not be overturned <begin.quote ID="QT_0003"/>“unless the witness actually lacks the appropriate credentials or the judge applied the wrong criteria.”<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0003"/>[<footnote.reference refid="Ic3b579437fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">10</footnote.reference>] In <cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="1990066231" w-seq-number="00029" w-ref-type="RT" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15afe9c27fc011ea988285db8533e975"><ital>Jones,</ital></cite.query> the trial court permitted an ob/gyn resident, who had examined over 200 rape victims in a two-year period, to testify about her examination of a rape victim. <eos/><bos/>However, the trial court&apos;s decision in <cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="1964125516" w-seq-number="00030" w-ref-type="RT" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15afe9c57fc011ea988285db8533e975"><ital>Southern Ry. Co. v. Cabe</ital></cite.query>[<footnote.reference refid="Ic3b5a0507fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">11</footnote.reference>] to allow a civil engineer to testify about optical illusions was reversed because such testimony was outside his area of expertise.<eos/><page no="185"/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Georgia Court of Appeals reversed the trial court&apos;s denial of defendant&apos;s motion to dismiss a medical malpractice complaint in <cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="2029655531" w-seq-number="00033" w-ref-type="RT" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15b149527fc011ea988285db8533e975"><ital>Bacon Cnty. Hosp. &amp; Health Sys. v. Whitley</ital></cite.query>[<footnote.reference refid="Ic3b5a0517fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">12</footnote.reference>] because the trial court abused its discretion by finding a chiropractor qualified to testify about a physical therapist&apos;s standard of care when they were not members of the same profession. <eos/><bos/>Likewise, the Court of Appeals upheld the trial court&apos;s exclusion of expert testimony in a medical malpractice claim where the expert&apos;s testimony failed to comport with Georgia law regarding the standard of care because the expert&apos;s testimony did not differentiate between the care expected of a physician and that of a nurse.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Ic3b5a0527fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">13</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <ital>Smith v. Liberty Chrysler-Plymouth-Dodge, Inc.</ital>, an experienced mechanic was not qualified as an expert to render an opinion as to the cause of vehicle accident in connection with a motorist&apos;s suit against car dealership and car manufacturer because he had no experience in the area of accident reconstruction or in evaluating the circumstances surrounding catastrophic mechanical failure. <eos/><bos/>In that same case, a police officer who had received training in accident investigation in the police academy and who had trained as an apprentice automotive mechanic was not qualified as an expert to render an opinion as to the cause of the vehicle accident.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="1991179246" w-seq-number="00037" w-ref-type="RT" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15b393427fc011ea988285db8533e975"><ital>Morris v. Chandler Exterminators, Inc.</ital></cite.query>,[<footnote.reference refid="Ic3b5a0537fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">14</footnote.reference>] the Georgia Court of Appeals held that a neuropsychologist with a Ph.D. in clinical psychology was qualified to give opinion testimony that the plaintiff had suffered organic brain damage as a result of inhaling a certain pesticide because Georgia law allows psychologists to diagnose and treat the type of disorder suffered by the plaintiff and it would be incongruous to prohibit these health care providers from testifying concerning the cause of an affliction that they were allowed to treat. <eos/><bos/>The Georgia Supreme Court reversed, in <page no="186"/>part, holding that the witness&apos; opinions were too speculative and incompetent as to medical causation.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Ic3b5c7607fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">15</footnote.reference>] Subsequently, in <cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="1993202182" w-seq-number="00040" w-ref-type="RT" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15b519e27fc011ea988285db8533e975"><ital>Handy v. Speth</ital></cite.query>,[<footnote.reference refid="Ic3b5c7617fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">16</footnote.reference>] the Georgia Court of Appeals held that the trial court had properly excluded a neuropsychologist&apos;s expert testimony to the effect that a blow to the head was the organic cause of a psychological disorder because the witness was not qualified to provide opinion evidence about the organic cause of a mental disorder.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Following the enactment of former O.C.G.A. § 24-9-67.1 (now <cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-seq-number="00043" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="GAST24-7-702" w-pub-number="1000468" ID="I15b652607fc011ea988285db8533e975">O.C.G.A. §§ 24-7-702</cite.query> and <cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-seq-number="00044" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="GAST24-7-703" w-pub-number="1000468" ID="I15b652617fc011ea988285db8533e975">24-7-703</cite.query>), the Georgia Court of Appeals explained that, in medical malpractice actions, it is the expert witness&apos;s qualifications in the area of practice or specialty in which the expert is providing the opinion, rather than the defendant doctor&apos;s specialty or area of practice, that controls whether the trial court should allow the expert&apos;s testimony.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Ic3b5c7627fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">17</footnote.reference>] Thus, in <cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="2011127379" w-seq-number="00047" w-ref-type="RT" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15b73cc27fc011ea988285db8533e975"><ital>Mays v. Ellis</ital></cite.query>,[<footnote.reference refid="Ic3b5c7637fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">18</footnote.reference>] the fact that a physician testifying as an expert witness in a patient&apos;s medical malpractice action was not a specialist in the same area of practice or specialty as the defendant physician did not bar the expert from offering testimony in support of patient&apos;s claims, so long as the expert had actual professional knowledge and experience in the area of practice or specialty in which the opinion was to be given. <eos/><bos/>However, in <ital>Dubois v. Bentley,</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="Ic3b5ee707fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">19</footnote.reference>] the Supreme Court held that the standards for qualifying an expert witness under <cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-seq-number="00051" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="GAST24-7-702" w-pub-number="1000468" ID="I15b8c3607fc011ea988285db8533e975">O.C.G.A. § 24-7-702</cite.query> had not been properly applied in a medical malpractice suit where the expert had experience enough to establish a reliable basis for the opinions he proposed to render and an appropriate level of knowledge in performing the procedure that was performed. <eos/><bos/>The Court opined that statutory construction did not render the expert&apos;s testimony inadmissible where he had only performed the exact procedure once during the previous five years, but had used the same methodology and was familiar with the procedure and the implements used.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In an action brought by a patient who became infected with HIV while undergoing heart surgery, the trial court properly found that the patient&apos;s physician expert qualified to testify that <page no="187"/>the hospital was negligent in failing to implement a patient notification program and to maintain proper records regarding the patient&apos;s transfusion history. <eos/><bos/>Although the witness was not a blood bank expert, his testimony concerned the hospital&apos;s administrative performance rather than his professional medical duties and services and his testimony did not have to meet the more restrictive standard applicable when an expert is testifying regarding the acceptable standard of professional conduct in a medical malpractice case.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Ic3b5ee717fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">20</footnote.reference>] Likewise, the Court of Appeals reversed a grant of summary judgment where the trial court rejected expert testimony because the expert had not taught in his profession for at least three of the last five years as required by <cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-seq-number="00054" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="GAST24-7-702" w-pub-number="1000468" ID="I15b9fbe07fc011ea988285db8533e975">O.C.G.A. § 24-7-702(c)(2)(D)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>The Court of Appeals applied a plain meaning analysis to the statute and held that it only applies to the qualifications of experts in medical malpractice cases, but not in cases where plaintiffs allege simple negligence, negligence per se, wrongful death, intentional infliction of emotional distress, breach of contract, and negligent supervision and training.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Ic3b5ee727fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">21</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>For an expert to be qualified to give an opinion in a medical malpractice case, the witness must demonstrate that he has regularly engaged in the active practice of the specialty area in which the opinion is to be given with sufficient frequency to establish an appropriate level of knowledge in performing the procedure, diagnosing the condition, or rendering the treatment at issue.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Ic3b5ee737fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">22</footnote.reference>] In <cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="2017473140" w-seq-number="00057" w-ref-type="RT" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15bb34627fc011ea988285db8533e975"><ital>Dawson v. Leder</ital></cite.query>,[<footnote.reference refid="Ic3b5ee747fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">23</footnote.reference>] a physician witness was not qualified to render an expert opinion in a malpractice case about the defendant physician&apos;s conduct because the witness had never managed the airway of a patient who had undergone surgery similar to that which patient had undergone, had never performed a similar surgical procedure, and stated that postsurgical airway maintenance was generally performed by an anesthesiologist, which she was not.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A family practice physician who did not practice surgery lacked the requisite knowledge required to give an expert opinion on whether surgery was medically necessary in patient&apos;s battery action against a surgeon who chose to remove necrotic tissue from plaintiff&apos;s buttock while performing neck and shoulder surgery <page no="188"/>because the difficulty plaintiff experienced with intubation made another surgery risky.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Ic3b615807fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">24</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A pulmonologist was not qualified to testify as an expert regarding standard of care for obtaining informed consent for otolaryngeal surgery to treat patient&apos;s obstructive sleep apnea because pulmonologist had not performed surgeries like the one in question, obtained informed consent for similar surgeries, or performed surgeries that involved risks similar to those involved in patient&apos;s surgery.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Ic3b615817fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">25</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>A registered nurse was competent to provide expert opinion in medical malpractice action brought by patient against a medical center for alleged nerve injury resulting from steroid injection administered by certified medical assistant because witness was familiar with degree and skills required of medical staff in giving intramuscular injections and gave approximately three to five intramuscular injections per day.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Ic3b615827fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">26</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Ic3b52b207fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="2028572526" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15a6e9127fc011ea988285db8533e975">Humphrey v. Riley, 291 Ga. 534, 731 S.E.2d 740 (2012)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic3b52b217fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="1879007319" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000359" ID="I15a785517fc011ea988285db8533e975">Central R. Co. v. Mitchell, 63 Ga. 173, 1879 WL 2476 (1879)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="1934107029" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000710" ID="I15a785557fc011ea988285db8533e975">Carter v. Marble Products, 179 Ga. 122, 175 S.E. 480 (1934)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="0280312273" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="TS" w-pub-number="0134642" ID="I15a785567fc011ea988285db8533e975">McCormick on Evidence § 13 (6th ed.)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="1979127184" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15a7fa827fc011ea988285db8533e975">Hicks v. State, 149 Ga. App. 459, 254 S.E.2d 461 (1979)</cite.query>, an experienced vice squad police officer could testify as to the street meaning of <begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>“get a quickie for twenty dollars.”<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0001"/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="1982110561" w-seq-number="00007" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15a8bdd27fc011ea988285db8533e975">Sandford v. Howard, 161 Ga. App. 495, 288 S.E.2d 739 (1982)</cite.query>, an orthopedist could testify as to the proper standard of care in a malpractice action against a podiatrist. <eos/><bos/>However, the court in <cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="1985157866" w-seq-number="00008" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15a8bdd57fc011ea988285db8533e975">Bethea v. Smith, 176 Ga. App. 467, 336 S.E.2d 295 (1985)</cite.query>, considered <cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="1982110561" w-seq-number="00009" w-ref-type="RT" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15a8bdd87fc011ea988285db8533e975"><ital>Sandford v. Howard</ital></cite.query> an exception and held that a podiatrist was not qualified to testify as to the proper standard of care by an orthopedist.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Formal education is not a requisite to admission of expert testimony. <eos/><bos/><page no="184"/>The street value of drugs is more in the ken of an officer working on the street than a laboratory chemist. <eos/><bos/><cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="1994231941" w-seq-number="00010" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15a95a117fc011ea988285db8533e975">Kimbrough v. State, 215 Ga. App. 303, 450 S.E.2d 457 (1994)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic3b552307fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="1963126663" w-seq-number="00011" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15a9a8327fc011ea988285db8533e975">American Fire &amp; Cas. Co. v. Grizzle, 108 Ga. App. 496, 133 S.E.2d 400 (1963)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="1964125516" w-seq-number="00012" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15a9a8357fc011ea988285db8533e975">Southern Ry. Co. v. Cabe, 109 Ga. App. 432, 136 S.E.2d 438 (1964)</cite.query>.<eos/><page no="185"/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic3b552317fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>4</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-seq-number="00013" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="GAST24-1-104" w-pub-number="1000468" ID="I15aa6b807fc011ea988285db8533e975">O.C.G.A. § 24-1-104</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>A good discussion of the qualifications of an expert appears in <cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="1981108444" w-seq-number="00014" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15aa6b837fc011ea988285db8533e975">Hicks v. State, 157 Ga. App. 79, 276 S.E.2d 129 (1981)</cite.query>, and <cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="1981123551" w-seq-number="00015" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15aa6b867fc011ea988285db8533e975">Dennis v. State, 158 Ga. App. 142, 279 S.E.2d 275 (1981)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic3b552327fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>5</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="1973127442" w-seq-number="00016" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15aae0b27fc011ea988285db8533e975">Braswell v. Owen of Georgia, Inc., 128 Ga. App. 528, 197 S.E.2d 463 (1973)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="1974127980" w-seq-number="00017" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15aae0b57fc011ea988285db8533e975">Merrill v. State, 130 Ga. App. 745, 204 S.E.2d 632 (1974)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="1988014689" w-seq-number="00018" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15aae0b87fc011ea988285db8533e975">Askew v. State, 185 Ga. App. 282, 363 S.E.2d 844 (1987)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic3b552337fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>6</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="1986113439" w-seq-number="00020" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15aba4027fc011ea988285db8533e975">Howard v. State, 177 Ga. App. 589, 340 S.E.2d 212 (1986)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic3b579407fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>7</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="1986125362" w-seq-number="00022" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15ac67527fc011ea988285db8533e975">Ingram v. State, 178 Ga. App. 292, 342 S.E.2d 765 (1986)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic3b579417fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>8</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="2015565690" w-seq-number="00023" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15ad03927fc011ea988285db8533e975">McGuire Holdings, LLLP v. TSQ Partners, LLC, 290 Ga. App. 595, 660 S.E.2d 397 (2008)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic3b579427fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>9</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="2014246426" w-seq-number="00025" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15adedf27fc011ea988285db8533e975">Spacht v. Troyer, 288 Ga. App. 898, 655 S.E.2d 656 (2007)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic3b579437fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>10</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="1990066231" w-seq-number="00027" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15aeff627fc011ea988285db8533e975">Jones v. State, 194 Ga. App. 356, 390 S.E.2d 623 (1990)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>The trial court has broad discretion in accepting or rejecting an expert&apos;s qualifications, and its judgment will not be disturbed on appeal absent an abuse of discretion. <eos/><bos/><cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="2035710412" w-seq-number="00028" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15aeff657fc011ea988285db8533e975">Allen v. State, 296 Ga. 785, 770 S.E.2d 824 (2015)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic3b5a0507fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>11</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="1964125516" w-seq-number="00031" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15b010d27fc011ea988285db8533e975">Southern Ry. Co. v. Cabe, 109 Ga. App. 432, 136 S.E.2d 438 (1964)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>See <cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="1993178235" w-seq-number="00032" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" w-pinpoint-page="134" ID="I15b086027fc011ea988285db8533e975">Davis v. State, 209 Ga. App. 572, 434 S.E.2d 132, 134 (1993)</cite.query>, where the trial court committed reversible error in a criminal case charging defendant with possession of heroin with intent to distribute by allowing police officer to testify that the quantity of heroin in defendant&apos;s possession at the time of arrest was more than a person would possess for ordinary consumption. <eos/><bos/>The police officer was not qualified as an expert in narcotics use or investigation and the State did not attempt to lay a foundation, which would demonstrate that the officer was otherwise qualified to testify.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic3b5a0517fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>12</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="2029655531" w-seq-number="00034" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15b197727fc011ea988285db8533e975">Bacon County Hosp. &amp; Health System v. Whitley, 319 Ga. App. 545, 737 S.E.2d 328 (2013)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic3b5a0527fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>13</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="2041239574" w-seq-number="00035" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15b233b27fc011ea988285db8533e975">Everson v. Phoebe Sumter Medical Center, Inc., 341 Ga. App. 182, 798 S.E.2d 667 (2017)</cite.query>, <case.history>judgment rev&apos;d in part</case.history> on other grounds, <cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="2042886399" w-seq-number="00036" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15b233b57fc011ea988285db8533e975">302 Ga. 364, 806 S.E.2d 533 (2017)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic3b5a0537fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>14</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="1991179246" w-seq-number="00038" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15b3ba527fc011ea988285db8533e975">Morris v. Chandler Exterminators, Inc., 200 Ga. App. 816, 409 S.E.2d 677 (1991)</cite.query>.<eos/><page no="186"/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic3b5c7607fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>15</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="1992098143" w-seq-number="00039" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15b47da27fc011ea988285db8533e975">Chandler Exterminators, Inc. v. Morris, 262 Ga. 257, 416 S.E.2d 277 (1992)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic3b5c7617fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>16</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="1993202182" w-seq-number="00041" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15b540f27fc011ea988285db8533e975">Handy v. Speth, 210 Ga. App. 155, 435 S.E.2d 623 (1993)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Contrast <cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="1994089344" w-seq-number="00042" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15b58f127fc011ea988285db8533e975">Monk v. Dial, 212 Ga. App. 362, 441 S.E.2d 857 (1994)</cite.query> (psychologist&apos;s testimony about visual perception at night and deterioration with age did not involve matters reserved to medical experts).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic3b5c7627fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>17</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="2010695528" w-seq-number="00045" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15b679727fc011ea988285db8533e975">Canas v. Al-Jabi, 282 Ga. App. 764, 639 S.E.2d 494 (2006)</cite.query>, <case.history>judgment rev&apos;d on other grounds</case.history>, <cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="2013856110" w-seq-number="00046" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15b679757fc011ea988285db8533e975">282 Ga. 830, 653 S.E.2d 691 (2007)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic3b5c7637fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>18</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="2011127379" w-seq-number="00048" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15b78ae27fc011ea988285db8533e975">Mays v. Ellis, 283 Ga. App. 195, 641 S.E.2d 201 (2007)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>See also <cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="2042941048" w-seq-number="00049" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15b78ae57fc011ea988285db8533e975">Graham v. Reynolds, 343 Ga. App. 274, 807 S.E.2d 39 (2017)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic3b5ee707fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>19</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="2036682083" w-seq-number="00050" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15b84e327fc011ea988285db8533e975">Dubois v. Brantley, 297 Ga. 575, 775 S.E.2d 512 (2015)</cite.query>.<eos/><page no="187"/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic3b5ee717fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>20</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="2010695528" w-seq-number="00052" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15b986b27fc011ea988285db8533e975">Canas v. Al-Jabi, 282 Ga. App. 764, 639 S.E.2d 494 (2006)</cite.query>, <case.history>judgment rev&apos;d on other grounds</case.history>, <cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="2013856110" w-seq-number="00053" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15b986b57fc011ea988285db8533e975">282 Ga. 830, 653 S.E.2d 691 (2007)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic3b5ee727fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>21</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="2038390452" w-seq-number="00055" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15ba22f27fc011ea988285db8533e975">Blake v. KES, Inc., 336 Ga. App. 43, 783 S.E.2d 432 (2016)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic3b5ee737fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>22</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="2017473140" w-seq-number="00056" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15babf327fc011ea988285db8533e975">Dawson v. Leder, 294 Ga. App. 717, 669 S.E.2d 720 (2008)</cite.query>.<eos/><page no="188"/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic3b5ee747fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>23</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="2017473140" w-seq-number="00058" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15bb82827fc011ea988285db8533e975">Dawson v. Leder, 294 Ga. App. 717, 669 S.E.2d 720 (2008)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic3b615807fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>24</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="2016245354" w-seq-number="00059" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15bc1ec27fc011ea988285db8533e975">Long v. Natarajan, 291 Ga. App. 814, 662 S.E.2d 876 (2008)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic3b615817fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>25</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="2014144870" w-seq-number="00060" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15bc93f27fc011ea988285db8533e975">Nathans v. Diamond, 282 Ga. 804, 654 S.E.2d 121 (2007)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic3b615827fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>26</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017113" w-serial-number="2013161455" w-seq-number="00061" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I15bd30327fc011ea988285db8533e975">Allen v. Family Medical Center, P.C., 287 Ga. App. 522, 652 S.E.2d 173 (2007)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Westlaw. © 2019 Thomson Reuters.  <eos/><bos/>No Claim to Orig. U.S. Govt. <eos/><bos/>Works.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>GAEVIDENCE § 7:6<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
