<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Ga. Evidence § 9:22<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Agnor&apos;s Georgia Evidence</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20191101"><bop/><bos/>November 2019 Update<eos/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><author.line><bop/><bos/><author>Ana Marcela Rountree</author><eos/><eop/></author.line><prop.head toc-guid="I288e2b10630a11eab5989292d3e01631"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>9.</label.designator><headtext>Hearsay</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copr. (C) West 2005 No Claim to Orig. U.S. Govt. Works</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Id7208c48682311ea83aee46e6decbb85"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>9:22.</label.designator><headtext>Prior statements of a witness—Child sexual abuse victims</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The new Evidence Code addresses prior statements made by children describing acts of sexual contact; <cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="GAST24-8-820" w-pub-number="1000468" ID="I49c3d2807fc011ea988285db8533e975">O.C.G.A. § 24-8-820</cite.query> reads as follows:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>A statement made by a child younger than 16 years of age describing any act of sexual contact or physical abuse performed with or on such child by another or with or on another in the presence of such child shall be admissible in evidence by the testimony of the person to whom made if the proponent of such statement provides notice to the adverse party prior to trial of the intention to use such out-of-court statement and such child testifies at the trial, unless the adverse party forfeits or waives such statements, the person to whom the child made such statement is subject to cross-examination regarding the out-of-court statements.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0001"/></paratext></para></display.quote><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Prior to 1998, Georgia Courts recognized an exception to the hearsay rule for children who were the victims of sexual abuse or witnessed another child being sexually abused. <eos/><bos/>This exception allowed the child&apos;s out-of-court statements into evidence, even if the child did not testify. <eos/><bos/>In <cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="1998061927" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="RT" w-pub-number="0004087" ID="I49c4bce37fc011ea988285db8533e975"><ital>Woodard v. State,</ital></cite.query>[<footnote.reference refid="Ic55ebc707fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">1</footnote.reference>] the Georgia Supreme Court found that the portion of the Child Hearsay Statute, former O.C.G.A. § 24-3-16, that provided for the admission of hearsay statements by children who witness acts of molestation was unconstitutional under the Equal Protection Clauses of the state and federal constitutions. <eos/><bos/>The court reasoned that it created disparate categories of child molestation defendants, with some having to defend against more evidence than others with no rational basis for doing so.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In February 2012, the Georgia Supreme Court found in <cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2026992972" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="RT" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49c5f5627fc011ea988285db8533e975"><ital>Hatley v. State</ital></cite.query>[<footnote.reference refid="Ic55ee3807fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">2</footnote.reference>] that the Georgia courts&apos; <ital>application</ital> of former O.C.G.A. § 24-3-16 was unconstitutional. <eos/><bos/>In <cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2026992972" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="RT" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49c754f27fc011ea988285db8533e975"><ital>Hatley,</ital></cite.query> police officers, forensic interviewers, and the victim&apos;s mother all testified about what the three-year-old victim had told them out of court. <eos/><bos/>Defendant <cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2026992972" w-seq-number="00007" w-ref-type="RT" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49c754f57fc011ea988285db8533e975"><ital>Hatley</ital></cite.query> objected that he never had the opportunity to confront his accuser in violation of his U.S. Sixth Amendment constitutional right. <eos/><bos/>The Georgia Supreme Court affirmed the lower court&apos;s de<page no="317"/>cision to admit into evidence the victim&apos;s testimony because her statement to her mother was nontestimonial.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Ic55ee3817fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">3</footnote.reference>] However, the court agreed that <cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2026992972" w-seq-number="00009" w-ref-type="RT" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49c8b4827fc011ea988285db8533e975"><ital>Hatley</ital></cite.query> should have been given the opportunity to object to the victim&apos;s testimony prior to or at trial. <eos/><bos/>The court established a procedural safeguard to protect the constitutional rights of defendants: (1) the prosecutor must notify the defendant within a reasonable period of time prior to trial of its intent to use a child victim&apos;s hearsay statements and give the defendant an opportunity to raise a Confrontation Clause objection; (2) if the defendant objects and the prosecutor wishes to introduce the statements under [former] O.C.G.A. § 24-2-16, the prosecutor must present the child witness at trial; (3) if the defendant does not object, the prosecutor can introduce the hearsay statements subject to the trial court&apos;s determination that the circumstances of the statements provide sufficient indicia of reliability; and (4) the trial court should take reasonable steps to ascertain, and put on the record, whether the defendant waives his right to confront the child witness.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Ic55ee3827fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">4</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2026992972" w-seq-number="00011" w-ref-type="RT" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49c9c5f27fc011ea988285db8533e975"><ital>Hatley</ital></cite.query> brought Georgia in line with the U.S. Supreme Court&apos;s interpretation of the Sixth Amendment&apos;s Confrontation Clause in <cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2019199714" w-seq-number="00012" w-ref-type="RT" w-pub-number="0000708" ID="I49c9c5f57fc011ea988285db8533e975"><ital>Melendez-Diaz v. Massachusetts.</ital></cite.query>[<footnote.reference refid="Ic55f0a907fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">5</footnote.reference>] In <cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2019199714" w-seq-number="00015" w-ref-type="RT" w-pub-number="0000708" ID="I49cafe727fc011ea988285db8533e975"><ital>Melendez-Diaz,</ital></cite.query> the accused objected to having notarized certificates from state laboratory analysts introduced at his drug trial as a violation of his right to confront his accusers. <eos/><bos/>The U.S. Supreme Court agreed stating that the sole purpose of the certificates was to provide prima facie evidence of the substance&apos;s composition, quality, and net weight and that the accused was entitled to be confronted with the persons giving this testimony at trial.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Ic55f0a917fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">6</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In June 2012, the Georgia Supreme Court overruled Woodard in <cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2027917283" w-seq-number="00017" w-ref-type="RT" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49cc0fe27fc011ea988285db8533e975"><ital>Bunn v. State,</ital></cite.query>[<footnote.reference refid="Ic55f0a927fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">7</footnote.reference>] finding that the <cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="1998061927" w-seq-number="00019" w-ref-type="RT" w-pub-number="0004087" ID="I49cd6f737fc011ea988285db8533e975"><ital>Woodard</ital></cite.query> court&apos;s reasoning on Equal Protection grounds could not be sustained. <eos/><bos/>Mr. Bunn moved in with his step-sister and was the primary after school caregiver for her daughters, aged nine and seven. <eos/><bos/>Both girls told their mother that the defendant touched and licked their private areas. <eos/><bos/>At trial, each victim testified about defendant&apos;s conduct toward her as well as what she witnesses him do to her sister. <eos/><bos/><page no="318"/>Also, a forensic therapist testified about what each child said about what she saw defendant do to the other child. <eos/><bos/>Defendant cross-examined each witness. <eos/><bos/>The court affirmed the lower court&apos;s decision to allow this testimony about what each child witnessed and to deny defendant&apos;s claim for ineffective assistance of counsel because his lawyer did not object to the testimony.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2027917283" w-seq-number="00020" w-ref-type="RT" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49cef6127fc011ea988285db8533e975"><ital>Bunn,</ital></cite.query> the court noted that the statutory language struck by the <cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="1998061927" w-seq-number="00021" w-ref-type="RT" w-pub-number="0004087" ID="I49cef6167fc011ea988285db8533e975"><ital>Woodard</ital></cite.query> court was omitted from the new Evidence Code and invited the General Assembly to restore it. <eos/><bos/><cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-seq-number="00022" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="GAST24-8-820" w-pub-number="1000468" ID="I49cef6177fc011ea988285db8533e975">O.C.G.A. § 24-8-820</cite.query> was enacted to address the child hearsay issues raised by <cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2026992972" w-seq-number="00023" w-ref-type="RT" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49cef61a7fc011ea988285db8533e975"><ital>Hatley</ital></cite.query> and <cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2027917283" w-seq-number="00024" w-ref-type="RT" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49cef61d7fc011ea988285db8533e975"><ital>Bunn.</ital></cite.query> Additionally, it raises the child&apos;s age from 13 to 16.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In order to introduce the statements, the state must put the witness on the stand to testify unless the defendant waives his right to confront the witness. <eos/><bos/>Interestingly, in March 2013, the Georgia Court of Appeals held in <cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2030184232" w-seq-number="00025" w-ref-type="RT" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49cfb9627fc011ea988285db8533e975"><ital>Maurer v. State</ital></cite.query>[<footnote.reference refid="Ic55f31a07fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">8</footnote.reference>] that a child witness who testifies at trial cannot be compelled to actually talk about the incident in question. <eos/><bos/>Further, a defendant&apos;s failure to object to the child&apos;s failure to testify about the alleged abuse waives his right of confrontation.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Ic55f31a17fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">9</footnote.reference>] In <cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2030699162" w-seq-number="00029" w-ref-type="RT" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49d0cad27fc011ea988285db8533e975"><ital>Walker v. State,</ital></cite.query>[<footnote.reference refid="Ic55f31a27fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">10</footnote.reference>] the Georgia Court of Appeals reaffirmed that defendant&apos;s right of confrontation is not violated when he waives his right to have a child victim testify and the child&apos;s hearsay statements are admitted into evidence. <eos/><bos/>The <cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2030699162" w-seq-number="00031" w-ref-type="RT" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49d1dc417fc011ea988285db8533e975"><ital>Walker</ital></cite.query> court exercised an abundance of caution in determining if defendant knowingly waived his right by bringing into the courtroom and allowing defense counsel to talk to her despite defense attestations that they did not want to speak to her or have her testify.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In order for the child hearsay statute to be applicable, the age of the child at the time the statements are made, not at the time the child testifies, must conform with the statutory scheme.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Ic55f31a37fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">11</footnote.reference>] The statute currently provides that the statement must be made by a child less than 16 years old. <eos/><bos/>While cases decided under the prior Code required that the trial court must determine that the child&apos;s out-of-court statements were sufficiently reliable. <eos/><bos/><cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="1991202834" w-seq-number="00033" w-ref-type="RT" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49d2c6a27fc011ea988285db8533e975"><ital>Gregg v. State</ital></cite.query>,[<footnote.reference refid="Ic55f31a47fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">12</footnote.reference>] the new statute contains no such requirements.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Ic55f58b07fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">13</footnote.reference>] Moreover, the permissibility of the statements rests on the statute in effect at <page no="319"/>the time the statements were made.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Ic55f58b17fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">14</footnote.reference>] If the hearsay statements are made after the child turns 16, they are inadmissible under the statute.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Ic55f58b27fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">15</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>It is reversible error for a judge to announce to the jury he has found the child&apos;s statements to be credible.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Ic55f58b37fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">16</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>It is sufficient that the reliability of the statement be apparent from the record. <eos/><bos/>The court need not hold a special hearing or make a specific finding of fact on the reliability of the child&apos;s out-of-court statement.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Ic55f58b47fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">17</footnote.reference>] Yet, in <cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2004581887" w-seq-number="00046" w-ref-type="RT" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49d75a827fc011ea988285db8533e975"><ital>Ferreri v. State</ital></cite.query>,[<footnote.reference refid="Ic55f58b57fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">18</footnote.reference>] the Georgia Court of Appeals held that a pretrial <cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="1991202834" w-seq-number="00048" w-ref-type="RT" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49d844e27fc011ea988285db8533e975"><ital>Gregg</ital></cite.query> hearing to determine whether the child victim&apos;s out-of-court statements had sufficient indicia of reliability was required given the evidence of tender age, inconsistent statements, coaching, involvement of law enforcement, the number of statements, and the fact that the child hearsay statements formed the bulk of the evidence against the defendant.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The United States Supreme Court has held that confrontation clause concerns are satisfied when a child testifies and can be adequately cross-examined.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Ic55f7fc07fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">19</footnote.reference>] The child is not deemed unavailable merely because he or she is incapable of reiterating the accusation at trial or is unresponsive or evasive during cross-examination. <eos/><bos/>In such cases, the jury must decide the child&apos;s credibility, taking into consideration the child&apos;s maturity and ability to withstand the pressure and intimidation of the courtroom environment.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Ic55f7fc17fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">20</footnote.reference>] However, a victim of child molestation who refused to take stand and could not be cross-examined was not “available” as required for admission of victim&apos;s statements to others concerning molestation.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Ic55f7fc27fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">21</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Child Hearsay statute applies only to statements made to the testifying witness and not merely overheard by the witness. <eos/><bos/><page no="320"/>Yet, in <cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2009645416" w-seq-number="00055" w-ref-type="RT" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49db04027fc011ea988285db8533e975"><ital>Brown v. State</ital></cite.query>,[<footnote.reference refid="Ic55f7fc37fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">22</footnote.reference>] an investigator&apos;s testimony about a child victim&apos;s statements to a forensic interviewer were admissible even though the statements were not made directly to the investigator. <eos/><bos/>The investigator overheard the statements while standing behind a two-way mirror when the child made the statements to the interviewer, and the victim was aware that the investigator was listening.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Ic55f7fc47fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">23</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>It is sufficient for the State to send an e-mail to counsel prior to trial that the state intends to use child hearsay pursuant to the statute. <eos/><bos/>The statute does not require a formal notice.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="Ic55fa6d07fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">24</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>In <cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2045678680" w-seq-number="00059" w-ref-type="RT" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49dcb1b27fc011ea988285db8533e975"><ital>State v. Almanza</ital></cite.query>,[<footnote.reference refid="Ic55fa6d17fc011eab41db41ad1c68132">25</footnote.reference>] while ruling on the admissibility of hearsay as part of medical diagnosis and treatment, the Supreme Court observed that the identity of an abuser may be allowed under two hearsay exceptions in the Code: statements made for purposes of medical treatment and diagnosis, and the child hearsay exception. <eos/><bos/>The two do not limit each other and provide separate avenues for admissibility of identity testimony.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></section.body></section><footnote.block><footnote ID="Ic55ebc707fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="1998061927" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0004087" ID="I49c50b037fc011ea988285db8533e975">Woodard v. State, 269 Ga. 317, 496 S.E.2d 896, 71 A.L.R.5th 787 (1998)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic55ee3807fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2026992972" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49c61c727fc011ea988285db8533e975">Hatley v. State, 290 Ga. 480, 722 S.E.2d 67 (2012)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>Note: The court did not find the statute itself unconstitutional.<eos/><page no="317"/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic55ee3817fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Under <cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2004190005" w-seq-number="00008" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000708" ID="I49c7a3127fc011ea988285db8533e975">Crawford v. Washington, 541 U.S. 36, 54, 124 S. Ct. 1354, 158 L. Ed. 2d 177, 63 Fed. R. Evid. Serv. 1077 (2004)</cite.query>, a witness must testify at trial if his statement falls within the “core class of testimonial statements” covered by the Confrontation Clause unless the defendant had a prior opportunity to cross-examine him.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic55ee3827fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>4</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2026992972" w-seq-number="00010" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49c8db927fc011ea988285db8533e975">Hatley v. State, 290 Ga. 480, 483, 722 S.E.2d 67 (2012)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic55f0a907fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>5</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2019199714" w-seq-number="00013" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000708" ID="I49ca3b227fc011ea988285db8533e975">Melendez-Diaz v. Massachusetts, 557 U.S. 305, 129 S. Ct. 2527, 174 L. Ed. 2d 314 (2009)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>See also <cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2004190005" w-seq-number="00014" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000708" ID="I49ca3b267fc011ea988285db8533e975">Crawford v. Washington, 541 U.S. 36, 124 S. Ct. 1354, 158 L. Ed. 2d 177, 63 Fed. R. Evid. Serv. 1077 (2004)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic55f0a917fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>6</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2019199714" w-seq-number="00016" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000708" ID="I49cb25827fc011ea988285db8533e975">Melendez-Diaz v. Massachusetts, 557 U.S. 305, 129 S. Ct. 2527, 174 L. Ed. 2d 314 (2009)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic55f0a927fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>7</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2027917283" w-seq-number="00018" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49cc36f27fc011ea988285db8533e975">Bunn v. State, 291 Ga. 183, 728 S.E.2d 569 (2012)</cite.query>.<eos/><page no="318"/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic55f31a07fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>8</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2030184232" w-seq-number="00026" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49d007827fc011ea988285db8533e975">Maurer v. State, 320 Ga. App. 585, 740 S.E.2d 318 (2013)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>Also see <cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2029863514" w-seq-number="00027" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49d007857fc011ea988285db8533e975">Estrada v. State, 319 Ga. App. 762, 738 S.E.2d 344 (2013)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic55f31a17fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>9</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2030184232" w-seq-number="00028" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49d07cb27fc011ea988285db8533e975">Maurer v. State, 320 Ga. App. 585, 740 S.E.2d 318 (2013)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic55f31a27fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>10</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2030699162" w-seq-number="00030" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49d118f27fc011ea988285db8533e975">Walker v. State, 322 Ga. App. 158, 744 S.E.2d 349 (2013)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic55f31a37fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>11</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2038521388" w-seq-number="00032" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49d22a627fc011ea988285db8533e975">Blackmon v. State, 336 Ga. App. 387, 785 S.E.2d 59 (2016)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic55f31a47fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>12</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="1991202834" w-seq-number="00034" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49d314c27fc011ea988285db8533e975">Gregg v. State, 201 Ga. App. 238, 411 S.E.2d 65 (1991)</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>See also <cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2009371019" w-seq-number="00035" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49d314c57fc011ea988285db8533e975">Nelson v. State, 279 Ga. App. 859, 632 S.E.2d 749 (2006)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic55f58b07fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>13</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2039787010" w-seq-number="00036" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49d362e27fc011ea988285db8533e975">McMurtry v. State, 338 Ga. App. 622, 791 S.E.2d 196 (2016)</cite.query>.<eos/><page no="319"/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic55f58b17fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>14</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2044763037" w-seq-number="00037" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49d3d8127fc011ea988285db8533e975">Blackwell v. State, 346 Ga. App. 833, 815 S.E.2d 288 (2018)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic55f58b27fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>15</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2045783524" w-seq-number="00038" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49d426327fc011ea988285db8533e975">Sullins v. State, 347 Ga. App. 628, 820 S.E.2d 468 (2018)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic55f58b37fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>16</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2004975532" w-seq-number="00039" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49d537a27fc011ea988285db8533e975">Starr v. State, 269 Ga. App. 466, 604 S.E.2d 297 (2004)</cite.query> (<case.history>overruled on other grounds by</case.history>, <cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2026992972" w-seq-number="00040" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49d537a57fc011ea988285db8533e975">Hatley v. State, 290 Ga. 480, 722 S.E.2d 67 (2012)</cite.query>).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic55f58b47fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>17</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2003490527" w-seq-number="00041" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49d5d3e27fc011ea988285db8533e975">Ingram v. State, 262 Ga. App. 304, 585 S.E.2d 211 (2003)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>See also <cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2009371019" w-seq-number="00042" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49d6be427fc011ea988285db8533e975">Nelson v. State, 279 Ga. App. 859, 632 S.E.2d 749 (2006)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2008373636" w-seq-number="00043" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49d6be457fc011ea988285db8533e975">Howell v. State, 278 Ga. App. 634, 629 S.E.2d 398 (2006)</cite.query> (<case.history>overruled on other grounds by</case.history>, <cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2026992972" w-seq-number="00044" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49d6be487fc011ea988285db8533e975">Hatley v. State, 290 Ga. 480, 722 S.E.2d 67 (2012)</cite.query>); <cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2010764278" w-seq-number="00045" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49d6be4b7fc011ea988285db8533e975">Johnson v. State, 283 Ga. App. 99, 640 S.E.2d 644 (2006)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic55f58b57fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>18</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2004581887" w-seq-number="00047" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49d781927fc011ea988285db8533e975">Ferreri v. State, 267 Ga. App. 811, 600 S.E.2d 793 (2004)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic55f7fc07fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>19</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2004190005" w-seq-number="00049" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000708" ID="I49d956527fc011ea988285db8533e975">Crawford v. Washington, 541 U.S. 36, 124 S. Ct. 1354, 158 L. Ed. 2d 177, 63 Fed. R. Evid. Serv. 1077 (2004)</cite.query>; see also <cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2008373636" w-seq-number="00050" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49d956587fc011ea988285db8533e975">Howell v. State, 278 Ga. App. 634, 629 S.E.2d 398 (2006)</cite.query> (<case.history>overruled on other grounds by</case.history>, <cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2026992972" w-seq-number="00051" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49d9565b7fc011ea988285db8533e975">Hatley v. State, 290 Ga. 480, 722 S.E.2d 67 (2012)</cite.query>).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic55f7fc17fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>20</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="1991028685" w-seq-number="00052" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49d9f2927fc011ea988285db8533e975">Bright v. State, 197 Ga. App. 784, 400 S.E.2d 18 (1990)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2010407108" w-seq-number="00053" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49d9f2957fc011ea988285db8533e975">In re S.S., 281 Ga. App. 781, 637 S.E.2d 151 (2006)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic55f7fc27fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>21</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2001243598" w-seq-number="00054" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49da67c27fc011ea988285db8533e975">Hines v. State, 248 Ga. App. 752, 548 S.E.2d 642 (2001)</cite.query>.<eos/><page no="320"/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic55f7fc37fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>22</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2009645416" w-seq-number="00056" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49db52227fc011ea988285db8533e975">Brown v. State, 280 Ga. App. 884, 635 S.E.2d 240 (2006)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic55f7fc47fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>23</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2009645416" w-seq-number="00057" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49dba0427fc011ea988285db8533e975">Brown v. State, 280 Ga. App. 884, 635 S.E.2d 240 (2006)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic55fa6d07fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>24</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2048414474" w-seq-number="00058" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49dc3c817fc011ea988285db8533e975">Adams v. State, 829 S.E.2d 412 (Ga. Ct. App. 2019)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="Ic55fa6d17fc011eab41db41ad1c68132"><label.designator>25</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0287017181" w-serial-number="2045678680" w-seq-number="00060" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000711" ID="I49dcffd27fc011ea988285db8533e975">State v. Almanza, 304 Ga. 553, 820 S.E.2d 1 (2018)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Westlaw. © 2019 Thomson Reuters.  <eos/><bos/>No Claim to Orig. U.S. Govt. <eos/><bos/>Works.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>GAEVIDENCE § 9:22<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
