<n-docbody>
	<doc bill="Y">
		<content.metadata.block>
			<cmd.identifiers>
				<cmd.cites>
					<cmd.second.line.cite>
						<bop/>
						<bos/>1 West&apos;s Fed. Forms, Supreme Court § 2 (5th ed.)<eos/>
						<eop/>
					</cmd.second.line.cite>
				</cmd.cites>
			</cmd.identifiers>
		</content.metadata.block>
		<prop.block>
			<prop.head toc-guid="">
				<bop/>
				<bos/>
				<headtext>West&apos;s Federal Forms</headtext>
				<eos/>
				<eop/>
			</prop.head>
			<prop.head toc-guid="I26ef4823c3ab11d9b108d818b64cc1e3">
				<bop/>
				<bos/>
				<headtext>Supreme Court</headtext>
				<eos/>
				<eop/>
			</prop.head>
			<content.metadata.block>
				<cmd.dates>
					<cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501">
						<bop/>
						<bos/>May 2020 Update<eos/>
						<eop/>
					</cmd.currency.default>
				</cmd.dates>
			</content.metadata.block>
			<author.line>
				<bop/>
				<bos/>
				<author>Bennett Boskey [<footnote.reference refid="I5e4878018ed411ea9f15a6eb8a891029">a0</footnote.reference>]</author>
				<eos/>
				<eop/>
			</author.line>
			<prop.head toc-guid="Iff2d8350843b11d98ec5912aed8d9ef1">
				<bop/>
				<bos/>
				<label.name>Part</label.name>
				<label.designator>I.</label.designator>
				<headtext>The Court</headtext>
				<eos/>
				<eop/>
			</prop.head>
			<prop.head toc-guid="Iff2e46a0843b11d98ec5912aed8d9ef1">
				<bop/>
				<bos/>
				<label.name>Chapter</label.name>
				<label.designator>1.</label.designator>
				<headtext>The Court and Its Offices</headtext>
				<eos/>
				<eop/>
			</prop.head>
		</prop.block>
		<message.block>
			<include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright>
		</message.block>
		<nav.links>
			<cite.query w-ref-type="DA" w-normalized-cite="1 FEDFORMS CH 1 REF" w-pub-number="124823" ID="I5e4e6b708ed411ea9f15a6eb8a891029">References</cite.query>
		</nav.links>
		<section>
			<section.front>
				<doc.title toc-guid="I26ef4823c3ab11d9b108d818b64cc1e3">
					<head parent="doc.title">
						<bop/>
						<bos/>
						<label.name>§ </label.name>
						<label.designator>2.</label.designator>
						<headtext>The Clerk&apos;s Office—General Comment</headtext>
						<eos/>
						<eop/>
					</head>
				</doc.title>
				<research.references>
					<reference.block>
						<bos/>
						<head style="l" parent="reference.block">
							<bop/>
							<headtext>West&apos;s Key Number Digest</headtext>
							<eop/>
						</head>
						<topic.key.ref>
							<bop/>
							<eos/>
							<bos/>West&apos;s Key Number Digest, <cite.query w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="KW" w-normalized-cite="79" ID="If414c6608ed211eaac6c889d7c4f9275">Clerks of Courts</cite.query>
							<n-private-char charName="TLRkey"></n-private-char>
							<cite.query w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="KW" w-normalized-cite="79k64.1" ID="If414c6618ed211eaac6c889d7c4f9275">64.1</cite.query> to <cite.query w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="KW" w-normalized-cite="79k72" ID="If414c6628ed211eaac6c889d7c4f9275">72</cite.query>
							<eos/>
							<eop/>
						</topic.key.ref>
					</reference.block>
					<reference.block>
						<bos/>
						<head style="l" parent="reference.block">
							<bop/>
							<headtext>Legal Encyclopedias</headtext>
							<eop/>
						</head>
						<reference>
							<bop/>
							<eos/>
							<bos/>
							<cite.query w-src-number="0112679999" w-serial-number="0289527608" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="TS" w-pub-number="0156440" ID="If41514808ed211eaac6c889d7c4f9275">C.J.S., Courts §§ 249</cite.query> to <cite.query w-src-number="0112679999" w-serial-number="0289527631" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="TS" w-pub-number="0156440" ID="If41514818ed211eaac6c889d7c4f9275">257</cite.query>
							<eos/>
							<eop/>
						</reference>
					</reference.block>
				</research.references>
			</section.front>
			<section.body>
				<para>
					<bop/>
					<bos/>
					<paratext>It is especially important in a work on forms to emphasize at the outset the role of the Supreme Court Clerk&apos;s Office in serving as the channel of communication between counsel and the Court.<eos/>
					</paratext>
					<eop/>
				</para>
				<para>
					<bop/>
					<bos/>
					<paratext>It is the Clerk&apos;s Office which receives all the papers to be filed with the Court and distributes them to the Justices at the appropriate time. <eos/>
						<bos/>It is the Clerk&apos;s Office which—subject to the direction and supervision of the Court—administers the Court&apos;s calendar and the Court&apos;s docket. <eos/>
						<bos/>Likewise, it is the Clerk&apos;s Office which maintains the Court&apos;s records and handles the collection of fees prescribed by the Court&apos;s Rules, the preparation of orders, judgments and mandates in conformity to the Court&apos;s directions, the taxing of costs, and many other comparable duties that are an essential part of the day-to-day activities in the work of the Court. <eos/>
						<bos/>Moreover, Rule 30.4 designates the Clerk as the one to act, in the first instance, on applications for extension of time, with the following four exceptions: applications for extension of time to file a petition for certiorari, to file a jurisdictional statement in an appeal, to file a reply brief on the merits, to file a petition for rehearing, and to issue a mandate. (<eos/>
						<bos/>These four exceptions are dealt with, respectively, in §§ <cite.query w-ref-type="NA" w-normalized-cite="WESTSFEDFORMSSUPREMECOURTs46" w-pub-number="212869" ID="I5e4ee0a08ed411ea9f15a6eb8a891029">46</cite.query>,  <cite.query w-ref-type="NA" w-normalized-cite="WESTSFEDFORMSSUPREMECOURTs244" w-pub-number="212869" ID="I5e4f07b08ed411ea9f15a6eb8a891029">244</cite.query>,  <cite.query w-ref-type="NA" w-normalized-cite="WESTSFEDFORMSSUPREMECOURTs374" w-pub-number="212869" ID="I5e5263108ed411ea9f15a6eb8a891029">374</cite.query> and  <cite.query w-ref-type="NA" w-normalized-cite="WESTSFEDFORMSSUPREMECOURTs544" w-pub-number="212869" ID="I5e528a208ed411ea9f15a6eb8a891029">544</cite.query>, infra.) <eos/>
						<bos/>Moreover, Rule 1.1 expressly states that the Clerk <begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>&quot;has authority to reject any submitted filing that does not comply with these Rules&quot;<end.quote refid="QT_0002"/>; and Rule 13.2 specifies that the Clerk <begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>&quot;will not file any petition for a writ of certiorari that is jurisdictionally out of time&quot;<end.quote refid="QT_0001"/> (see <cite.query w-ref-type="NA" w-normalized-cite="WESTSFEDFORMSSUPREMECOURTs45" w-pub-number="212869" ID="I5e53e9b08ed411ea9f15a6eb8a891029">§ 45</cite.query>, infra).<eos/>
					</paratext>
					<eop/>
				</para>
				<para>
					<bop/>
					<bos/>
					<paratext>Counsel will find the officials in the Clerk&apos;s Office an unfailing source of help and assistance in connection with questions and problems as to the Court&apos;s practice and procedure. <eos/>
						<bos/>Inquiries received from counsel—whether by telephone, by fax or by letter—are handled with a promptness, efficiency and courtesy which reflect a long tradition of outstanding public service. <eos/>
						<bos/>This is of special importance in a period like the present when, as indicated elsewhere throughout this work, the Court has tightened up considerably in requiring more literal compliance with its Rules, particularly those relating to the form of documents being submitted for filing. <eos/>
						<bos/>Much anguish, and sometimes much extra expense, can be avoided by timely prior consultation with the Clerk&apos;s Office.<eos/>
					</paratext>
					<eop/>
				</para>
				<para>
					<bop/>
					<bos/>
					<paratext>Rule 1.3 provides that the Office of the Clerk will be open except on a federal legal holiday, from 9:00 a.m. to 5:00 p.m., Monday through Friday, unless otherwise ordered by the Court or the Chief Justice. <eos/>
						<bos/>Thus, the Clerk&apos;s Office is closed on Saturdays. <eos/>
						<bos/>As a corollary, in the provisions governing computation of time, the Court has made it clear that if the last day of the period falls on a Saturday, a Sunday or a federal legal holiday, or day on which the Court building is closed by order, then the period extends until the end of the next day which is not a Saturday, a Sunday, a federal legal holiday, or a day on which the Court building is closed (Rule 30.1).<eos/>
						<bos/> Rules 1.3 and 30.1 cross-reference <cite.query w-src-number="0112679999" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="5USCAS6103" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="If42170908ed211eaac6c889d7c4f9275">5 U.S.C. § 6103</cite.query> for a list of federal holidays. <eos/>
						<bos/>
						<cite.query w-src-number="0112679999" w-seq-number="00007" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="5USCAS6103" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="If42170918ed211eaac6c889d7c4f9275">Section 6103(a)</cite.query> currently lists the following holidays: New Year&apos;s Day (January 1); Martin Luther King, Jr., birthday (3rd Monday in January); Washington&apos;s birthday (3rd Monday in February); Memorial Day (last Monday in May); Independence Day (July 4); Labor Day (1st Monday in September); Columbus Day (2nd Monday in October); Veterans Day (November 11); Thanksgiving Day (4th Thursday in November); Christmas Day (December 25).<eos/>
						<bos/>
						<cite.query w-src-number="0112679999" w-seq-number="00008" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="5USCAS6103" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="If42170928ed211eaac6c889d7c4f9275">Section 6103(c)</cite.query> states that the Presidential Inauguration Day, which occurs on January 20 every fourth year (or the next succeeding day if January 20 falls on a Sunday) is also a legal public holiday in the District of Columbia area. <eos/>
						<bos/>The Court&apos;s practice has been to be closed on Inauguration Day.<eos/>
					</paratext>
					<eop/>
				</para>
				<para>
					<bop/>
					<bos/>
					<paratext>It should also be noted that <cite.query w-src-number="0112679999" w-seq-number="00009" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="28USCAS452" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="If42233e08ed211eaac6c889d7c4f9275">28 U.S.C. § 452</cite.query> provides: <begin.quote ID="QT_0003"/>&quot;All courts of the United States shall be deemed always open for the purpose of filing proper papers, issuing and returning process, and making motions and orders.&quot;<eos/>
						<bos/>
						<end.quote refid="QT_0003"/> For some years it has been the practice at the Supreme Court that papers will be accepted for timely filing when physically delivered to the guard at the Supreme Court building after the regular office hours of the Clerk&apos;s Office, before midnight, on the last day available for filing.[<eos/>
						<bos/>
						<footnote.reference refid="I5e5410c08ed411ea9f15a6eb8a891029">1</footnote.reference>] When this is done, a receipt can be obtained from the guard, establishing the exact time of delivery, which then will be deemed the time of filing. <eos/>
						<bos/>Reliance on the possibility of such last-minute measures is a hazardous way to practice law. <eos/>
						<bos/>Yet in an emergency this may be far better than to risk having the Court lose jurisdiction of the case, or otherwise to decline to consider it, because of expiration of the time prescribed by law.[<eos/>
						<bos/>
						<footnote.reference refid="I5e5437d08ed411ea9f15a6eb8a891029">2</footnote.reference>] The Rules make available another last-minute alternative by providing in Rule 29.2 that mailing to the Clerk within the time allowed for filing will be deemed timely. <eos/>
						<bos/>See <cite.query w-ref-type="NA" w-normalized-cite="WESTSFEDFORMSSUPREMECOURTs45" w-pub-number="212869" ID="I5e56f6f08ed411ea9f15a6eb8a891029">§ 45</cite.query>, infra.<eos/>
					</paratext>
					<eop/>
				</para>
				<para>
					<bop/>
					<bos/>
					<paratext>In February 1993, the Clerk prepared and issued an informative document entitled <begin.quote ID="QT_0004"/>“Guide for Counsel in Cases to be Argued Before the Supreme Court of the United States.”<eos/>
						<bos/>
						<end.quote refid="QT_0004"/> The Clerk has subsequently issued new editions of this Guide to reflect changes in the Rules. <eos/>
						<bos/>This Guide, which is sent by the Clerk to counsel in cases the Court has accepted for oral argument, includes instructions and suggestions relating to matters such as the record; the joint appendix; the brief for petitioner; the brief for respondent; the reply brief; the supplemental brief; the amicus curiae brief; the argument; courtroom seating; the decisional process; and a list of pertinent telephone numbers of Court personnel. <eos/>
						<bos/>Instead of dividing the Guide into segments pertaining to particular sections of this work, it seems more helpful to print it in its entirety, as a unit, with references in particular sections to the fact that the Guide too should be consulted. <eos/>
						<bos/>Accordingly, the October 2019 edition of the Guide will be found as <cite.query w-ref-type="DA" w-normalized-cite="WESTSFEDFORMSSUPREMECOURTAPPB" w-pub-number="212869" ID="I5e571e008ed411ea9f15a6eb8a891029">Appendix B</cite.query>.<eos/>
					</paratext>
					<eop/>
				</para>
				<para>
					<bop/>
					<bos/>
					<paratext>With respect to the Clerk&apos;s authority under the Rules to act on applications for extensions of time in certain matters, see the Comment in <cite.query w-ref-type="NA" w-normalized-cite="WESTSFEDFORMSSUPREMECOURTs461" w-pub-number="212869" ID="I5e5745108ed411ea9f15a6eb8a891029">§ 461</cite.query>, infra.<eos/>
					</paratext>
					<eop/>
				</para>
				<para>
					<bop/>
					<bos/>
					<paratext>The Supreme Court has inherent supervisory authority over its clerk. <eos/>
						<bos/>As such, it is the right and duty of the Supreme Court to correct irregularities of its officer and compel the officer to perform the officer&apos;s duty. <eos/>
						<bos/>Because supervisory responsibility over its clerks is exclusive to the Supreme Court, neither a district court nor a circuit court of appeals has jurisdiction to interfere with that authority by mandamus or otherwise.[<eos/>
						<bos/>
						<footnote.reference refid="I5e5745118ed411ea9f15a6eb8a891029">3</footnote.reference>]</paratext>
					<eos/>
					<eop/>
				</para>
			</section.body>
		</section>
		<author.footnotes>
			<footnote ID="I5e4878018ed411ea9f15a6eb8a891029">
				<label.designator>a0</label.designator>
				<footnote.body>
					<para>
						<bop/>
						<bos/>
						<paratext>Washington D.C.</paratext>
						<eos/>
						<eop/>
					</para>
				</footnote.body>
			</footnote>
		</author.footnotes>
		<footnote.block>
			<footnote ID="I5e5410c08ed411ea9f15a6eb8a891029">
				<label.designator>1</label.designator>
				<footnote.body>
					<para>
						<bop/>
						<bos/>
						<paratext>Compare Stern, Gressman, Shapiro and Geller, Supreme Court Practice (7th ed.1993), pp. 277–278.<eos/>
						</paratext>
						<eop/>
					</para>
				</footnote.body>
			</footnote>
			<footnote ID="I5e5437d08ed411ea9f15a6eb8a891029">
				<label.designator>2</label.designator>
				<footnote.body>
					<para>
						<bop/>
						<bos/>
						<paratext>With respect to the limited classes of cases where the Court has sometimes treated the prescribed time limit for filing a petition for certiorari or an appeal as non-jurisdictional, and hence waivable by the Court in a clearly appropriate case, see §§ <cite.query w-ref-type="NA" w-normalized-cite="WESTSFEDFORMSSUPREMECOURTs45" w-pub-number="212869" ID="I5e5437d18ed411ea9f15a6eb8a891029">45</cite.query> and  <cite.query w-ref-type="NA" w-normalized-cite="WESTSFEDFORMSSUPREMECOURTs242" w-pub-number="212869" ID="I5e545ee08ed411ea9f15a6eb8a891029">242</cite.query>, infra.<eos/>
						</paratext>
						<eop/>
					</para>
				</footnote.body>
			</footnote>
			<footnote ID="I5e5745118ed411ea9f15a6eb8a891029">
				<label.designator>3</label.designator>
				<footnote.body>
					<para>
						<bop/>
						<bos/>
						<paratext>
							<cite.query w-src-number="0112679999" w-serial-number="2042096679" w-seq-number="00010" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0007903" ID="If42a71418ed211eaac6c889d7c4f9275">Fuller v. Harris, 258 F. Supp. 3d 204 (D.D.C. 2017)</cite.query>.<eos/>
						</paratext>
						<eop/>
					</para>
				</footnote.body>
			</footnote>
		</footnote.block>
		<content.metadata.block>
			<cmd.royalty>
				<cmd.copyright>
					<bop/>
					<bos/>Westlaw. © 2020 Thomson Reuters.  <eos/>
					<bos/>No Claim to Orig. U.S. Govt. <eos/>
					<bos/>Works.<eos/>
					<eop/>
				</cmd.copyright>
			</cmd.royalty>
			<cmd.identifiers>
				<cmd.cites>
					<cmd.first.line.cite>
						<bop/>
						<bos/>1 FEDFORMS § 2<eos/>
						<eop/>
					</cmd.first.line.cite>
				</cmd.cites>
			</cmd.identifiers>
		</content.metadata.block>
	</doc>
</n-docbody>
