<Document>
 <document-data>
  <collection>w_an_rcc_texts</collection> 
  <datetime>20120216154541</datetime> 
  <versioned>False</versioned> 
  <doc-type>Analytical Treatise  other</doc-type> 
  <doc-type-id>14</doc-type-id> 
  <cite>Immigr. Proc. Handbook § 2:15</cite> 
  <title>§ 2:15. Obtaining Form I-20 from the school</title> 
</document-data>
<n-metadata>
 <metadata.block>
 <md.identifiers>
 <md.cites>
  <md.first.line.cite>IMPH § 2:15</md.first.line.cite> 
  <md.second.line.cite>Immigr. Proc. Handbook § 2:15</md.second.line.cite> 
  <md.normalizedcite>IMPH§2:15</md.normalizedcite> 
  </md.cites>
 <md.westlawids>
  <md.dmsserial>283703869</md.dmsserial> 
  <md.case.slug>IMPH</md.case.slug> 
  <md.case.slug.code>10021</md.case.slug.code> 
  </md.westlawids>
  <md.uuid>Iff49dfd67c8f11da9de6e47d6d5aa7a5</md.uuid> 
  </md.identifiers>
 <md.sortkeys>
  <md.volsequence>IMPH</md.volsequence> 
  <md.ordersequence>0839000100540</md.ordersequence> 
  </md.sortkeys>
 <md.descriptions>
  <md.doc.family.uuid>Ief5ccfc4b3d611d8ab979fe6cf43003e</md.doc.family.uuid> 
  </md.descriptions>
 <md.dates>
  <md.publisheddate>20111028</md.publisheddate> 
  <md.revisiondate>20111101</md.revisiondate> 
  <md.currency.default>Database updated November 2011</md.currency.default> 
  <md.pubyear /> 
  <md.vol.year /> 
  </md.dates>
 <md.subjects>
 <md.subject>
 <md.keywords>
  <md.keyword>ADDTERM</md.keyword> 
  </md.keywords>
  <md.pubtype.name>WGR</md.pubtype.name> 
  <md.doctype.name>3A</md.doctype.name> 
  <md.doctype.rank>0022</md.doctype.rank> 
  <md.view>FE</md.view> 
  <md.view>INT</md.view> 
  <md.view>IMM</md.view> 
  <md.view>LAB</md.view> 
  <md.view>RTX</md.view> 
  <md.view>RTA</md.view> 
  <md.view>IMP</md.view> 
  </md.subject>
  </md.subjects>
 <md.jurisdictions>
 <md.jurisdiction>
  <md.jurisnum>2612</md.jurisnum> 
  <md.jurisstate>FE</md.jurisstate> 
  </md.jurisdiction>
  </md.jurisdictions>
 <md.publications>
 <md.publication>
  <md.pubid>135081</md.pubid> 
  <md.pubname>IMPH</md.pubname> 
  <md.pubpage>s 2:15</md.pubpage> 
  </md.publication>
 <md.publication>
  <md.pubid>135081</md.pubid> 
  <md.pubname>IMPH</md.pubname> 
  <md.pubpage>s 2:15</md.pubpage> 
  </md.publication>
 <md.publication>
  <md.pubid>999</md.pubid> 
  <md.pubname>WL</md.pubname> 
  <md.pubvolume>2001</md.pubvolume> 
  <md.pubpage>437091</md.pubpage> 
  </md.publication>
  <md.sourcepubid>135081</md.sourcepubid> 
  </md.publications>
 <md.royalty>
  <md.royalty.code>17267</md.royalty.code> 
  <md.copyright>Westlaw. © 2011 Thomson Reuters. No Claim to Orig. U.S. Govt. Works.</md.copyright> 
  </md.royalty>
  </metadata.block>
  <n-tocview>Iff49dfd57c8f11da9de6e47d6d5aa7a5 Ie0274b00675a11da90ebf04471783734 Idd2dba10675a11da90ebf04471783734 Ic96d44f0675a11da90ebf04471783734 I7b3ec600675a11da90ebf04471783734</n-tocview> 
  <n-view>FE</n-view> 
  <n-view>INT</n-view> 
  <n-view>IMM</n-view> 
  <n-view>LAB</n-view> 
  <n-view>RTX</n-view> 
  <n-view>RTA</n-view> 
  <n-view>IMP</n-view> 
  <prism-clipdate>20111028050928</prism-clipdate> 
  </n-metadata>
 <n-docbody>
 <doc bill="Y">
 <content.metadata.block>
 <cmd.identifiers>
 <cmd.cites>
 <cmd.second.line.cite>
  <bop /> 
  <bos /> 
  Immigr. Proc. Handbook § 2:15 
  <eos /> 
  <eop /> 
  </cmd.second.line.cite>
  </cmd.cites>
  </cmd.identifiers>
  </content.metadata.block>
 <prop.block>
 <prop.head toc-guid="">
  <bop /> 
  <bos /> 
  <headtext>Immigration Procedures Handbook</headtext> 
  <eos /> 
  <eop /> 
  </prop.head>
 <content.metadata.block>
 <cmd.dates>
 <cmd.currency.default iso.d="20111101">
  <bop /> 
  <bos /> 
  Database updated November 2011 
  <eos /> 
  <eop /> 
  </cmd.currency.default>
  </cmd.dates>
  </content.metadata.block>
 <author.line>
  <bop /> 
  <bos /> 
  <author>Austin T. Fragomen, Jr., Careen Shannon, and Daniel Montalvo</author> 
  <eos /> 
  <eop /> 
  </author.line>
 <prop.head toc-guid="Ic96d44f0675a11da90ebf04471783734">
  <bop /> 
  <bos /> 
  <label.name>Chapter</label.name> 
  <label.designator>2.</label.designator> 
  <headtext>The F Visa Category</headtext> 
  <eos /> 
  <eop /> 
  </prop.head>
 <prop.head toc-guid="Idd2dba10675a11da90ebf04471783734">
  <bop /> 
  <bos /> 
  <label.designator>III.</label.designator> 
  <headtext>Procedures For Obtaining F-1 Status</headtext> 
  <eos /> 
  <eop /> 
  </prop.head>
 <prop.head toc-guid="Ie0274b00675a11da90ebf04471783734">
  <bop /> 
  <bos /> 
  <label.designator>B.</label.designator> 
  <headtext>THE CERTIFICATE OF ELIGIBILITY AND PAYMENT OF SEVIS FEE</headtext> 
  <eos /> 
  <eop /> 
  </prop.head>
  </prop.block>
 <message.block>
  <include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Current through MR 11.27 11/17/2011</include.copyright> 
  </message.block>
 <nav.links>
  <cite.query w-ref-type="DA" w-normalized-cite="IMPHDMYREFCH2" w-pub-number="135162" ID="I8f0af750014411e184750000837bc6dd">References</cite.query> 
  </nav.links>
 <section>
 <section.front>
 <doc.title toc-guid="Iff49dfd57c8f11da9de6e47d6d5aa7a5">
 <head parent="doc.title">
  <bop /> 
  <bos /> 
  <label.name>§</label.name> 
  <label.designator>2:15.</label.designator> 
  <headtext>Obtaining Form I-20 from the school</headtext> 
  <eos /> 
  <eop /> 
  </head>
  </doc.title>
 <research.references ID="resrefIe028aa90675a11da90ebf04471783734">
 <reference.block>
  <bos /> 
 <head style="l" parent="reference.block">
  <bop /> 
  <headtext>West's Key Number Digest</headtext> 
  <eop /> 
  </head>
 <topic.key.ref>
  <bop /> 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  West's Key Number Digest, 
  <cite.query w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="KW" w-normalized-cite="24" ID="Id5bb8090014211e1b055a89deb9e3aa8">Aliens, Immigration, and Citizenship</cite.query> 
  <n-private-char charName="TLRkey">?</n-private-char> 
  <cite.query w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="KW" w-normalized-cite="24k193" ID="Id5bb8091014211e1b055a89deb9e3aa8">193</cite.query> 
  <eos /> 
  <eop /> 
  </topic.key.ref>
  </reference.block>
  </research.references>
  </section.front>
 <section.body>
 <para>
  <bop /> 
  <bos /> 
 <paratext>
  In order to obtain admission to the U.S. as a student, the alien must first be admitted to a school approved by the DHS to issue certificates of eligibility (Form I-20) to foreign students. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  The DHS requires that a school not issue a Form I-20 unless a student has made a 
  <bold>written</bold> 
  application to the school for admission, and has been accepted in the school. 
  <eos /> 
  </paratext>
  <eop /> 
  </para>
 <para>
  <bop /> 
  <bos /> 
 <paratext>
  Another prerequisite to issuance of the Form I-20 imposed by the DHS is that the school be assured of the student's proficiency in English, and of the financial resources of the student to pay for his or her educational program. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  Thus, the student usually needs to take an English language examination as a part of the application and admission process (often the TOEFL exam), and needs to present the school with financial data demonstrating his or her ability to meet academic and living expenses for at least the first 12-month period of the student's education. 
  <eos /> 
  </paratext>
  <eop /> 
  </para>
 <para>
  <bop /> 
  <bos /> 
 <paratext>
  Once the school has accepted the student, it can issue the Form I-20 to him or her, certifying that he or she is enrolled in an academic program consisting of a full course of study. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  The student plays no role in completing this form other than to sign it. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  Nevertheless, he or she should be familiar with its contents. 
  <eos /> 
  </paratext>
  <eop /> 
  </para>
 <para>
  <bop /> 
  <bos /> 
 <paratext>
 <bold>
  SEVIS-generated Forms I-20 mandatory. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  </bold>
  The use of the SEVIS-generated Form I-20 is mandatory for all students seeking F-1 student visas. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  Unless the school is enrolled in SEVIS, therefore, it will not be able to enroll foreign students. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  SEVIS is the electronic reporting system covering students and exchange visitors that was mandated by IIRIRA. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  The SEVIS tracking system is discussed in detail in 
  <cite.query w-ref-type="NA" w-normalized-cite="IMPHs2:33" w-pub-number="135081" ID="I8f0be1b0014411e184750000837bc6dd">§ 2:33</cite.query> 
  , below. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  When utilized, the SEVIS system itself generates the I-20 form that must be given to the student to take to the U.S. consulate abroad as evidence of eligibility to apply for a F-1 nonimmigrant visa. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  The designated school official must access the system and enter information electronically in order to create the Form I-20. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  Only SEVIS certificates of eligibility are recognized for visa issuance and admission purposes. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  Note also that spouses and minor children seeking F-2 status must individually present an original SEVIS Form I-20 issued in the name of each F-2 dependent. 
  <eos /> 
  </paratext>
  <eop /> 
  </para>
 <para>
  <bop /> 
  <bos /> 
 <paratext>
  The SEVIS Form I-20 has three pages. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  Information on the student's status is contained on Page 1. Page 2 contains instructions to the school and the student. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  Page 3 provides space for designated school official endorsements and for reportable events that occur during the student's period of stay. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  The form contains a two-dimensional (2D) bar code on the right hand corner of pages 1 and 3 of the form, with the word "SEVIS" printed above the bar code. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  Dependents are provided with their own SEVIS Form I-20. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  The student copy of the SEVIS Form I-20 should be endorsed and returned to the student. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  The SEVIS version of the form is illustrated below as Sample Form 2-1. 
  <eos /> 
  </paratext>
  <eop /> 
  </para>
 <para>
  <bop /> 
  <bos /> 
 <paratext>
  <bold>Pre-admission rules and importance of reasonable start date on Form I-20</bold> 
  . 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  Rules issued in December 2002 provide that an F-1 student may be admitted for a period up to 30 days before the indicated report date or start date listed on Form I-20. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  As a result, an F-1 visa cannot be issued to any applicant seeking to enter the U.S. more than 30 days prior to the designated start date. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  When determining the report date on Form I-20, however, the DSO may choose a start date to accommodate a student's need to be in attendance for required activities at the school prior to the actual start of classes. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  Such activities may include, for example, research projects and orientation sessions. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  In these cases, an F-1 visa may still be issued because the applicant is seeking to enter the U.S. within 30 days of the report date listed on Form I-20. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  Keep in mind that the DSO may not list a report date more than 30 days prior to the start of classes for purposes of employment. 
  <eos /> 
  </paratext>
  <eop /> 
  </para>
 <para>
  <bop /> 
  <bos /> 
 <paratext>
 <bold>
  Issuance of Form I-20 in concurrent enrollment situations. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  </bold>
  As discussed above, a student may be enrolled in two different schools at one time as long as the schools are Service-approved and the combined enrollment amounts to a full time course of study. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  In these cases, the school from which the student will earn his or her degree or certification should issue the Form I-20 and conduct subsequent certifications and updates to the Form I-20. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  The DSO from this school is also responsible for all of the reporting requirements to the Service under the SEVIS program. 
  <eos /> 
  </paratext>
  <eop /> 
  </para>
 <para>
  <bop /> 
  <bos /> 
 <paratext>
  <bold>SEVIS II to be implemented, new SEVIS forms and user accounts to be created</bold> 
  . 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  In May 2009, ICE announced that it will make several major enhancements to SEVIS in the next few years in an effort to address limitations in the original system. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  Once SEVIS II is fully deployed, ICE will retire the original SEVIS. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  All necessary data from the original system will be migrated to SEVIS II prior to the deployment of the first phase. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  Among other enhancements, SEVIS II will create an entirely paperless process for all activities related to the admission and tracking of F and J students and exchange visitors. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  Under SEVIS II, F and J nonimmigrants and school and sponsor officials will use digital signatures to sign electronic forms related to the student and exchange visitor process. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  DHS and State Department officials will also use SEVIS II (or a system that links to SEVIS II) to document electronically decisions about visa issuance, changes of status, entry into the U.S., and other requests for nonimmigrant benefits (including employment authorization). 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  In addition, SEVIS II will permit F and J nonimmigrants to create user accounts and directly access their own information. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  This feature of SEVIS II will allow F and J nonimmigrants to view information about their status, immigration benefits, and payment of SEVIS fees in real time and to request a change if any information is inaccurate. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  The new paperless version of SEVIS has not been deployed as of August 22, 2011. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  Until fully implemented, F and J visa applicants must present signed I-20 or DS-2019 forms. 
  <eos /> 
  </paratext>
  <eop /> 
  </para>
 <para>
  <bop /> 
  <bos /> 
 <paratext>
  While ICE has not scheduled an implementation date the agency has provided some information regarding the transition to SEVIS II in a document published in May 2011. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  The agency has indicated that the initial release of SEVIS II will have limited functionality. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  During this initial phase, the agency will migrate records from SEVIS I to SEVIS II. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  The agency has indicated that it will notify the stakeholders at least six months prior to the start of the initial phase which will last about six months. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  Schools will continue to maintain school and student information in SEVIS I during this initial phase but the DSOs will need to create SEVIS II accounts and provide updated school information. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  Finally, ICE stated that there will be a transition period during which students will still be able to use the paper Forms I-20. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  The length of the transition period has not been defined. 
  <eos /> 
  </paratext>
  <eop /> 
  </para>
 <head parent="section.body">
  <bop /> 
  <bos /> 
 <headtext>
  <bold>(a). Sample Form 2-1: SEVIS Form I-20</bold> 
  </headtext>
  <eos /> 
  <eop /> 
  </head>
 <image.block>
  <image.link target="Ie0435e80675a11da90ebf04471783734" /> 
  </image.block>
 <image.block>
  <image.link target="Ie043aca0675a11da90ebf04471783734" /> 
  </image.block>
 <image.block>
  <image.link target="Ie043fac0675a11da90ebf04471783734" /> 
  </image.block>
  </section.body>
  </section>
 <content.metadata.block>
 <cmd.royalty>
 <cmd.copyright>
  <bop /> 
  <bos /> 
  Westlaw. © 2011 Thomson Reuters. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  No Claim to Orig. U.S. Govt. 
  <eos /> 
  <bos /> 
  Works. 
  <eos /> 
  <eop /> 
  </cmd.copyright>
  </cmd.royalty>
 <cmd.identifiers>
 <cmd.cites>
 <cmd.first.line.cite>
  <bop /> 
  <bos /> 
  IMPH § 2:15 
  <eos /> 
  <eop /> 
  </cmd.first.line.cite>
  </cmd.cites>
  </cmd.identifiers>
  </content.metadata.block>
  </doc>
  </n-docbody>
  </Document>
  