<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Immigr. Proc. Handbook § 5:42<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Immigration Procedures Handbook</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20111101"><bop/><bos/>Database updated November 2011<eos/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><author.line><bop/><bos/><author>Austin T. Fragomen, Jr., Careen Shannon, and Daniel Montalvo</author><eos/><eop/></author.line><prop.head toc-guid="Id19775a0675b11da90ebf04471783734"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>5.</label.designator><headtext>The L-1 Visa Category</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I0900caf0675c11da90ebf04471783734"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>VI.</label.designator><headtext>Extensions And Other Post-Admission Issues</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I0901b550675c11da90ebf04471783734"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>A.</label.designator><headtext>Extensions of Stay</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA" n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg"/></message.block><nav.links><cite.query w-ref-type="DA" w-normalized-cite="IMPHDMYREFCH5" w-pub-number="135162" ID="Ic6a6af900bbe11e1b1520000837bc6dd">References</cite.query></nav.links><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="Iff5a5a9a7c8f11da9de6e47d6d5aa7a5"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>5:42.</label.designator><headtext>Papers required for extensions of stay</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title><research.references ID="resrefI145d1e30675c11da90ebf04471783734"><reference.block><bos/><head style="l" parent="reference.block"><bop/><headtext>West&apos;s Key Number Digest</headtext><eop/></head><topic.key.ref><bop/><eos/><bos/>West&apos;s Key Number Digest, <cite.query w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="KW" w-normalized-cite="24" ID="I37bb14300bbc11e1b1bf8ea888646160">Aliens, Immigration, and Citizenship</cite.query> <n-private-char charName="TLRkey"></n-private-char><cite.query w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="KW" w-normalized-cite="24k192" ID="I37bb14310bbc11e1b1bf8ea888646160">192</cite.query><eos/><eop/></topic.key.ref></reference.block></research.references></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Current procedures require the following papers be submitted for an L extension of stay: </paratext><tbl ID="I90db00f0fca511e0966982a28495d395"><table frame="all"><eos/><bos/><tgroup cols="2"><colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="1*"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="14*"/><tbody><row rowsep="1"><entry style="block">1.</entry><entry style="block"><bold>Form I-129 and L supplement,</bold> the petition form for nonimmigrant work categories</entry></row><row rowsep="1"><entry style="block">2.</entry><entry style="block">Copy of the <bold>approval notice of the initial petition</bold> (Form I-797)</entry></row><row rowsep="1"><entry style="block">3.</entry><entry style="block"><bold>Company letter</bold> in support of the extension request</entry></row><row rowsep="1"><entry style="block">4.</entry><entry style="block"><bold>Copy of Form I-94</bold> for the L alien (original need not be submitted)</entry></row><row rowsep="1"><entry style="block">5.</entry><entry style="block"><bold>Filing fee of $325</bold></entry></row><row rowsep="1"><entry style="block">6.</entry><entry style="block"><bold>Form I-539</bold> including all family members of the L alien</entry></row><row rowsep="1"><entry style="block">7.</entry><entry style="block"><bold>Copy of Form I-94</bold> for each family member (original need not be submitted)</entry></row><row rowsep="1"><entry style="block">8.</entry><entry style="block"><bold>Filing fee of $290</bold></entry></row><row rowsep="1"><entry style="block">9.</entry><entry style="block"><bold>Form I-907</bold> with premium processing fee of $1,225 (if premium processing is sought)</entry></row><row><entry style="block">10.</entry><entry style="block"><bold>Form G-28,</bold> the attorney notice of appearance (if the employer is represented by an attorney or representative)</entry></row></tbody></tgroup><eos/></table></tbl><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><bold>Application for employment authorization by L spouses</bold>. <eos/><bos/>Legislation enacted in 2002 provides work authorization for spouses of L-1 nonimmigrants. <eos/><bos/>USCIS guidelines provide that spouses seeking employment authorization must apply for an employment authorization document (EAD) on I-765. <eos/><bos/>Such applications may be submitted concurrently with the I-129/I-539 change of status package submitted by the L principal and family members. <eos/><bos/>The documents required to be submitted in connection with the EAD application are discussed in detail in <cite.query w-ref-type="NA" w-normalized-cite="IMPHs5:5" w-pub-number="135081" ID="Ic6a836300bbe11e1b1520000837bc6dd">§ 5:5</cite.query>, above.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><bold>Duplicate Form I-129 and supporting documents recommended to facilitate visa renewal</bold>. <eos/><bos/>Before nonimmigrant visas can be issued to beneficiaries of H, L, O, P, and Q petitions approval of the employer&apos;s underlying petition must first be verified through the Petition Information Management Service (PIMS).<eos/><bos/> In light of the PIMS requirement, it is also recommended that all L-1 petition packages include duplicate copies of the forms and supporting documents regardless of the type of action requested on the petition in Part 2, Item 4. Even if the beneficiary has no imminent plans to travel abroad, if there is any chance whatsoever that the beneficiary will need to obtain a visa at a U.S. consulate at any time after a change, extension, or petition amendment, it is advisable to file a duplicate petition to avoid later delays in visa issuance. <eos/><bos/>Under the new procedures, USCIS will send the duplicate copy to the KCC provided a duplicate copy is submitted by the petitioner. <eos/><bos/>If a duplicate copy is not sent, no data on the petition approval will be entered in PIMS leading to delays in verification. <eos/><bos/>Petitioners are encouraged to identify the duplicate petition with a brightly-colored cover sheet and to mark it with <begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>“Please send this copy to KCC upon approval.”<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0001"/> While the best practice is for all forms, including duplicates, to include original signatures, USCIS has confirmed that duplicate forms with photocopied signatures are also acceptable.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><bold>Form I-129 and Form I-539</bold>. <eos/><bos/>The extension of stay is sought on Form I-129 and L supplement, the same form used for the initial L-1 petition. <eos/><bos/>The form is illustrated as Sample Form 5-1 (<cite.query w-ref-type="NA" w-normalized-cite="IMPHs5:22" w-pub-number="135081" ID="Ic6a884500bbe11e1b1520000837bc6dd">§ 5:22</cite.query>), above. <eos/><bos/>A line-by-line analysis of the form follows the illustration and covers all uses of the form in L-1 cases (including use of the form to submit extension requests).<eos/><bos/> Form I-129 and L supplement need not be filed with supporting documentation when it is used for the extension of stay, unless there has been a change in the circumstances of employment. <eos/><bos/>Otherwise, only a letter from the employer needs to be submitted, describing the continuing employment.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Form I-539 must be used for the extension of stay of the principal L-1 alien&apos;s family members. <eos/><bos/>All family members may be included on one Form I-539. <eos/><bos/>Form I-539 for the family members must be filed concurrently with Form I-129 and L supplement. <eos/><bos/>The latest version of Form I-539 completed for family members of a work-category nonimmigrant is illustrated in <cite.query w-ref-type="NA" w-normalized-cite="IMPHs4:38" w-pub-number="135081" ID="Ic6a8d2700bbe11e1b1520000837bc6dd">§ 4:38</cite.query> (as Sample Form 4-5).<eos/><bos/> A line-by-line analysis of the form follows the illustration. <eos/><bos/>The annotation covers use of the form by family members of principal E, H, L, O, P, and TN nonimmigrants.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><bold>Standard filing fee.<eos/><bos/></bold> USCIS charges a standard filing fee, $325, for any I-129 filing, whether it is an initial petition, a change of status application, or an extension of stay application. <eos/><bos/>Family members must file a separate application, Form I-539, to request a change of status or extension. <eos/><bos/>The filing for this application is $290. <eos/><bos/>The $290 fee applies regardless of the number of co-applicants listed on the form.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><bold>Anti-fraud fee and <cite.query w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="SL" w-normalized-cite="IDD474D90A9-3611DFB1E7A-A5E642A0D53" w-pub-number="1077005" ID="I37c0e0910bbc11e1b380a9c70bea9a4d">Public Law 111-230</cite.query> fees not applicable</bold>. <eos/><bos/>All initial L-1 petitions for principal aliens must include payment of an additional $500 to cover an anti-fraud fee implemented by legislation enacted in December 2004. <eos/><bos/>Apart from the standard filing fee and the anti-fraud fee, a fee of $2,250 is required under <cite.query w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="SL" w-normalized-cite="IDD474D90A9-3611DFB1E7A-A5E642A0D53" w-pub-number="1077005" ID="I37c107a10bbc11e1b380a9c70bea9a4d">Public Law 111-230</cite.query> with initial L-1 petitions filed by employers with fifty or more employees where H-1B and L employees make up more than fifty percent of the employer&apos;s U.S. workforce. <eos/><bos/>These fees do not apply with regard to extension requests when the request involves an extension with the current employer.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><bold>G-28 (when the employer is represented by an attorney)</bold>. <eos/><bos/>The G-28 must be signed by the employer/petitioner under USCIS rules. <eos/><bos/>See §§ <cite.query w-ref-type="NA" w-normalized-cite="IMPHs4:32" w-pub-number="135081" ID="Ic6a947a00bbe11e1b1520000837bc6dd">4:32</cite.query> to  <cite.query w-ref-type="NA" w-normalized-cite="IMPHs4:41" w-pub-number="135081" ID="Ic6a947a10bbe11e1b1520000837bc6dd">4:41</cite.query> in this <ital>Handbook</ital> for information about Form G-28, and Sample Form 4-6 in for an annotated illustration of a completed Form G-28.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><bold>Form I-907 and $1,225 fee in premium processing cases.<eos/><bos/></bold> Legislation enacted in 2000 creates a premium processing adjudication program. <eos/><bos/>Under the program, business petitioners may choose to pay a $1,225 fee to obtain expedited processing of their cases. <eos/><bos/>Such cases must be adjudicated within 15 days. <eos/><bos/>L-1 petitions filed on Form I-129 are eligible for expedited processing. <eos/><bos/>In addition, when an I-539 application for a family member is concurrently filed with the I-129 petition where premium processing is requested, USCIS will also process the application within the 15 calendar days without requiring an additional fee. <eos/><bos/>Petitioners requesting premium processing must submit Form I-907 and the $1,225 fee required for such requests. <eos/><bos/>The fee is separate from the standard filing fee for the I-129 petition described above. <eos/><bos/>The premium processing fee must be paid by separate check or money order; do not include it in the same check as the usual filing fee for the I-129. <eos/><bos/>Form I-907 is illustrated as Sample Form 5-2, above. <eos/><bos/>Note that there is a designated premium processing address at each center with a distinct Post Office box number, zip code, or other special designation. <eos/><bos/>These addresses are listed in Ch 23, below. <eos/><bos/>The program is discussed in detail in <cite.query w-ref-type="NA" w-normalized-cite="IMPHs5:27" w-pub-number="135081" ID="Ic6a995c00bbe11e1b1520000837bc6dd">§§ 5:27</cite.query>, above.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></section.body></section><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Westlaw. © 2011 Thomson Reuters.  <eos/><bos/>No Claim to Orig. U.S. Govt. <eos/><bos/>Works.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>IMPH § 5:42<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
