<n-docbody>
	<doc bill="Y">
		<content.metadata.block>
			<cmd.identifiers>
				<cmd.cites>
					<cmd.second.line.cite>
						<bop/>
						<bos/>Cloud Computing Legal Deskbook § 12:4<eos/>
						<eop/>
					</cmd.second.line.cite>
				</cmd.cites>
			</cmd.identifiers>
		</content.metadata.block>
		<prop.block>
			<prop.head toc-guid="">
				<bop/>
				<bos/>
				<headtext>Cloud Computing Legal Deskbook</headtext>
				<eos/>
				<eop/>
			</prop.head>
			<content.metadata.block>
				<cmd.dates>
					<cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200701">
						<bop/>
						<bos/>July 2020 Update<eos/>
						<eop/>
					</cmd.currency.default>
				</cmd.dates>
			</content.metadata.block>
			<author.line>
				<bop/>
				<bos/>
				<author>Sheppard Mullin</author>
				<eos/>
				<eop/>
			</author.line>
			<prop.head toc-guid="Ic187c3d0ab5b11e28c700000833f9e5b">
				<bop/>
				<bos/>
				<label.name>Part</label.name>
				<label.designator>II.</label.designator>
				<headtext>Cloud Computing Issues for Industry</headtext>
				<eos/>
				<eop/>
			</prop.head>
			<prop.head toc-guid="Idbda32e0ab5b11e28c700000833f9e5b">
				<bop/>
				<bos/>
				<label.name>Chapter</label.name>
				<label.designator>12.</label.designator>
				<headtext>IP Risks for Government Users and Contractors</headtext>
				<eos/>
				<eop/>
			</prop.head>
			<author.line>
				<bop/>
				<bos/>
				<author>By Keith R. Szeliga and Louis Victorino[<footnote.reference refid="Ic2261520b5c211eaa32eeac3ffa29302">*</footnote.reference>]</author>
				<eos/>
				<eop/>
			</author.line>
		</prop.block>
		<message.block>
			<include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright>
		</message.block>
		<section>
			<section.front>
				<doc.title toc-guid="I3b0f4e06dd7f11e2ba1ed13bd3320788">
					<head parent="doc.title">
						<bop/>
						<bos/>
						<label.name>§ </label.name>
						<label.designator>12:4.</label.designator>
						<headtext>Standard commercial license protections</headtext>
						<eos/>
						<eop/>
					</head>
				</doc.title>
			</section.front>
			<section.body>
				<para>
					<bop/>
					<bos/>
					<paratext>Unfortunately, many of the standard commercial license terms that might mitigate intellectual property (IP) liability risks will be deleted either in the award process or as a function of the application of federal law.[<eos/>
						<bos/>
						<footnote.reference refid="Ic2263c30b5c211eaa32eeac3ffa29302">1</footnote.reference>] While applicable law and regulations require that the Government acquire the use of commercial software pursuant to the supplier&apos;s standard commercial license, the law and regulations also provide caveats to that basic rule. <eos/>
						<bos/>Perhaps the most important exception is one that precludes the inclusion of a license term in the commercial license where it is inconsistent with federal law.[<eos/>
						<bos/>
						<footnote.reference refid="Ic2263c32b5c211eaa32eeac3ffa29302">2</footnote.reference>]</paratext>
					<eos/>
					<eop/>
				</para>
				<para>
					<bop/>
					<bos/>
					<paratext>Provisions that, as a result of this rule, will be deleted from the standard commercial license will include those related to disputes (including choice of law, forum, and certain remedies).<eos/>
						<bos/>[<footnote.reference refid="Ic2266340b5c211eaa32eeac3ffa29302">3</footnote.reference>] Federal law requires that any dispute under a government procurement contract be resolved pursuant to the requirements of the Contract Disputes Act of 1978, <cite.query w-src-number="0390196555" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="41USCAS7101" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I73e82ce0b5c211eab8ebbbc35b121994">41 U.S.C.A. §§ 7101</cite.query> to <cite.query w-src-number="0390196555" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="41USCAS7109" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I73e82ce1b5c211eab8ebbbc35b121994">7109</cite.query> and its implementing regulations, Federal Acquisition Regulation (FAR) Subpart 33.2 and <cite.query w-src-number="0390196555" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="48CFR52.233-1" w-pub-number="1017185" ID="I73e82ce2b5c211eab8ebbbc35b121994">FAR 52.233-1</cite.query> (cumulatively, the “Disputes Act”).<eos/>
						<bos/> The Disputes Act requires that all disputes regarding a contract and licenses be resolved at one of two administrative boards of contract appeals or at the United States Court of Federal Claims. <eos/>
						<bos/>If the Government discloses or uses a contractor&apos;s intellectual property in a way not permitted by the license given to the Government, the contractor generally cannot terminate the license or its performance under the contract. <eos/>
						<bos/>The contractor&apos;s only remedy under the contract/license is to file a claim for money damages under the Disputes Act (notwithstanding a provision in the license providing for an automatic termination of the license upon its breach).<eos/>
						<bos/>[<footnote.reference refid="Ic2266341b5c211eaa32eeac3ffa29302">4</footnote.reference>]</paratext>
					<eos/>
					<eop/>
				</para>
				<para>
					<bop/>
					<bos/>
					<paratext>Additionally, standard license provisions requiring an indemnification by the Government will likely be deleted. <eos/>
						<bos/>The prohibition against government contractual indemnification provisions has a less certain foundation but is, nevertheless, consistently enforced. <eos/>
						<bos/>In 1982, the Comptroller General issued an opinion finding that to comply with the Federal Anti-Deficiency Act indemnity clauses in government contracts must specify that the indemnity is available only to the extent of available authorized appropriations.[<eos/>
						<bos/>
						<footnote.reference refid="Ic2266342b5c211eaa32eeac3ffa29302">5</footnote.reference>] The Government&apos;s position is that there are only very limited circumstances under which government indemnification of contractors has been authorized by Congress; in all other situations, a government indemnity provision is illegal. <eos/>
						<bos/>Based on this view, indemnification provisions in commercial software licenses are generally stricken as inconsistent with federal law. <eos/>
						<bos/>Thus, a company&apos;s standard license/contract indemnification provision will not likely protect the company from third party liability in connection with the Government&apos;s use of its cloud.<eos/>
					</paratext>
					<eop/>
				</para>
				<para>
					<bop/>
					<bos/>
					<paratext>Contractors should note that a standard commercial software license is often accepted by the contracting officer (CO) without discussion of license provisions related to disputes, rights to terminate the license upon breach, and indemnification. <eos/>
						<bos/>Meaning, the final contract will contain the standard license terms <ital>despite</ital> being void as a matter of federal law. <eos/>
						<bos/>While there is no legal decision directly dealing with such a situation, existing law almost certainly would impose the obligations and restrictions of the Disputes Act on the license. <eos/>
						<bos/>Courts consistently have held that clauses required by law and fundamental to the procurement process will be treated, under the so-called Christian Doctrine, as included in the contract if omitted (even if intentionally omitted by the parties).<eos/>
						<bos/>[<footnote.reference refid="Ic2266343b5c211eaa32eeac3ffa29302">6</footnote.reference>] The Disputes Clause certainly meets the criteria for application of the Christian Doctrine because it is a clause required by law.[<eos/>
						<bos/>
						<footnote.reference refid="Ic2266344b5c211eaa32eeac3ffa29302">7</footnote.reference>] Thus, that clause would be read into a standard commercial software license and be given precedence over a commercial disputes-related clause. <eos/>
						<bos/>There is no clause in applicable procurement regulations that restricts unfunded indemnity provisions and, as a result, the Christian Doctrine would not be available. <eos/>
						<bos/>However, similar indemnification clauses have been held unenforceable as either beyond the authority of the Contracting Officer or precluded by the Anti-Deficiency Act.[<eos/>
						<bos/>
						<footnote.reference refid="Ic2268a50b5c211eaa32eeac3ffa29302">8</footnote.reference>] Thus, an indemnification provision in a standard commercial software license likely will provide no relief.<eos/>
					</paratext>
					<eop/>
				</para>
				<para>
					<bop/>
					<bos/>
					<paratext>Without standard commercial license protections, a cloud provider must adopt other contract provisions to establish other bases for protection. <eos/>
						<bos/>As discussed in the next section, the provisions could be included in a standard commercial license or the contract vehicle pursuant to which the software is acquired by the Government.<eos/>
					</paratext>
					<eop/>
				</para>
			</section.body>
		</section>
		<author.footnotes>
			<footnote ID="Ic2261520b5c211eaa32eeac3ffa29302">
				<label.designator>*</label.designator>
				<footnote.body>
					<para>
						<bop/>
						<bos/>
						<paratext>Keith R. Szeliga is a partner in the Government Contracts, Investigations &amp; International Trade Practice Group in Sheppard Mullin&apos;s Washington, D.C. office. <eos/>
							<bos/>Mr. Szeliga represents clients ranging from small businesses to the nation&apos;s largest defense contractors in a broad range of Government contracts matters. <eos/>
							<bos/>Representative areas in which Mr. Szeliga has specialized expertise include bid protests and claims; audits and investigations; rights in technical data, computer software, and patents; cost and pricing issues; mergers and acquisitions; personal and organizational conflicts of interest; post-government employment restrictions; small business counseling; procurement fraud; and the FAR Mandatory Disclosure Rule. <eos/>
							<bos/>Mr. Szeliga frequently lectures and writes on these and other topics of interest to the procurement community.<eos/>
						</paratext>
						<eop/>
					</para>
					<para>
						<bop/>
						<bos/>
						<paratext>Louis Victorino is a special counsel in the Government Contracts, Investigations, and International Trade Group in the firm&apos;s Washington, D.C. office. <eos/>
							<bos/>Mr. Victorino&apos;s practice involves both counseling and litigation in the Public Contract Law field, representing domestic and foreign concerns that sell products, construction or services to Federal, State, or local government agencies. <eos/>
							<bos/>In his 40-year career, he has litigated in excess of thirty matters before the Court of Federal Claims, the Boards of Contract Appeals, the Comptroller General, and various Federal District Courts. <eos/>
							<bos/>Recent, significant matters include representing an Aerospace and Defense company&apos;s claim of commercial and government purpose rights licenses in technical data and software related to aircrafts purchased by the United States Air Force in a Contract Dispute before the Armed Services Board of Contract Appeals and the negotiation of complex satellite hosted payload subcontract agreements involving U.S. Government assets.<eos/>
						</paratext>
						<eop/>
					</para>
				</footnote.body>
			</footnote>
		</author.footnotes>
		<footnote.block>
			<footnote ID="Ic2263c30b5c211eaa32eeac3ffa29302">
				<label.designator>1</label.designator>
				<footnote.body>
					<para>
						<bop/>
						<bos/>
						<paratext>See supra <cite.query w-ref-type="NA" w-normalized-cite="CLOUDCDBs11:9" w-pub-number="219598" ID="Ic2263c31b5c211eaa32eeac3ffa29302">§ 11:9</cite.query>, Federal cloud acquisition strategies—Cloud terms of service (TOS) and end user license agreements (EULAs), for a discussion on the legal issues implicated by standard commercial licenses with the Government.<eos/>
						</paratext>
						<eop/>
					</para>
				</footnote.body>
			</footnote>
			<footnote ID="Ic2263c32b5c211eaa32eeac3ffa29302">
				<label.designator>2</label.designator>
				<footnote.body>
					<para>
						<bop/>
						<bos/>
						<paratext>See <cite.query w-src-number="0390196555" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="48CFR12.212" w-pub-number="1017185" ID="I73e60a00b5c211eab8ebbbc35b121994">FAR 12.212(a)</cite.query>.<eos/>
						</paratext>
						<eop/>
					</para>
				</footnote.body>
			</footnote>
			<footnote ID="Ic2266340b5c211eaa32eeac3ffa29302">
				<label.designator>3</label.designator>
				<footnote.body>
					<para>
						<bop/>
						<bos/>
						<paratext>See, e.g., Dep&apos;t of Def. Inspector Gen. Report, The Navy&apos;s Mgmt. of Software Licenses Needs Improvement (Aug. 7, 2013), available at http://www.dodig.mil/reports.html/Article/1118957/the-navys-management-of-software-licenses-needs-improvement/ (last visited Feb. 28, 2018); Army PEO Enter. <eos/>
							<bos/>Info. <eos/>
							<bos/>Sys. PowerPoint, <ital>Software That Goes Bump in the Night: Software Licensing Do&apos;s and Don&apos;ts</ital> (Sept. 2012).<eos/>
							<bos/> Indeed, several agencies other than the Department of Defense have developed lists of standard commercial end user license agreements (EULA) provisions viewed as unacceptable including the General Services Administration (GSA) and the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA).<eos/>
						</paratext>
						<eop/>
					</para>
				</footnote.body>
			</footnote>
			<footnote ID="Ic2266341b5c211eaa32eeac3ffa29302">
				<label.designator>4</label.designator>
				<footnote.body>
					<para>
						<bop/>
						<bos/>
						<paratext>Most importantly, the Disputes Act essentially denies a contractor&apos;s right to stop work as a result of a breach of contract by the Government. <eos/>
							<bos/>Except in very limited circumstances, the Disputes Act requires that a contractor not stop work in the event that the Government commits a material breach of an agreement. <eos/>
							<bos/>Instead, performance continues, and the contractor must seek monetary relief for the Government&apos;s actions.<eos/>
						</paratext>
						<eop/>
					</para>
				</footnote.body>
			</footnote>
			<footnote ID="Ic2266342b5c211eaa32eeac3ffa29302">
				<label.designator>5</label.designator>
				<footnote.body>
					<para>
						<bop/>
						<bos/>
						<paratext>The Federal Anti-Deficiency Act, <cite.query w-src-number="0390196555" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="31USCAS1341" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I73e9da90b5c211eab8ebbbc35b121994">31 U.S.C.A. § 1341</cite.query>; see B-201072, May 2, 1982; recon. <eos/>
							<bos/>
							<cite.query w-src-number="0390196555" w-serial-number="1983035717" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="CA" w-pub-number="0001008" ID="I73e9da92b5c211eab8ebbbc35b121994">62 Comp. Gen. 361 (1983)</cite.query>.<eos/>
						</paratext>
						<eop/>
					</para>
				</footnote.body>
			</footnote>
			<footnote ID="Ic2266343b5c211eaa32eeac3ffa29302">
				<label.designator>6</label.designator>
				<footnote.body>
					<para>
						<bop/>
						<bos/>
						<paratext>
							<cite.query w-src-number="0390196555" w-serial-number="1963204001" w-seq-number="00007" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000708" ID="I73eb6132b5c211eab8ebbbc35b121994">G. L. Christian and Associates v. United States., 375 U.S. 954, 84 S. Ct. 444, 11 L. Ed. 2d 314 (1963)</cite.query>.<eos/>
						</paratext>
						<eop/>
					</para>
				</footnote.body>
			</footnote>
			<footnote ID="Ic2266344b5c211eaa32eeac3ffa29302">
				<label.designator>7</label.designator>
				<footnote.body>
					<para>
						<bop/>
						<bos/>
						<paratext>
							<cite.query w-src-number="0390196555" w-seq-number="00008" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="48CFR52.233-1" w-pub-number="1017185" ID="I73ebd660b5c211eab8ebbbc35b121994">FAR 52.233-1</cite.query>.<eos/>
						</paratext>
						<eop/>
					</para>
				</footnote.body>
			</footnote>
			<footnote ID="Ic2268a50b5c211eaa32eeac3ffa29302">
				<label.designator>8</label.designator>
				<footnote.body>
					<para>
						<bop/>
						<bos/>
						<paratext>
							<cite.query w-src-number="0390196555" w-seq-number="00009" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="31USCAS1341" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I73ec99b0b5c211eab8ebbbc35b121994">31 U.S.C.A. § 1341</cite.query>; see discussion supra, in <cite.query w-ref-type="NA" w-normalized-cite="CLOUDCDBs11:9" w-pub-number="219598" ID="Ic2268a51b5c211eaa32eeac3ffa29302">§ 11:9</cite.query>, Federal cloud acquisition strategies—Cloud terms of service (TOS) and end user license agreements (EULAs).<eos/>
						</paratext>
						<eop/>
					</para>
				</footnote.body>
			</footnote>
		</footnote.block>
		<content.metadata.block>
			<cmd.royalty>
				<cmd.copyright>
					<bop/>
					<bos/>Westlaw. © 2020 Thomson Reuters.  <eos/>
					<bos/>No Claim to Orig. U.S. Govt. <eos/>
					<bos/>Works.<eos/>
					<eop/>
				</cmd.copyright>
			</cmd.royalty>
			<cmd.identifiers>
				<cmd.cites>
					<cmd.first.line.cite>
						<bop/>
						<bos/>CLOUDCDB § 12:4<eos/>
						<eop/>
					</cmd.first.line.cite>
				</cmd.cites>
			</cmd.identifiers>
		</content.metadata.block>
	</doc>
</n-docbody>
