<n-docbody>
	<doc bill="Y">
		<content.metadata.block>
			<cmd.identifiers>
				<cmd.cites>
					<cmd.second.line.cite>
						<bop/>
						<bos/>Profiting from Risk Management and Compliance § 1:1<eos/>
						<eop/>
					</cmd.second.line.cite>
				</cmd.cites>
			</cmd.identifiers>
		</content.metadata.block>
		<prop.block>
			<prop.head toc-guid="">
				<bop/>
				<bos/>
				<headtext>Profiting from Risk Management and Compliance</headtext>
				<eos/>
				<eop/>
			</prop.head>
			<content.metadata.block>
				<cmd.dates>
					<cmd.currency.default iso.d="20200501">
						<bop/>
						<eop/>
					</cmd.currency.default>
				</cmd.dates>
			</content.metadata.block>
			<author.line>
				<bop/>
				<bos/>
				<author>Todd L. Archibald</author>
				<eos/>
				<eop/>
			</author.line>
			<author.line>
				<bop/>
				<bos/>
				<author>Kenneth E. Jull</author>
				<eos/>
				<eop/>
			</author.line>
			<prop.head toc-guid="I6783a890582411eaa028e73673abd724">
				<bop/>
				<bos/>
				<label.name>Chapter</label.name>
				<label.designator>1.</label.designator>
				<headtext>Introduction and Overview</headtext>
				<eos/>
				<eop/>
			</prop.head>
			<prop.head toc-guid="I678492f0582411eaa028e73673abd724">
				<bop/>
				<bos/>
				<label.designator>I.</label.designator>
				<headtext>Risk</headtext>
				<eos/>
				<eop/>
			</prop.head>
		</prop.block>
		<message.block>
			<include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright>
		</message.block>
		<section>
			<section.front>
				<doc.title toc-guid="Iffedf8e19b5611ea99ceec6cca1d5c1a">
					<head parent="doc.title">
						<bop/>
						<bos/>
						<label.name>§ </label.name>
						<label.designator>1:1.</label.designator>
						<headtext>Profiting from Risk Management and Compliance: Basic Principles</headtext>
						<eos/>
						<eop/>
					</head>
				</doc.title>
			</section.front>
			<section.body>
				<classification.block source="trillium">
					<para>
						<bop/>
						<tbl ID="abxbrownbeatty-2_1205_49">
							<table frame="all" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
								<bos/>
								<tgroup cols="1">
									<colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="50*"/>
									<thead>
										<row rowsep="hsingle">
											<entry colname="col1" namest="col1" nameend="col1" align="left" valign="top">
												<para>
													<paratext>
														<bold>Legal Topics</bold>
													</paratext>
												</para>
												<para>
													<paratext>Find other content related to these topics or navigate subheadings within this document.</paratext>
												</para>
											</entry>
										</row>
										<row rowsep="hsingle">
											<entry colname="col1" namest="col1" nameend="col1" align="left" valign="top">Legal Topics</entry>
										</row>
									</thead>
									<tbody>
										<row rowsep="hsingle">
											<entry colname="col1" namest="col1" nameend="col1" align="left" valign="top">
												<para>
													<paratext>
														<digest.classif>
															<digest.classification ID="" search-string="CNL.VII.4.a.vi">CNL.VII.4.a.vi Constitutional law—Distribution of legislative powers—Areas of legislation—Commercial regulation—Miscellaneous</digest.classification>
														</digest.classif>
													</paratext>
												</para>
											</entry>
										</row>
										<row rowsep="hsingle">
											<entry colname="col1" namest="col1" nameend="col1" align="left" valign="top">
												<para>
													<paratext>
														<digest.classif>
															<digest.classification ID="" search-string="CNL.VII.4.a.i">CNL.VII.4.a.i Constitutional law—Distribution of legislative powers—Areas of legislation—Commercial regulation—General principles</digest.classification>
														</digest.classif>
													</paratext>
												</para>
											</entry>
										</row>
										<row rowsep="hsingle">
											<entry colname="col1" namest="col1" nameend="col1" align="left" valign="top">
												<para>
													<paratext>
														<digest.classif>
															<digest.classification ID="" search-string="BUS.IV.10">BUS.IV.10 Business associations—Powers, rights and liabilities—Liability of corporations</digest.classification>
														</digest.classif>
													</paratext>
												</para>
											</entry>
										</row>
									</tbody>
								</tgroup>
								<eos/>
							</table>
						</tbl>
						<eop/>
					</para>
				</classification.block>
				<para>
					<bop/>
					<bos/>
					<paratext>Traditional risk management and compliance systems may be viewed as a necessary evil, akin to going to the dentist or getting a regular medical check-up. <eos/>
						<bos/>We argue that there is a financial incentive to accompany the more traditional measurement of risk. <eos/>
						<bos/>There is hard data that the more financially successful companies value leadership, fairness and the interests of their constituencies more highly than the lower-yielding firms. <eos/>
						<bos/>
						<ital>In other words, higher risk control leads to higher financial rewards</ital>.<eos/>
					</paratext>
					<eop/>
				</para>
				<para>
					<bop/>
					<bos/>
					<paratext>In her book entitled <ital>Value Shift</ital>,[<footnote.reference refid="I0b5395f0af1611ea903cf5d4be638fe0">1</footnote.reference>] Professor Paine of the Harvard Business School makes a convincing case for new ethical standards as a method of increasing profits. <eos/>
						<bos/>The costs of scandals in any organization go far beyond the obvious legal fees and fines to encompass lost customers, employees and productivity. <eos/>
						<bos/>As illustrated by the experiences of Enron, Arthur Anderson, Tyco and others, a company caught in misconduct can quickly find its reputation in tatters and its core relationships shattered. <eos/>
						<bos/>It can also find itself saddled with millions of dollars in fines, litigation expenses and legal fees. <eos/>
						<bos/>An entire industry may be impacted in loss of reputation by the misconduct of some in that industry. <eos/>
						<bos/>For example, consumers have less faith in food retailers in 2018 than before Loblaw Ltd. disclosed it had been part of what it called an industry-wide conspiracy to fix the price of bread. <eos/>
						<bos/>Consumer trust in Loblaw, Canada&apos;s largest supermarket retailer, tumbled by 10%, while overall trust in grocery chains dropped 6.31%.[<eos/>
						<bos/>
						<footnote.reference refid="I0b53bd00af1611ea903cf5d4be638fe0">2</footnote.reference>]</paratext>
					<eos/>
					<eop/>
				</para>
				<para>
					<bop/>
					<bos/>
					<paratext>At the opposite end of the spectrum, Paine uses the example of Sealed Air Corporation, which is a leader in combining high ethical standards and profitability.<eos/>
					</paratext>
					<eop/>
				</para>
				<para>
					<bop/>
					<bos/>
					<paratext>Sealed Air Corporation is best known for its product “Bubble Wrap”.<eos/>
						<bos/> In 2001, the company&apos;s sales were $3.1 billion. <eos/>
						<bos/>This company has identified “bedrock values” such as personal accountability, respect for the individual, truth and fair dealing to be at the core of its structure.[<eos/>
						<bos/>
						<footnote.reference refid="I0b53e410af1611ea903cf5d4be638fe0">3</footnote.reference>] These values are translated into practice by training. <eos/>
						<bos/>For example, sales representatives learn to recommend objective solutions to customer problems, even if this approach results in the loss of a sale. <eos/>
						<bos/>New employee training includes health, safety and environmental issues. <eos/>
						<bos/>The values translate into profitability in ways that might not be expected. <eos/>
						<bos/>Interviews with Sealed Air executives revealed that their value systems allowed the company to function with fewer layers of management when compared to companies of similar size. <eos/>
						<bos/>This was accomplished because of a value system that <begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>“cultivates people&apos;s capacities for self-direction and self-co-ordination”<end.quote refid="QT_0002"/>.[<eos/>
						<bos/>
						<footnote.reference refid="I0b53e411af1611ea903cf5d4be638fe0">4</footnote.reference>] A corporate culture based on core values is well suited to successful globalization by a company, a point made by Bill Hickey, who became the CEO of Sealed Air in 2000:</paratext>
					<display.quote>
						<para>
							<paratext>
								<begin.quote ID="QT_0003"/>To the contrary, Hickey sees a “seamless corporate culture” based on the company&apos;s stated values as the key to successful globalization. <eos/>
								<bos/>Such a culture, he believes, is necessary to foster effective working relationships across the company&apos;s various divisions and with its many customers around the world. <eos/>
								<bos/>Moreover, it is in his view crucial to growing the company without becoming a highly centralized, bureaucratic organization. <eos/>
								<bos/>Still, from Hickey&apos;s perspective, Sealed Air&apos;s values are more than just financial tools; they represent a very “human” approach to people both inside and outside the company. <eos/>
								<bos/>They not only contribute to good financial results, but they also, in his judgment, make Sealed Air an enjoyable place to work.<eos/>
								<bos/>
								<end.quote refid="QT_0003"/>[<footnote.reference refid="I0b53e412af1611ea903cf5d4be638fe0">5</footnote.reference>]</paratext>
						</para>
					</display.quote>
					<eos/>
					<eop/>
				</para>
				<para>
					<bop/>
					<bos/>
					<paratext>In this book, we develop user-friendly risk management matrix diagrams, flow charts, checklists, and codes of conduct. <eos/>
						<bos/>We strongly believe that these templates will lead to greater profit in corporations and efficiencies in non-profit organizations.<eos/>
					</paratext>
					<eop/>
				</para>
				<para>
					<bop/>
					<bos/>
					<paratext>We recognize that the causal link between risk management, compliance, and profit is a difficult link to measure empirically and that more work needs to be done in this area. <eos/>
						<bos/>We also recognize that there are skeptics. <eos/>
						<bos/>For example, in the context of corporate governance reforms in relation to firm directors and other governance issues, Anthony Duggan, Jacob S. Ziegel and Jassmine Girgis have argued that there is no evidence corporate governance best practices positively impact the financial returns to companies or shareholders:</paratext>
					<display.quote>
						<para>
							<paratext>
								<begin.quote ID="QT_0005"/>Since 2000, empirical studies published in peer-reviewed journals have generally found corporate financial results are not connected to the principal best practices promulgated for corporate boards: majority or super-majority independent boards, independent board committees, board diversity, separating the CEO and chair, and restricting directors&apos; outside board commitments. <eos/>
								<bos/>Of these practices, only the latter is not directly contradicted by the empirical evidence and, in its case, there is evidence suggesting it would also fail if researchers decided to address it directly. <eos/>
								<bos/>Corporate governance best practices also do not appear to produce outcomes investors should care about.<eos/>
								<bos/>
								<end.quote refid="QT_0005"/>[<footnote.reference refid="I0b540b20af1611ea903cf5d4be638fe0">6</footnote.reference>]</paratext>
						</para>
					</display.quote>
					<eos/>
					<eop/>
				</para>
				<para>
					<bop/>
					<bos/>
					<paratext>Our response to the above research would be that corporate governance reforms are relatively narrow in scope compared to our much more ambitious risk management and compliance strategies.<eos/>
					</paratext>
					<eop/>
				</para>
				<para>
					<bop/>
					<bos/>
					<paratext>Alan Barlow&apos;s book <ital>Profiting From Integrity</ital>[<footnote.reference refid="I0b543230af1611ea903cf5d4be638fe0">7</footnote.reference>] argues that integrity manifested in feedback, vision, leadership and staff relations leads to greater business success as well as moral satisfaction.[<eos/>
						<bos/>
						<footnote.reference refid="I0b543231af1611ea903cf5d4be638fe0">8</footnote.reference>] Barlow&apos;s background includes extensive senior executive roles in a variety of business structures. <eos/>
						<bos/>Barlow surveys the literature that shows a causal link between financial performance and workplace quality.[<eos/>
						<bos/>
						<footnote.reference refid="I0b543232af1611ea903cf5d4be638fe0">9</footnote.reference>] He also relies on his own experience to show that integrity is an integral part of business growth. <eos/>
						<bos/>The reference to the concept of profiting from integrity, which mirrors our title of <ital>Profiting from Risk Management</ital>, is a happy coincidence. <eos/>
						<bos/>We first published our Student Edition in 2018 under the new title of <ital>Profiting From Risk Management and Compliance</ital> before we became aware of Barlow&apos;s work.[<eos/>
						<bos/>
						<footnote.reference refid="I0b562e00af1611ea903cf5d4be638fe0">10</footnote.reference>]</paratext>
					<eos/>
					<eop/>
				</para>
				<para>
					<bop/>
					<bos/>
					<paratext>Barlow&apos;s vision of integrity is an integrated business model which does not treat ethics in a silo. <eos/>
						<bos/>He makes the ironic observation that the corporate social responsibility (CSR) movement has failed because it has been treated as a “fluffy largely irrelevant cost centre”.<eos/>
						<bos/>[<footnote.reference refid="I0b562e01af1611ea903cf5d4be638fe0">11</footnote.reference>] Research has shown that companies with the highest CSR scores make the greatest efforts to avoid tax. <eos/>
						<bos/>This apparent contradiction can be explained by the fact that the management responsible for tax affairs operate in a separate silo apart from the management of CSR.[<eos/>
						<bos/>
						<footnote.reference refid="I0b562e02af1611ea903cf5d4be638fe0">12</footnote.reference>] Moreover, Barlow cites evidence that found a zero or negative effect of high CSR scores and stock returns. <eos/>
						<bos/>A cynical view of CSR is that it is window dressing which serves to increase employee and customer morale. <eos/>
						<bos/>Barlow&apos;s view of CSR can be linked to our discussion of governance at <cite.query w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="NA" w-normalized-cite="ARCHIBALDRCWLs1:27" w-pub-number="0236469" ID="I0b598960af1611ea903cf5d4be638fe0">1:27</cite.query>, <begin.quote ID="QT_0006"/>“Governance and the Best Interests of the Corporation”<end.quote refid="QT_0006"/>. <eos/>
						<bos/>We argue that it is the duty of legislators in the regulatory state to set out the parameters of appropriate conduct. <eos/>
						<bos/>It should not be the duty of corporate directors, whose expertise relates primarily to business, to formulate social or moral policy.<eos/>
					</paratext>
					<eop/>
				</para>
				<para>
					<bop/>
					<bos/>
					<paratext>There is growing evidence that the marketplace responds to ethical conduct. <eos/>
						<bos/>Businesses that ignore ethical considerations do so at their own peril. <eos/>
						<bos/>Consider, in this regard, the Volkswagen emissions scandal (discussed in <cite.query w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="NA" w-normalized-cite="ARCHIBALDRCWLs2:1" w-pub-number="0236469" ID="I0b59b070af1611ea903cf5d4be638fe0">Chapter 2 §§ 2:1 et seq.</cite.query>) with devastating impacts on corporate profitability. <eos/>
						<bos/>The marketplace is an increasingly interdependent and complex economic system. <eos/>
						<bos/>An unscrupulous move by a corporation can have ripple effects throughout its supply, distribution, and sales chain.[<eos/>
						<bos/>
						<footnote.reference refid="I0b59b071af1611ea903cf5d4be638fe0">13</footnote.reference>]</paratext>
					<eos/>
					<eop/>
				</para>
				<para>
					<bop/>
					<bos/>
					<paratext>The matrix risk model advanced in this book solves the silo riddle by implementing consistent risk priorities across the entire organization on a macro and micro level. (<eos/>
						<bos/>See below, <cite.query w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="NA" w-normalized-cite="ARCHIBALDRCWLs1:4" w-pub-number="0236469" ID="I0b59b072af1611ea903cf5d4be638fe0">1:4</cite.query> “Risk Matrix: Basic Principles”, <cite.query w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="NA" w-normalized-cite="ARCHIBALDRCWLs1:5" w-pub-number="0236469" ID="I0b59d780af1611ea903cf5d4be638fe0">1:5</cite.query> “Matrix: Macro Priorities”, <cite.query w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="NA" w-normalized-cite="ARCHIBALDRCWLs1:6" w-pub-number="0236469" ID="I0b59d781af1611ea903cf5d4be638fe0">1:6</cite.query> “Micro Calculations”.<eos/>
						<bos/>)</paratext>
					<eos/>
					<eop/>
				</para>
				<para>
					<bop/>
					<bos/>
					<paratext>We argue that compliance must be linked to compensation and profit. <eos/>
						<bos/>A simple example from a law school class illustrates the point. <eos/>
						<bos/>If ethics are taught as a sub component of a substantive course, students will inquire as to whether the ethics portion is marked. <eos/>
						<bos/>If there is no incentive or reward for reading the ethics materials, it is likely that students will put this reading to the bottom of the list, in order to compete with the other students who are focused on the subject areas that are marked. <eos/>
						<bos/>Compliance is linked to compensation, and this starts from the beginning of legal education.<eos/>
					</paratext>
					<eop/>
				</para>
				<para>
					<bop/>
					<bos/>
					<paratext>The United States Department of Justice has updated its compliance guidance in 2019. <eos/>
						<bos/>The DOJ explicitly recognizes the link between compliance and incentives:</paratext>
					<display.quote>
						<para>
							<paratext>
								<begin.quote ID="QT_0008"/>Incentive System—Has the company considered the implications of its incentives and rewards on compliance? <eos/>
								<bos/>How does the company incentivize compliance and ethical behavior? <eos/>
								<bos/>Have there been specific examples of actions taken (e.g., promotions or awards denied) as a result of compliance and ethics considerations? <eos/>
								<bos/>Who determines the compensation, including bonuses, as well as discipline and promotion of compliance personnel.<eos/>
								<bos/>
								<end.quote refid="QT_0008"/>[<footnote.reference refid="I0b59fe90af1611ea903cf5d4be638fe0">14</footnote.reference>]</paratext>
						</para>
					</display.quote>
					<eos/>
					<eop/>
				</para>
			</section.body>
		</section>
		<footnote.block>
			<footnote ID="I0b5395f0af1611ea903cf5d4be638fe0">
				<label.designator>1</label.designator>
				<footnote.body>
					<para>
						<bop/>
						<bos/>
						<paratext>L. Sharpe Paine, Value Shift: Why Companies Must Merge Social and Financial Imperatives to Achieve Superior Performances (Toronto: McGraw-Hill, 2003), at p. 141.<eos/>
						</paratext>
						<eop/>
					</para>
				</footnote.body>
			</footnote>
			<footnote ID="I0b53bd00af1611ea903cf5d4be638fe0">
				<label.designator>2</label.designator>
				<footnote.body>
					<para>
						<bop/>
						<bos/>
						<paratext>See https://www.theglobeandmail.com/report-on-business/consumer-trust-in-grocers-tumbles-after-bread-price-fixing-scheme-study/article38308074. For details about the disclosure by Loblaws, see https://www.theglobeandmail.com/report-on-business/rob-commentary/competition-bureau-what-canadians-need-to-know-about-price-fixing-probes/article37830190, and see remarks of former Commissioner Pecman in <begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>“Competition Bureau: What Canadians Need to Know About Price-Fixing Probes”<end.quote refid="QT_0001"/>, in The Globe and Mail (February 2, 2018).<eos/>
						</paratext>
						<eop/>
					</para>
				</footnote.body>
			</footnote>
			<footnote ID="I0b53e410af1611ea903cf5d4be638fe0">
				<label.designator>3</label.designator>
				<footnote.body>
					<para>
						<bop/>
						<bos/>
						<paratext>L. Sharpe Paine, Value Shift: Why Companies Must Merge Social and Financial Imperatives to Achieve Superior Performances (Toronto: McGraw-Hill, 2003), at p. 13.<eos/>
						</paratext>
						<eop/>
					</para>
				</footnote.body>
			</footnote>
			<footnote ID="I0b53e411af1611ea903cf5d4be638fe0">
				<label.designator>4</label.designator>
				<footnote.body>
					<para>
						<bop/>
						<bos/>
						<paratext>L. Sharpe Paine, Value Shift: Why Companies Must Merge Social and Financial Imperatives to Achieve Superior Performances (Toronto: McGraw-Hill, 2003), at p. 15.<eos/>
						</paratext>
						<eop/>
					</para>
				</footnote.body>
			</footnote>
			<footnote ID="I0b53e412af1611ea903cf5d4be638fe0">
				<label.designator>5</label.designator>
				<footnote.body>
					<para>
						<bop/>
						<bos/>
						<paratext>L. Sharpe Paine, Value Shift: Why Companies Must Merge Social and Financial Imperatives to Achieve Superior Performances (Toronto: McGraw-Hill, 2003), at p. 16.<eos/>
						</paratext>
						<eop/>
					</para>
				</footnote.body>
			</footnote>
			<footnote ID="I0b540b20af1611ea903cf5d4be638fe0">
				<label.designator>6</label.designator>
				<footnote.body>
					<para>
						<bop/>
						<bos/>
						<paratext>Anthony Duggan, Jacob S. Ziegel and Jassmine Girgis, <begin.quote ID="QT_0004"/>“What Do We Really Know About Corporate Governance? <eos/>
							<bos/>A Review of the Empirical Research Since 2000”<end.quote refid="QT_0004"/> (2017), 59 C.B.L.J. 293.<eos/>
						</paratext>
						<eop/>
					</para>
				</footnote.body>
			</footnote>
			<footnote ID="I0b543230af1611ea903cf5d4be638fe0">
				<label.designator>7</label.designator>
				<footnote.body>
					<para>
						<bop/>
						<bos/>
						<paratext>Alan Barlow, Profiting From Integrity: How CEOs Can Deliver Superior Profitability And Be Relevant To Society (London: Routledge, 2018).<eos/>
						</paratext>
						<eop/>
					</para>
				</footnote.body>
			</footnote>
			<footnote ID="I0b543231af1611ea903cf5d4be638fe0">
				<label.designator>8</label.designator>
				<footnote.body>
					<para>
						<bop/>
						<bos/>
						<paratext>Book review by Dr. Eamonn Butler, at https://www.adamsmith.org/blog/book-review-profiting-from-integrity-by-alan-barlow.</paratext>
						<eos/>
						<eop/>
					</para>
				</footnote.body>
			</footnote>
			<footnote ID="I0b543232af1611ea903cf5d4be638fe0">
				<label.designator>9</label.designator>
				<footnote.body>
					<para>
						<bop/>
						<bos/>
						<paratext>Alan Barlow, Profiting From Integrity: How CEOs Can Deliver Superior Profitability And Be Relevant To Society (London: Routledge, 2018), in Chapter 2.</paratext>
						<eos/>
						<eop/>
					</para>
				</footnote.body>
			</footnote>
			<footnote ID="I0b562e00af1611ea903cf5d4be638fe0">
				<label.designator>10</label.designator>
				<footnote.body>
					<para>
						<bop/>
						<bos/>
						<paratext>https://deskcopy.thomsonreuters.ca/product-detail/profiting-from-risk-management-and-compliance-2018-student-edition-formerly-risk-management-financial-crimes-and-corporate-compliance-2017-student-edition.</paratext>
						<eos/>
						<eop/>
					</para>
				</footnote.body>
			</footnote>
			<footnote ID="I0b562e01af1611ea903cf5d4be638fe0">
				<label.designator>11</label.designator>
				<footnote.body>
					<para>
						<bop/>
						<bos/>
						<paratext>Alan Barlow, Profiting From Integrity: How CEOs Can Deliver Superior Profitability And Be Relevant To Society (London: Routledge, 2018), at p. 7.</paratext>
						<eos/>
						<eop/>
					</para>
				</footnote.body>
			</footnote>
			<footnote ID="I0b562e02af1611ea903cf5d4be638fe0">
				<label.designator>12</label.designator>
				<footnote.body>
					<para>
						<bop/>
						<bos/>
						<paratext>Alan Barlow, Profiting From Integrity: How CEOs Can Deliver Superior Profitability And Be Relevant To Society (London: Routledge, 2018), at p. 6.</paratext>
						<eos/>
						<eop/>
					</para>
				</footnote.body>
			</footnote>
			<footnote ID="I0b59b071af1611ea903cf5d4be638fe0">
				<label.designator>13</label.designator>
				<footnote.body>
					<para>
						<bop/>
						<bos/>
						<paratext>Arthur Acevedo, <begin.quote ID="QT_0007"/>“Corporate Ethics: Approaches and Implications to Expanding the Corporate Mindset of Profitability”<end.quote refid="QT_0007"/> (2018), 49 Loy. <eos/>
							<bos/>U. Chi. <eos/>
							<bos/>L.J. 637 at 654.<eos/>
						</paratext>
						<eop/>
					</para>
				</footnote.body>
			</footnote>
			<footnote ID="I0b59fe90af1611ea903cf5d4be638fe0">
				<label.designator>14</label.designator>
				<footnote.body>
					<para>
						<bop/>
						<bos/>
						<paratext>U.S. Department of Justice Criminal Division Evaluation of Corporate Compliance Programs (Updated April 2019) https://www.justice.gov/criminal-fraud/page/file/937501/download).<eos/>
						</paratext>
						<eop/>
					</para>
				</footnote.body>
			</footnote>
		</footnote.block>
		<content.metadata.block>
			<cmd.royalty>
				<cmd.copyright>
					<bop/>
					<bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada, a division of Thomson Reuters Canada Limited is not engaged in rendering legal or other professional advice, and this research document is not a substitute for independent legal research. <eos/>
					<bos/>Thomson Reuters Canada distributes this research document &quot;as is&quot;.<eos/>
					<bos/> Thomson Reuters Canada disclaims any representations, warranties or conditions, express or implied, including those of performance, accuracy, completeness, currency, or fitness or applicability for a particular purpose or situation, with respect to the contents of the research document.<eos/>
					<eop/>
				</cmd.copyright>
			</cmd.royalty>
			<cmd.identifiers>
				<cmd.cites>
					<cmd.first.line.cite>
						<bop/>
						<bos/>ARCHIBALDRC-WL § 1:1<eos/>
						<eop/>
					</cmd.first.line.cite>
				</cmd.cites>
			</cmd.identifiers>
		</content.metadata.block>
	</doc>
</n-docbody>
