<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Multidistrict Lit Man § 4:23<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Multidistrict Litigation Manual</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20190501"><bop/><bos/>May 2019 Update<eos/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><author.line><bop/><bos/><author>David F. Herr[<footnote.reference refid="If2e59f706b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">a0</footnote.reference>]</author><eos/><eop/></author.line><prop.head toc-guid="I97b7f560933b11da99e2b07024dacc26"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Part</label.name><label.designator>I.</label.designator><headtext>Handling Cases Before the Judicial Panel on Multidistrict Litigation</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="Ib978dbb0933b11da99e2b07024dacc26"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>4.</label.designator><headtext>Procedure Before the Panel</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="I94eeba73e1e311da9c26e67ca3b71335"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>4:23.</label.designator><headtext>Hearing—Oral argument</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Hearings before the Panel are traditionally held six times a year. <eos/><bos/>The place for hearing may be in Washington, or it may be at any other federal courthouse. <eos/><bos/>In practice, the Panel attempts to hear calendars throughout the country.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Panel Rules require that the Panel not consider transfer or remand without hearing of any matter if a party opposes transfer or remand without hearing.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If2e5c6806b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">1</footnote.reference>] The Panel is allowed to dispense with argument in two situations: if the dispositive issues have been &quot;authoritatively decided,&quot; or if the facts and legal arguments are adequately presented by the written submissions and the Panel concludes <begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>&quot;oral argument would not significantly aid the decisional process.&quot;<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0001"/>[<footnote.reference refid="If2e5c6816b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">2</footnote.reference>] </paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Panel issues notice of an oral argument calendar, advising counsel of those matters for which oral argument is allowed. <eos/><bos/>The Panel allows no more than 20 minutes per matter for argument.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If2e5c6826b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">3</footnote.reference>] In many dockets, the Panel will allow five or ten minutes to an entire side, and will leave allocation of the time to the parties. <eos/><bos/>This practice is not so draconian as it may sound, for many cases involve issues that have been frequently considered by the Panel and for which clear rules have emerged. <eos/><bos/>For example, if the matter involves numerous cases arising from an air crash disaster in the United States, both the question of transfer[<footnote.reference refid="If2e5c6836b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">4</footnote.reference>] and the selection of a transferee district[<footnote.reference refid="If2e5ed916b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">5</footnote.reference>] may be virtually decided before argument. <eos/><bos/>The Panel may only want answers to specific questions concerning the anticipated or intended discovery or the location of evidence.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Oral argument before the Panel is similar in form to any appellate argument. <eos/><bos/>A prepared presentation is likely to be punctuated by questions from the Panel. <eos/><bos/>Although oral argument is an opportunity to persuade the Panel, the time available for persuasion is limited. <eos/><bos/>Oral arguments should therefore be well planned. <eos/><bos/>It is important to focus the argument on matters likely to be of concern to the Panel. <eos/><bos/>Cogent explanations of how the case before it differs from other cases or why some predictable action should not be taken in the case may be effective.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If2e5ed936b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">6</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The sequence of events relating to the hearing is worth understanding. <eos/><bos/>First, the Panel publishes the calendar to all the parties in all the cases to be heard on that occasion. <eos/><bos/>An actual calendar appears in Appendix A, Forms <cite.query w-ref-type="DA" w-normalized-cite="MDLITMANAPPA" w-pub-number="185218" ID="If2e614a06b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">11</cite.query> &amp;  <cite.query w-ref-type="DA" w-normalized-cite="MDLITMANAPPA" w-pub-number="185218" ID="If2e614a16b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">12</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>Following receipt of the calendar each party is allowed to file a statement setting forth why argument should, or need not, be heard. <eos/><bos/>In addition, the party can expressly waive argument at this time.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If2e614a26b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">7</footnote.reference>] Following receipt of these forms, the Panel Clerk&apos;s office creates a calendar that allocates time to the various dockets being heard, and to the lawyers requesting argument.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The hearing calendar will include all related cases on the Panel&apos;s “radar screen” at the time it is prepared. <eos/><bos/>This is not surprising, but the obvious corollary to that rule is: if a case comes to the attention of the Panel after the “cut-off” for the hearing passes, it will not be considered at the hearing and will not be part of an initial order on transfer. <eos/><bos/>It will be treated as a potential tag-along action. <eos/><bos/>This rule is inexorable, and occasionally disappointing to a lawyer or party whose action misses the initial calendar. <eos/><bos/>If treated as a potential tag-along action, the question will be a fairly simple one for the Panel—should this action be treated along with the others. <eos/><bos/>The decisions about transfer of the entire docket and selection of transferee district and judge will have been made. <eos/><bos/>Accordingly, lawyers with cases that might be part of MDL proceedings should be vigilant to monitor the Panel&apos;s docket and should consult with other lawyers or parties who might be aware of MDL proceedings if they have been commenced. <eos/><bos/>This is especially important if the party believes it will have a position on the appropriateness of transfer or selection of the transferee court that may differ from the position of other parties. <eos/><bos/>If it is an action that is not known to the other litigants, it may escape inclusion on the Panel&apos;s service list; if this happens, the party&apos;s first opportunity to participate in the Panels actions will be in response to a conditional transfer order, where the options are distinctly limited.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>One observer on the unhappy status of having a recently filed lawsuit end up as a potential tag-along action on a docket where the Panel has ordered transfer has observed:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>For example, if you are the respondent to a transfer motion or counsel for a party in a ‘tag along’ action (a case subject to transfer by the Panel and consolidation with cases previously transferred and consolidated), the Panel can seize control of your case, thrust you into someone else&apos;s litigation halfway across the country, and relegate you to “100<super>th</super> chair” status in an already over-lawyered mass litigation where coveted ‘lead counsel,’ ‘liaison counsel’ and ‘executive committee’ court-appointed case management and litigation leadership positions have already been divvied up.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0002"/>[<footnote.reference refid="If2e63bb06b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">8</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para></section.body></section><author.footnotes><footnote ID="If2e59f706b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>a0</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Maslon Edelman Borman &amp; Brand, LLP, Minneapolis, Minnesota.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></author.footnotes><footnote.block><footnote ID="If2e5c6806b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See</ital> J.P.M.L. <eos/><bos/><cite.query w-src-number="0304913990" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="USMULTIDISTLITR11.1" w-pub-number="1000604" ID="I57765cf06b3e11e9a5a983883834314b">R. 11.1(c)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If2e5c6816b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See</ital> J.P.M.L. <eos/><bos/><cite.query w-src-number="0304913990" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="USMULTIDISTLITR11.1" w-pub-number="1000604" ID="I57796a306b3e11e9a5a983883834314b">R. 11.1(c)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If2e5c6826b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See</ital> J.P.M.L. R. 11(f) (20-minuted limit applies &quot;barring exceptional circumstances.&quot;<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If2e5c6836b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>4</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Transfer of mass disaster cases is considered in <cite.query w-ref-type="NA" w-normalized-cite="MDLITMANs5:14" w-pub-number="185218" ID="If2e5ed906b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">§ 5:14</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If2e5ed916b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>5</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The role the place of a disaster has on selection of a transferee district is discussed in <cite.query w-ref-type="NA" w-normalized-cite="MDLITMANs6:6" w-pub-number="185218" ID="If2e5ed926b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">§ 6:6</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If2e5ed936b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>6</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>For a more extensive discussion of effective oral advocacy, see <csc>David F. Herr, Roger S. Haydock &amp; Jeffrey W. Stempel, Motion Practice</csc>, chs. 4 and 6 (8th ed. 2019.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If2e614a26b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>7</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>This form is also reproduced in <cite.query w-ref-type="DA" w-normalized-cite="MDLITMANAPPA" w-pub-number="185218" ID="If2e614a36b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">Appendix A, Form 14</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If2e63bb06b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>8</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Earle F. Kyle, IV, <cite.query w-src-number="0304913990" w-serial-number="0108757959" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="LR" w-pub-number="0000344" w-pinpoint-page="590" ID="I578502f16b3e11e9a5a983883834314b"><ital>The Mechanics of Motion Practice before the Judicial Panel of Multidistrict Litigation</ital>, 175 F.R.D. 589, 590 to 591 (1998)</cite.query> (footnotes omitted).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Westlaw. © 2019 Thomson Reuters.  <eos/><bos/>No Claim to Orig. U.S. Govt. <eos/><bos/>Works.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>MDLITMAN § 4:23<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
