<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Multidistrict Lit Man § 3:19<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Multidistrict Litigation Manual</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20190501"><bop/><bos/>May 2019 Update<eos/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><author.line><bop/><bos/><author>David F. Herr[<footnote.reference refid="If24456616b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">a0</footnote.reference>]</author><eos/><eop/></author.line><prop.head toc-guid="I97b7f560933b11da99e2b07024dacc26"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Part</label.name><label.designator>I.</label.designator><headtext>Handling Cases Before the Judicial Panel on Multidistrict Litigation</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I9f85f1c0933b11da99e2b07024dacc26"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>3.</label.designator><headtext>Powers of the Panel</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="I94edd019e1e311da9c26e67ca3b71335"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>3:19.</label.designator><headtext>Statutes relating to the Panel&apos;s authority</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><tbl ID="Ib7d20980933b11da99e2b07024dacc26"><bop/><table><bos/><tgroup cols="1" align="left"><colspec colnum="1" colname="1GENERATED" colwidth="1*"/><tbody><row><entry colname="1GENERATED">1. <cite.query w-src-number="0304913967" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="28USCAS1407" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I573e84106b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">28 U.S.C. § 1407</cite.query>. Multidistrict litigation</entry></row><row><entry colname="1GENERATED">2. <cite.query w-src-number="0304913967" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="28USCAS292" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I573eab206b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">28 U.S.C. § 292</cite.query>. District judges</entry></row><row><entry colname="1GENERATED">3. § 2112. Record on review and enforcement of agency orders</entry></row><row><entry colname="1GENERATED">4. <cite.query w-src-number="0304913967" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="ES" w-normalized-cite="28USCAS2212" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I573ef9406b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">28 U.S.C. § 2212</cite.query>. Multiparty, multiforum jurisdiction</entry></row><row><entry colname="1GENERATED">5. <cite.query w-src-number="0304913967" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="45USCAS719" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I573ef9416b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">45 U.S.C. § 719</cite.query>. Judicial review</entry></row><row><entry colname="1GENERATED">6. <cite.query w-src-number="0304913967" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="28USCAS1332" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I573f20506b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">28 U.S.C. § 1332</cite.query>. Diversity of citizenship; amount in controversy; costs (as amended by Class Action Fairness Act of 2005)</entry></row><row><entry colname="1GENERATED">7. <cite.query w-src-number="0304913967" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="28USCAS1453" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I573f47606b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">28 U.S.C.A. § 1453</cite.query>. Removal of class actions (adopted as part of Class Action Fairness Act of 2005)</entry></row></tbody></tgroup><eos/></table><eop/></tbl><codes.excerpt ID="I0bfae2a0516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.section ID="I0bfae2a1516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><head parent="codes.section"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>1. </label.designator><headtext><cite.query w-src-number="0304913967" w-seq-number="00007" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="28USCAS1407" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I573f6e706b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">28 U.S.C. § 1407</cite.query>. Multidistrict litigation</headtext><eos/><eop/></head><codes.subsection ID="I0bfb09b0516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(a)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>When civil actions involving one or more common questions of fact are pending in different districts, such actions may be transferred to any district for coordinated or consolidated pretrial proceedings. <eos/><bos/>Such transfers shall be made by the judicial panel on multidistrict litigation authorized by this section upon its determination that transfers for such proceedings will be for the convenience of parties and witnesses and will promote the just and efficient conduct of such actions. <eos/><bos/>Each action so transferred shall be remanded by the panel at or before the conclusion of such pretrial proceedings to the district from which it was transferred unless it shall have been previously terminated: Provided, however, That the panel may separate any claim, cross-claim, counter-claim, or third-party claim and remand any of such claims before the remainder of the action is remanded.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0001"/></paratext><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection><codes.subsection ID="I0bfb57d0516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(b)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>Such coordinated or consolidated pretrial proceedings shall be conducted by a judge or judges to whom such actions are assigned by the judicial panel on multidistrict litigation. <eos/><bos/>For this purpose, upon request of the panel, a circuit judge or a district judge may be designated and assigned temporarily for service in the transferee district by the Chief Justice of the United States or the chief judge of the circuit, as may be required, in accordance with the provisions of chapter 13 of this title. <eos/><bos/>With the consent of the transferee district court, such actions may be assigned by the panel to a judge or judges of such district. <eos/><bos/>The judge or judges to whom such actions are assigned, the members of the judicial panel on multidistrict litigation, and other circuit and district judges designated when needed by the panel may exercise the powers of a district judge in any district for the purpose of conducting pretrial depositions in such coordinated or consolidated pretrial proceedings.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0002"/></paratext><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection><codes.subsection ID="I0bfbcd00516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(c)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0003"/>Proceedings for the transfer of an action under this section may be initiated by—<end.quote refid="QT_0003"/></paratext><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(i)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0004"/>the judicial panel on multidistrict litigation upon its own initiative, or<end.quote refid="QT_0004"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(ii)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0005"/>motion filed with the panel by a party in any action in which transfer for coordinated or consolidated pretrial proceedings under this section may be appropriate. <eos/><bos/>A copy of such motion shall be filed in the district court in which the moving party&apos;s action is pending.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0005"/></paratext></codes.para><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection><codes.subsection ID="I0bff2860516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0006"/>The panel shall give notice to the parties in all actions in which transfers for coordinated or consolidated pretrial proceedings are contemplated, and such notice shall specify the time and place of any hearing to determine whether such transfer shall be made. <eos/><bos/>Orders of the panel to set a hearing and other orders of the panel issued prior to the order either directing or denying transfer shall be filed in the office of the clerk of the district court in which a transfer hearing is to be or has been held. <eos/><bos/>The panel&apos;s order of transfer shall be based upon a record of such hearing at which material evidence may be offered by any party to an action pending in any district that would be affected by the proceedings under this section, and shall be supported by findings of fact and conclusions of law based upon such record. <eos/><bos/>Orders of transfer and such other orders as the panel may make thereafter shall be filed in the office of the clerk of the district court of the transferee district and shall be effective when thus filed. <eos/><bos/>The clerk of the transferee district court shall forthwith transmit a certified copy of the panel&apos;s order to transfer to the clerk of the district court from which the action is being transferred. <eos/><bos/>An order denying transfer shall be filed in each district wherein there is a case pending in which the motion for transfer has been made.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0006"/></paratext><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection><codes.subsection ID="I0bff2861516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(d)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0007"/>The judicial panel on multidistrict litigation shall consist of seven circuit and district judges designated from time to time by the Chief Justice of the United States, no two of whom shall be from the same circuit. <eos/><bos/>The concurrence of four members shall be necessary to any action by the panel.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0007"/></paratext><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection><codes.subsection ID="I0bff7680516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(e)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0008"/>No proceedings for review of any order of the panel may be permitted except by extraordinary writ pursuant to the provisions of <cite.query w-src-number="0304913967" w-seq-number="00008" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="28USCAS1651" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I5742a2c06b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">title 28, section 1651, United States Code</cite.query>. <eos/><bos/>Petitions for an extraordinary writ to review an order of the panel to set a transfer hearing and other orders of the panel issued prior to the order either directing or denying transfer shall be filed only in the court of appeals having jurisdiction over the district in which a hearing is to be or has been held. <eos/><bos/>Petitions for an extraordinary writ to review an order to transfer or orders subsequent to transfer shall be filed only in the court of appeals having jurisdiction over the transferee district. <eos/><bos/>There shall be no appeal or review of an order of the panel denying a motion to transfer for consolidated or coordinated proceedings.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0008"/></paratext><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection><codes.subsection ID="I0bff9d90516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(f)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0009"/>The panel may prescribe rules for the conduct of its business not inconsistent with Acts of Congress and the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0009"/></paratext><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection><codes.subsection ID="I0c025cb0516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(g)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0010"/>Nothing in this section shall apply to any action in which the United States is a complainant arising under the antitrust laws. “<eos/><bos/>Antitrust laws” as used herein include those acts referred to in the Act of October 15, 1914, as amended (38 Stat. 730; <cite.query w-src-number="0304913967" w-seq-number="00009" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="15USCAS12" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I574317f06b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">15 U.S.C. 12</cite.query>), and also include the Act of June 19, 1936 (49 Stat. 1526; <cite.query w-src-number="0304913967" w-seq-number="00010" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="15USCAS13" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I574317f16b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">15 U.S.C. 13</cite.query>, <cite.query w-src-number="0304913967" w-seq-number="00011" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="15USCAS13A" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I574317f26b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">13a</cite.query>, and <cite.query w-src-number="0304913967" w-seq-number="00012" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="15USCAS13B" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I574317f36b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">13b</cite.query>) and the Act of September 26, 1914, as added March 21, 1938 (52 Stat. 116, 117; <cite.query w-src-number="0304913967" w-seq-number="00013" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="15USCAS56" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I574317f46b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">15 U.S.C. 56</cite.query>); but shall not include section 4A of the Act of October 15, 1914, as added July 7, 1955 (69 Stat. 282; <cite.query w-src-number="0304913967" w-seq-number="00014" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="15USCAS15A" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I574317f56b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">15 U.S.C. 15a</cite.query>).<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0010"/></paratext><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection><codes.subsection ID="I0c05df20516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(h)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0011"/>Notwithstanding the provisions of section 1404 or subsection (f) of this section, the judicial panel on multidistrict litigation may consolidate and transfer with or without the consent of the parties, for both pretrial purposes and for trial, any action brought under section 4C of the Clayton Act.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0011"/></paratext><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection></codes.section><codes.section ID="I0c073eb0516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><head parent="codes.section"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>2. </label.designator><headtext><cite.query w-src-number="0304913967" w-seq-number="00015" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="28USCAS292" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I57438d206b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">28 U.S.C.A. § 292</cite.query>. District judges</headtext><eos/><eop/></head><codes.subsection ID="I0c0765c0516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(a)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0012"/>The chief judge of a circuit may designate and assign one or more district judges within the circuit to sit upon the court of appeals or a division thereof whenever the business of that court so requires. <eos/><bos/>Such designations or assignments shall be in conformity with the rules or orders of the court of appeals of the circuit.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0012"/></paratext><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection><codes.subsection ID="I0c078cd0516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(b)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0013"/>The chief judge of a circuit may, in the public interest, designate and assign temporarily any district judge of the circuit to hold a district court in any district within the circuit.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0013"/></paratext><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection><codes.subsection ID="I0c07daf0516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(c)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0014"/>The chief judge of the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit may, upon presentation of a certificate of necessity by the chief judge of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia pursuant to <cite.query w-src-number="0304913967" w-seq-number="00016" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="DCCODES11-908" w-pub-number="1000869" ID="I57453ad06b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">section 11-908(c) of the District of Columbia Code</cite.query>, designate and assign temporarily any district judge of the circuit to serve as a judge of such Superior Court, if such assignment (1) is approved by the Attorney General of the United States following a determination by him to the effect that such assignment is necessary to meet the ends of justice, and (2) is approved by the chief judge of the United States District Court for the District of Columbia.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0014"/></paratext><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection><codes.subsection ID="I0c080200516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(d)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0015"/>The Chief Justice of the United States may designate and assign temporarily a district judge of one circuit for service in another circuit, either in a district court or court of appeals, upon presentation of a certificate of necessity by the chief judge or circuit justice of the circuit wherein the need arises.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0015"/></paratext><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection><codes.subsection ID="I0c0a24e0516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(e)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0016"/>The Chief Justice of the United States may designate and assign temporarily any district judge to serve as a judge of the Court of International Trade upon presentation to him of a certificate of necessity by the chief judge of the court.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0016"/></paratext><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection></codes.section><codes.section ID="I0c0a7300516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><head parent="codes.section"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>3. </label.designator><headtext>§ 2112. Record on review and enforcement of agency orders</headtext><eos/><eop/></head><codes.subsection ID="I0c0a9a10516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(a)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0017"/>The rules prescribed under the authority of section 2072 of this title may provide for the time and manner of filing and the contents of the record in all proceedings instituted in the courts of appeals to enjoin, set aside, suspend, modify, or otherwise review or enforce orders of administrative agencies, boards, commissions, and officers. <eos/><bos/>Such rules may authorize the agency, board, commission, or officer to file in the court a certified list of the materials comprising the record and retain and hold for the court all such materials and transmit the same or any part thereof to the court, when and as required by it, at any time prior to the final determination of the proceeding, and such filing of such certified list of the materials comprising the record and such subsequent transmittal of any such materials when and as required shall be deemed full compliance with any provision of law requiring the filing of the record in the court. <eos/><bos/>The record in such proceedings shall be certified and filed in or held for and transmitted to the court of appeals by the agency, board, commission, or officer concerned within the time and in the manner prescribed by such rules. <eos/><bos/>If proceedings are instituted in two or more courts of appeals with respect to the same order, the following shall apply:<end.quote refid="QT_0017"/></paratext><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(1)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0018"/>If within ten days after issuance of the order the agency, board, commission, or officer concerned receives, from the persons instituting the proceedings, the petition for review with respect to proceedings in at least two courts of appeals, the agency, board, commission, or officer shall proceed in accordance with paragraph (3) of this subsection. <eos/><bos/>If within ten days after the issuance of the order the agency, board, commission, or officer concerned receives, from the persons instituting the proceedings, the petition for review with respect to proceedings in only one court of appeals, the agency, board, commission, or officer shall file the record in that court notwithstanding the institution in any other court of appeals of proceedings for review of that order. <eos/><bos/>In all other cases in which proceedings have been instituted in two or more courts of appeals with respect to the same order, the agency, board, commission, or officer concerned shall file the record in the court in which proceedings with respect to the order were first instituted.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0018"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(2)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0019"/>For purposes of paragraph (1) of this subsection, a copy of the petition or other pleading which institutes proceedings in a court of appeals and which is stamped by the court with the date of filing shall constitute the petition for review. <eos/><bos/>Each agency, board, commission, or officer, as the case may be, shall designate by rule the office and the officer who must receive petitions for review under paragraph (1).<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0019"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(3)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0020"/>If an agency, board, commission, or officer receives two or more petitions for review of an order in accordance with the first sentence of paragraph (1) of this subsection, the agency, board, commission, or officer shall, promptly after the expiration of the ten-day period specified in that sentence, so notify the judicial panel on multidistrict litigation authorized by <cite.query w-src-number="0304913967" w-seq-number="00017" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="28USCAS1407" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I574980906b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">section 1407</cite.query> of this title, in such form as that panel shall prescribe. <eos/><bos/>The judicial panel on multidistrict litigation shall, by means of random selection, designate one court of appeals, from among the courts of appeals in which petitions for review have been filed and received within the ten-day period specified in the first sentence of paragraph (1), in which the record is to be filed, and shall issue an order consolidating the petitions for review in that court of appeals. <eos/><bos/>The judicial panel on multidistrict litigation shall, after providing notice to the public and an opportunity for the submission of comments, prescribe rules with respect to the consolidation of proceedings under this paragraph. <eos/><bos/>The agency, board, commission, or officer concerned shall file the record in the court of appeals designated pursuant to this paragraph.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0020"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(4)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0021"/>Any court of appeals in which proceedings with respect to an order of an agency, board, commission, or officer have been instituted may, to the extent authorized by law, stay the effective date of the order. <eos/><bos/>Any such stay may thereafter be modified, revoked, or extended by a court of appeals designated pursuant to paragraph (3) with respect to that order or by any other court of appeals to which the proceedings are transferred.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0021"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(5)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0022"/>All courts in which proceedings are instituted with respect to the same order, other than the court in which the record is filed pursuant to this subsection, shall transfer those proceedings to the court in which the record is so filed. <eos/><bos/>For the convenience of the parties in the interest of justice, the court in which the record is filed may thereafter transfer all the proceedings with respect to that order to any other court of appeals.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0022"/></paratext></codes.para><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection><codes.subsection ID="I0c108d80516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(b)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0023"/>The record to be filed in the court of appeals in such a proceeding shall consist of the order sought to be reviewed or enforced, the findings or report upon which it is based, and the pleadings, evidence, and proceedings before the agency, board, commission, or officer concerned, or such portions thereof (1) as the rules prescribed under the authority of section 2072 of this title may require to be included therein, or (2) as the agency, board, commission, or officer concerned, the petitioner for review or respondent in enforcement, as the case may be, and any intervenor in the court proceeding by written stipulation filed with the agency, board, commission, or officer concerned or in the court in any such proceeding may consistently with the rules prescribed under the authority of section 2072 of this title designate to be included therein, or (3) as the court upon motion of a party or, after a prehearing conference, upon its own motion may by order in any such proceeding designate to be included therein. <eos/><bos/>Such a stipulation or order may provide in an appropriate case that no record need be filed in the court of appeals. <eos/><bos/>If, however, the correctness of a finding of fact by the agency, board, commission, or officer is in question all of the evidence before the agency, board, commission, or officer shall be included in the record except such as the agency, board, commission, or officer concerned, the petitioner for review or respondent in enforcement, as the case may be, and any intervenor in the court proceeding by written stipulation filed with the agency, board, commission, or officer concerned or in the court agree to omit as wholly immaterial to the questioned finding. <eos/><bos/>If there is omitted from the record any portion of the proceedings before the agency, board, commission, or officer which the court subsequently determines to be proper for it to consider to enable it to review or enforce the order in question the court may direct that such additional portion of the proceedings be filed as a supplement to the record. <eos/><bos/>The agency, board, commission, or officer concerned may, at its option and without regard to the foregoing provisions of this subsection, and if so requested by the petitioner for review or respondent in enforcement shall, file in the court the entire record of the proceedings before it without abbreviation.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0023"/></paratext><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection><codes.subsection ID="I0c10dba0516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(c)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0024"/>The agency, board, commission, or officer concerned may transmit to the court of appeals the original papers comprising the whole or any part of the record or any supplemental record, otherwise true copies of such papers certified by an authorized officer or deputy of the agency, board, commission, or officer concerned shall be transmitted. <eos/><bos/>Any original papers thus transmitted to the court of appeals shall be returned to the agency, board, commission, or officer concerned upon the final determination of the review or enforcement proceeding. <eos/><bos/>Pending such final determination any such papers may be returned by the court temporarily to the custody of the agency, board, commission, or officer concerned if needed for the transaction of the public business. <eos/><bos/>Certified copies of any papers included in the record or any supplemental record may also be returned to the agency, board, commission, or officer concerned upon the final determination of review or enforcement proceedings.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0024"/></paratext><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection><codes.subsection ID="I0c1102b0516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(d)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0025"/>The provisions of this section are not applicable to proceedings to review decisions of the Tax Court of the United States or to proceedings to review or enforce those orders of administrative agencies, boards, commissions, or officers which are by law reviewable or enforceable by the district courts.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0025"/></paratext><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection></codes.section><codes.section ID="I0c1150d0516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><head parent="codes.section"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>4. </label.designator><headtext><cite.query w-src-number="0304913967" w-seq-number="00018" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="28USCAS1369" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I574ba3706b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">28 U.S.C.A. § 1369</cite.query>. Multiparty, multiforum jurisdiction</headtext><eos/><eop/></head><codes.subsection ID="I0c1177e0516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(a) </label.designator><headtext>In general.—</headtext></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0026"/>The district courts shall have original jurisdiction of any civil action involving minimal diversity between adverse parties that arises from a single accident, where at least 75 natural persons have died in the accident at a discrete location, if—<end.quote refid="QT_0026"/></paratext><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(1)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0027"/>a defendant resides in a State and a substantial part of the accident took place in another State or other location, regardless of whether that defendant is also a resident of the State where a substantial part of the accident took place;<end.quote refid="QT_0027"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(2)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0028"/>any two defendants reside in different States, regardless of whether such defendants are also residents of the same State or States; or<end.quote refid="QT_0028"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(3)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0029"/>substantial parts of the accident took place in different States.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0029"/></paratext></codes.para><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection><codes.subsection ID="I0c132590516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(b) </label.designator><headtext>Limitation of jurisdiction of district courts.—</headtext></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0030"/>The district court shall abstain from hearing any civil action described in subsection (a) in which—<end.quote refid="QT_0030"/></paratext><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(1)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0031"/>the substantial majority of all plaintiffs are citizens of a single State of which the primary defendants are also citizens; and<end.quote refid="QT_0031"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(2)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0032"/>the claims asserted will be governed primarily by the laws of that State.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0032"/></paratext></codes.para><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection><codes.subsection ID="I0c14fa50516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(c) </label.designator><headtext>Special rules and definitions.—</headtext></head><paratext>For purposes of this section—</paratext><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(1)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0033"/>minimal diversity exists between adverse parties if any party is a citizen of a State and any adverse party is a citizen of another State, a citizen or subject of a foreign state, or a foreign state as defined in section 1603(a) of this title;<end.quote refid="QT_0033"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(2)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0034"/>a corporation is deemed to be a citizen of any State, and a citizen or subject of any foreign state, in which it is incorporated or has its principal place of business, and is deemed to be a resident of any State in which it is incorporated or licensed to do business or is doing business;<end.quote refid="QT_0034"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(3)</label.designator></head><paratext>the term “injury” means—</paratext><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(A)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0035"/>physical harm to a natural person; and<end.quote refid="QT_0035"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(B)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0036"/>physical damage to or destruction of tangible property, but only if physical harm described in subparagraph (A) exists;<end.quote refid="QT_0036"/></paratext></codes.para></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(4)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0037"/>the term “accident” means a sudden accident, or a natural event culminating in an accident, that results in death incurred at a discrete location by at least 75 natural persons; and<end.quote refid="QT_0037"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(5)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0038"/>the term “State” includes the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and any territory or possession of the United States.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0038"/></paratext></codes.para><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection><codes.subsection ID="I0c191900516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(d) </label.designator><headtext>Intervening parties.—</headtext></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0039"/>In any action in a district court which is or could have been brought, in whole or in part, under this section, any person with a claim arising from the accident described in subsection (a) shall be permitted to intervene as a party plaintiff in the action, even if that person could not have brought an action in a district court as an original matter.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0039"/></paratext><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection><codes.subsection ID="I0c19b540516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(e) </label.designator><headtext>Notification of judicial panel on multidistrict litigation.—</headtext></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0040"/>A district court in which an action under this section is pending shall promptly notify the judicial panel on multidistrict litigation of the pendency of the action.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0040"/></paratext><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection></codes.section><codes.section ID="I0c1a0360516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><head parent="codes.section"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>5. </label.designator><headtext><cite.query w-src-number="0304913967" w-seq-number="00019" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="45USCAS719" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I574e14706b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">45 U.S.C. § 719</cite.query>. Judicial review</headtext><eos/><eop/></head><codes.subsection ID="I0c1a2a70516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(a) </label.designator><headtext>General</headtext></head><eos/><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection><codes.subsection ID="I0c1a5180516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0041"/>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the final system plan which is adopted by the Association and which becomes effective after review by the Congress is not subject to review by any court except in accordance with this section. <eos/><bos/>After the final system plan becomes effective under section 718 of this title, it may be reviewed with respect to matters concerning the value of the rail properties to be conveyed under the plan and the value of the consideration to be received for such properties.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0041"/></paratext><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection><codes.subsection ID="I0c1a7890516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(b) </label.designator><headtext>Special court</headtext></head><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(1)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0042"/>Within 30 days after January 2, 1974, the Association shall make application to the judicial panel on multi-district litigation authorized by <cite.query w-src-number="0304913967" w-seq-number="00020" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="28USCAS1407" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I57536ba06b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">section 1407 of Title 28</cite.query> for the consolidation in a single, three-judge district court of the United States of all judicial proceedings with respect to the final system plan. <eos/><bos/>Within 30 days after such application is received, the panel shall make the consolidation in a district court (cited herein as the “special court”) which the panel determines to be convenient to the parties and the one most likely to be able to conduct any proceedings under this section with the least delay and the greatest possible fairness and ability. <eos/><bos/>Such proceedings shall be conducted by the special court which shall be composed of three Federal judges who shall be selected by the panel, except that none of the judges selected may be a judge assigned to a proceeding involving any railroad in reorganization in the region under section 77 of the Bankruptcy Act. <eos/><bos/>The special court is authorized to exercise the powers of a district judge in any judicial district with respect to such proceedings and such powers shall include those of a reorganization court. <eos/><bos/>The special court shall have the power to order the conveyance of rail properties of railroads leased, operated, or controlled by a railroad in reorganization in the region. <eos/><bos/>The special court may issue rules for the conduct of any proceedings under this section and under section 745 of this title, including rules with respect to the time within which motions may be filed, and with respect to appropriate representation of interests not otherwise represented (including the Secretary with respect to a petition by the Association in the case of a proposal developed by the Secretary, under such section 745 of this title).<eos/><bos/> No determination by the panel under this subsection may be reviewed in any court.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0042"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(2)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0043"/>The special court referred to in paragraph (1) of this subsection is abolished effective 90 days after October 19, 1996. <eos/><bos/>On such effective date, all jurisdiction and other functions of the special court shall be assumed by the United States District Court for the District of Columbia. <eos/><bos/>With respect to any proceedings that arise or continue after the date on which the special court is abolished, the references in the following provisions to the special court established under this subsection shall be deemed to refer to the United States District Court for the District of Columbia:<end.quote refid="QT_0043"/></paratext><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(A)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0044"/>Subsections (c), (e)(1), (e)(2), (f) and (g) of this section.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0044"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(B)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0045"/>Sections 712(d)(3), (g), 717(a)(1), (b)(1), (b)(2), 718(d)(2), 741(e)(2), (g), (k)(3), (k)(15), 743(a)(1), (a)(2), (b)(1), (b)(6)(A), (c)(1), (c)(2), (c)(3), (c)(4), (c)(5), 744(a)(1)(B), (i)(3), 745(c), (d)(1), (d)(2), (d)(3), (d)(4), (d)(5), (d)(8), (e), (f)(1), (f)(2)(B), (f)(2)(D), (f)(2)(E), (f)(3), 746(a), (b), (c)(4), and 791(b)(3), (c) of this title.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0045"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(C)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0046"/>Sections 1105(a) and 1115 of this title.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0046"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(D)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0047"/>Sections 1323(2)(A)(iii), (2)(B), (2)(C), (3)(C), (3)(E), (4)(A) and 1324(b) of this title.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0047"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(E)</label.designator></head><paratext>Section 24907(b) of Title 49.<eos/><bos/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(F)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0048"/>Any other Federal law (other than this subsection and section 605 of the Federal Courts Improvement Act of 1996), Executive order, rule, regulation, delegation of authority, or document of or relating to the special court as previously established under paragraph (1) of this subsection.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0048"/></paratext></codes.para></codes.para><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection><codes.subsection ID="I0c20ba20516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(c) </label.designator><headtext>Delivery of plan to special court</headtext></head><eos/><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection><codes.subsection ID="I0c20e130516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0049"/>Within 90 days after its effective date, the Association shall deliver a certified copy of the final system plan to the special court and shall certify to the special court—<end.quote refid="QT_0049"/></paratext><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(1)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0050"/>which rail properties of the respective railroads in reorganization in the region and of any person leased, operated, or controlled by such railroads in reorganization are to be transferred to the Corporation, or any subsidiary thereof, in accordance with the final system plan;<end.quote refid="QT_0050"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(2)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0051"/>which rail properties of the respective railroads in reorganization in the region or person leased, operated, or controlled by such railroads in reorganization are to be conveyed to profitable railroads, in accordance with the final system plan;<end.quote refid="QT_0051"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(3)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0052"/>the amount, terms, and value of the securities of the Corporation or any subsidiary thereof (including any certificates of value of the Association) to be exchanged for those rail properties to be transferred to the Corporation or any subsidiary thereof pursuant to the final system plan, and as indicated in paragraph (1) of this subsection; and<end.quote refid="QT_0052"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(4)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0053"/>that the transfer of rail properties in exchange for securities of the Corporation or any subsidiary thereof (including any certificates of value of the Association) and other benefits is fair and equitable and in the public interest.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0053"/></paratext></codes.para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0054"/>Notwithstanding any other provisions of this subsection and subsection (d) of this section, the time for the delivery of a certified copy of the final system plan shall be March 12, 1976, and may be extended to a date not more than 30 days thereafter, prescribed in a notice filed by the Association not later than February 17, 1976, with the special court, the Congress, and each court referred to in such subsection (d) of this section. <eos/><bos/>Such notice shall contain the certification of the Association that an orderly conveyance of rail properties cannot reasonably be effected before the date for conveyance determined with respect to such notice. <eos/><bos/>The time prescribed in section 743(a) of this title shall be determined with respect to the date prescribed in such notice.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0054"/></paratext><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection><codes.subsection ID="I0c2219b0516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(d) </label.designator><headtext>Bankruptcy courts</headtext></head><eos/><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection><codes.subsection ID="I0c2240c0516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0055"/>Within 90 days after its effective date, the Association shall deliver a certified copy of the final system plan to each district court of the United States or any other court having jurisdiction over a railroad in reorganization in the region and shall certify to each such court—<end.quote refid="QT_0055"/></paratext><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(1)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0056"/>which rail properties of that railroad in reorganization are to be transferred to the Corporation or any subsidiary thereof under the final system plan; and<end.quote refid="QT_0056"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(2)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0057"/>which rail properties of that railroad in reorganization, if any, are to be conveyed to profitable railroads operating in the region, under the final system plan.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0057"/></paratext></codes.para><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection><codes.subsection ID="I0c22dd00516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(e) </label.designator><headtext>Original and exclusive jurisdiction</headtext></head><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(1)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0058"/>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any civil action—<end.quote refid="QT_0058"/></paratext><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(A)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0059"/>for injunctive or other relief against the Association from the enforcement, operation, or execution of this chapter or any provision thereof, or from any action taken by the Association pursuant to authority conferred or purportedly conferred under this chapter;<end.quote refid="QT_0059"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(B)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0060"/>challenging the constitutionality of this chapter or any provision thereof;<end.quote refid="QT_0060"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(C)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0061"/>challenging the legality of any action of the Association, or any failure of the Association to take any action, pursuant to authority conferred or purportedly conferred under this chapter;<end.quote refid="QT_0061"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(D)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0062"/>to obtain, inspect, copy, or review any document in the possession or control of the Association that would be discoverable in litigation pursuant to section 743(c) of this title;<end.quote refid="QT_0062"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(E)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0063"/>brought after a conveyance, pursuant to section 743(b) of this title, to set aside or annul such conveyance or to secure in any way the reconveyance of any rail properties so conveyed; or<end.quote refid="QT_0063"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(F)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0064"/>with respect to continuing reorganization and supplemental transactions, in accordance with section 745 of this title;<end.quote refid="QT_0064"/></paratext></codes.para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0065"/>shall be within the original and exclusive jurisdiction of the special court. <eos/><bos/>The special court shall not hear or determine any such action prior to the date of conveyance, pursuant to section 743(b)(1) of this title, except as the Constitution may require. <eos/><bos/>Relief shall not be granted in any action referred to in subparagraph (A), (C), or (E) unless the person seeking such relief establishes that the Association acted in reckless or deliberate disregard of applicable law.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0065"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(2)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0066"/>The original and exclusive jurisdiction of the special court shall include any action, whether filed by any interested person or initiated by the special court itself, to interpret, alter, amend, modify, or implement any of the orders entered by such court pursuant to section 743(b) of this title in order to effect the purposes of this chapter or the goals of the final system plan. <eos/><bos/>During the pendency of any proceeding described in this paragraph, the special court may enter such orders as it determines to be appropriate, including orders enjoining, restraining, conditioning, or limiting any conveyance, transfer, or use of any asset or right which is subject to such an order or which is at issue in such a proceeding, or which involves the enforcement of any liens or encumbrances upon such assets or rights. <eos/><bos/>Any orders pursuant to this paragraph which interpret, alter, amend, modify, or implement orders entered by the special court shall be final and shall not be restrained or enjoined by any court.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0066"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(3)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0067"/>An order or judgment of the United States District Court for the District of Columbia in any action referred to in this section shall be reviewable in accordance with sections 1291, 1292, and 1294 of Title 28.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0067"/></paratext></codes.para><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection><codes.subsection ID="I0c268680516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(f) </label.designator><headtext>Disposition of cash deposits</headtext></head><eos/><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection><codes.subsection ID="I0c26d4a0516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0068"/>Whenever the compensation which is deposited with the special court under section 743(a) of this title is in the form of cash, such cash shall be invested and reinvested upon such terms and conditions as the special court shall determine, pending the making of the findings referred to in paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of section 743(c) of this title. <eos/><bos/>Notwithstanding section 743(c)(4) of this title, the special court may order (1) the income from such investments, (2) the dividends or interest, if any, received on any securities or obligations deposited with the special court under such section 743(a) of this title, and (3) the income, if any, received with respect to any other form of compensation so deposited, to be distributed to the trustee of each railroad in reorganization and to any person leased, operated or controlled by such a railroad which conveyed the right, title, and interest in the rail properties with respect to which such cash, securities, obligations, or other compensation have been so deposited with the special court. <eos/><bos/>Notwithstanding section 743(c)(4) of this title, the special court may, within 90 days after the date of conveyance of rail properties pursuant to section 743(b) of this title, order up to 25 percent of any cash (including investments made with cash) and other compensation deposited with the special court to be distributed to such trustee or person. <eos/><bos/>On petition of the applicable trustee or person, the special court may order such additional distributions as it finds reasonable and appropriate, prior to the making of the findings referred to in paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of such section 743(c) of this title.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0068"/></paratext><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection><codes.subsection ID="I0c2770e0516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(g) </label.designator><headtext>Stay of court proceedings</headtext></head><eos/><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection><codes.subsection ID="I0c2797f0516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0069"/>The special court may stay or enjoin any action or proceeding in any State court or in any court of the United States other than the Supreme Court or Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit if such action or proceeding is contrary to any provision of this chapter, impairs the effective implementation of this chapter, or interferes with the execution of any order of the special court pursuant to this chapter.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0069"/></paratext><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection><codes.subsection ID="I0c27bf00516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(h) </label.designator><headtext>Repealed.</headtext></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0070"/><cite.query w-seq-number="00021" w-ref-type="SL" w-normalized-cite="I7C34237561-1B4EB9997CD-ED20ABB83D0" w-pub-number="1077005" ID="I575d7dc16b3e11e9ac68aff86f85b2c9">Pub.L. 104-317, Title VI, § 605(c)(1)(B)</cite.query>, Oct. 19, 1996, 110 Stat. 3859<end.quote refid="QT_0070"/></paratext><eos/><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection></codes.section><codes.section ID="I0c283430516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><head parent="codes.section"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>6. </label.designator><headtext><cite.query w-src-number="0304913967" w-seq-number="00022" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="28USCAS1332" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I575da4d06b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">28 U.S.C. § 1332</cite.query>. Diversity of citizenship; amount in controversy; costs (as amended by Class Action Fairness Act of 2005)</headtext><eos/><eop/></head><codes.subsection ID="I0c288250516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(a)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0071"/>The district courts shall have original jurisdiction of all civil actions where the matter in controversy exceeds the sum or value of $75,000, exclusive of interest and costs, and is between—<end.quote refid="QT_0071"/></paratext><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(1)</label.designator></head><paratext>citizens of different States;</paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(2)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0072"/>citizens of a State and citizens or subjects of a foreign state;<end.quote refid="QT_0072"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(3)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0073"/>citizens of different States and in which citizens or subjects of a foreign state are additional parties; and<end.quote refid="QT_0073"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(4)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0074"/>a foreign state, defined in section 1603(a) of this title, as plaintiff and citizens of a State or of different States.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0074"/></paratext></codes.para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0075"/>For the purposes of this section, section 1335, and section 1441, an alien admitted to the United States for permanent residence shall be deemed a citizen of the State in which such alien is domiciled.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0075"/></paratext><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection><codes.subsection ID="I0c29bad0516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(b)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0076"/>Except when express provision therefor is otherwise made in a statute of the United States, where the plaintiff who files the case originally in the Federal courts is finally adjudged to be entitled to recover less than the sum or value of $75,000, computed without regard to any setoff or counterclaim to which the defendant may be adjudged to be entitled, and exclusive of interest and costs, the district court may deny costs to the plaintiff and, in addition, may impose costs on the plaintiff.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0076"/></paratext><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection><codes.subsection ID="I0c29e1e0516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(c)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0077"/>For the purposes of this section and section 1441 of this title—<end.quote refid="QT_0077"/></paratext><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(1)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0078"/>a corporation shall be deemed to be a citizen of any State by which it has been incorporated and of the State where it has its principal place of business, except that in any direct action against the insurer of a policy or contract of liability insurance, whether incorporated or unincorporated, to which action the insured is not joined as a party-defendant, such insurer shall be deemed a citizen of the State of which the insured is a citizen, as well as of any State by which the insurer has been incorporated and of the State where it has its principal place of business; and<end.quote refid="QT_0078"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(2)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0079"/>the legal representative of the estate of a decedent shall be deemed to be a citizen only of the same State as the decedent, and the legal representative of an infant or incompetent shall be deemed to be a citizen only of the same State as the infant or incompetent.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0079"/></paratext></codes.para><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection><codes.subsection ID="I0c2a7e20516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(d)</label.designator></head><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(1)</label.designator></head><paratext>In this subsection—</paratext><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(A)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0080"/>the term “class” means all of the class members in a class action;<end.quote refid="QT_0080"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(B)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0081"/>the term “class action” means any civil action filed under <cite.query w-src-number="0304913967" w-seq-number="00023" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="USFRCPR23" w-pub-number="1000600" ID="I575f79906b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">rule 23 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure</cite.query> or similar State statute or rule of judicial procedure authorizing an action to be brought by 1 or more representative persons as a class action;<end.quote refid="QT_0081"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(C)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0082"/>the term “class certification order” means an order issued by a court approving the treatment of some or all aspects of a civil action as a class action; and<end.quote refid="QT_0082"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(D)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0083"/>the term “class members” means the persons (named or unnamed) who fall within the definition of the proposed or certified class in a class action.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0083"/></paratext></codes.para></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(2)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0084"/>The district courts shall have original jurisdiction of any civil action in which the matter in controversy exceeds the sum or value of $5,000,000, exclusive of interest and costs, and is a class action in which—<end.quote refid="QT_0084"/></paratext><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(A)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0085"/>any member of a class of plaintiffs is a citizen of a State different from any defendant;<end.quote refid="QT_0085"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(B)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0086"/>any member of a class of plaintiffs is a foreign state or a citizen or subject of a foreign state and any defendant is a citizen of a State; or<end.quote refid="QT_0086"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(C)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0087"/>any member of a class of plaintiffs is a citizen of a State and any defendant is a foreign state or a citizen or subject of a foreign state.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0087"/></paratext></codes.para></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(3)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0088"/>A district court may, in the interests of justice and looking at the totality of the circumstances, decline to exercise jurisdiction under paragraph (2) over a class action in which greater than one-third but less than two-thirds of the members of all proposed plaintiff classes in the aggregate and the primary defendants are citizens of the State in which the action was originally filed based on consideration of—<end.quote refid="QT_0088"/></paratext><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(A)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0089"/>whether the claims asserted involve matters of national or interstate interest;<end.quote refid="QT_0089"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(B)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0090"/>whether the claims asserted will be governed by laws of the State in which the action was originally filed or by the laws of other States;<end.quote refid="QT_0090"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(C)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0091"/>whether the class action has been pleaded in a manner that seeks to avoid Federal jurisdiction;<end.quote refid="QT_0091"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(D)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0092"/>whether the action was brought in a forum with a distinct nexus with the class members, the alleged harm, or the defendants;<end.quote refid="QT_0092"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(E)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0093"/>whether the number of citizens of the State in which the action was originally filed in all proposed plaintiff classes in the aggregate is substantially larger than the number of citizens from any other State, and the citizenship of the other members of the proposed class is dispersed among a substantial number of States; and<end.quote refid="QT_0093"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(F)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0094"/>whether, during the 3-year period preceding the filing of that class action, 1 or more other class actions asserting the same or similar claims on behalf of the same or other persons have been filed.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0094"/></paratext></codes.para></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(4)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0095"/>A district court shall decline to exercise jurisdiction under paragraph (2)—<end.quote refid="QT_0095"/></paratext><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(A)</label.designator></head><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(i)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0096"/>over a class action in which—<end.quote refid="QT_0096"/></paratext><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(I)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0097"/>greater than two-thirds of the members of all proposed plaintiff classes in the aggregate are citizens of the State in which the action was originally filed;<end.quote refid="QT_0097"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(II)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0098"/>at least 1 defendant is a defendant—<end.quote refid="QT_0098"/></paratext><codes.unit ID="I0c3e2d30516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(aa)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0099"/>from whom significant relief is sought by members of the plaintiff class;<end.quote refid="QT_0099"/></paratext></codes.para></codes.unit><codes.unit ID="I0c3e7b50516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(bb)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0100"/>whose alleged conduct forms a significant basis for the claims asserted by the proposed plaintiff class; and<end.quote refid="QT_0100"/></paratext></codes.para></codes.unit><codes.unit ID="I0c3ec970516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(cc)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0101"/>who is a citizen of the State in which the action was originally filed; and<end.quote refid="QT_0101"/></paratext></codes.para></codes.unit></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(III)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0102"/>principal injuries resulting from the alleged conduct or any related conduct of each defendant were incurred in the State in which the action was originally filed; and<end.quote refid="QT_0102"/></paratext></codes.para></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(ii)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0103"/>during the 3-year period preceding the filing of that class action, no other class action has been filed asserting the same or similar factual allegations against any of the defendants on behalf of the same or other persons; or<end.quote refid="QT_0103"/></paratext></codes.para></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(B)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0104"/>two-thirds or more of the members of all proposed plaintiff classes in the aggregate, and the primary defendants, are citizens of the State in which the action was originally filed.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0104"/></paratext></codes.para></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(5)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0105"/>Paragraphs (2) through (4) shall not apply to any class action in which—<end.quote refid="QT_0105"/></paratext><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(A)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0106"/>the primary defendants are States, State officials, or other governmental entities against whom the district court may be foreclosed from ordering relief; or<end.quote refid="QT_0106"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(B)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0107"/>the number of members of all proposed plaintiff classes in the aggregate is less than 100.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0107"/></paratext></codes.para></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(6)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0108"/>In any class action, the claims of the individual class members shall be aggregated to determine whether the matter in controversy exceeds the sum or value of $5,000,000, exclusive of interest and costs.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0108"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(7)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0109"/>Citizenship of the members of the proposed plaintiff classes shall be determined for purposes of paragraphs (2) through (6) as of the date of filing of the complaint or amended complaint, or, if the case stated by the initial pleading is not subject to Federal jurisdiction, as of the date of service by plaintiffs of an amended pleading, motion, or other paper, indicating the existence of Federal jurisdiction.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0109"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(8)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0110"/>This subsection shall apply to any class action before or after the entry of a class certification order by the court with respect to that action.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0110"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(9)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0111"/>Paragraph (2) shall not apply to any class action that solely involves a claim—<end.quote refid="QT_0111"/></paratext><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(A)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0112"/>concerning a covered security as defined under 16(f)(3) [FN1] of the Securities Act of 1933 (<cite.query w-src-number="0304913967" w-seq-number="00024" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="15USCAS78P" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I576398406b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">15 U.S.C. 78p(f)(3)</cite.query>) and section 28(f)(5)(E) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<cite.query w-src-number="0304913967" w-seq-number="00025" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="15USCAS78BB" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I576398416b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">15 U.S.C. 78bb(f)(5)(E)</cite.query>);<end.quote refid="QT_0112"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(B)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0113"/>that relates to the internal affairs or governance of a corporation or other form of business enterprise and that arises under or by virtue of the laws of the State in which such corporation or business enterprise is incorporated or organized; or<end.quote refid="QT_0113"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(C)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0114"/>that relates to the rights, duties (including fiduciary duties), and obligations relating to or created by or pursuant to any security (as defined under section 2(a)(1) of the Securities Act of 1933 (<cite.query w-src-number="0304913967" w-seq-number="00026" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="15USCAS77B" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I5763e6606b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">15 U.S.C. 77b(a)(1)</cite.query>) and the regulations issued thereunder).<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0114"/></paratext></codes.para></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(10)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0115"/>For purposes of this subsection and <cite.query w-src-number="0304913967" w-seq-number="00027" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="28USCAS1453" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I576609406b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">section 1453</cite.query>, an unincorporated association shall be deemed to be a citizen of the State where it has its principal place of business and the State under whose laws it is organized.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0115"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(11)</label.designator></head><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(A)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0116"/>For purposes of this subsection and <cite.query w-src-number="0304913967" w-seq-number="00028" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="28USCAS1453" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I576c71e06b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">section 1453</cite.query>, a mass action shall be deemed to be a class action removable under paragraphs (2) through (10) if it otherwise meets the provisions of those paragraphs.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0116"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(B)</label.designator></head><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(i)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0117"/>As used in subparagraph (A), the term “mass action” means any civil action (except a civil action within the scope of section 1711(2)) in which monetary relief claims of 100 or more persons are proposed to be tried jointly on the ground that the plaintiffs&apos; claims involve common questions of law or fact, except that jurisdiction shall exist only over those plaintiffs whose claims in a mass action satisfy the jurisdictional amount requirements under subsection (a).<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0117"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(ii)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0118"/>As used in subparagraph (A), the term “mass action” shall not include any civil action in which—<end.quote refid="QT_0118"/></paratext><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(I)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0119"/>all of the claims in the action arise from an event or occurrence in the State in which the action was filed, and that allegedly resulted in injuries in that State or in States contiguous to that State;<end.quote refid="QT_0119"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(II)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0120"/>the claims are joined upon motion of a defendant;<end.quote refid="QT_0120"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(III)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0121"/>all of the claims in the action are asserted on behalf of the general public (and not on behalf of individual claimants or members of a purported class) pursuant to a State statute specifically authorizing such action; or<end.quote refid="QT_0121"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(IV)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0122"/>the claims have been consolidated or coordinated solely for pretrial proceedings.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0122"/></paratext></codes.para></codes.para></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(C)</label.designator></head><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(i)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0123"/>Any action(s) removed to Federal court pursuant to this subsection shall not thereafter be transferred to any other court pursuant to <cite.query w-src-number="0304913967" w-seq-number="00029" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="28USCAS1407" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I57712cd06b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">section 1407</cite.query>, or the rules promulgated thereunder, unless a majority of the plaintiffs in the action request transfer pursuant to <cite.query w-src-number="0304913967" w-seq-number="00030" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="28USCAS1407" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I57712cd16b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">section 1407</cite.query>.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0123"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(ii)</label.designator></head><paratext>This subparagraph will not apply—</paratext><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(I)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0124"/>to cases certified pursuant to <cite.query w-src-number="0304913967" w-seq-number="00031" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="USFRCPR23" w-pub-number="1000600" ID="I5771c9106b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">rule 23 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure</cite.query>; or<end.quote refid="QT_0124"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(II)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0125"/>if plaintiffs propose that the action proceed as a class action pursuant to <cite.query w-src-number="0304913967" w-seq-number="00032" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="USFRCPR23" w-pub-number="1000600" ID="I5771f0206b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">rule 23 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure</cite.query>.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0125"/></paratext></codes.para></codes.para></codes.para></codes.para><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection><codes.subsection ID="I0c5055a0516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(d)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0126"/>The limitations periods on any claims asserted in a mass action that is removed to Federal court pursuant to this subsection shall be deemed tolled during the period that the action is pending in Federal court.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0126"/></paratext><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection><codes.subsection ID="I0c516710516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(e)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0127"/>The word “States”, as used in this section, includes the Territories, the District of Columbia, and the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0127"/></paratext><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection></codes.section><codes.section ID="I0c51b530516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><head parent="codes.section"><bop/><bos/><label.designator>7. </label.designator><headtext><cite.query w-src-number="0304913967" w-seq-number="00033" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="28USCAS1453" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I577265506b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">28 U.S.C.A. § 1453</cite.query>. Removal of class actions (adopted as part of Class Action Fairness Act of 2005)</headtext><eos/><eop/></head><codes.subsection ID="I0c51dc40516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(a) </label.designator><headtext>Definitions.—</headtext></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0128"/>In this section, the terms “class”, “class action”, “class certification order”, and “class member” shall have the meanings given such terms under <cite.query w-src-number="0304913967" w-seq-number="00034" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="28USCAS1332" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I57743a106b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">section 1332(d)(1)</cite.query>.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0128"/></paratext><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection><codes.subsection ID="I0c52c6a0516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(b) </label.designator><headtext>In general.—</headtext></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0129"/>A class action may be removed to a district court of the United States in accordance with section 1446 (except that the 1-year limitation under section 1446(b) shall not apply), without regard to whether any defendant is a citizen of the State in which the action is brought, except that such action may be removed by any defendant without the consent of all defendants.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0129"/></paratext><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection><codes.subsection ID="I0c533bd0516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(c) </label.designator><headtext>Review of remand orders.—</headtext></head><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(1) </label.designator><headtext>In general.—</headtext></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0130"/>Section 1447 shall apply to any removal of a case under this section, except that notwithstanding section 1447(d), a court of appeals may accept an appeal from an order of a district court granting or denying a motion to remand a class action to the State court from which it was removed if application is made to the court of appeals not less than 7 days after entry of the order.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0130"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(2) </label.designator><headtext>Time period for judgment.—</headtext></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0131"/>If the court of appeals accepts an appeal under paragraph (1), the court shall complete all action on such appeal, including rendering judgment, not later than 60 days after the date on which such appeal was filed, unless an extension is granted under paragraph (3).<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0131"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(3) </label.designator><headtext>Extension of time period.—</headtext></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0132"/>The court of appeals may grant an extension of the 60-day period described in paragraph (2) if—<end.quote refid="QT_0132"/></paratext><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(A)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0133"/>all parties to the proceeding agree to such extension, for any period of time; or<end.quote refid="QT_0133"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(B)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0134"/>such extension is for good cause shown and in the interests of justice, for a period not to exceed 10 days.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0134"/></paratext></codes.para></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(4) </label.designator><headtext>Denial of appeal.—</headtext></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0135"/>If a final judgment on the appeal under paragraph (1) is not issued before the end of the period described in paragraph (2), including any extension under paragraph (3), the appeal shall be denied.<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0135"/></paratext></codes.para><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection><codes.subsection ID="I0c5844e0516c11e990b1a6d77342e6e8"><codes.para><bop/><bos/><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(d) </label.designator><headtext>Exception.—</headtext></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0136"/>This section shall not apply to any class action that solely involves—<end.quote refid="QT_0136"/></paratext><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(1)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0137"/>a claim concerning a covered security as defined under section 16(f) (3) of the Securities Act of 1933 (<cite.query w-src-number="0304913967" w-seq-number="00035" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="15USCAS78P" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I577684006b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">15 U.S.C. 78p(f)(3)</cite.query>) and section 28(f)(5)(E) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<cite.query w-src-number="0304913967" w-seq-number="00036" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="15USCAS78BB" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I577684016b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">15 U.S.C. 78bb(f)(5)(E)</cite.query>);<end.quote refid="QT_0137"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(2)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0138"/>a claim that relates to the internal affairs or governance of a corporation or other form of business enterprise and arises under or by virtue of the laws of the State in which such corporation or business enterprise is incorporated or organized; or<end.quote refid="QT_0138"/></paratext></codes.para><codes.para><head parent="codes.para"><label.designator>(3)</label.designator></head><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0139"/>a claim that relates to the rights, duties (including fiduciary duties), and obligations relating to or created by or pursuant to any security (as defined under section 2(a)(1) of the Securities Act of 1933 (<cite.query w-src-number="0304913967" w-seq-number="00037" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="15USCAS77B" w-pub-number="1000546" ID="I5776d2206b3e11e9bfe8894985907fa8">15 U.S.C. 77b(a)(1)</cite.query>) and the regulations issued thereunder).<eos/><end.quote refid="QT_0139"/></paratext></codes.para><eop/></codes.para></codes.subsection></codes.section></codes.excerpt></section.body></section><author.footnotes><footnote ID="If24456616b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>a0</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Maslon Edelman Borman &amp; Brand, LLP, Minneapolis, Minnesota.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></author.footnotes><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Westlaw. © 2019 Thomson Reuters.  <eos/><bos/>No Claim to Orig. U.S. Govt. <eos/><bos/>Works.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>MDLITMAN § 3:19<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
