<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Multidistrict Lit Man § 6:3<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Multidistrict Litigation Manual</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20190501"><bop/><bos/>May 2019 Update<eos/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><author.line><bop/><bos/><author>David F. Herr[<footnote.reference refid="If4eb5a816b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">a0</footnote.reference>]</author><eos/><eop/></author.line><prop.head toc-guid="I97b7f560933b11da99e2b07024dacc26"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Part</label.name><label.designator>I.</label.designator><headtext>Handling Cases Before the Judicial Panel on Multidistrict Litigation</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="I1c3ad730933c11da99e2b07024dacc26"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>6.</label.designator><headtext>Selection of a Transferee District</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="I94f37569e1e311da9c26e67ca3b71335"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>6:3.</label.designator><headtext>Factors articulated by the Panel in selecting transferee district</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Panel&apos;s decisions on transfer generally recite at least one reason for selecting a particular transferee district; often they shed little light on how the various factors are viewed or weighed by the Panel, however. <eos/><bos/>By reviewing the wide array of decisions, it is possible to discern some valuable insights into the Panel&apos;s decision-making process and priorities.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The factors considered by the Panel can be grouped together, at least to some degree. <eos/><bos/>Broadly, these groups may be viewed as describing the “center of gravity” of the litigation, the views of the parties, the efficiencies inherent in this group of cases, the opportunities for coordination, and those relating to capacity or resources of various courts. <eos/><bos/>These groups often involve consideration of several related factors, but may also involve a single, compelling, factor. <eos/><bos/>For example, to assess the “center of gravity” of the litigation, the Panel looks to where various actions have been filed, where the Panel believes additional actions are likely to be filed, where centrally involved parties are located, and where documents are likely to be found.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4eb81906b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">1</footnote.reference>] In a particular case, however, the fact that the vast majority of the actions have been filed in a particular district may dwarf any other factor in this group.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Similarly, the opportunity to coordinate proceedings may cause the Panel to look at a state where a large number of related cases are pending, where parallel federal criminal or bankruptcy proceedings are being held, or where other federal litigation is underway. <eos/><bos/>Many dockets may not present any opportunities on the coordination front, and this group of factors will be unimportant in the transfer decision. <eos/><bos/>In others, one or more of these factors may be the primary factors considered in selecting a transferee district. <eos/><bos/>The capacity or efficiency of potential districts is evidently a significant group of factors, and may include the consideration of docket conditions, experience (and success in) handling similar complex litigation or experience in handing factually-related litigation. <eos/><bos/>This group of factors can include ease of access to the courthouse (favoring a metropolitan district) and accessibility to the district from the rest of the country by air travel. <eos/><bos/>Because of consideration of this group of factors, transfer to an isolated, district with few judges and a backlogged docket will be unlikely, even if other factors might militate in favor of that forum.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Cataloging the factors the Panel has actually articulated as driving its transfer and transferee-district selection decisions is a relatively easy task. <eos/><bos/>The following sections do so. <eos/><bos/>The much harder task is to predict what is going to be most persuasive in a particular docket. <eos/><bos/>This grouping of factors may be helpful, however, in that it relates to the major concerns the Panel may be considering.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Choice of transferee forum is anything but formulaic. <eos/><bos/>Every “rule” has an exception, and there aren&apos;t even that many clear rules. <eos/><bos/>The major factors vary by type of case, and have evolved over time. <eos/><bos/>The location of documents and witnesses was once a very important factor in selection of a transferee court; in the internet age the Panel recognizes that discovery can be conducted essentially anywhere and the fruits of discovery made available to all parties without needing to travel to the district where the action is pending. <eos/><bos/>While the Panel once tended to transfer to a small core of elite, experienced judges, in recent years it is more interested in transferring to districts and judges having dockets that permit them to give attention to the MDL matter. <eos/><bos/>There is clearly a goal of spreading transfers around the country and to districts and judges who are not overburdened with pending MDL dockets. <eos/><bos/>The overarching goal of the Panel is to use centralization as a tool to accomplish the efficient and effective resolution of litigation. <eos/><bos/>The factors that have affected the Panel&apos;s decision in earlier dockets are informative, but hartly determinative, of the managerial decision the Panel will make in a future docket.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></section.body></section><author.footnotes><footnote ID="If4eb5a816b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>a0</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Maslon Edelman Borman &amp; Brand, LLP, Minneapolis, Minnesota.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></author.footnotes><footnote.block><footnote ID="If4eb81906b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>These factors are individually discussed in <cite.query w-ref-type="NA" w-normalized-cite="MDLITMANs6:4" w-pub-number="185218" ID="If4ece1206b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">§§ 6:4 to 6:22</cite.query>, below.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Westlaw. © 2019 Thomson Reuters.  <eos/><bos/>No Claim to Orig. U.S. Govt. <eos/><bos/>Works.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>MDLITMAN § 6:3<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
