<n-docbody><doc bill="Y"><content.metadata.block><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.second.line.cite><bop/><bos/>Multidistrict Lit Man § 5:59<eos/><eop/></cmd.second.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block><prop.block><prop.head toc-guid=""><bop/><bos/><headtext>Multidistrict Litigation Manual</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><content.metadata.block><cmd.dates><cmd.currency.default iso.d="20190501"><bop/><bos/>May 2019 Update<eos/><eop/></cmd.currency.default></cmd.dates></content.metadata.block><author.line><bop/><bos/><author>David F. Herr[<footnote.reference refid="If4d70f316b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">a0</footnote.reference>]</author><eos/><eop/></author.line><prop.head toc-guid="I97b7f560933b11da99e2b07024dacc26"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Part</label.name><label.designator>I.</label.designator><headtext>Handling Cases Before the Judicial Panel on Multidistrict Litigation</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head><prop.head toc-guid="Id8e3eb20933b11da99e2b07024dacc26"><bop/><bos/><label.name>Chapter</label.name><label.designator>5.</label.designator><headtext>Factors in Deciding Whether Transfer Is Appropriate</headtext><eos/><eop/></prop.head></prop.block><message.block><include.copyright n-include_collection="w_wlnv_msg" n-include_guid="I1DA35ED81DD211B281BAD200220BDFCA">Copyright (c) 2017 Thomson/RIA All rights reserved.</include.copyright></message.block><section><section.front><doc.title toc-guid="I94f37560e1e311da9c26e67ca3b71335"><head parent="doc.title"><bop/><bos/><label.name>§ </label.name><label.designator>5:59.</label.designator><headtext>Partial transfer—Reasons for partial transfer</headtext><eos/><eop/></head></doc.title></section.front><section.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>There are a number of different circumstances that may cause the Panel to exercise its power to separate and remand actions or claims. <eos/><bos/>Although the ultimate reason for not transferring a claim or action while ordering transfer of others is the absence of benefit to be derived from transfer, the Panel has separated and remanded cases in a few well-defined situations.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><bold><ital>Advancement toward Trial.<eos/><bos/></ital></bold> The Panel may decline to transfer a single case because of its advanced progress towards trial despite transferring the balance of the cases to a single district for coordinated or consolidated pretrial proceedings.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4d736406b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">1</footnote.reference>] In one case the Panel initially declined to transfer the case for the same reason, but subsequently transferred the case when it appeared that the case had not progressed as far towards trial as initially thought.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4d736416b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">2</footnote.reference>] In another case the Panel excluded three cases from a transfer order because they had progressed so far towards trial that transfer for coordinated or consolidated pretrial proceedings might not result in any efficiencies.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4d75d506b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">3</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Panel does not order separation and remand in these circumstances unless the differences in the actions are clear. <eos/><bos/>Even if there appear to be differences, the Panel may order transfer with the express indication that it would consider remand if the transferee court agrees with the parties&apos; assessment of readiness for trial.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4d75d516b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">4</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><bold><ital>Unrelatedness.<eos/><bos/></ital></bold> Another basis for separating actions arises when one of the potentially transferable actions appears not to share common factual issues with the others. <eos/><bos/>If the Panel determines to transfer the actions for coordinated or consolidated pretrial proceedings, it may decline to transfer a single action.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4d75d526b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">5</footnote.reference>] If it later appears that the actions do share common issues, however, the action is likely to be transferred as well.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4d75d536b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">6</footnote.reference>] It&apos;s not nice to fool the Panel.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The standard for exercise of the power to separate and remand is a high one. <eos/><bos/>The Panel has stated: <begin.quote ID="QT_0001"/>“[b]efore we exercise that power, however, we must be convinced that the claims to be returned to the transferor court involve little or no factual overlap with the claims to be transferred.”<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0001"/>[<footnote.reference refid="If4d75d546b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">7</footnote.reference>] Separation and remand may be appropriate if one of the cases is fundamentally different from the balance of the litigation, even if some overlap and common factual issues exist. <eos/><bos/>For example, if the Panel orders transfer of a group of securities cases, it may separate and remand a single case presenting conventional breach-of-contract issues.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4d75d556b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">8</footnote.reference>] Similarly, a simple contract action may be separated from antitrust actions ordered transferred for coordinated or consolidated pretrial proceedings.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4d784606b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">9</footnote.reference>] An action asserting claims based on different conduct may be separated and remanded.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4d784616b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">10</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><bold><ital>Claims within Actions.<eos/><bos/></ital></bold> Separation and remand may also be ordered for claims within actions where the actions are transferred for coordinated or consolidated pretrial proceedings. <eos/><bos/>In one case a group of similar cases were pending and the Panel ordered them transferred to a single district. <eos/><bos/>It also ordered that all claims against individual local school districts be separated and remanded to the districts in which they were filed.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4d784626b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">11</footnote.reference>] The Panel has also separated and transferred a counterclaim alleging antitrust violations while it remanded the breach of contract claims of the plaintiff.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4d784636b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">12</footnote.reference>] The Panel will not separate and remand claims that share common factual issues on the grounds of differing legal theories.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4d784646b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">13</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><bold><ital>Tag-Along Cases.<eos/><bos/></ital></bold> Separation and remand is also available in tag-along cases. <eos/><bos/>The Panel essentially remands a tag-along case that it determines does not share sufficient common factual issues with the previously transferred cases or if they would present undue management difficulties to the litigants or the courts.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4d784656b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">14</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Panel has shown in this area, as in most,[<footnote.reference refid="If4d784666b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">15</footnote.reference>] a great willingness to defer to transferee courts on the question of whether cases should be coordinated or consolidated for pre trial proceedings. <eos/><bos/>The Panel has readily found that the transferee judge should determine whether separation and remand are appropriate. <eos/><bos/>In one decision the Panel stated:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0003"/>We are not persuaded that the claims delineated by these parties as purely local in nature involve questions of fact distinct from those arising in other actions. <eos/><bos/>It may be, for example, that alleged instances of local mismanagement reflect practices or policies instituted on a nationwide basis. <eos/><bos/>Upon further refinement of the issues, perhaps some or all of those claims will prove to be unrelated and can be remanded to their transferor courts. <eos/><bos/>We believe that the transferee judge will be in the best position to make that determination. <eos/><bos/>Should he conclude that remand of claims is appropriate, procedures are available whereby this may be accomplished with a minimum of delay.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0003"/>[<footnote.reference refid="If4d7ab706b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">16</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Panel does not readily separate claims within a single civil action, but has done so. <eos/><bos/>For example, the Panel has transferred all claims in a group of actions but separated a single counterclaim and remanded it to the district in which it was filed where it presented simple issues not factually related to those present in the transferred actions.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4d7ab716b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">17</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Panel has also separated cases where the claims against the common defendant had been settled.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4d7ab726b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">18</footnote.reference>] In one case the Panel noted:</paratext><display.quote><para><paratext><begin.quote ID="QT_0004"/>We do not believe, however, that it would advance the just and efficient conduct of the litigation or serve the convenience of the parties or witnesses to transfer the causes of action against those defendants with whom settlement has been reached. <eos/><bos/>Settlement orders have already been entered in the [transferor court] setting out a complex scheme for notice of the settlement to the class, payments from the fund to claiming class members, use of any remaining amounts for the benefit of the class and setting of attorneys fees for plaintiffs&apos; counsel. <eos/><bos/>Effectuation of these settlements under <cite.query w-src-number="0304914061" w-seq-number="00029" w-ref-type="LQ" w-normalized-cite="USFRCPR23" w-pub-number="1000600" ID="I87b19f606b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">Rule 23, Fed. R. Civ. P</cite.query>., will require continuing judicial supervision and we believe it best to leave that supervision in the hands of the transferor court that entered the initial settlement orders.<eos/><bos/><end.quote refid="QT_0004"/>[<footnote.reference refid="If4d7ab736b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">19</footnote.reference>]</paratext></para></display.quote><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Panel may sever separate claims in an action, and transfer only some of them to a single district for coordinated or consolidated pretrial proceedings, remanding the balance for proceedings in the district in which they were filed. <eos/><bos/>In one case the Panel severed certain third-party claims while transferring the balance of the action.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4d7d2806b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">20</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Panel&apos;s willingness to order partial transfer in these cases should not be construed to be a tremendous preference for partial transfer. <eos/><bos/>Indeed, if there is a common thread to the Panel decisions in cases involving separate issues it is that the Panel will be quite likely to order transfer of all the cases and leave to the transferee court questions of how the similarities and differences in the transferred cases can best be managed.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4d7d2816b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">21</footnote.reference>] In one case the Panel ordered transfer of a contractual claim case for coordinated or consolidated pretrial proceedings with antitrust cases it was also transferring. <eos/><bos/>The Panel simply determined that the contract case&apos;s best handling should be decided by the transferee court.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4d7d2826b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">22</footnote.reference>] Similarly, the Panel has rejected arguments that it should bifurcate cases advancing different legal theories in favor of the broad discretion of the transferee judge to fashion an appropriate program for management of pretrial proceedings in the transferred cases.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4d7d2836b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">23</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Panel has sparingly ordered separation and remand. <eos/><bos/>It has rejected arguments that separation and remand should be ordered because of the pendency of motions before the transferor court since the motions can be presented to and decided by the transferee court.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4d7d2846b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">24</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><bold><ital>Transfer to Multiple Districts.<eos/><bos/></ital></bold> Parties have occasionally urged the Panel to separate actions and transfer them for coordinated or consolidated pretrial proceedings in more than one district. <eos/><bos/>This was proposed in the Sugar Antitrust litigation,[<footnote.reference refid="If4d90b006b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">25</footnote.reference>] in which the plaintiffs alleged different geographic areas and different conspiracies to monopolize. <eos/><bos/>The Panel nonetheless declined to divide the cases by transferring them to different transferee courts even if it assumed that different conspiracies and geographic markets were involved.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4d932106b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">26</footnote.reference>] The Panel has reached this result in other multidistrict antitrust cases.[<eos/><bos/><footnote.reference refid="If4d932116b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2">27</footnote.reference>]</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></section.body></section><author.footnotes><footnote ID="If4d70f316b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>a0</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>Maslon Edelman Borman &amp; Brand, LLP, Minneapolis, Minnesota.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></author.footnotes><footnote.block><footnote ID="If4d736406b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>1</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See, e.g.,</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304914061" w-serial-number="2017252629" w-seq-number="00001" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0004637" ID="I87a5df916b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Lending Tree, LLC, Customer Data Security Breach Litigation, 581 F. Supp. 2d 1367 (J.P.M.L. 2008)</cite.query> (advanced state of one mass tort action results in it not being <case.history>transferred</case.history>); <cite.query w-src-number="0304914061" w-serial-number="1986162810" w-seq-number="00002" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="189" ID="I87a5df936b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Dow Chemical Co. Sarabond Products Liability Litigation, 650 F. Supp. 187, 189 (J.P.M.L. 1986)</cite.query> (action only one of fourteen not <case.history>transferred</case.history>); <cite.query w-src-number="0304914061" w-serial-number="1978122006" w-seq-number="00003" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="1170" ID="I87a5df956b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Upjohn Co. Antibiotic “Cleocin” Products Liability Litigation, 450 F. Supp. 1168, 1170–1171 (J.P.M.L. 1978)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0304914061" w-serial-number="1969105529" w-seq-number="00004" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="40" ID="I87a5df976b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Protection Devices and Equipment and Central Station Protection Service Antitrust Cases, 295 F. Supp. 39, 40 (J.P.M.L. 1968)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4d736416b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>2</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304914061" w-serial-number="1969102654" w-seq-number="00005" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="1405" ID="I87a67bd16b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Grain Shipments, 300 F. Supp. 1402, 1405 (J.P.M.L. 1969)</cite.query> (two cases not <case.history>transferred</case.history>); <cite.query w-src-number="0304914061" w-serial-number="1971104971" w-seq-number="00006" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="319" ID="I87a67bd36b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Grain Shipments, 325 F. Supp. 318, 319 (J.P.M.L. 1971)</cite.query> (transfer ordered).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4d75d506b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>3</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304914061" w-serial-number="1970116047" w-seq-number="00007" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="515" ID="I87a718116b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Butterfield Patent Infringement, 328 F. Supp. 513, 515 (J.P.M.L. 1970)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4d75d516b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>4</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See, e.g.</ital>, <cite.query w-src-number="0304914061" w-serial-number="1978123904" w-seq-number="00008" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="677" ID="I87a7b4516b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Helicopter Crash Near Marsh Island, La., on December 8, 1977, 461 F. Supp. 675, 677 (J.P.M.L. 1978)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4d75d526b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>5</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See, e.g.,</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304914061" w-serial-number="2025871927" w-seq-number="00009" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0004637" ID="I87a877a16b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re: Countrywide Financial Corp. Mortgage-Backed Securities Litigation, 812 F. Supp. 2d 1380 (U.S.J.P.M.L. 2011)</cite.query> (transfer of cases except for 4 not involving the common claims); <cite.query w-src-number="0304914061" w-serial-number="2016261911" w-seq-number="00010" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0004637" ID="I87a877a36b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Kugel Mesh Hernia Patch Products Liability Litigation, 560 F. Supp. 2d 1362 (J.P.M.L. 2008)</cite.query> (Panel orders transfer of tag-along actions except for one that includes an entirely different claim); <cite.query w-src-number="0304914061" w-serial-number="1971106511" w-seq-number="00011" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="560" ID="I87a877a56b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Four Seasons Securities Laws Litigation, 331 F. Supp. 559, 560 (J.P.M.L. 1971)</cite.query> (any party allowed to move for transfer should discovery in that action uncover common questions of fact).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4d75d536b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>6</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304914061" w-serial-number="1972105590" w-seq-number="00012" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" ID="I87a913e16b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Four Seasons Securities Litigation, 344 F. Supp. 1404 (J.P.M.L. 1972)</cite.query> (action not <case.history>transferred</case.history> in Fetman transferred).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4d75d546b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>7</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0304914061" w-serial-number="1975105148" w-seq-number="00013" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="1403" ID="I87a9b0216b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Midwest Milk Monopolization Litigation, 386 F. Supp. 1401, 1403 (J.P.M.L. 1975)</cite.query>; <ital>see also</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304914061" w-serial-number="1981102724" w-seq-number="00014" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="650" ID="I87a9b0236b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re 1980 Decennial Census Adjustment Litigation, 506 F. Supp. 648, 650 (J.P.M.L. 1981)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4d75d556b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>8</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0304914061" w-serial-number="1975105493" w-seq-number="00015" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="983" ID="I87aa4c616b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Pennsylvania Life Co. Securities Litigation, 389 F. Supp. 981, 983–984 (J.P.M.L. 1975)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4d784606b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>9</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304914061" w-serial-number="1979115529" w-seq-number="00016" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="962" ID="I87aa9a816b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Uranium Industry Antitrust Litigation, 466 F. Supp. 958, 962 (J.P.M.L. 1979)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4d784616b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>10</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304914061" w-serial-number="2008986093" w-seq-number="00017" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0004637" ID="I87ab0fb16b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Aredia and Zometa Products Liability Litigation, 429 F. Supp. 2d 1371 (J.P.M.L. 2006)</cite.query> (Panel groups cases into one list for transfer, another list of cases involving other defendants and other drugs and denies transfer of that list); <cite.query w-src-number="0304914061" w-serial-number="2006243939" w-seq-number="00018" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0004637" ID="I87ab0fb36b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Vioxx Products Liability Litigation, 360 F. Supp. 2d 1352 (J.P.M.L. 2005)</cite.query> (transfer ordered of mass tort case, but one action involving a different drug not <case.history>transferred</case.history>); <cite.query w-src-number="0304914061" w-serial-number="1976126393" w-seq-number="00019" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="402" ID="I87ab0fb56b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Olympia Brewing Co. Antitrust Litigation, 415 F. Supp. 398, 402 (J.P.M.L. 1976)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4d784626b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>11</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304914061" w-serial-number="1979140135" w-seq-number="00020" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="328" ID="I87abfa116b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Alien Children Ed. Litigation, 482 F. Supp. 326, 328 (J.P.M.L. 1979)</cite.query> (claims present only <begin.quote ID="QT_0002"/>“minimal, if any, common questions of fact”<end.quote refid="QT_0002"/>).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4d784636b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>12</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304914061" w-serial-number="1979115529" w-seq-number="00021" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="962" ID="I87ac48316b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Uranium Industry Antitrust Litigation, 466 F. Supp. 958, 962 (J.P.M.L. 1979)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4d784646b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>13</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304914061" w-serial-number="1972105164" w-seq-number="00022" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="1402" ID="I87acbd616b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Air Crash Disaster at Huntington, W. Va. on November 14, 1970, 342 F. Supp. 1400, 1402 (J.P.M.L. 1972)</cite.query> (third-party claims not separated).<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4d784656b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>14</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0304914061" w-serial-number="1975108589" w-seq-number="00023" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="1401" ID="I87ad80b16b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Mack Trucks, Inc. Antitrust Litigation, 405 F. Supp. 1400, 1401 (J.P.M.L. 1975)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4d784666b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>15</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Panel&apos;s deference to the transferee court is discussed at length in Chapter 9. The limitations on the power of the Panel requiring it to have a limited role are discussed in Chapter 3.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4d7ab706b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>16</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See, e.g.</ital>, <cite.query w-src-number="0304914061" w-serial-number="1981102724" w-seq-number="00024" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="650" ID="I87af07516b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re 1980 Decennial Census Adjustment Litigation, 506 F. Supp. 648, 650–51 (J.P.M.L. 1981)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0304914061" w-serial-number="1975108425" w-seq-number="00025" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="318" ID="I87af07536b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Westinghouse Elec. Corp. Uranium Contracts Litigation, 405 F. Supp. 316, 318 n.7 (J.P.M.L. 1975)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0304914061" w-serial-number="1975105148" w-seq-number="00026" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="1403" ID="I87af07556b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Midwest Milk Monopolization Litigation, 386 F. Supp. 1401, 1403 (J.P.M.L. 1975)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4d7ab716b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>17</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0304914061" w-serial-number="1973106613" w-seq-number="00027" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="461" ID="I87afcaa16b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Boise Cascade Securities Litigation, 364 F. Supp. 459, 461 (J.P.M.L. 1973)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4d7ab726b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>18</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304914061" w-serial-number="1969103260" w-seq-number="00028" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="799" ID="I87b03fd16b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re IBM, 302 F. Supp. 796, 799 (J.P.M.L. 1969)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4d7ab736b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>19</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0304914061" w-serial-number="1972104858" w-seq-number="00030" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="773" ID="I87b1c6716b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Hotel Telephone Charge Antitrust Litigation, 341 F. Supp. 771, 773 (J.P.M.L. 1972)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4d7d2806b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>20</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304914061" w-serial-number="1971104969" w-seq-number="00031" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="311" ID="I87b262b16b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Penn Cent. Securities Litigation, 325 F. Supp. 309, 311–12 (J.P.M.L. 1971)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4d7d2816b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>21</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext>The Panel&apos;s deference to the transferee court in matters of managing the actions after transfer is discussed in greater detail in Chapter 9.</paratext><eos/><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4d7d2826b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>22</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304914061" w-serial-number="1973105561" w-seq-number="00032" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="544" ID="I87b39b316b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Cessna Aircraft Distributorship Antitrust Litigation, 359 F. Supp. 543, 544 (J.P.M.L. 1973)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4d7d2836b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>23</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304914061" w-serial-number="1974105890" w-seq-number="00033" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="1384" ID="I87b410616b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Equity Funding Corp. of America Securities Litigation, 375 F. Supp. 1378, 1384 (J.P.M.L. 1973)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4d7d2846b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>24</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See</ital> <cite.query w-src-number="0304914061" w-serial-number="1975107076" w-seq-number="00034" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="678" ID="I87b485916b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Midwest Milk Monopolization Litigation, 398 F. Supp. 676, 678 (J.P.M.L. 1975)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4d90b006b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>25</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0304914061" w-serial-number="1975106597" w-seq-number="00035" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" ID="I87b597016b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Sugar Industry Antitrust Litigation, 395 F. Supp. 1271 (J.P.M.L. 1975)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4d932106b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>26</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><cite.query w-src-number="0304914061" w-serial-number="1975106597" w-seq-number="00036" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" w-pinpoint-page="1273" ID="I87b60c316b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">395 F. Supp. at 1273</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote><footnote ID="If4d932116b3e11e99b03e53d6dd36aa2"><label.designator>27</label.designator><footnote.body><para><bop/><bos/><paratext><ital>See, e.g.</ital>, <cite.query w-src-number="0304914061" w-serial-number="1974106650" w-seq-number="00037" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" ID="I87b65a516b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Midwest Milk Monopolization Litigation, 379 F. Supp. 989 (J.P.M.L. 1974)</cite.query>; <cite.query w-src-number="0304914061" w-serial-number="1969105439" w-seq-number="00038" w-ref-type="RP" w-pub-number="0000345" ID="I87b65a536b3e11e99f73e2698c313519">In re Plumbing Fixture Cases, 295 F. Supp. 33 (J.P.M.L. 1968)</cite.query>.<eos/></paratext><eop/></para></footnote.body></footnote></footnote.block><content.metadata.block><cmd.royalty><cmd.copyright><bop/><bos/>Westlaw. © 2019 Thomson Reuters.  <eos/><bos/>No Claim to Orig. U.S. Govt. <eos/><bos/>Works.<eos/><eop/></cmd.copyright></cmd.royalty><cmd.identifiers><cmd.cites><cmd.first.line.cite><bop/><bos/>MDLITMAN § 5:59<eos/><eop/></cmd.first.line.cite></cmd.cites></cmd.identifiers></content.metadata.block></doc></n-docbody>
